<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 19:10:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 19:10:20 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Everything you need to know about voting right now]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Denis Novikov/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/24039536/GettyImages_1353809931.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Election season is in full swing, and in case you’ve forgotten the specifics, the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections">2024 election</a> will take place on Tuesday, November 5. Americans will be casting their votes in a historic presidential race, as well as a slew of other federal, state, and local offices. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before Americans cast their ballot, there are a few bits of practical information they should have on hand:<strong> </strong>They’ll want to make sure they’re registered to vote, know where their polling place is, and what forms of identification to bring with them (if any). Here’s what you should know about voting in this election.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Are you registered to vote?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You must be registered to vote before stepping into the voting booth. (<a href="https://vote.gov/register/nd/">Except in North Dakota</a>, which does not have voter registration.) Some states, like California, Washington, Michigan, and Maine, allow <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/same-day-registration.aspx">same-day registration</a> at the polls on Election Day. Other states require <a href="https://www.vote.org/voter-registration-deadlines/">voters to register</a> anywhere from 10 days (Massachusetts) to 30 days (Alaska, Arkansas, Mississippi, Ohio) ahead of the election. The <a href="https://www.usvotefoundation.org/vote/state-elections/state-election-dates-deadlines.htm">US Vote Foundation</a> has a tool that lists election deadlines, including for voter registration, by state. Depending on where you live, you can register online, in person at a local election office, or by mail. Vote.gov has state-by-state resources on <a href="https://vote.gov/">how to register to vote</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.usa.gov/who-can-vote">In order to register to vote</a>, you must be a US citizen, at least 18 years old by Election Day, and meet your state’s eligibility requirements. In some states, people <a href="https://www.justice.gov/voting/file/1507306/downloadhttps://www.justice.gov/d9/2024-01/voting_with_a_criminal_conviction_7.6.23.pdf">currently incarcerated or convicted for a felony</a> do not have the right to vote. The <a href="https://www.usvotefoundation.org/state-voter-information"><strong>US Vote Foundation</strong></a> has an online tool that lists voter requirements and registration options for each state.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you can’t remember whether you’re registered to vote, <a href="https://www.vote.org/am-i-registered-to-vote/">you can check online</a>. For people who moved, or changed their name or party affiliation, since the last election, you’ll need to <a href="https://www.usa.gov/change-voter-registration">update your voter registration</a>. You can change this information online via your state’s online voter registration website, by mail, by phone, or in person the same way you would to register. If you moved to another state, you will need to re-register in your new state.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Do you know how you’ll cast your vote?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How much flexibility you have about when and where you vote depends on where you live. Voters can cast their ballots in person on Election Day, <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/early-voting-in-state-elections.aspx">in person during early voting</a>, or by mail (also referred to as voting absentee). Some states — like California, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania — <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/vopp-table-1-states-with-no-excuse-absentee-voting.aspx">do not require voters to list a reason to vote by mail</a>. Voters in states like Alabama and Kentucky <a href="https://tracker.votingrightslab.org/issues/requesting-mail-ballots">must give a reason to vote by mail</a>, like being too sick to vote or not being in the country. Be aware of both the deadlines for requesting a mail ballot and for postmarking it in order to be counted; you can find both dates by selecting your state on the <a href="https://www.usvotefoundation.org/vote/state-elections/state-election-dates-deadlines.htm">US Vote Foundation’s tool</a>. Either mail your ballot in via USPS, drop it off at an election office, or locate a dropbox (each county will list the locations of its ballot drop boxes online).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you are traveling or have to work a long shift on Election Day, you may want to vote early in person. <a href="https://www.vote.org/early-voting-calendar/">Early voting windows</a> vary from state to state (and even county to county) and can begin as early as 45 days before the election&nbsp; like in <a href="https://sos.vermont.gov/elections/voters/early-absentee-voting/">Vermont</a>). Check to see your <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/early-voting-in-state-elections.aspx">state’s rules for early in-person voting</a> and where you can cast your vote before Election Day.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For in-person voting on Election Day, you can find your polling place on your state’s board of elections website, which you can <a href="https://www.vote.org/polling-place-locator/">find on Vote.org</a>. All you’ll need is to enter your name and/or address. Most states have laws allowing employees to take time off to vote, but <a href="https://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/taking-time-off-voting-jury-29708.html">specifics vary from state to state</a>. For example, workers in Alabama, Arkansas, Georgia, Kentucky, Massachusetts, North Dakota, and Wisconsin are not paid for time off to vote. Other states, including Idaho, Maine, Michigan, New Jersey, and Virginia, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/11/01/us-states-where-employers-have-to-give-you-paid-time-off-to-vote.html">do not have laws granting employees time off to vote</a>. Workers in states like Maryland and Oklahoma <a href="https://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/taking-time-off-voting-jury-29708.html">must show their employers proof</a> that they voted or attempted to vote.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A final method of voting is via a <a href="https://electionlab.mit.edu/research/provisional-ballots">provisional ballot</a>. This occurs when a voter’s name is not on the voter roll but the person believes they are registered. They can cast their vote on a provisional ballot that won’t be counted until the registration status of the person is confirmed after the polls close. <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/provisional-ballots.aspx#how">Local election officials will verify the voter’s identity</a> and the voter may have to confirm their address or other information. The <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/elections-and-campaigns/provisional-ballots#how">main reasons provisional ballots are rejected</a> are when the voter is not registered in the state they are trying to vote in, or they are in the wrong jurisdiction.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Do you know who’s on the ballot?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Top billing for this election is voting for president. <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/367990/kamala-harris-policy-positions-issues-guide">Vice President Kamala Harris</a> is the Democratic candidate, and former President <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368004/donald-trump-policy-positions-issues-guide">Donald Trump</a> is the Republican nominee. You may also be voting for governor, Senate, and House of Representatives, as well as lieutenant governor, state attorney general, secretary of state, state legislators, judges, mayor, district attorney, city council, and ballot measures. You can look up a sample ballot on <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/wiki/index.php?title=Sample_Ballot_Lookup&amp;Source=sidebar">Ballotpedia</a> to find out which candidates are running for which seats in your district. Ballotpedia also explains the wording and interpretation of ballot measures, which can be difficult to parse.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To find out where these candidates stand on important issues, you can check their campaign websites, read local news coverage, and tune in to debates.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What to expect on Election Day</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before you show up to your polling place, double check the <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/State_Poll_Opening_and_Closing_Times_(2024)">hours the site opens and closes.</a> While it differs by state (and even by county), most polling stations open between 6 and 9 am and close between 6 and 9 pm local time. Remember, if you are still in line when the polls close, <a href="https://www.aclu.org/know-your-rights/voting-rights">you are allowed to vote, so don’t leave</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once inside, you’ll check in with a poll worker who will find your name on the list of registered voters. If the poll worker says they <a href="https://www.aclu.org/know-your-rights/voting-rights">can’t find your name</a>, ask if they can check a statewide list or help you make sure you’re at the correct polling place. If they still can’t find your name, ask for a provisional ballot.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some states require voters to <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/elections-and-campaigns/voter-id">show identification prior to voting</a> — like Indiana and Wisconsin — or ask that first-time voters show ID. The National Conference of State Legislatures lists the <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/elections-and-campaigns/voter-id.aspx">voter ID laws for each state</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The poll worker will then show you to the <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Voting_methods_and_equipment_by_state">voting machine or where you’ll fill out a paper ballot</a> and tell you how to cast your vote. <a href="https://allvotingislocal.org/poll-worker-faq/">Poll workers are available to answer any questions</a> you may have.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.aclu.org/know-your-rights/voting-rights">Voters with disabilities</a> can ask for a chair to sit in, a quiet place to wait for their turn to vote, and to use a voting machine that assists those with vision and mobility disabilities — every polling place must have at least one. Voters with disabilities and who have trouble reading and writing English can also bring a family member or friend to offer assistance.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If anyone questions you about your citizenship, your criminal history, your ethnicity, your race, the language you speak, or your education level, that’s voter intimidation — and it’s illegal. <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Intimidation_of_voters">Other examples of voter intimidation </a>include violent behavior inside and outside the polling place, blocking the entrance of a polling place, displaying weapons, threats of violence, and spreading false information of voter fraud.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.aclu.org/sites/default/files/field_pdf_file/kyr-voterintimidation-v03.pdf">According to the ACLU</a>, “if your qualifications are challenged, you can give a sworn statement that you satisfy the qualifications to vote in your state, and then proceed to cast a regular ballot.”<br><a href="https://www.aclu.org/know-your-rights/voting-rights">Report an instance of voter intimidation</a>, whether you yourself experienced it or you witnessed it, to your local election officials and the Election Protection Hotline at 1-866-OUR-VOTE or 1-888-VE-Y-VOTA (en Español).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, October 8, 3:05 pm: </em></strong><em>This story was originally published on September 20, 2022, and has been updated to include new information regarding the 2024 election season.</em></p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/even-better/23363748/voting-guide-registration-polling-place-voter-suppression</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/even-better/23363748/voting-guide-registration-polling-place-voter-suppression</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Allie Volpe]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 19:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[1000s Of Terrorists Including Nasrallah, His Successor Killed: Israeli PM]]></title><description><![CDATA[Israeli forces have killed the would-be successors of late Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Tuesday, without naming them.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-1000s-of-terrorists-including-nasrallah-his-successor-killed-israeli-pm-6746957</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-1000s-of-terrorists-including-nasrallah-his-successor-killed-israeli-pm-6746957</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 17:53:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Live Updates: Iranian and Syrian Media Report Strike in Damascus]]></title><description><![CDATA[The reports, some of which said the strike was near the Iranian Embassy in the Syrian capital, came as Israel continued its campaign in Lebanon against Hezbollah, an Iranian proxy. Iranian and Syrian reports blamed Israel, but the Israeli military had no comment.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/10/08/world/israel-iran-lebanon-hezbollah</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/10/08/world/israel-iran-lebanon-hezbollah</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 19:07:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What We Know About the Israeli Forces Fighting in Lebanon]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Israeli military has sent troops from four divisions across the border into Lebanon, but has not publicly disclosed how many.]]></description><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/08/world/middleeast/israel-military-lebanon.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/08/world/middleeast/israel-military-lebanon.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:55:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 takeaways from Kamala Harris’ one-on-one interview with ‘60 Minutes’ - CNN]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOaVhpeE9ERFpqbEVwSVB4cjdraWdYUEtDaFlyR0VoaE1YTktKeGpKTFBoaUNoM0J5TUVtUGRtNDJ5M0luM0o5c3FROTY0cEpJNm9rV1BGdHAyTzJoQlNpcmd6MGlUU0F1bmo3eHVrVVFmT1VkVXI1bmVFQ1R1MmlwZ2duYkU4QjVEMlpkV1F30gGEAUFVX3lxTE1ib1BqR3NtQ3RHSlFvUFVNYlBOUzRFb0VWRllJVWtNVU9vWmx3WjBjWVhGVUllUWVjMUo2ZlJMX05TbnVFVXRBVjBvY3dPRmdaNEhkR2dnX0VTLURaSkFSZTBZSUVhV0NNajUtSG5Wam12U2hTQlU0eTRoMWlYbXdIZ0N6cQ?oc=5" target="_blank">5 takeaways from Kamala Harris’ one-on-one interview with ‘60 Minutes’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVkFVX3lxTE1GMDVLQlY3TkRzdWk2a0RUcE9xaHZDVnVYTVBKMTlNZVg5b1JyOFpnX0daZ18xQkN1UlBfUGp5b2RsX0c2eDdWZ2hwbU9wUlRUSFdtOFhR?oc=5" target="_blank">Vice President Harris BOMBS '60 Minutes' Interview! PLUS, Gov. DeSantis calls her out over hurricane | Will Cain Show</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMickFVX3lxTE1za1duc1ltUG5UV0xVQU9zRi1GUnJqZkJCX1hpVTYwb1VkUHV1a0tZVnBXQ2l1Qmd2dWRZdWF2NjUyTG9kZDgxV0R0d1l1Tnk5cDFwQ1JaU1dFWW55MWFtb2VEVmIwdkFQLTVyVmNrelh3QQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris Visits 'The View' in Continued Media Push and Denounces Trump: Election Live Updates</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVkFVX3lxTE9WWVF2UGRXakUxVjIydTRjZzhIRmpDb1llY0E1aVVldlJjMkphTUFiTGhJQUhFS2o2aGN6MDRuNEtta1BDUHNqbXFBbDl0NEtWTFppZXJ3?oc=5" target="_blank">Kennedy roasts Kamala Harris for ‘View’ appearance: What an ‘unserious buffoon’</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOTXM5TGdIbHhGSmpZd204ekZsYnV3dzM5QVBLSWRrdnFSWWt6QmtDWnVQc1JueHFyc3pQeEFMLUJ3UkVRSHpnZ0hZMjdDWEFWcjl0cE95SzkyX09IMFljQlV3VVNnLTRYcFA0MzlxSzJCY0pncVN1SjRSeHpwY0lpOThDNlhqdHJ6dDRxZnV5R3hWRUJ1dHZPYWpyelk?oc=5" target="_blank">Election 2024 live updates: Harris appears on ‘The View,’ with Howard Stern, Stephen Colbert</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOaVhpeE9ERFpqbEVwSVB4cjdraWdYUEtDaFlyR0VoaE1YTktKeGpKTFBoaUNoM0J5TUVtUGRtNDJ5M0luM0o5c3FROTY0cEpJNm9rV1BGdHAyTzJoQlNpcmd6MGlUU0F1bmo3eHVrVVFmT1VkVXI1bmVFQ1R1MmlwZ2duYkU4QjVEMlpkV1F30gGEAUFVX3lxTE1ib1BqR3NtQ3RHSlFvUFVNYlBOUzRFb0VWRllJVWtNVU9vWmx3WjBjWVhGVUllUWVjMUo2ZlJMX05TbnVFVXRBVjBvY3dPRmdaNEhkR2dnX0VTLURaSkFSZTBZSUVhV0NNajUtSG5Wam12U2hTQlU0eTRoMWlYbXdIZ0N6cQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOaVhpeE9ERFpqbEVwSVB4cjdraWdYUEtDaFlyR0VoaE1YTktKeGpKTFBoaUNoM0J5TUVtUGRtNDJ5M0luM0o5c3FROTY0cEpJNm9rV1BGdHAyTzJoQlNpcmd6MGlUU0F1bmo3eHVrVVFmT1VkVXI1bmVFQ1R1MmlwZ2duYkU4QjVEMlpkV1F30gGEAUFVX3lxTE1ib1BqR3NtQ3RHSlFvUFVNYlBOUzRFb0VWRllJVWtNVU9vWmx3WjBjWVhGVUllUWVjMUo2ZlJMX05TbnVFVXRBVjBvY3dPRmdaNEhkR2dnX0VTLURaSkFSZTBZSUVhV0NNajUtSG5Wam12U2hTQlU0eTRoMWlYbXdIZ0N6cQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 10:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump Secretly Stayed in Touch With Putin After Leaving Office, Book Says - The New York Times]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxPS2k5cTFULUFCS0N6aUpLMWRja2pXUFNkalRYd1M4cklUSWl1WDV1TDhWQm5HVVphWjM2SEpyNnY1ejBzbldCYmFnVl9tYVBrNEVKb0h5ZXphcG1KS2QzRmNKN2tjTVJEOHBzcnlUaUYzM0tlZHJnQUlYV2tLQ2RxQ0J0RQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump Secretly Stayed in Touch With Putin After Leaving Office, Book Says</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxQZkRXaGctMUMtU3hVdVpNZnZXNFFxMUdTWHhUZ2ttSm5CYlhTdDZxS3pIOU9wMTN5ZXkxaUtZT1JKUXFXa25Ca2dfUzNDdW55TTBqcWRnaE05cDhDcXg0MlBoSlBMT2FsdndlLTdBeGRBa1A2T2JMTGNLWVlZWHlGblpHUmxJYjJORktZ?oc=5" target="_blank">5 key revelations from Bob Woodward’s new book</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxNc0N5Qnl4MjFNaWswd2wzSjRtY1d5ZTMxYUN3OTJkV0toZU5FTUw4dDhHcVFTZXpRNjVyQVRaZUFvSEE1cWh5cjI4X1RBSWpPVW14TjI5X1A5eWR6cXhZNHZYT240a0RNb2hUYUpyamEyenVrZDdkbEx3c2NGZWJOT3pTUmFldjZUc3FQMDBib2NCVFg0ZWcteUpkcVJMQW5Jc0lHT2JtN2NScTNsQkZyODNGMlphWm9MejFYekFfVmxWZXd4REsw?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris continues media blitz with appearance on The View as she takes narrow lead over Trump in new poll: Live</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Independent</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxOckxBU2ZxcHJCMnZ5M0FpQm9TNmNZYVlFREYxdkRCZ1l2dzJSYkJoaVhHckZnV2F5cEJMRThFZWZCZXJ5ak9JUlpGUVpEOW1SdjE0Z0Y0ajlHSVdObE0xRXNzZDRMQkdaSzVvdzF0ekhGNnR6Y2tOZzU2cGJHVlAwYm9ZU2NYamlFUGJDcGw5RGVWLU9Ram5j0gGXAUFVX3lxTE5FcmxZX29pejJhWTB4ZmgwLVJVR0VZVm1JRjdRakh3OWZ5NkVwaHhSS2tVVEVhYVJkZjNESUtoVmZZZ0pjT3M3LWVjbFY0dDltVDN4NXhxTk4ybURFUUhwb1ZnbmVCa09lcHBrby10eDI4WERpSEhqSy1vaUdvWjRHWGcxX0d2ZWg4VWxCMHluMzgweG1sa1k?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump secretly gave Putin Covid test machines, Bob Woodward book says</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Guardian US</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPTU9maFNxUzZnZU02aWZjLXhCaThmeHQ3d2VGaGU3UEI1UEdnalAtTEdWZnpRZmtLbG45WlN3bUdRM0loQUo1cHBsbE5WeXJGZUZnOXNaM3d3NzJhcjNoMWdwRzRYSW80TktkMUs0SHdsc3g5WEtWLXNzVkZsMkVsT2xNRGRiLU85Z0NxbkR0dy1idlVWZF9PNUV5MF9PSFF4Q0ozeVRR?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump and Putin have talked as many as 7 times since 2021, new book claims</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxPS2k5cTFULUFCS0N6aUpLMWRja2pXUFNkalRYd1M4cklUSWl1WDV1TDhWQm5HVVphWjM2SEpyNnY1ejBzbldCYmFnVl9tYVBrNEVKb0h5ZXphcG1KS2QzRmNKN2tjTVJEOHBzcnlUaUYzM0tlZHJnQUlYV2tLQ2RxQ0J0RQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxPS2k5cTFULUFCS0N6aUpLMWRja2pXUFNkalRYd1M4cklUSWl1WDV1TDhWQm5HVVphWjM2SEpyNnY1ejBzbldCYmFnVl9tYVBrNEVKb0h5ZXphcG1KS2QzRmNKN2tjTVJEOHBzcnlUaUYzM0tlZHJnQUlYV2tLQ2RxQ0J0RQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:01:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Former New York City Hall Official Charged With Witness Tampering And Destruction Of Evidence - Department of Justice]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQdGl0aGVyYmhkVmQ1THJUYjJ0T0Q1MzhuRW1yMmw1QzR1eDdEak9QSm1WSzJQV0tSc2N2WnRJMzVjWnRNOFBYUEZCZDBsM2tHeUFFR2dkTzM3RmxQbC1HMHVQZWdKLXZETEVSZHEtNlFPUkFDY3N1RWVsYmN0RjRjUlU5Z0JTczNEY3R2a3JJOTNhd2tfNy1TbzFxZTdMbGNtT2xZYzRUdHpLNl9vR2h0YzZDb1czdEF2ZTF6aGRfQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Former New York City Hall Official Charged With Witness Tampering And Destruction Of Evidence</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Department of Justice</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxQNzdWWGRGZ0IxeWtSQTFNY1RsNGpkRHgxY1N3WGh0aDExOExSaHlMNjB0UDdGYkNtT09CTl83RFpSTWNUbnRnNVdLaEZQbnlCcThYRnhrRmgwX0RPd1BBMFZyQkl6cWdEdjQwVURxdVNKSEpEVk1na25obWVaemZKU1lubzExV3BncUJRWl9Ma2JvYy1KSTZXMng5WDN5RGJ5dmk2cm5QTVhJeFBGR3JlRk5JTC1kV3hFeVR1V3NfbXZpZEF2NVJwUFl4WXItWjVsNzhYNzdPRFd1Y2dCQXNSLWNyTEvSAewBQVVfeXFMT0xucXRRVE5fQlZvZnVvNkpheXZpUHNTcUtOQ24yaGFQdXZzNzF5clFBbXhLcG80MTFsMlRKREpwUEFod0h3VGtSUnVsTHdXYktqbzdlQXNNckpmclg1RUVyTXJWd1VBcnV0bllHRlU2RnZLdGwtaUhTMVJLWkhLaWVTZ0RHOFc2VkhZRm9XOHFkM29uUVdhSEdqTUNaOTQ4QnlWV0tXUENvVnhyOWp6OUlVTVpheTlvYmZGdTRyMmpWN09WYU95UVFuTG11NGxHS29OQ2U3TGt2b0h1MmhoTGFWaExnV0NCTjNzUno?oc=5" target="_blank">Ex-Adams aide charged with witness tampering in campaign finance probe day after resigning</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC New York</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxQckF5emJVY1dISjBtcDB5a0wtOTRpNXhUVE02b0NMQ0lDaWxhRkxOajNWcFhqRXZNdGFMSzVqZ3lRQjU5cVhfNkNyaDhpakdhRXR4X2pQdzJMODBZN3p2RW9jWlY2ZXZpWlBqdlpOTm5oa1RXVmZSaXVnMEhfY2p6a3hR?oc=5" target="_blank">City Hall Official Charged With Witness Tampering in Adams Inquiry</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPR0ZEMWhvQXE2b1JjcUY2RndRWHFiWGlvSG9fT0RYaFpXRUVTNTJCY09sTXZhbmdvRnBEc05yUC1CNFp3cnlpd1hSN2k3c0hTaUtJa0VoY0RSU1hKLTdDNWFDOW84Y0Z2T1FoY1gtd25OR3hrREhKSi1iUk9FY3pyUHhkSjlWb2c3Q2NVcW1zRWJ4akxJWWkxNmdERQ?oc=5" target="_blank">A former aide to New York Mayor Eric Adams is charged with destroying evidence as top deputy quits</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxNV0NXWU96SmlQT05lbUIwX1RuVk9HMXE2X0xWbTVVWWYyRG1hRE5QdjB3c0ZvekNwTFhUczhDalVkVnQzMHg5dmpSWndJNFhSWDlBcHl5R0VaWnhtczd6bFM0RmxLcFFpLWxCNFNxSnpDWUZ5TzdEV2IxVlFFRmlsOEN6QjFLUnNORXBaSERhWTB6b1c5NXFIRDl3M1lDQXgxdXpMc200SlExblF0Ml9nVGk4X2dyZWJ4dzFvQ0tYQTZVcDNaTzYxS1UzOG9EQU5DUnJjetIB2gFBVV95cUxOWHhjTW92a0Y0UGxZTmdjWUhiYUhRU3RIYmxoWHliOVdoY1pTNjdrQTlCS29EczRCZEtNaFhMRk5SZDNyYmdDTVR3YWQ1UlU5cnpJa0lfNkpWbkd5Rkxyb3V1cTFpNUR1YXBFNGZzOXdNeVM5aHNxdWt3Wl9kNWZhVTBhbDR1dEZTRkExaHJpTkpRT2h3Y3V6emJpSkFYWjFTcE9rS1VMcXY1SHN4OG9rbGlQV2hCd3FNSGlkRXA2bTRHcWVwMDBkaHBiMkpVNlVSNC1GYlhuSGs3QQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Former City Hall official Mohamed Bahi arrested, charged with witness tampering in Mayor Eric Adams investigation</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC7 New York</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQdGl0aGVyYmhkVmQ1THJUYjJ0T0Q1MzhuRW1yMmw1QzR1eDdEak9QSm1WSzJQV0tSc2N2WnRJMzVjWnRNOFBYUEZCZDBsM2tHeUFFR2dkTzM3RmxQbC1HMHVQZWdKLXZETEVSZHEtNlFPUkFDY3N1RWVsYmN0RjRjUlU5Z0JTczNEY3R2a3JJOTNhd2tfNy1TbzFxZTdMbGNtT2xZYzRUdHpLNl9vR2h0YzZDb1czdEF2ZTF6aGRfQQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQdGl0aGVyYmhkVmQ1THJUYjJ0T0Q1MzhuRW1yMmw1QzR1eDdEak9QSm1WSzJQV0tSc2N2WnRJMzVjWnRNOFBYUEZCZDBsM2tHeUFFR2dkTzM3RmxQbC1HMHVQZWdKLXZETEVSZHEtNlFPUkFDY3N1RWVsYmN0RjRjUlU5Z0JTczNEY3R2a3JJOTNhd2tfNy1TbzFxZTdMbGNtT2xZYzRUdHpLNl9vR2h0YzZDb1czdEF2ZTF6aGRfQQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 13:51:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Osama bin Laden's son ordered to leave France, says minister]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fywldj/osama_bin_ladens_son_ordered_to_leave_france_says/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/cE3aOh--vIhAme4OL_qovPayi_ZIcBS7Adk9MXYi55g.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=df9a8bedacedb1d4b48fb495d847fb84ca75524c" alt="Osama bin Laden's son ordered to leave France, says minister" title="Osama bin Laden's son ordered to leave France, says minister" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/pierrepaul"> /u/pierrepaul </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/en/politics/article/2024/10/08/osama-bin-laden-s-son-ordered-to-leave-france-says-minister_6728613_5.html">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fywldj/osama_bin_ladens_son_ordered_to_leave_france_says/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fywldj/osama_bin_ladens_son_ordered_to_leave_france_says/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fywldj/osama_bin_ladens_son_ordered_to_leave_france_says/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/pierrepaul]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 10:32:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hungary blocks EU sanctions changes, holding up $50 billion G7 loan package for Ukraine]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz5vaz/hungary_blocks_eu_sanctions_changes_holding_up_50/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/zjmDy6XDmRFz2ACR8xLJexQYvRJUyJ1ePsX26NlB4lM.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=c8502757dcdbaeffec02cb78cd224444ddd43665" alt="Hungary blocks EU sanctions changes, holding up $50 billion G7 loan package for Ukraine" title="Hungary blocks EU sanctions changes, holding up $50 billion G7 loan package for Ukraine" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/nurshakil10"> /u/nurshakil10 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://kyivindependent.com/hungary-to-hold-up-50-billion-g7-loan-for-ukraine-until-after-the-us-election/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz5vaz/hungary_blocks_eu_sanctions_changes_holding_up_50/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz5vaz/hungary_blocks_eu_sanctions_changes_holding_up_50/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz5vaz/hungary_blocks_eu_sanctions_changes_holding_up_50/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/nurshakil10]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 17:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[France to deliver first Mirage 2000 jets to Ukraine in early 2025]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fyynbx/france_to_deliver_first_mirage_2000_jets_to/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/RMEmcFNdEx8k-dY3ukAb8-JvIoKixPH4QGfrHZgk3Fs.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=ebba283d2f939f6db0caa28264bc20822e48abaf" alt="France to deliver first Mirage 2000 jets to Ukraine in early 2025" title="France to deliver first Mirage 2000 jets to Ukraine in early 2025" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/AdSpecialist6598"> /u/AdSpecialist6598 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://kyivindependent.com/france-jets-ukraine/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fyynbx/france_to_deliver_first_mirage_2000_jets_to/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fyynbx/france_to_deliver_first_mirage_2000_jets_to/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fyynbx/france_to_deliver_first_mirage_2000_jets_to/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/AdSpecialist6598]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 12:32:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel’s military expands invasion into south-west Lebanon]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz274a/israels_military_expands_invasion_into_southwest/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/826nLjV4IbrRrYDdZjq7Er_hAg1IZTSx5mNQULA3m9Q.jpg?width=640&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=86d7d3242ac100fe6621977925372f02fe8b3bd2" alt="Israel’s military expands invasion into south-west Lebanon" title="Israel’s military expands invasion into south-west Lebanon" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/GeoWa"> /u/GeoWa </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cly3x1w0595o">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz274a/israels_military_expands_invasion_into_southwest/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz274a/israels_military_expands_invasion_into_southwest/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz274a/israels_military_expands_invasion_into_southwest/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/GeoWa]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 15:13:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hezbollah calls for unconditional cease-fire regardless of fighting in Gaza]]></title><description><![CDATA[<table> <tr><td> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz71yl/hezbollah_calls_for_unconditional_ceasefire/"> <img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/uTNnn7PmTI61XpVazHyXFlOTET2vCb6f-8pXejbI_lM.jpg?width=320&amp;crop=smart&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=549ff4c3d61e44a1f1859f372f5e75b78f967170" alt="Hezbollah calls for unconditional cease-fire regardless of fighting in Gaza" title="Hezbollah calls for unconditional cease-fire regardless of fighting in Gaza" /> </a> </td><td> &#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Brilliant_User_7673"> /u/Brilliant_User_7673 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.ynetnews.com/article/h1huyrz1ye">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz71yl/hezbollah_calls_for_unconditional_ceasefire/">[comments]</a></span> </td></tr></table>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz71yl/hezbollah_calls_for_unconditional_ceasefire/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fz71yl/hezbollah_calls_for_unconditional_ceasefire/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Brilliant_User_7673]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:35:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israeli tanks push deeper into Jabalia in northern Gaza, residents say]]></title><description><![CDATA[&#32; submitted by &#32; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Advanced_Drink_8536"> /u/Advanced_Drink_8536 </a> <br/> <span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-tanks-push-deeper-into-jabalia-northern-gaza-residents-say-2024-10-08/">[link]</a></span> &#32; <span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fyuqu9/israeli_tanks_push_deeper_into_jabalia_in/">[comments]</a></span>]]></description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fyuqu9/israeli_tanks_push_deeper_into_jabalia_in/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/worldnews/comments/1fyuqu9/israeli_tanks_push_deeper_into_jabalia_in/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[/u/Advanced_Drink_8536]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 08:12:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Doubts over legal regime to redetain those released from Australian immigration detention, FoI documents reveal]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Exclusive:</strong> Meeting minutes show that without any offending by those released, it is hard to ‘illustrate that they pose an ongoing risk’</p><ul><li>Get our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl">breaking news email</a>, <a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3">free app</a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl">daily news podcast</a></li></ul><p>Officials responsible for <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/dec/04/labor-preventive-detention-scheme-indefinite-immigration-high-court-ruling">a regime to re-detain people released from immigration detention</a> have cast doubt on its effectiveness, warning the minimum nine-month timeframe to put cases together could make it harder for the government to win.</p><p>“In the absence of any offending, [it is] hard to illustrate that they pose an ongoing risk – so the longer it takes it weakens [the applicants’] case,” officials said, according to minutes of a January meeting discussing the operation of the scheme, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/dec/06/labor-preventive-detention-laws-pass-immigration-cancel-citizenship-ntwnfb">passed</a> after the high court’s ruling that <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/nov/08/australia-high-court-indefinite-detention-ruling-government">indefinite immigration detention is unlawful</a>.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed">Sign up for Guardian Australia’s breaking news email</a></strong></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/oct/09/australia-indefinite-immigration-detention-foi-documents-released-ntwnfb">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/oct/09/australia-indefinite-immigration-detention-foi-documents-released-ntwnfb</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/oct/09/australia-indefinite-immigration-detention-foi-documents-released-ntwnfb</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:00:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Middle East crisis live: Netanyahu warns Lebanon of destruction ‘like Gaza’; seven people reported killed in Israeli airstrike on Damascus]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Netanyahu says Israel has ‘taken out’ Nasrallah’s successors; Syrian defence ministry says at least 11 others injured in attack on residential building</p><p></p><p><strong>Turkey will evacuate its citizens who have applied to leave Lebanon by sea on Wednesday, the Turkish foreign ministry said on Tuesday.</strong></p><p>Reuters reports it said in a statement that two Turkish navy ships were expected to set off for Beirut on Tuesday with a total capacity of about 2,000 passengers, adding that the evacuation process will continue in the following days if necessary.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/08/israel-iran-live-blog-hezbollah-lebanon-gaza-hamas-war-middle-east-crisis-news-updates">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/08/israel-iran-live-blog-hezbollah-lebanon-gaza-hamas-war-middle-east-crisis-news-updates</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/oct/08/israel-iran-live-blog-hezbollah-lebanon-gaza-hamas-war-middle-east-crisis-news-updates</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 19:00:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reeves to press ahead with capital spending plans despite rising debt costs]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Exclusive: chancellor’s plan to change rules to allow more borrowing for investment comes as cost of government debt rises</p><p>Rachel Reeves is pushing ahead with plans to borrow billions of pounds extra for infrastructure investment, the Guardian has learned, despite concerns about the rising cost of UK government debt.</p><p>The chancellor told the cabinet on Tuesday she wanted to change how the Treasury accounted for capital spending to reflect its benefits, as allies say she intends to finalise her debt rule in the coming days.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2024/oct/08/reeves-to-press-ahead-with-capital-spending-plans-despite-rising-debt-costs">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2024/oct/08/reeves-to-press-ahead-with-capital-spending-plans-despite-rising-debt-costs</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2024/oct/08/reeves-to-press-ahead-with-capital-spending-plans-despite-rising-debt-costs</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 18:51:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel's Gallant says it appears Nasrallah's replacement has been eliminated]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/israels-gallant-says-appears-nasrallahs-125240684.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/israels-gallant-says-appears-nasrallahs-125240684.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 12:52:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hamas will rise 'like a phoenix' from the ashes, leader-in-exile says]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/exclusive-hamas-rise-phoenix-ashes-205310330.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/exclusive-hamas-rise-phoenix-ashes-205310330.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 20:53:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump retreat! 45 bails as Kamala Harris faces '60 Minutes,' town hall & Howard Stern in blitz]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/trump-retreat-45-bails-kamala-233801085.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/trump-retreat-45-bails-kamala-233801085.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 23:38:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Turkish lawmakers discuss Mideast in closed session after Erdogan's Israel claim]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/turkish-lawmakers-discuss-mideast-closed-134256239.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/turkish-lawmakers-discuss-mideast-closed-134256239.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 13:42:56 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>