<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 06:41:19 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 06:41:19 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Trump sentencing delayed as judge in "hush money" case weighs Supreme Court immunity ruling - CBS News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNic25ld3MuY29tL25ld3MvdHJ1bXAtc2VudGVuY2luZy1kZWxheWVkLWh1c2gtbW9uZXktY2FzZS1zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWltbXVuaXR5L9IBYWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNic25ld3MuY29tL2FtcC9uZXdzL3RydW1wLXNlbnRlbmNpbmctZGVsYXllZC1odXNoLW1vbmV5LWNhc2Utc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1pbW11bml0eS8?oc=5" target="_blank">Trump sentencing delayed as judge in "hush money" case weighs Supreme Court immunity ruling</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnVzYXRvZGF5LmNvbS9zdG9yeS9vcGluaW9uL2NvbHVtbmlzdC8yMDI0LzA3LzAyL3N1cHJlbWUtY291cnQtZGVjaXNpb24taW1tdW5pdHktdHJ1bXAtYmlkZW4tZGViYXRlLzc0MjcwNTU5MDA3L9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Supreme Court immunity decision helps Biden deflect debate disaster</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">USA TODAY</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiV2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LnlhaG9vLmNvbS9uZXdzL2F1dGhvcml0YXJpYW4taW1wdWxzZXMtc2NvdHVzLWltbXVuaXR5LXJ1bGluZy0wNDM0MDczMjIuaHRtbNIBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">'Authoritarian impulses': what SCOTUS immunity ruling could mean if Trump wins</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo! Voices</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZWh0dHBzOi8vYWJjbmV3cy5nby5jb20vVVMvbWFuaGF0dGFuLWRhLW9wcG9zZS10cnVtcHMtcmVxdWVzdC1odXNoLW1vbmV5LWNvbnZpY3Rpb24vc3Rvcnk_aWQ9MTExNjExOTE30gFpaHR0cHM6Ly9hYmNuZXdzLmdvLmNvbS9hbXAvVVMvbWFuaGF0dGFuLWRhLW9wcG9zZS10cnVtcHMtcmVxdWVzdC1odXNoLW1vbmV5LWNvbnZpY3Rpb24vc3Rvcnk_aWQ9MTExNjExOTE3?oc=5" target="_blank">Judge in Trump's criminal hush money case postpones sentencing to Sept. 18</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiS2h0dHBzOi8vd3d3LndhdnkuY29tL25ld3MvbWVhbmluZy1vZi1zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWltbXVuaXR5LXJ1bGluZy1kZWJhdGVkL9IBAA?oc=5" target="_blank">Meaning of Supreme Court immunity ruling debated</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">WAVY.com</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNic25ld3MuY29tL25ld3MvdHJ1bXAtc2VudGVuY2luZy1kZWxheWVkLWh1c2gtbW9uZXktY2FzZS1zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWltbXVuaXR5L9IBYWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNic25ld3MuY29tL2FtcC9uZXdzL3RydW1wLXNlbnRlbmNpbmctZGVsYXllZC1odXNoLW1vbmV5LWNhc2Utc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1pbW11bml0eS8?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNic25ld3MuY29tL25ld3MvdHJ1bXAtc2VudGVuY2luZy1kZWxheWVkLWh1c2gtbW9uZXktY2FzZS1zdXByZW1lLWNvdXJ0LWltbXVuaXR5L9IBYWh0dHBzOi8vd3d3LmNic25ld3MuY29tL2FtcC9uZXdzL3RydW1wLXNlbnRlbmNpbmctZGVsYXllZC1odXNoLW1vbmV5LWNhc2Utc3VwcmVtZS1jb3VydC1pbW11bml0eS8?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 23:45:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA['China can end Russia’s war in Ukraine with one phone call']]></title><description><![CDATA[<img border="0" hspace="10" align="left" style="margin-top:3px;margin-right:5px;" src="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/photo/111450296.cms" />Finnish President Alexander Stubb said that Russia's dependence on China has reached a level where Beijing could potentially end the war in Ukraine. In a Helsinki interview, Stubb emphasized that a single phone call from Chinese President Xi Jinping could resolve the crisis. Stubb's remarks highlight the growing frustration among Ukraine's allies regarding China's perceived support for Russia, which includes providing technologies, weapon parts, and aiding in circumventing trade restrictions.]]></description><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/xi-jinping-phone-call-to-putin-ukraine-war-finnish-president-alexander-stubb-china-and-russia/articleshow/111450296.cms</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/xi-jinping-phone-call-to-putin-ukraine-war-finnish-president-alexander-stubb-china-and-russia/articleshow/111450296.cms</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 06:13:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza war live: Israel insists campaign against Hamas will be ‘long’, after reports generals favour truce]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Benjamin Netanyahu said his country would not give in to the ‘winds of defeatism’, as thousands continue to evacuate from Khan Younis</p><p>Overnight Israel’s military has claimed to have struck at multiple targets inside <strong>Lebanon</strong>. It says that “Hezbollah terrorist infrastructure sites”, “military structures” and “threats” were targeted in six different places.</p><p>Hello and welcome to the Guardian’s continuing coverage of the Israel-Gaza war and the wider crisis in the Middle East.</p><p><strong>Hundreds of Palestinians were fleeing Khan Younis in southern Gaza after the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/israel">Israel</a> Defense Forces (IDF) once again bombarded the largely ruined city and ordered a mass evacuation of residents. </strong>Witnesses reported strikes on Tuesday in and around the city, where eight people were killed and more than 30 were wounded, according to the Palestinian Red Crescent and a medical source, Agence France-Presse said</p><p><strong>The United Nations said that the order to evacuate was the largest such edict in the Gaza Strip since 1.1 million people were told to leave the north of the territory in October</strong>. UN spokesperson Stéphane Dujarric said “an evacuation of such a massive scale will only heighten the suffering of civilians and drive humanitarian needs even higher.”</p><p><strong>The deputy leader of the Lebanese militant group Hezbollah has said the only sure path to a ceasefire on the Lebanon-Israel border is a full ceasefire in Gaza</strong>. “If there is a ceasefire in Gaza, we will stop without any discussion,” Hezbollah’s deputy leader, Sheikh Naim Kassem, said in an interview with The Associated Press. But, he said, if Israel scales back its military operations without a formal ceasefire agreement and full withdrawal from Gaza, the implications for the Lebanon-Israel border conflict are less clear.</p><p><strong>French president Emmanuel Macron urged Benjamin Netanyahu to prevent a “conflagration” between Israel and Hezbollah militants in Lebanon</strong>, during a telephone call between the two leaders. Macron “reiterated his serious concern over a deepening of tensions between Hezbollah and Israel … and underscored the absolute need to prevent a conflagration that would harm the interests of Lebanon as well as Israel,” the French presidency said in a statement.</p><p><strong>Far-right finance minister Bezalel Smotrich protested against an Israeli decision to increase the electricity supply to Gaza</strong>. Defense minister Yoav Gallant has described the work, which will enable a desalination plant in Gaza to produce more water, as “a basic humanitarian need” but Smotrich has called it a “folly”, asking prime minister Benjamin Netanyahu to intervene</p><p><strong>The mother of rescued hostage Noa Argamani died in Ichilov hospital in Tel Aviv, Israeli media reports</strong>. Liora Argamani, who was 61, had been terminally ill, and was reunited with her daughter last month</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/jul/03/israel-gaza-war-hamas-netanyahu-middle-east-latest">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/jul/03/israel-gaza-war-hamas-netanyahu-middle-east-latest</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2024/jul/03/israel-gaza-war-hamas-netanyahu-middle-east-latest</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 06:26:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hunter Biden sues Fox News over explicit images featured in a streaming series]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/hunter-biden-sues-fox-news-234335465.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/hunter-biden-sues-fox-news-234335465.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 23:43:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Xi, Putin arrive for Kazakhstan conference]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/xi-putin-arrive-kazakhstan-conference-061428735.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/xi-putin-arrive-kazakhstan-conference-061428735.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 06:14:28 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>