<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Politics Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Politics articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 18:17:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/politics.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 18:17:02 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Theo Von’s interview with Donald Trump makes more sense than you think]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Theo Von, flanked by Jared Leto and David Spade, attends a UFC event in Las Vegas, Nevada in April 2024. | Chris Unger/Zuffa LLC via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Chris Unger/Zuffa LLC via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2148559642.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Theo Von, flanked by Jared Leto and David Spade, attends a UFC event in Las Vegas, Nevada in April 2024. | Chris Unger/Zuffa LLC via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Even among a long list of bizarre Donald Trump moments, this clip was a head-turner: The former president <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R80tJ4lAz20">asking</a> his interviewer a series of questions about his cocaine use. “That’s down and dirty, isn’t it?” Trump asked Theo Von, who <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vC5cHjcgt5g">interviewed</a> him on August 20 for his YouTube podcast, <em>This Past Weekend</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The clip went viral almost immediately, not only because it’s rare to hear a presidential candidate so openly discussing drug usage, but because Trump, for once, seemed genuinely interested in a conversation that wasn’t about himself. It was also a strange “&#8230;who?” moment for those unfamiliar with Von, a mulleted stand-up comedian turned podcaster, in the style of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/22945864/joe-rogan-politics-spotify-controversy">Joe Rogan</a>. Digital media has responded with a series of Theo Von explainers, attempting to convey what about the relatively unobtrusive comic may have caught Trump’s attention.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But in fact, there really isn’t that much to explain — at least not about Von himself. The shifts in internet culture that brought him his platform, though, are a bit more interesting.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Von — his full name is Theodor von Kurnatowski — is something of a one-size-fits-all commentator, one whose personal political beliefs seem anodyne enough to make him palatable to people across the political spectrum; he interviewed Sen. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TwED_Znc9XQ">Bernie Sanders</a> (I-VT) the week just prior. With Trump, Von stuck mainly to the personal (mutual friends from the world of UFC, Kid Rock’s brother’s golf swing, sobriety, how good the Trump boys are at hunting) before getting lightly political (they briefly discussed health care reform but mostly talked about how much they hate lobbyists). The interview’s big viral conversation about cocaine came when Von tried in vain to get Trump to talk policy regarding the opioid epidemic. The subsequent chat about doing drugs was Trump redirecting the subject, but it was much more aligned with Von’s typical podcast conversations, which normally veer away from more incendiary subjects and toward topics like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VkfQ3fivwF8">wrangling drunk mall Santas</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A veteran of the same early-2000s reality TV industry that former <em>Fear Factor </em>host Rogan once thrived in, Von first made his mark as a young contestant on MTV’s reality travel competition show <em>Road Rules</em>. He later gained acclaim on comic competition shows like <em>Last Comic Standing</em> and <em>Reality Bites Back</em>, holding his own against other comedians like Amy Schumer and Tiffany Haddish. In the early era of comedians turning into podcasters and vloggers, Von became popular as a guest on other standups’ shows, all while his own show, launched in 2016, took off and grew to its current audience of nearly 3 million subscribers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The interview, which the pair alluded to having been orchestrated by UFC CEO Dana White, was apparently part of a recent series of drop-ins to UFC-adjacent podcasters, including Von, Adin Ross, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/1/3/16841160/logan-paul-aokigahara-suicide-controversy">Logan Paul</a>. Yet there’s a lot more at play here than Trump appealing to wrestling fandom. In his newsletter, writer Max Read coined the term “<a href="https://maxread.substack.com/p/a-guide-to-the-streamer-dipshits">dipshit outreach</a>” to describe the kind of everyman tour Trump and his running mate Sen. JD Vance have embarked on. Read’s thesis is that Von, along with the other podcasts, vlogs, and livestreams that Trump has appeared on, attract a specific type of Trump-loving demographic. As he puts it, these are “guys who like ‘edgy,’ trollish, hedonistic, attention-seeking personalities.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Von has skillfully branded himself as a relatable, down-to-earth type, a Southern boy originally from what he’s described as the rural, poor side of Covington, Louisiana. He comes across as more interested in people than in their politics, so we might think of Von as more or less on the wholesome end of the troll-dipshit-magnet spectrum. That may well be true compared to the other men on Trump’s roster, but he has had his moments.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Most notably, his 2015 appearance on <em>Bertcast</em> with Bert Kreischer includes an <a href="https://youtu.be/6b_ei1bZ0lQ?t=2493">extended segment</a> in which Von repeatedly drops the n-word — hard ‘r.’&nbsp; Von couches his use in an anecdote in which he claims that Black kids in his neighborhood were the ones ironically using the word, which he’s just conveying to his audience. He then proceeds, with Kreischer, to spend several minutes expounding upon why his use of the n-word in this context is fine, actually. That’s not the only time he and Kreischer defended the indefensible; last year, he <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@bertkreischer/video/7264617383518833966">joined</a> Kreischer’s show <em>Two Bears, One Cave</em> to do the same sort of performative justification — this time for white men doing blackface.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While difficult to listen to, these conversations sum up what might set Von slightly apart from some of his colleagues in comedy — he doesn’t think just anyone should be able to say the n-word because of free speech; he thinks he personally gets to say it, because he somehow earned it. As for blackface, he doesn’t think it should “count” when it’s donned by someone who’s marginalized in a different way, because that person also somehow earned it.&nbsp;This is, in America, a whole type of guy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is exactly the kind of content Read’s “dipshit” demographic loves and the kind of contrarianism Trump himself delights in and gravitates toward. Though most of Von’s more recent content is inoffensive, it’s not insignificant that his popularity was built on this kind of vibe.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Von is older than both Ross and Paul, who carry a more direct appeal to Gen Z. But Von’s own persona, while less brash and irony-tinged, has its own broad allure; much like country mega-star <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23842173/oliver-anthony-rich-men-controversy-morgan-wallen-jason-aldean-small-town-political">Morgan Wallen</a>, he’s frequently self-effacing and self-deprecating, both as a way of performing relatability and as a way of preempting any moral objections to his tone. Like Wallen, he’s already confessed to being an imperfect narrator and commentator, so how can you hate him for it?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">His stand-up comedy weaponizes this strategy as well. At <a href="https://youtu.be/BUI0sGnx9Us?t=294">one point</a> during a 2012 Comedy Central special, he pauses mid-sentence to admonish people who are laughing at the “wrong” part of a joke about Black people. “That’s not the joke, people that are laughing, that’s racism,” he says, in the middle of a string of jokes full of racist assumptions. The admonishment functions as both a deflection and a defense.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, many comedians believe the cause of comedy itself makes it an unimpeachable high ground that justifies the performance of outlandish and offensive material, and likewise <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2022/5/26/23141865/netflix-transphobia-ricky-gervais-supernature-terf">lament the rise</a> of fabled “woke scolds” who criticize comedy that targets the vulnerable and the marginalized. Unlike other similar comics — <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/24081214/shane-gillis-snl-saturday-night-live-hosting-controversy-racism">Shane Gillis</a> comes to mind — who’ve doubled down on their offensive material in recent years, Von tends to avoid falling back on this rhetoric and mostly seems to avoid the conversation altogether. He’s interested in pushing the buttons, but he’s not so interested in pointing to the consequences he might face for pushing them. Much like Rogan, while he aligns with Trump on vibes, and his jokes frequently give trolls and racists permission to laugh for all the wrong reasons, his own politics seem far more middle-of-the-road. In comedy, that effectively makes him a moderate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s appearance on Von’s show, then, just a week after Sanders, says something about the breadth and potential of these so-called dipshits in his audience. That two major figures from either side of the political spectrum chose to appear on a former <em>Road Rules</em>-er’s video podcast is a shockingly in-kind outcome for a modern internet culture that turns comedians into influencers and podcasters into pundits. Who will ultimately win their hearts — and votes — remains the question.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/culture/368563/theo-von-trump-interview-podcast</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/culture/368563/theo-von-trump-interview-podcast</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aja Romano]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 18:00:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Texas, other GOP-led states sue over program to give immigrant spouses of US citizens legal status - The Associated Press]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxPRC1BZDRoTkVGSHhwakFybUV0OGlROFZpdmt2by1relpmMEhwbXcxM1duWnNZcDVtcmRNakh5R3FleUxQalE4YWpuczV1WDlnU2FPOGwxVEVORjVvRmZIdDFlVnprU3RiaC01YW9VNzVUbTdjVmNpUFVmdS1Lc1ktcjcxZ1lGZWRIZjZPQzVOUS14VEVrYTdJ?oc=5" target="_blank">Texas, other GOP-led states sue over program to give immigrant spouses of US citizens legal status</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Associated Press</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOcXdWWDVEallLZEwxc0h0M3JFYUZNU2FoNzNGa1ZlMV9TNGpHLVZ1ZWVQbGRKWE45UnhqN0R5cWljMVd4ejNlMFMyMjN6MkQ1T0VNZHRwb3lIcUNOTmhHNXlzcThDS2F0a0FaTVNMMnNqTFp5U09wa09tYkdwMHJ0VFBndWVVeFhfcmlxa0ZveUZGbkxka280eGJEMHd1V3FhXzlwX0MtS3I5WmR1ZFB5YjJONGhWZ9IBuwFBVV95cUxNeFRsM184ZGtPUXotNzdrOExSRzZ2SEF6TWhnZEdMemszb0dUdGExMFZPRVVSd1hDM2s3RUdUeW9nMTFzSjZFbHNMZXRvQjV6a0t6MTgzT3M5THpycy0xVC15anV4TnVaZENpbDVYOG9IZGNPSmRqQndKeG5xeXVkWXIwUks5RjV3SWlWV05BNVQ0ZUdOcEtmV3E1bDIzUms5YUNWYnFEcXFSMmx0VmI2aHJwVDg1OXBzREd3?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden-Harris admin launched new illegal migrant 'amnesty' while DNC was underway: Critics</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxOWkRvVGQtbk9aVVRUeFItVGhPUUtVMXhhWkx6dTlwRktqS2ZzSERyWkJwX08xWERER0lUVnJDbk4td2hyOHVVWlFwWEFsb2xpRHB4bXlPYklZa2M1bkZ0cjJOb3Q2RDZCZmxFb2NFbHNabGNHM3NKV2pzR2REOGpHUGpJSkhuTGM1S2RrNjdwX2lnbDhBcTVWZGZ30gFWQVVfeXFMTVdEUy1LTkJsSmJjUlhNYk1CcDliSDlsRTJaTW9sM29VQTBvSDhXMnc3Nk9fM2Vuc0c2a2U1NHM4RlE3ZXM2Z2Z2cE1JVXRwVzMxMXhZUlE?oc=5" target="_blank">Biden's 'parole in place' immigration plan could transform lives — and the 2024 election</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxPakRwMDBhblFJV09nUlRybTRDUklTelQ2Y0hzOXYzcmNoZ2lzRG9iZ3REZk01UnBFYUh5YUxnSHRvd2xVbG9JOGFnOHQxYVd1QTZucXo5MzJjc1c5Rlp3UHIyZkcwbkR1UjlHYWM0anZrVFdFLWJ5S0xWQkF0WkZwZE1GTGJheks3TXdDYTVmLW9ZWVdsMS1uMlpNX1dsZ2p3ZzNKY0VNV1VPMHpHMXl1dVdLX0RDdw?oc=5" target="_blank">Texas sues over Biden legalization program for immigrants married to US citizens</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxQZjZRWjU3VDJEdDE2TnRkT2pYODhJa0l2UFVuM3lIM0xCOURMVHFRMERiUkotc0RqVUkxcW00cS0zbGhMV196dVVoSTdUc29wc0FDaW1zdGxUbzFYbU5JdXQwSUhsMlhxZ2NoQ3JlbnRwbVBNQ292dnF6VWpCSmlnU2w2ckJrMVcydmc?oc=5" target="_blank">Half a Million Migrant Spouses of US Citizens Get Pathway to Green Cards</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Newsweek</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxPRC1BZDRoTkVGSHhwakFybUV0OGlROFZpdmt2by1relpmMEhwbXcxM1duWnNZcDVtcmRNakh5R3FleUxQalE4YWpuczV1WDlnU2FPOGwxVEVORjVvRmZIdDFlVnprU3RiaC01YW9VNzVUbTdjVmNpUFVmdS1Lc1ktcjcxZ1lGZWRIZjZPQzVOUS14VEVrYTdJ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxPRC1BZDRoTkVGSHhwakFybUV0OGlROFZpdmt2by1relpmMEhwbXcxM1duWnNZcDVtcmRNakh5R3FleUxQalE4YWpuczV1WDlnU2FPOGwxVEVORjVvRmZIdDFlVnprU3RiaC01YW9VNzVUbTdjVmNpUFVmdS1Lc1ktcjcxZ1lGZWRIZjZPQzVOUS14VEVrYTdJ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 15:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Harris tells her story on historic night. And who else showed up on DNC's final night - NPR]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxPOHQ1eUx0TmdCRE83WER1T3VDYlVuRjJYeEZCczV4dXRXZ0l6QUtORzlLdG5zRGRvaWRtRU9mZDFUTEw3Z3BZSXRiMHRObkxIbFRLNGViVHE0N041eGJFX0Fxdm9teTBwMk9BVEVPVTNHb0k1MlJtZThBSWdaWjJTa1FDV2RVUEtELWhyTVp0YjlQejVsYVBYb3lTcmlNWWx4bUtiNy0wUFYtUExfWWZjTW1Md1Jtcmc?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris tells her story on historic night. And who else showed up on DNC's final night</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxOMkp4UnJXWWNTMnlpbVktbWRfMXRjWlJwMVB4ZG9WVWRMTTdEUnZKXy1kRFd2QlpJSkdyYWdvT1pwNVZLVW9HSHU3eTlLc0JXeTVsUEE3LUp0bkFBc1UtUE1oV2ZhN09hc1hwNWszUDlMTWY5SFRSNUhtRTUzRlVtcjFYWUVBOGhxZTY4RFlXZlJZRnM?oc=5" target="_blank">DNC reactions, analysis and 2024 campaign news</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxPTmd2R29WX1VkWWxVaG9uRFdJTGFDY3l1OGtlLXhnV1l0Y0tSQ2gtMnE0eDdoTTBHVFlfVk5scmlWcERFYzBSdmZWQmlvSTd5Y2VmUFpobkthQVNxbmNVc2t6bmdKZnJidVEwUUxCWVNkc3lVMnZrc0dBODRwM0VrQ0laazRoZDNiRWk5c2IwSFNFRlV1U2h2THBtQXEzbUk?oc=5" target="_blank">It’s Sorkin Again in America</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Atlantic</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxPX2EyWWlHYkY2SWVUaklDMU1CMF9ZVzIyVy04dmtTdWtuWXY0RXd1VnpxaTYyZmVFazd1TzdEMkVNVnV0VzJuY3IyTFZET2FIVkozMDlHYjBENGFPYUc4cGlsOFpveG5iRTUzZlBsbzJ3LUgydTZwcHpETDkwby1lMXFUM1dTSWwyY19j?oc=5" target="_blank">Our reporters’ biggest takeaways from Kamala Harris’ DNC</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">POLITICO</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidkFVX3lxTFBsOGdrMXBQS1JhdkJQb3FlaFdFM3NwOUloNVRSWV91ckNMUHJPTkJOMVc4Ulg2UkdYMGNMYURzc2FNdl92alNuNVZBNWJCZ3YxSUZJRUd1M1hDSHhXUHRpWWpicXk1c0lsRlpCXzF2dUxBVERrLWfSAXtBVV95cUxQbHBIWXg0ZktyX3BVV282TWFURUd0aG5zbkZGMUpvYWtuRWptQUxVa3FnS0dFN19ZNHAyY3h6ODNVcG9jQzBoSlNVOGVCMkN3cHBGZC1SVDYxVm5lUkw4VGFhMnlIVVYtMmRHN3JBQ2Y4djNxRFJwemhlOEE?oc=5" target="_blank">Harris and Democrats envision a brighter future at DNC</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Hill</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxPOHQ1eUx0TmdCRE83WER1T3VDYlVuRjJYeEZCczV4dXRXZ0l6QUtORzlLdG5zRGRvaWRtRU9mZDFUTEw3Z3BZSXRiMHRObkxIbFRLNGViVHE0N041eGJFX0Fxdm9teTBwMk9BVEVPVTNHb0k1MlJtZThBSWdaWjJTa1FDV2RVUEtELWhyTVp0YjlQejVsYVBYb3lTcmlNWWx4bUtiNy0wUFYtUExfWWZjTW1Md1Jtcmc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxPOHQ1eUx0TmdCRE83WER1T3VDYlVuRjJYeEZCczV4dXRXZ0l6QUtORzlLdG5zRGRvaWRtRU9mZDFUTEw3Z3BZSXRiMHRObkxIbFRLNGViVHE0N041eGJFX0Fxdm9teTBwMk9BVEVPVTNHb0k1MlJtZThBSWdaWjJTa1FDV2RVUEtELWhyTVp0YjlQejVsYVBYb3lTcmlNWWx4bUtiNy0wUFYtUExfWWZjTW1Md1Jtcmc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 12:15:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Secret Service places at least 5 agents on leave in Trump assassination attempt probe - CBS News]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPbUt6N2pvWERVNDFBVGtVS1hQUEIxbmd4d0U1MlhhUW8zdjItSGFockhKRjNMOWJuSkdxWDFfY3VOa01QTEl0U1FqY3VxMDkyS2hKNkhqY29wRUN0U3J5LWc2dlBOMmVxd1dOMldORFhsVm5fX2JqaEl0TEFublJYa9IBhgFBVV95cUxNN19FNFRiaVJYWGpxdktGNjRSSlBha2E3M3plSjR1MHVzT2Q2ejhYN2tFX3ZYbUtnOUJOMnJtYXUxeVRNc1hmdXYwSW5TWUxZR3hwYkVuUEJaZXZFUWprbWRpVkZCd2h0SXFZNF85WkVGc0NoTFZaU1FjNGkyZlpmbTVZUXl1Zw?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service places at least 5 agents on leave in Trump assassination attempt probe</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CBS News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxNVWstaF9paGdEenU1SWU1T25LeHdZYUtBNV84djN4RDFIcGtMVE40c1BDMXgtN3d3WjFRR1ZTeDN5a3hPMjBlU3AyU21raklTa3FTUmROaHlaTFlJdXgzMXRJVE01UnRZSGNoWHgtRzRFdjlTTjF3bHZTOWR5Y2NPWXQ0cmVJSjlpY3kxUDZ3MFNPWDRyOEoxTmV30gGQAUFVX3lxTE53RVlCRGdURFFBNkVjMGhtTHVTTjVwMktzaW0zNlMzVHVncjBXaW5JdUhNS09KaWo2Smx5TXlwNVUyYlV2QnhmSnVSZlQ4WWdUUE1oblFaUlRqSENmU1l4MEZ5T21udjBTZXZObjZpV0JhWTRyLWFOWFE4d0llNHk2TXFlMzEzY3NjWk54U3Nabg?oc=5" target="_blank">Forgotten radios and missed warnings: New details emerge about communication failures before Trump rally shooting</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxPaUFYTldud0Q5WXJnSHUyeTZSRzYyRTNoNDA2cHJxMFdGbDRvNzhpM2JrN1FjOUl3U0luZDVNYm5NVW5qNjR0bmFOTnhncnB6M3l3cXVKSFNLeGVkdTc0dm5hNmpyUmVPSDhkX0RyQ1dxMVVfa3RodG9jNVpvQ3pMRXVhLTFVb0NLS0s1bkJ0LU5IQXRqVWdNZUJ6eUwxUmNHai0zVGtZa0lLU2NG0gGyAUFVX3lxTE9OanExdjFOZFc5OUNXMGkxLTZmS0lzSnpoUVQzS0trUDd1R1NCT2JlbEJ4Yjk4dC1QNGZnRk1wNnBTbGk0bFcxQjhaWlc4MUpuLUxORGdyUnFIak93M040Y2RLVWRXdXo0UTkwV3VVdU42WW5pN0lvRWVnUmNNQ3d3emVzRkJocFoxOEhpVF9TSTZ6MXVUNDJ4RnNneVZhblBDVzB1OUR5OVlLdzgxUTFjT2c?oc=5" target="_blank">Multiple Secret Service agents put on leave following Trump assassination attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Fox News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQNzdRRWxOeTV4d2UxVVplTjR6VnJLbDQtN1FlR1d1RTBrbC1fdnd0NWdhT1lXMnVKNXpvX1BGSlFRdWRrLUtfMktkZFE0Y0pHdkl5eGtTQmFkQ3JYYmZMVDczdmhDV0x0ZkZWTEl4c2N1RGpDc0N5MGJlY3ZDQWZZWE9TcVdTQWZ3MnQ3TmJ5ampsZmgxRlZaMVFhNUZ3aDJyeWJJQmRLYlRhUk8wMVBtTUNDWlUtd9IBVkFVX3lxTE1lXzRwNGR2ak9WbmlYb1UwZ0pEUERMcVdKS2U1S3lVb3lDUTBoay1JZEk3VEpLLWxodS10RktWMWZpZng3dUh4WGwwWjV4YXpBYU5IVkVR?oc=5" target="_blank">Some Secret Service officials have been placed on leave in response to Trump assassination attempt</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTFA1RU81YlpwWFY2bUhuUjhWeUVOZVhuS1dBMmxPLVVGUnZsZGNjTDk0WlZPempSTm9yc2p5SFlZSy1CSF9lYnFMUnBqZ01pR3VUTmRsUkl2LTFlUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Secret Service agents put on leave over Trump shooting</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPbUt6N2pvWERVNDFBVGtVS1hQUEIxbmd4d0U1MlhhUW8zdjItSGFockhKRjNMOWJuSkdxWDFfY3VOa01QTEl0U1FqY3VxMDkyS2hKNkhqY29wRUN0U3J5LWc2dlBOMmVxd1dOMldORFhsVm5fX2JqaEl0TEFublJYa9IBhgFBVV95cUxNN19FNFRiaVJYWGpxdktGNjRSSlBha2E3M3plSjR1MHVzT2Q2ejhYN2tFX3ZYbUtnOUJOMnJtYXUxeVRNc1hmdXYwSW5TWUxZR3hwYkVuUEJaZXZFUWprbWRpVkZCd2h0SXFZNF85WkVGc0NoTFZaU1FjNGkyZlpmbTVZUXl1Zw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPbUt6N2pvWERVNDFBVGtVS1hQUEIxbmd4d0U1MlhhUW8zdjItSGFockhKRjNMOWJuSkdxWDFfY3VOa01QTEl0U1FqY3VxMDkyS2hKNkhqY29wRUN0U3J5LWc2dlBOMmVxd1dOMldORFhsVm5fX2JqaEl0TEFublJYa9IBhgFBVV95cUxNN19FNFRiaVJYWGpxdktGNjRSSlBha2E3M3plSjR1MHVzT2Q2ejhYN2tFX3ZYbUtnOUJOMnJtYXUxeVRNc1hmdXYwSW5TWUxZR3hwYkVuUEJaZXZFUWprbWRpVkZCd2h0SXFZNF85WkVGc0NoTFZaU1FjNGkyZlpmbTVZUXl1Zw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 16:10:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[India’s Modi visits Ukraine, urges Zelensky to hold peace talks - The Washington Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxNZmE4dWRyRnRGcVBpSVI2OHhMUk85MVlxb2oweW1YNVhjVzNRUEw1NVE0QXI3WUt4OFpzYWFEVXdLaVh3VXkxMnpyUTVPM0Z1MzUzWmlyZ2pCT1d1MENfYlQzWDZKOWpkT0J2OGlHWnIyelVWSjlhaWZHN3o1OGpuVEo3WjQxSEwwTFE?oc=5" target="_blank">India’s Modi visits Ukraine, urges Zelensky to hold peace talks</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Washington Post</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiWkFVX3lxTE1MejR0NVU3V0dNVnJHWUZBa0dza2xER2xtRlhuUVRENm9DM3FacjFrSnk4U1RIcS0tR21JbzRqY19nVEFsdFVWdWhEUzA4SEwzVDctQUNZMXRXQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">India ready to help find peace, Modi tells Ukraine's Zelensky</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">BBC.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxPYzN1alBBV0pmMktOX1A1bE04TkliRDNYSldVdWpnRUxPalJ2U0ZpVGFvcWdWaWl2SExvNVVBd19weHRuZWw1UVNZSlB3WnM3YlJrZnI1Q0NyUHdmRU9RVDBFUXBORUlMbHp4SmZONWQ2dTd1d2pzWnVoekpZVW8zTmREZ09CRGdpWDQ0WUFLZ3RsNUtl?oc=5" target="_blank">India's 'Strategic Partnership' with Kyiv's NATO Ally Deals Blow to Putin</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Newsweek</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTE42QUs5dHpYdFQwN1JveUV2LWZwdkhVRlFjWEdha21hUll3anBJUTFfaER5U1VwSmt3bThTYURfM2MzMFlwejJLaUx5Q2VSZXNlQVdpa0FRZkllYkNEYXhJUXNQNTlIQTR2cmM2UkJnY2VFaEI1RlJXOTI1OA?oc=5" target="_blank">Indian Leader Visits Kyiv as Ukraine Pushes Diplomacy</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxPOExOSE14dFRocE13TWpGRzBTdDZNdUQ0SU9qUzlCbjdtUFRxVXVVbjU0cWhrS3NVOTczanR1aEtHXy1XRGV4aVkxY1lHN3lzYkN2RVZvYkdiME93SnpYUkE4NTFEaEdiSWlFcWxZSVNCX1U4dWc3cTF0dlBtODUyRHZrWVdQbUMwbTA0dGNENC1rLXU1cUhPYTR3UUJBM2RVazMzZ2x2cTltckV1?oc=5" target="_blank">In Kyiv, Indian PM urges Zelenskiy to sit down for talks with Russia</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxNZmE4dWRyRnRGcVBpSVI2OHhMUk85MVlxb2oweW1YNVhjVzNRUEw1NVE0QXI3WUt4OFpzYWFEVXdLaVh3VXkxMnpyUTVPM0Z1MzUzWmlyZ2pCT1d1MENfYlQzWDZKOWpkT0J2OGlHWnIyelVWSjlhaWZHN3o1OGpuVEo3WjQxSEwwTFE?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxNZmE4dWRyRnRGcVBpSVI2OHhMUk85MVlxb2oweW1YNVhjVzNRUEw1NVE0QXI3WUt4OFpzYWFEVXdLaVh3VXkxMnpyUTVPM0Z1MzUzWmlyZ2pCT1d1MENfYlQzWDZKOWpkT0J2OGlHWnIyelVWSjlhaWZHN3o1OGpuVEo3WjQxSEwwTFE?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 17:58:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Would a Taylor Swift Endorsement Actually Impact the Presidential Race? - Hollywood Reporter]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNR0c4ZXJ3T2dzbjdjazhHc1FRQ3gxRXJlbWU0UllrVkwxVC1kT0pfY2lmdWZSMVotT0R2a3FLOXFIS3Z4TkZnaWpKTURVNWtjeVNhZHFnQ05Qalkxa19ycHhfY0REQ2ZZSTFvNGZfT2NLN2RzTTUwdV83ODJKTlFpWkhnbmRMNUVaOWU1cFliMFFHRjhKc1pNU0hTWmoyaGw5NUt5M1BJTVNhR2FaTVI1QdIBtgFBVV95cUxPcEJsaGtRMzRQRllwa20wb1BCOHpBZkdReTJ6eUx3b3hqeWxDenpSUE02Wk5tdVptLUdacnZra01JaHRPMFRLOGE2elJaRkpwc3pCYjZEX1BPaEk1azc4YkJmQnU5MTVVNGF1MHNBdTJpUGwyZHQ2VjlSTWRSd0ZpZE9hQkNEVHBDckVmS3B1ME8tZjVSYVVUWkZFZ2NheXNoWEF5Y000U09LRmhQSk5xRDN0OGlSZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Would a Taylor Swift Endorsement Actually Impact the Presidential Race?</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Hollywood Reporter</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxNUFJjUy1HWEwyaml0TkFua1Bxd0JYa1FzWmlWU3E0MWdSeThNU0hKXzg5VzNBajJCT3BZRjl2bGMzT0ZNRUl2R0JqLXVIOFgyZ1NyUEVsM05YS0VPWUtoVTA2aXl6T2twNF9qU1F4bFlOMGpDdXFtX2h6Y0lIc1hiQmp6MkhpdUNNNDJqRmdldHQtYXV0VWo0dmpzUElGQWxVc25yMWV1TQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Everyone wants Taylor Swift's vote. But celebrity endorsements are complicated.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NPR</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNdHJObjE1Q1hwSUNHbXhOMFIySzJwTVRweG5WM2hIbjRpZXdHTjRSLTc1bGJ4TlZ2bjloRUlkZFFwNWh1aC1NdVQ2dWRlTW10UUR3RjBsN2c3V29COWxCdVJpQk54UVBOR0l1RDV1Z3cwTWZjUVl1bTNCVi1TLTY1dGY2enJhU05seDQtVGZWN0dWaEs0RWtJZ2lXVGw3OHAyZzJVNWZPVGtrTFNzaVNHRWQ0Yi02cXdDM0JMVnR3QVJzakpMRm9hcGJRd2tvUWtpYlpWVHlZZ2dmOXFJYm52M2NwZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Did Taylor Swift perform at 2024 DNC Day 4? Sorry, Swifties. No appearance with Kamala Harris</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">IndyStar</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQd0drTGltbU5LR0JPQm0weWg0VDB2ZU5QSnJXMFJFQ1NTSGV6bXRBbE1SN0h1MU9BcUt5cWlSRnNabVdQMUk2VGF1ZzRBc3AzdGYtWUlYdFJpMzRRcDgzNzNTcWcyWWU3aDQ5MXZ5NFFnSE9Db2VuZFV6b3Q5M1VOaGVtV1N4SG05M05rTDRKZ0xxX1JBQWVyTUJ0OA?oc=5" target="_blank">T-Swift’s ‘Modern Family’ Friend Teases a Harris Endorsement</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Daily Beast</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQUlJSSjBNczhQdV9HUFdKajhSYmw4bjVLdjZzbE9IcWFMRWlDVy1vOW1kS0VLb1NRTG5BTTRaLWRmR3dBM2hPMHR0c0FBMjZYYV81TUwtSEJpeW9FdHcwRW9fOV9GV1lsYkRqd3gzQ1QxeTF5WDNFTkRwenVHQmJvUzNfYU8wcXZ0dlc2WWVpNllEUWthem9QNXQ1NXhRRm9rMmpuMXZSQ3V3dHNZWFZIeU5QRVVyN1BpeFAya2dBUFM?oc=5" target="_blank">Taylor Swift at the DNC? Speculation of the singer's appearance mounts as Chicago event goes on</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Tennessean</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNR0c4ZXJ3T2dzbjdjazhHc1FRQ3gxRXJlbWU0UllrVkwxVC1kT0pfY2lmdWZSMVotT0R2a3FLOXFIS3Z4TkZnaWpKTURVNWtjeVNhZHFnQ05Qalkxa19ycHhfY0REQ2ZZSTFvNGZfT2NLN2RzTTUwdV83ODJKTlFpWkhnbmRMNUVaOWU1cFliMFFHRjhKc1pNU0hTWmoyaGw5NUt5M1BJTVNhR2FaTVI1QdIBtgFBVV95cUxPcEJsaGtRMzRQRllwa20wb1BCOHpBZkdReTJ6eUx3b3hqeWxDenpSUE02Wk5tdVptLUdacnZra01JaHRPMFRLOGE2elJaRkpwc3pCYjZEX1BPaEk1azc4YkJmQnU5MTVVNGF1MHNBdTJpUGwyZHQ2VjlSTWRSd0ZpZE9hQkNEVHBDckVmS3B1ME8tZjVSYVVUWkZFZ2NheXNoWEF5Y000U09LRmhQSk5xRDN0OGlSZw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNR0c4ZXJ3T2dzbjdjazhHc1FRQ3gxRXJlbWU0UllrVkwxVC1kT0pfY2lmdWZSMVotT0R2a3FLOXFIS3Z4TkZnaWpKTURVNWtjeVNhZHFnQ05Qalkxa19ycHhfY0REQ2ZZSTFvNGZfT2NLN2RzTTUwdV83ODJKTlFpWkhnbmRMNUVaOWU1cFliMFFHRjhKc1pNU0hTWmoyaGw5NUt5M1BJTVNhR2FaTVI1QdIBtgFBVV95cUxPcEJsaGtRMzRQRllwa20wb1BCOHpBZkdReTJ6eUx3b3hqeWxDenpSUE02Wk5tdVptLUdacnZra01JaHRPMFRLOGE2elJaRkpwc3pCYjZEX1BPaEk1azc4YkJmQnU5MTVVNGF1MHNBdTJpUGwyZHQ2VjlSTWRSd0ZpZE9hQkNEVHBDckVmS3B1ME8tZjVSYVVUWkZFZ2NheXNoWEF5Y000U09LRmhQSk5xRDN0OGlSZw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 17:05:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US and 10 Latin American states reject Nicolás Maduro’s vote certification]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>‘I have no doubt this election has been stolen,’ says Chile’s leftwing president after Venezuelan supreme court ruling</p><p>Ten Latin American governments and the US have said they “categorically reject” the Venezuelan supreme court’s decision to confirm Nicolás Maduro’s widely contested claim to have won re-election, with Chile’s president declaring: “I have no doubt this election has been stolen.”</p><p><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/aug/22/maduro-accused-power-grab-top-court-endorses-venezuela-election-win">Thursday’s verdict from Venezuela’s top court</a>, which is stacked with Maduro loyalists, has been widely questioned internationally from across the political spectrum.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/aug/23/latin-american-states-and-us-reject-maduro-vote-certification-election-venezuela-supreme-court">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/aug/23/latin-american-states-and-us-reject-maduro-vote-certification-election-venezuela-supreme-court</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/aug/23/latin-american-states-and-us-reject-maduro-vote-certification-election-venezuela-supreme-court</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 17:46:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Which benefits are available to vulnerable people under Labour?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As the winter fuel allowance is scrapped for many pensioners, we outline some other key benefits</p><p>• <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/article/2024/aug/23/millions-facing-cruel-winter-without-fuel-payments-labour-mps-warn">Millions facing ‘cruel winter’ without fuel payments, Labour MPs warn</a></p><p>Labour backbenchers are warning that <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/article/2024/aug/23/millions-facing-cruel-winter-without-fuel-payments-labour-mps-warn">millions of vulnerable people will face a “cruel winter”</a> amid rising energy prices and a reduction in benefits, including the removal of winter fuel payments for millions of pensioners.</p><p>Keir Starmer’s government has promised to improve conditions for those most in need, with a commitment to <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/child-poverty-taskforce-kicks-off-urgent-work-to-publish-strategy-in-spring">“reduce and alleviate” child poverty</a> and end the “moral scar” of food banks. And while Labour sees economic growth and creating more reliable and well-paid jobs as crucial to achieving these aims, it cannot ignore a number of pressing and often interrelated problems in the social security and benefits system.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/aug/23/the-benefits-challenges-facing-labour-as-millions-prepare-for-a-tough-winter">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/aug/23/the-benefits-challenges-facing-labour-as-millions-prepare-for-a-tough-winter</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/aug/23/the-benefits-challenges-facing-labour-as-millions-prepare-for-a-tough-winter</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 17:24:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RFK Jr to hold press conference amid speculation he will end campaign and endorse Trump – live]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Independent candidate to speak soon after filing paperwork to withdraw from presidential ballots in Arizona</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/23/trump-reaction-harris-dnc-speech">Trump reacts to Harris’s DNC speech</a></li><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/23/harris-convention-speech-trump">Analysis: Harris’s speech skewers Mar-a-Lago menace</a></li><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/23/robert-f-kennedy-jr-withdraws-presidential-bid-in-arizona">RFK Jr withdraws presidential bid in Arizona</a></li></ul><p><strong>Merrick Garland announced this morning that the justice department has filed an anti-trust lawsuit against the real estate software company</strong><strong> RealPage.</strong></p><p>The DoJ alleges that RealPage’s algorithm provided landlords with recommended prices for rentals that allowed them to align their rents.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/aug/23/dnc-kamala-harris-trump-rfk-campaign-election-updates">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/aug/23/dnc-kamala-harris-trump-rfk-campaign-election-updates</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2024/aug/23/dnc-kamala-harris-trump-rfk-campaign-election-updates</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 17:56:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan's China trip could lead to Biden-Xi meeting]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/national-security-adviser-jake-sullivans-173737897.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/national-security-adviser-jake-sullivans-173737897.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 17:37:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ted Cruz or Colin Allred for Senate? Here’s what these Texas voters said in new poll]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/ted-cruz-collin-allred-senate-110000388.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/news/ted-cruz-collin-allred-senate-110000388.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>