<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:21:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:21:39 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Approach to Neuromorphic Computing - AZoOptics]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A New Approach to Neuromorphic Computing</h1><p><strong>Published on: [Publication Date]</strong><br/><strong>Source: [Source Name]</strong></p><img src="https://d36nqgmw98q4v5.cloudfront.net/images/news/ImageForNews_30113_1736162479866370.png" width="800" height="320" alt="Neuromorphic systems based on the structure of biological neurons."><figcaption><em>Neuromorphic systems based on the structure of biological neurons. Image Credit: Light: Science & Applications</em></figcaption><p>Scientists led by Professor Nazek El-Atab at KAUST have created a MOSCap device that mimics neuron-like adaptive behavior and memory retention using Hafnium diselenide (HfSe<sub>2</sub>). Their study showcases advancements in neuromorphic computing.</p><ul><li>The separation of sensing, processing, and memory in traditional systems causes inefficiencies.</li><li>Neuromorphic computing combines these functions into a single device, enhancing efficiency.</li><li>Incorporation of HfSe<sub>2</sub> nanosheets allows unique data retention and adaptability.</li><li>Real-world tests show memory retention stability under high temperatures.</li><li>Potential applications include astronomy for detecting exoplanets.</li></ul><blockquote>“The memory window of the device remained above the failure threshold for 106 seconds at 60–80 °C.”</blockquote><p>This discovery represents a significant improvement in neuromorphic technology, highlighting its potential to develop systems that mimic the dynamic learning processes of biological neurons.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.azooptics.com/News.aspx?newsID=30113</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.azooptics.com/News.aspx?newsID=30113</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Macroscopic oscillators move as one at the quantum level ... - eeNews Europe]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxNcWp4NGNOR1F1aFlrX2pvRC15aWVBZkl6dzlMaWxqa1g5RVZOTlFHdnZCUVBzUzV2ejBXaTVJR2VQY2JuUkxLbl9QRTdWWkhSMVYzQ2Jlcm1HSmE0cXBEUW5PWWhsMUQ1QURCcUN6OUtaM3RITVN2d3FrZU1NYVRHRFhiYjctRm1STlUtLWhTSS1pT0k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxNcWp4NGNOR1F1aFlrX2pvRC15aWVBZkl6dzlMaWxqa1g5RVZOTlFHdnZCUVBzUzV2ejBXaTVJR2VQY2JuUkxLbl9QRTdWWkhSMVYzQ2Jlcm1HSmE0cXBEUW5PWWhsMUQ1QURCcUN6OUtaM3RITVN2d3FrZU1NYVRHRFhiYjctRm1STlUtLWhTSS1pT0k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:16:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Discovering “Avalanching” Nanocrystals with Revolutionary Switching Capabilities - AZoNano]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Discovering “Avalanching” Nanocrystals with Revolutionary Switching Capabilities</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Not specified, Source: Oregon State University</strong></p>
<img src="https://d1otjdv2bf0507.cloudfront.net/images/news/ImageForNews_41210_17361593701796443.png" alt="Nanocrystals Image">
<figcaption><em>Optically bistable nanocrystals can store information that is written and read entirely through light, making them useful for building small and scalable optical memory units. These nanocrystals are controlled by lasers: one delivers continuous power, while the other triggers them to emit light after a brief pulse. This functionality mimics the behavior of electronic transistors and paves the way for devices where light controls light. Image Credit: Artiom Skripka, OSU College of Science</em></figcaption>
<p>Scientists at Oregon State University have identified luminescent nanocrystals that can quickly switch between light and dark states, which holds potential for advancements in optical computing and memory technologies.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The study was published in <em>Nature Photonics</em>.</li>
  <li>Avalanching nanocrystals exhibit highly non-linear light emission properties.</li>
  <li>Controlled by lasers, these nanocrystals mimic electronic transistor behavior.</li>
  <li>Research could lead to more efficient optical communication and artificial intelligence processing.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p><em>“The extraordinary switching and memory capabilities of these nanocrystals may one day become integral to optical computing…”</em> - Artiom Skripka, Assistant Professor, Oregon State University</p>
</blockquote>
<p>These nanocrystals may be key in reducing energy consumption in electronic devices and data centers as they can operate on low power.</p>
<p>In conclusion, while the findings are promising, further research is necessary for real-world applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.azonano.com/news.aspx?newsID=41210</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.azonano.com/news.aspx?newsID=41210</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Catalyst for Efficient CO2 Conversion - AZoM]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A New Catalyst for Efficient CO2 Conversion</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Nature Synthesis</p>
<img src="https://d12oja0ew7x0i8.cloudfront.net/images/news/ImageForNews_64080_17361599103494645.jpg" alt="Copper-cluster catalysts on activated carbon. Image Credit: Cedric Koolen (EPFL)"><figcaption><em>Copper-cluster catalysts on activated carbon. Image Credit: Cedric Koolen (EPFL)</em></figcaption>
<p>Researchers have developed a copper-based catalyst that converts carbon dioxide to acetaldehyde with 92% efficiency, providing a sustainable alternative to traditional methods.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The catalyst was created by a public-private consortium led by Cedric David Koolen and others.</li>
  <li>Acetaldehyde is primarily derived from ethylene, a process with a significant carbon footprint.</li>
  <li>This new electrochemical reduction method effectively addresses CO2 emissions while producing valuable chemicals.</li>
  <li>The catalyst shows promise for scalability and cost-effectiveness in industrial applications.</li>
  <li>During testing, it maintained performance and selectivity over multiple cycles.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p><em>The Wacker process effectively hasn’t changed in the past 60 years. It is still based on the same basic chemistry. The time was ripe for a green breakthrough.</em> - Cedric David Koolen</p></blockquote>
<p>This breakthrough could transform industries reliant on acetaldehyde, including pharmaceuticals and agriculture, while reducing reliance on fossil fuels.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.azom.com/news.aspx?newsID=64080</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.azom.com/news.aspx?newsID=64080</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saturn crosses the Moon to get closer to Venus. You can see it with naked eyes - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/saturn-crosses-the-moon-to-get-closer-to-venus-you-can-see-it-with-naked-eyes-2660484-2025-01-06</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/saturn-crosses-the-moon-to-get-closer-to-venus-you-can-see-it-with-naked-eyes-2660484-2025-01-06</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:33:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Positron and electron catalysis of neutrino hadronization: How our universe was made - Open Access Government]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxNZFN4SUZJRW9iSnZDWGQydnFMZDZZLUFpeTBIdk5pMUhRQlVZYjJUZDFWZmNCWjduNlBZc0RvRGgwYVE0ODFJQ2tJXzhSLXRDdHZyVTdCV1lySjFLODE5OWhVT0dKTlFsQzRtWWhlVmY4WklubV92M2ZZVFNvaVNvOVdjS242blZfc2xVNEdqaTk1MjJHbURLRWhBYm43LVRvMGJoYlBwclhjc3JOd241dUU2WkRIZHctZnd1NXI0cV9ia1Y0R0Vaa0N2RklLOWNzT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxNZFN4SUZJRW9iSnZDWGQydnFMZDZZLUFpeTBIdk5pMUhRQlVZYjJUZDFWZmNCWjduNlBZc0RvRGgwYVE0ODFJQ2tJXzhSLXRDdHZyVTdCV1lySjFLODE5OWhVT0dKTlFsQzRtWWhlVmY4WklubV92M2ZZVFNvaVNvOVdjS242blZfc2xVNEdqaTk1MjJHbURLRWhBYm43LVRvMGJoYlBwclhjc3JOd241dUU2WkRIZHctZnd1NXI0cV9ia1Y0R0Vaa0N2RklLOWNzT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:27:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Android may soon add a new shortcut to launch Google Wallet - Android Authority]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Android may soon add a new shortcut to launch Google Wallet</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Android Authority</p>
<img src="https://www.androidauthority.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Google-Wallet-logo-on-smartphone-next-to-credit-cards-and-cash-Stock-photo-7.jpg" alt="Google Wallet logo on smartphone next to credit cards and cash" />
<figcaption>Google Wallet logo on smartphone next to credit cards and cash</figcaption>
<p>Google is developing a new feature that will enable users to launch the default wallet app using a double press of the power button, replacing the current functionality that opens the camera app.</p>
<ul>
<li>A new configuration for this feature has been discovered in the latest Android beta and developer preview builds.</li>
<li>The feature is named <code>config_walletDoubleTapPowerGestureEnabled</code> and suggests that users will be able to change the default app for this gesture.</li>
<li>This capability is currently unavailable on Google Pixel phones, which may change with future updates.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If Google provided the option to launch Google Wallet with a double tap of the power button, would you use it?”</blockquote>
<p>This potential update reflects Google's continuous efforts to enhance user experience on Android devices, particularly in the realm of digital wallets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.androidauthority.com/double-tap-power-google-wallet-3513029/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.androidauthority.com/double-tap-power-google-wallet-3513029/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:10:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Could a 3.5-Million-Year-Old Bacterium Unlock the Secret to Eternal Youth? - YourStory]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNYkR1RkdPa0xXU09YeWlnSmI3Z2xOclBibnpGblZqMDMyOGVfOXkwWEhiUkw5MUwxUmpYOGlxajlDcGdsS0ZZdVdXOEk0Rmk4ZDRJYnRWS3dxcEpOSGVMVFR4NVFpWk14Q2lMaC1RYVBsSzZwV1Fodzl1ckhKMFpQZDJ6YnlSRVN0T1Fv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNYkR1RkdPa0xXU09YeWlnSmI3Z2xOclBibnpGblZqMDMyOGVfOXkwWEhiUkw5MUwxUmpYOGlxajlDcGdsS0ZZdVdXOEk0Rmk4ZDRJYnRWS3dxcEpOSGVMVFR4NVFpWk14Q2lMaC1RYVBsSzZwV1Fodzl1ckhKMFpQZDJ6YnlSRVN0T1Fv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unveiling the Key Mechanisms of Organic Carbon Preservation in Marine Sediments - AZoCleantech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unveiling the Key Mechanisms of Organic Carbon Preservation in Marine Sediments</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023-10-20 | <strong>Source:</strong> Nature Geoscience</p><p>Researchers from the University of Manchester and the University of Leeds have identified key mechanisms that sustain organic carbon in the ocean, influencing fossil fuel formation, the climate, and carbon cycles. Their findings elucidate the mystery of organic carbon preservation in marine environments.</p><img src='image_url.jpg' alt='Organic Carbon Preservation' /><figcaption>Illustration of organic carbon processes in marine sediments.</figcaption><p>Key Points:</p><ul><li>Organic carbon decomposes in most environments but remains preserved in marine sediments.</li><li>Two critical processes were identified: sorption and molecular transformation.</li><li>This research aids in developing strategies for reducing ocean carbon emissions.</li></ul><blockquote><p><em>Understanding how and why carbon is stored in marine sediments is crucial if we are to harness or replicate these natural processes to combat climate change.</em> - Dr. Peyman Babakhani</p></blockquote><p>The study highlights the importance of these mechanisms in carbon cycling, presenting new insights that could significantly influence future climate change mitigation strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.azocleantech.com/news.aspx?newsID=35454</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.azocleantech.com/news.aspx?newsID=35454</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anatomical Alterations Caused by Meloidogyne incognita in the Rhizospheric Region of Curcuma longa in Baruasagar Town of Jhansi (U.P.) India - Wiley Online Library]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZEFVX3lxTE1LZndtTFY5X2lxUEQwN3JvOHdjamtSZHE0NWY0MmRrakhNcEY2T0ktSnZaUXR5TEZ0SEUtNlpoNU02dUZnWGV0VkhVR2lETzJEZXNvR3l6THBmZHUyclVBeEtCZGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZEFVX3lxTE1LZndtTFY5X2lxUEQwN3JvOHdjamtSZHE0NWY0MmRrakhNcEY2T0ktSnZaUXR5TEZ0SEUtNlpoNU02dUZnWGV0VkhVR2lETzJEZXNvR3l6THBmZHUyclVBeEtCZGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:45:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Kessler Syndrome alert: Could we lose internet, TV, and phones forever - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Kessler Syndrome alert: Could we lose internet, TV, and phones forever</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>The article discusses NASA's warning regarding Kessler Syndrome and its potential to severely disrupt global communication systems, including the internet, television, and mobile phones.</p><ul><li>Kessler Syndrome refers to the scenario in which the density of objects in low Earth orbit is high enough to trigger a cascade of collisions.</li><li>NASA emphasizes the increasing risk due to the growing amount of space debris.</li><li>The implications for everyday technology and communication systems could be significant.</li></ul><blockquote>“If we don’t address the issue of space debris, we risk losing critical communication services.” - NASA Official</blockquote><p>This alert signals an urgent need for space debris management to safeguard our communication infrastructure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/nasas-kessler-syndrome-alert-could-we-lose-internet-tv-and-phones-forever/articleshow/116994619.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/nasas-kessler-syndrome-alert-could-we-lose-internet-tv-and-phones-forever/articleshow/116994619.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Updates Mars Sample Return Mission, Plans to Lower Costs - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/nasa-updates-mars-sample-return-mission-plans-to-lower-costs-risks-7411231</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/nasa-updates-mars-sample-return-mission-plans-to-lower-costs-risks-7411231</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:30:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Uncover the Ideal Physique for Keeping a Hula Hoop Spinning - ZME Science]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Uncover the Ideal Physique for Keeping a Hula Hoop Spinning</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> ZME Science</p>
<figure><img src="https://cdn.zmescience.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/hopa-hoop-1024x683.jpg" alt="woman hoola hooping" height="683" width="1024"><figcaption>Image via Flickr.</figcaption></figure>
<p>A hula hoop is more than a simple toy; it involves complex physics that a team of mathematicians at NYU has finally unraveled, revealing the ideal body shape for successful hula hooping.</p>
<ul>
<li>The NYU researchers explored the physics behind hula hooping, an activity that dates back to the 1950s but lacked scientific understanding.</li>
<li>The study showed that both synchronization of the hoop's orbit with a gyrating body and specific body shapes—the hourglass shape performs the best—are crucial for keeping the hoop aloft.</li>
<li>The results could have implications beyond play, inspiring innovations in robotics and energy extraction from vibrations.</li>
<li>The researchers emphasized that play can lead to significant scientific discoveries that inspire engineering advancements.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The math and physics involved are very subtle,” said Leif Ristroph, the study’s senior author.</blockquote>
<p>This research not only enhances our understanding of a popular children's activity but also paves the way for future technological innovations based on the principles of motion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.zmescience.com/science/physics/scientists-uncover-the-ideal-physique-for-keeping-a-hula-hoop-spinning/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zmescience.com/science/physics/scientists-uncover-the-ideal-physique-for-keeping-a-hula-hoop-spinning/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:17:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Productivity “hacks” don’t work. These do. - Vox.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Productivity “hacks” don’t work. These do.</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>As we enter a new year, many seek ways to enhance productivity. Unlike the endless search for the latest tools, experts suggest that traditional methods and simple systems can often yield better results.</p>
<ul>
<li>Productivity cannot be achieved through one-size-fits-all hacks; individual systems work best.</li>
<li>Basic tools like to-do lists can be more effective than complex organization systems.</li>
<li>Prioritizing tasks and utilizing a calendar can improve productivity significantly.</li>
<li>Setting professional boundaries helps protect personal time and collectively benefits others.</li>
<li>Constant optimization efforts can lead to exhaustion rather than fulfillment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Constant efforts to optimize yourself are more exhausting than they are rewarding.” - Alex Soojung-Kim Pang</blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, rather than chasing productivity hacks, focusing on what already works and allowing for flexibility may enhance both productivity and satisfaction.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.vox.com/even-better/393114/productivity-hacks-calendar-to-do-list-deadlines</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/even-better/393114/productivity-hacks-calendar-to-do-list-deadlines</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explained: Will Pluto Disappear By 2030? Know What Is In Store For Dwarf Planet - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Explained: Will Pluto Disappear By 2030? Know What Is In Store For Dwarf Planet</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 06, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Free Press Journal</p>
<img src="https://media.assettype.com/freepressjournal/2025-01-06/dahi3sj2/26e8ae9b733f5b71798c450c6b85da1c.jpg" alt="Pluto" />
<figcaption>Image of Pluto</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the potentially alarming fate of Pluto by 2030, elaborating on the studies that suggest its atmosphere may collapse due to several shifting climatic factors.</p>
<ul>
  <li>According to a 2019 study, Pluto's atmosphere could completely collapse and freeze by 2030.</li>
  <li>Pluto's atmosphere is already thin and composed of nitrogen, methane, and carbon monoxide.</li>
  <li>The dwarf planet is moving away from the sun, leading to colder temperatures.</li>
  <li>Nitrogen is expected to freeze out of the atmosphere when Pluto is at its farthest from the sun.</li>
  <li>The atmosphere could frost out and vanish entirely, causing Pluto to appear brighter from Earth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If Pluto does freeze over, it will appear much brighter to Earth.”</blockquote>
<p>This raises significant concerns about the impacts of climate fluctuations even in distant celestial bodies, encouraging ongoing research and observation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/ampstories/photo-gallery/explained-will-pluto-disappear-by-2030-know-what-is-in-store-for-dwarf-planet</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/ampstories/photo-gallery/explained-will-pluto-disappear-by-2030-know-what-is-in-store-for-dwarf-planet</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:55:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tricorder Tech: A Nanopore Diagnostic Tool Breakthrough Had Multiple Applications - Astrobiology News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tricorder Tech: A Nanopore Diagnostic Tool Breakthrough Had Multiple Applications</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Publication Date not provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> Astrobiology</p>
<img src="https://astrobiology.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Tricorder-Tech-A-Nanopore-Diagnostic.png" alt="Tricorder Tech: A Nanopore Diagnostic Tool Breakthrough Had Multiple Applications">
<figcaption>The sensor, a glass tube that is melted at the tip to form a sharp needle-like structure, is dipped into a fluid containing molecules. (Kevin Freedman/ImageFX/UCR)</figcaption>
<p>UC Riverside scientists have developed a nanopore-based diagnostic tool that may revolutionize disease detection by accurately capturing signals from individual molecules.</p>
<ul>
<li>The nanopore sensor allows for precise disease diagnostics with a focus on individual protein and DNA molecules.</li>
<li>Current testing methods require millions of molecules, but the new approach can yield useful data from a single molecule.</li>
<li>This technology could lead to the development of portable diagnostic kits capable of early infection detection within 24 to 48 hours.</li>
<li>It offers improvements over traditional sensors by filtering out background noise, enhancing accuracy in diagnostics.</li>
<li>The technology could also advance protein research, aiding in understanding healthcare and disease progression.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Nanopores offer a way to catch infections sooner—before symptoms appear and before the disease spreads.” - Kevin Freedman</blockquote>
<p>The potential applications of this technology indicate a future where affordable nanopore tools could be commonplace in both research and clinical settings, marking a significant step towards personalized medicine.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://astrobiology.com/2025/01/tricorder-tech-a-nanopore-diagnostic-tool-breakthrough-had-multiple-applications.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrobiology.com/2025/01/tricorder-tech-a-nanopore-diagnostic-tool-breakthrough-had-multiple-applications.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:54:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nascent galaxy discovered in formation at the end of the longest tidal tail of NGC 3785 galaxy - Department Of Science & Technology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxQdTllNlZqWXdTRTIwRWdOVnV4WHhmRGx4SzctWW9Ka2VySnY0dEhQa3BWM0w1YzctQmJZcEhDNWhJMGgycmd4R0NOZ1k1eVdDS3J4N3JGcWNCSHZxNUJ3OEZlOWZpOW1VQVl0WjhnY2djSDVNQS1IbnRoa3U2TFJmV2tqeU5aZGZiMzVmUmhnaU1FeGNpWkY4eA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxQdTllNlZqWXdTRTIwRWdOVnV4WHhmRGx4SzctWW9Ka2VySnY0dEhQa3BWM0w1YzctQmJZcEhDNWhJMGgycmd4R0NOZ1k1eVdDS3J4N3JGcWNCSHZxNUJ3OEZlOWZpOW1VQVl0WjhnY2djSDVNQS1IbnRoa3U2TFJmV2tqeU5aZGZiMzVmUmhnaU1FeGNpWkY4eA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:54:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chimpanzees Use Stone Tools like Ancient Human, Study Finds - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxOZWJDR3paZUhNY1REclU2bzhBSlpnanhMdmtpRVN3ZlFOMWlodjJVVkpxa1diOTJzbUh0T3NZOUNGUFNxY0tLVC1VeUlyWDR2MU5PLUc0ZHBrTXAyTUNPQmY0ejdpMkczZEZzcGNLVnZqMkE2N0RWbTEwcndTUnBTWEhTVm8weGtaN1IxVkt6azRMOFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxOZWJDR3paZUhNY1REclU2bzhBSlpnanhMdmtpRVN3ZlFOMWlodjJVVkpxa1diOTJzbUh0T3NZOUNGUFNxY0tLVC1VeUlyWDR2MU5PLUc0ZHBrTXAyTUNPQmY0ejdpMkczZEZzcGNLVnZqMkE2N0RWbTEwcndTUnBTWEhTVm8weGtaN1IxVkt6azRMOFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:49:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The carbon in our bodies probably feft the galaxy and came back on cosmic 'conveyer belt' - Nanowerk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The carbon in our bodies probably left the galaxy and came back on cosmic 'conveyer belt'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 06, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Nanowerk News</p>
<img src="id66228_1.jpg" alt="In this artistic rendering, light from a distant quasar passes through the halo-like circumgalactic medium of a galaxy on its way to Earth, where it is measured by Hubble's Cosmic Origins Spectrograph to determine the composition of the halo">
<figcaption>In this artistic rendering, light from a distant quasar passes through the halo-like circumgalactic medium of a galaxy on its way to Earth, where it is measured by Hubble's Cosmic Origins Spectrograph to determine the composition of the halo. (Image: NASA/ESA/A. Field)</figcaption>
<p>Life on Earth relies on carbon, which originates from stars. Recent findings reveal that carbon atoms cycle through the universe on giant currents that act as cosmic conveyer belts, returning material to form new celestial bodies.</p>
<ul>
<li>A team of scientists confirmed that carbon and star-formed atoms travel through the circumgalactic medium, a process essential for galaxy formation.</li>
<li>This circumgalactic medium can be likened to a train station, constantly pushing material out and pulling it back in.</li>
<li>The study suggests these carbon atoms in our bodies likely spent time outside our galaxy.</li>
<li>Future research will quantify the elements in the circumgalactic medium to understand galaxy transition into stellar deserts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The implications for galaxy evolution, and for the nature of the reservoir of carbon available to galaxies for forming new stars, are exciting.” – Jessica Werk</blockquote>
<p>Understanding the circumgalactic medium's role in recycling material could provide insights into the long-term evolution of galaxies, including our own.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nanowerk.com/news2/space/newsid=66228.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nanowerk.com/news2/space/newsid=66228.php</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:06:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What temperature is the moon? - Livescience.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livescience.com/space/the-moon/what-temperature-is-the-moon</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livescience.com/space/the-moon/what-temperature-is-the-moon</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What temperature is the moon? - Livescience.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livescience.com/space/the-moon/what-temperature-is-the-moon</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livescience.com/space/the-moon/what-temperature-is-the-moon</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space42 Launches Thuraya 4 for Wider Coverage Across EMEA, Central Asia - SpaceWatch.Global]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://spacewatch.global/2025/01/space42-launches-thuraya-4-for-wider-coverage-across-emea-central-asia/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://spacewatch.global/2025/01/space42-launches-thuraya-4-for-wider-coverage-across-emea-central-asia/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 09:55:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Discovery of Bistable Nanocrystals Promises Faster, More Energy-Efficient Optical Computing - Technology Networks]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Discovery of Bistable Nanocrystals Promises Faster, More Energy-Efficient Optical Computing</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Nature Photonics</p><p>Scientists have made a significant advancement in optical computing through the discovery of luminescent nanocrystals that can rapidly toggle between light and dark states. This breakthrough could revolutionize information processing and storage using light.</p><ul><li>Research by Oregon State University and collaborators identifies luminescent nanocrystals with unique switching capabilities.</li><li>These nanocrystals can change states under the same laser power, showcasing intrinsic optical bistability.</li><li>The low power consumption of these materials aligns with global efforts to reduce energy usage in AI and data processing.</li><li>Possible applications include enhanced machine learning algorithms and more efficient light-based devices for telecommunications and imaging.</li></ul><blockquote>“Integrating photonic materials with intrinsic optical bistability could mean faster and more efficient data processors.” - Artiom Skripka</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while this research presents exciting potential for future technologies, further studies are necessary to overcome current challenges before practical applications can be realized.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.technologynetworks.com/applied-sciences/news/discovery-of-bistable-nanocrystals-promises-faster-more-energy-efficient-optical-computing-394669</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.technologynetworks.com/applied-sciences/news/discovery-of-bistable-nanocrystals-promises-faster-more-energy-efficient-optical-computing-394669</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 09:42:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Einstein and Adam Grant Agree: The ‘Puzzle Principle’ Will Make You Instantly Smarter - Inc.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Einstein and Adam Grant Agree: The 'Puzzle Principle' Will Make You Instantly Smarter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Inc.com</p><p>The article discusses how the 'Puzzle Principle', as interpreted from Einstein's philosophy, can enhance intelligence and problem-solving in everyday life. Author Benyamin Cohen highlights key insights from Einstein's work and modern psychology, particularly the views of Adam Grant.</p><ul><li>The 'Puzzle Principle' encourages viewing problems as puzzles rather than tests of intelligence.</li><li>Einstein is noted for his humility and openness to being wrong, which contributed to his groundbreaking theories.</li><li>Adam Grant emphasizes the importance of intellectual humility and curiosity in learning and problem-solving.</li><li>Studies show that adopting a puzzle-like approach in business can lead to greater financial success.</li><li>Embracing humility helps improve evidence evaluation and motivates ongoing learning.</li></ul><blockquote>“Favor humility over pride and curiosity over conviction,” says Adam Grant.</blockquote><p>The 'Puzzle Principle' underscores that anyone can enhance their problem-solving skills and intelligence by adopting a playful and inquisitive mindset, just as Einstein did.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.inc.com/jessica-stillman/einstein-and-adam-grant-agree-the-puzzle-principle-will-make-you-instantly-smarter/91102339</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.inc.com/jessica-stillman/einstein-and-adam-grant-agree-the-puzzle-principle-will-make-you-instantly-smarter/91102339</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 09:41:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quadrantids Meteor Shower Shines Above Mt. Fuji; Photographers Exclaim in Delight - The Japan News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE1nM0xKc3N4WEhrRmNrVU1IRUlLdXdxSXA1NjhhdVlKYm4yVXBWQ1ZRdzBFREpZTXpYUU1KV3Y5TTRWRUVKOWtjaHBtY0hzM0pFdlg4YjI2d2ZCNlhCVFgwUWJUYlZycWRJRVRoakxDdVlQVzIzU3FOaQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE1nM0xKc3N4WEhrRmNrVU1IRUlLdXdxSXA1NjhhdVlKYm4yVXBWQ1ZRdzBFREpZTXpYUU1KV3Y5TTRWRUVKOWtjaHBtY0hzM0pFdlg4YjI2d2ZCNlhCVFgwUWJUYlZycWRJRVRoakxDdVlQVzIzU3FOaQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 08:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space42 launches Thuraya 4 satellite into orbit from SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket - Telecompaper EN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.telecompaper.com/news/space42-launches-thuraya-4-satellite-into-orbit-from-spacex-falcon-9-rocket--1523638</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.telecompaper.com/news/space42-launches-thuraya-4-satellite-into-orbit-from-spacex-falcon-9-rocket--1523638</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 08:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Find 200 Fresh Dino Footprints on UKs Dinosaur Highway - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/science/scientists-find-200-fresh-dino-footprints-on-uks-dinosaur-highway</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/science/scientists-find-200-fresh-dino-footprints-on-uks-dinosaur-highway</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 08:56:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GPT-4 demonstrates high accuracy in analyzing multilingual medical notes - News-Medical.Net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GPT-4 demonstrates high accuracy in analyzing multilingual medical notes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2025-01-06 <strong>Source:</strong> The Lancet Digital Health</p><img src="https://d2jx2rerrg6sh3.cloudfront.net/images/news/ImageForNews_799194_17361521783149517.jpg" alt="ChatGPT Chat with AI or Artificial Intelligence technology." width="2000" height="1205"><figcaption>GPT-4 demonstrates high accuracy in analyzing multilingual medical notes</figcaption><p>This study published in <em>The Lancet Digital Health</em> evaluates GPT-4’s ability to process medical notes in English, Spanish, and Italian, achieving physician agreement in 79% of responses.</p><ul><li>Involving eight university hospitals from the USA, Colombia, Singapore, and Italy.</li><li>A total of 56 de-identified medical notes were analyzed.</li><li>Physician agreement rates varied by language, with the highest for Spanish (88%) and Italian (84%).</li><li>Challenges included contextual inference and variability in documentation styles.</li></ul><blockquote>“GPT-4 accurately analyzed medical notes in English, Italian, and Spanish, performing surprisingly better with non-English notes.”</blockquote><p>The study highlights GPT-4’s strengths in extracting explicit information while presenting challenges with implicit contextual understanding.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250106/GPT-4-demonstrates-high-accuracy-in-analyzing-multilingual-medical-notes.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250106/GPT-4-demonstrates-high-accuracy-in-analyzing-multilingual-medical-notes.aspx</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 08:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[​6 Amazing Pictures Of Interacting Galaxies Captured By NASA Telescope ​ - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Amazing Pictures Of Interacting Galaxies Captured By NASA Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116985221/116985221.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=1399492" alt="6 Amazing Pictures Of Interacting Galaxies Captured By NASA Telescope" />
<figcaption>Credit: NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases stunning images of interacting galaxies captured by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting their unique features and beauty.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Image of NGC 7049 showing a collection of globular clusters.</li>
  <li>Portrait of Stephan’s Quintet, a group of five galaxies including a foreground galaxy.</li>
  <li>NGC 5128 known for its dramatic dark lanes of dusty material.</li>
  <li>NGC 3717, a beautiful spiral galaxy located about 60 million light-years away.</li>
  <li>NGC 1316, depicting the results of a merger between two galaxies.</li>
  <li>Arp 148 showing a ring-shaped galaxy involved in a collision.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It has intricate loops and blobs of cosmic dust, evidence of past galactic mergers.”</blockquote>
<p>This collection of images emphasizes the complexity and dynamic nature of our universe as seen through NASA's advanced technologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-amazing-pictures-of-interacting-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-telescope/photostory/116985182.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-amazing-pictures-of-interacting-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-telescope/photostory/116985182.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 06:44:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mysterious object found orbiting the Sun once every 50 years - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mysterious object found orbiting the Sun once every 50 years</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 6, 2025 | <strong>Published By:</strong> Sibu Kumar Tripathi</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/comet-or-asteroid-063022268-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=KbBP2OlwOU3FkKPjoUvCQbWI4.Xlr5jR&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Comet or asteroid" title="Artistic representation of an active centaur like Chiron. The different colors in the coma indicate varying compositions of gas, ice, and dust. (Image Credit: William Gonzalez Sierra)" height="388"><figcaption>Artistic representation of an active centaur like Chiron. The different colors in the coma indicate varying compositions of gas, ice, and dust. (Image Credit: William Gonzalez Sierra)</figcaption><p>Recent observations from the James Webb Space Telescope have revealed important details about Chiron, a celestial body with features of both asteroids and comets. Discovered in 1977, it has a 50-year orbit between Jupiter and Neptune.</p><ul><li>Findings indicate the presence of frozen carbon dioxide, carbon monoxide, and methane gases in Chiron’s coma.</li><li>This is the first time such a combination of ices has been observed on a centaur.</li><li>The study enhances understanding of the primordial conditions of our solar system.</li><li>Researchers are exploring Chiron's dynamic behavior and interactions with its environment.</li></ul><blockquote>“Active centaurs like Chiron provide a unique opportunity to learn about both surface and subsurface layers.” - Noemi Pinilla-Alonso</blockquote><p>This research not only signifies a breakthrough in planetary science but also paves the way for further studies as Chiron approaches Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/mysterious-object-found-orbiting-the-sun-once-every-50-years-james-webb-telescope-2660227-2025-01-06</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/mysterious-object-found-orbiting-the-sun-once-every-50-years-james-webb-telescope-2660227-2025-01-06</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 06:31:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>