<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:18:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:18:28 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024: The year US private companies reached new frontiers in space exploration | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Private Companies Reach New Frontiers in Space Exploration in 2024</h1><p><strong>Published on: January 31, 2024, Source: Live Mint</strong></p><img src='https://www.livemint.com/img/2024/01/spacex_axiom_mission_3_1685462329207_1685462331972.jpg' alt='SpaceX Axiom Mission 3' /><figcaption>SpaceX's Axiom Mission 3 crew members (left to right): Michael López-Alegría, Walter Villadei, Alper Gezeravcı, and Marcus Wandt.</figcaption><p>The year 2024 has been a remarkable year for US private space companies, with several significant launches pushing the boundaries of space exploration, technology, and commercial space endeavors. These launches showcase the rapid progress of private companies in the space industry and pave the way for more advanced missions, scientific research, and commercial opportunities.</p><ol><li><strong>SpaceX Axiom Mission 3 (Ax-3)</strong> – Launched on January 18, 2024, this mission carried a crew to the International Space Station (ISS), where they conducted scientific research and technology demonstrations. The mission marked another major achievement in commercial spaceflight.</li><li><strong>Virgin Galactic’s SpaceShipTwo VSS Unity – Galactic 06</strong> – On January 26, 2024, Virgin Galactic completed its first spaceflight of the year, carrying four private astronauts on a suborbital journey, highlighting the growing viability of commercial space tourism.</li><li><strong>Blue Origin’s New Shepard NS-25 and NS-26 missions</strong> – These suborbital missions, launched on May 19 and August 29, 2024, carried scientific payloads and private passengers into space, advancing reusable rocket technology and reducing the cost of space access.</li><li><strong>Polaris Dawn – First Commercial Spacewalk</strong> – Launched on September 10, 2024, the Polaris Dawn mission made history by completing the first-ever commercial spacewalk and achieving the highest orbit since the Apollo era.</li><li><strong>ULA’s Atlas V Rocket with Boeing Starliner</strong> – On June 5, 2024, ULA's Atlas V launched Boeing’s CST-100 Starliner with NASA astronauts, marking the return of human spaceflight to Cape Canaveral since 1962 and demonstrating the reliability of private sector-developed spacecraft.</li><li><strong>Rocket Lab’s Electron Achieves 50th Launch Milestone</strong> – On June 21, 2024, Rocket Lab’s Electron rocket became the fastest privately developed orbital launch vehicle to achieve 50 launches, solidifying its position as a leading provider in the small satellite launch market.</li></ol><blockquote>“This is a new era of space exploration, and private companies are leading the way.” – Bob Richards, CEO of Moon Express</blockquote><p>These launches and missions demonstrate the incredible progress and potential of private space companies, which are rapidly expanding the possibilities for space exploration and commercialization.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/2024-the-year-us-private-companies-reached-new-frontiers-in-space-exploration-11735574794024.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/2024-the-year-us-private-companies-reached-new-frontiers-in-space-exploration-11735574794024.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 16:59:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aurora alert: Powerful geomagnetic storm could spark northern lights as far south as Illinois tonight and tomorrow - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aurora Alert: Powerful Geomagnetic Storm Could Spark Northern Lights as Far South as Illinois Tonight and Tomorrow</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Dec. 30, 2024, Space.com</p>
<img src="https://www.space.com/images/i/000/000/000/000i0000000.jpg" alt="Aurora" width="800" height="533"><figcaption>Potential aurora sightings could be visible deep into mid-latitudes tonight and tomorrow (Dec. 30 to Dec. 31).</figcaption>
<p>Due to an incoming solar storm, also known as a <a href="https://www.space.com/coronal-mass-ejections-cme">coronal mass ejection</a> (CME), the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Space Weather Prediction Center issued a G3 (strong) geomagnetic storm warning for Dec. 31.</p>
<p>This is great news for those wishing to <a href="https://www.space.com/32601-where-to-see-northern-lights.html">see the northern lights</a> as the predicted geomagnetic storm could spark auroras as far south as <a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/noaa-scales-explanation">Illinois and Oregon</a> (around 50° latitude).</p>
<ol>
<li>The culprit is a CME, a vast plume of plasma and magnetic field, hurled out into space by the sun on Dec. 29.</li>
<li>When CMEs strike Earth's magnetosphere, they bring electrically charged particles called ions that collide with Earth's magnetic field, sparking geomagnetic storms.</li>
<li>During these storms, ions collide with atmospheric gases, releasing energy that manifests as light, creating the stunning displays known as the northern lights, or aurora borealis, in the Northern Hemisphere.</li>
<li>NOAA classifies geomagnetic storms using a G-scale, which ranks their intensity from G1 (minor) to G5 (extreme). The recent geomagnetic storm watch NOAA issued is rated as a G3, indicating strong storm conditions.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>"The Sun has really stepped up over the past few days, with frequent solar flares including a strong X-class event! A selection of these flares produced Earth-directed eruptions, expected to trigger a strong geomagnetic storm (bringing aurora) on the 31st!" - Ryan French, Solar Astrophysicist</blockquote>
<p>Current predictions place the highest level of activity between 10 p.m. EST on Dec. 30 and 10 a.m. EST on Dec. 31. Another spate of activity is anticipated for between 4:00 p.m. EST on Dec. 31 and 10:00 p.m. EST on Jan 1, with G1 conditions expected.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that <a href="https://www.space.com/space-weather">space weather</a> is unpredictable and difficult to forecast. Even though geomagnetic storm warnings at this level are rare, they can occasionally amount to nothing.</p>
<p>If you're interested in tracking space weather and knowing when and where to spot auroras, download a space weather app that provides forecasts based on your location.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/stargazing/aurora-borealis/aurora-alert-powerful-geomagnetic-storm-could-spark-northern-lights-as-far-south-as-illinois-tonight-and-tomorrow</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/stargazing/aurora-borealis/aurora-alert-powerful-geomagnetic-storm-could-spark-northern-lights-as-far-south-as-illinois-tonight-and-tomorrow</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:50:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025’s 10 biggest NASA space mission launches: From lunar exploration to supersonic travel | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxOaUQyYUFoWUdXQTZaLXpTMWJ0c2NMZ2pqbWt2UWRZeS1KZUQwcXltWklZQWhNeHJCdGpTcW55bXJEQjAyS3o5UWZEa014bEdYanZobGVOeEZLSWE1Y3U4emZKWkRBTWx6Q3RoOVpYaHFGeHN1LWVsMThLVDFjTjJJLV9YZndrdUdIaklVUkRub2tRRTEwUkpYc0ltVDlWZk5wUmpwQzRnbTI4YUFUam9FMHE1ZTFEY0xDTHJfeWJyUUE1VEh1YXpza3ZTb0M2NUo1MzZBeDFZdW9DWjJPR2FZ0gHkAUFVX3lxTE1GMUtiekdYakpyU01pQUZNckxxQm1ueWNLQ05kV2I4YUNSXzVPRHl1c2xnbHhMVDFKSkhscjZUTXR4ZEMzamk4SjNnaWdHc1UyRTJmZEZ0SjMwMFl6TXpnVWJEUE5Zd2toSWx1RUFOZlBza1JXNWZVWnBaNHdzQ0czSll4dzNQMXRINGZRdVVQVmlSWVJuZXVkTFZQazkwWndTOUhGSXpHc2ZNOFA4aTZTRW8wOU0yVG9DX1hJUWJqdl9ENDNsdldXdThldGZnOUxCQ29za3p2SWhzekhlYmJtQ1NZdg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxOaUQyYUFoWUdXQTZaLXpTMWJ0c2NMZ2pqbWt2UWRZeS1KZUQwcXltWklZQWhNeHJCdGpTcW55bXJEQjAyS3o5UWZEa014bEdYanZobGVOeEZLSWE1Y3U4emZKWkRBTWx6Q3RoOVpYaHFGeHN1LWVsMThLVDFjTjJJLV9YZndrdUdIaklVUkRub2tRRTEwUkpYc0ltVDlWZk5wUmpwQzRnbTI4YUFUam9FMHE1ZTFEY0xDTHJfeWJyUUE1VEh1YXpza3ZTb0M2NUo1MzZBeDFZdW9DWjJPR2FZ0gHkAUFVX3lxTE1GMUtiekdYakpyU01pQUZNckxxQm1ueWNLQ05kV2I4YUNSXzVPRHl1c2xnbHhMVDFKSkhscjZUTXR4ZEMzamk4SjNnaWdHc1UyRTJmZEZ0SjMwMFl6TXpnVWJEUE5Zd2toSWx1RUFOZlBza1JXNWZVWnBaNHdzQ0czSll4dzNQMXRINGZRdVVQVmlSWVJuZXVkTFZQazkwWndTOUhGSXpHc2ZNOFA4aTZTRW8wOU0yVG9DX1hJUWJqdl9ENDNsdldXdThldGZnOUxCQ29za3p2SWhzekhlYmJtQ1NZdg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 15:09:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronomy and space: highlights of 2024 - physicsworld.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTE9hTXNyWjFTQTVYR1FMQlZUUXBNOEFHOFZGcGdBaVdnUDlTUXBZMElVSTh0R29nN0FtSGhoZkhtV1lyYXdVZDdJSnBPUU5tLWxaSURfTTh3T3F6QWNlbXZxQzRpRmJXMmJlYjVHeGpIcDNRS0Zy?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTE9hTXNyWjFTQTVYR1FMQlZUUXBNOEFHOFZGcGdBaVdnUDlTUXBZMElVSTh0R29nN0FtSGhoZkhtV1lyYXdVZDdJSnBPUU5tLWxaSURfTTh3T3F6QWNlbXZxQzRpRmJXMmJlYjVHeGpIcDNRS0Zy?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:05:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Artemis program needs a new public relations angle - SpaceNews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Artemis Program Needs a New PR Strategy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Current Date<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Source Name</p><p>As NASA's Artemis program progresses, questions around its purpose and the need for a space race echo past concerns over the Apollo missions. With increasing skepticism towards Artemis, NASA must redefine its message focusing on technological advancements and scientific discoveries rather than competition.</p><ul><li>Revisiting the motivations behind the moon missions amidst public skepticism.</li><li>The need for a compelling narrative that highlights technological and economic benefits of the Artemis program.</li><li>Recent delays jeopardize the timeline for crewed lunar landings, prompting calls for a strategic pause.</li><li>Public opinion polls indicate low prioritization of lunar missions, emphasizing the need for NASA to better communicate benefits.</li><li>Historical context from Apollo missions presents lessons on the significance of public relations in space exploration.</li></ul><blockquote>“What we need is to purge and purify the great enterprise of exploring the universe.” - Walter Lippmann</blockquote><p>NASA faces a critical juncture in framing its lunar ambitions. Moving forward requires building public trust and understanding the broader implications of space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://spacenews.com/nasas-artemis-program-needs-a-new-public-relations-angle/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://spacenews.com/nasas-artemis-program-needs-a-new-public-relations-angle/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quadrantids Meteor Shower 2025: When And Where To Watch In India - Jagran English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxOSS1mRGFiUFlhTnNNLW9HQVJEdzFrU040VkhOZzRyMlI0TzM3b2xLdDczZjhkRzdhWkRUS2Q2MjRLZEs2OEFmQnlxakxEVXgwY0czdHkwVjh2Vzd0dnRJTXVRVkdYTW5EZnpBM0l2c0hnSVkwdllTRGw3VW1wYTdqUkhhaVZQWHp1T1U3Y2RLQUgtZ0xVZE1BRHh1cS1FU1JmUnhlNUhhR3hUTFROSE9TeVdLY2YyVTByZmw0MFpGYkxiNHlMVlNsOHJkSFdMeU5hS01oTG45U1ByUEI3Z2JR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxOSS1mRGFiUFlhTnNNLW9HQVJEdzFrU040VkhOZzRyMlI0TzM3b2xLdDczZjhkRzdhWkRUS2Q2MjRLZEs2OEFmQnlxakxEVXgwY0czdHkwVjh2Vzd0dnRJTXVRVkdYTW5EZnpBM0l2c0hnSVkwdllTRGw3VW1wYTdqUkhhaVZQWHp1T1U3Y2RLQUgtZ0xVZE1BRHh1cS1FU1JmUnhlNUhhR3hUTFROSE9TeVdLY2YyVTByZmw0MFpGYkxiNHlMVlNsOHJkSFdMeU5hS01oTG45U1ByUEI3Z2JR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These are the 7 biggest milestones in the aerospace industry so far this millennium: Review 24 years of rockets with us - Softonic EN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>These are the 7 biggest milestones in the aerospace industry so far this millennium: Review 24 years of rockets with us</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Softonic</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://articles-img.sftcdn.net/t_articles/auto-mapping-folder/sites/3/2024/09/newsletter.png?GoogleAccessId=wp-stateless%40kubertonic.iam.gserviceaccount.com&amp;Expires=1735556186&amp;Signature=PaekQb29Z%2F7we3VlWwvMB0e1sFZt73DauDbuAwtGf%2Bo%2FscFkJIbq5hWE97tUrPWnP3YiC4seX5B6al3PM9R3%2BHwF7izpXKueza9%2BJLMuV4cmyfx5g%2FJgaXPgthRsNBUwQZsW1H0auBi86PBfsd6N81L2jvKjb66jMTMqubVlmWFSijzu3OvUAVtPy5rUFBhLzsbFOYN3ZUOcMwPrRmkBKSUzOdLVKGoQTqgr98ovH0lPLCQEB3sUf3DbSzKu%2FDIXoeUcvTLoW1nK3iA1IM0c84WI2KiYV10Ut2iULMe2HEHXqqA1Q3xBxr0LZsJHIfCYJCHoguq0XlNPfbHYOJ0IYA%3D%3D" width="100px" height="100px">
<p>Introduction: From 2000 to 2024, the aerospace industry has seen remarkable advancements marked by significant milestones. This article reviews seven of the most crucial achievements that have reshaped space exploration.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Artemis I mission marks the revival of lunar exploration.</li>
  <li>SpaceX's Dragon capsule enables crewed spaceflights and research opportunities.</li>
  <li>Detection of gravitational waves confirmed Einstein’s theory of relativity.</li>
  <li>Space tourism gained momentum with significant private missions.</li>
  <li>China's Chang’e program made historic lunar landings and aims for human missions.</li>
  <li>SpaceX's Starship reusability innovation showcased next-gen capabilities.</li>
  <li>Falcon Heavy demonstrated the viability of commercial heavy-lift space travel.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“SpaceX demonstrated that a private company could independently finance and fly the largest and most powerful rocket in the world.”</blockquote>
<p>Conclusion: The developments in aerospace over the last two decades reflect not only technological advancements but also a shift towards privatization and international competition in space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://en.softonic.com/articles/these-are-the-7-biggest-milestones-in-the-aerospace-industry-so-far-this-millennium-review-24-years-of-rockets-with-us</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.softonic.com/articles/these-are-the-7-biggest-milestones-in-the-aerospace-industry-so-far-this-millennium-review-24-years-of-rockets-with-us</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:34:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hubble Space Telescope captures spiral galaxy in aftermath of supernova - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hubble Telescope Captures Spiral Galaxy After Supernova Explosion</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date & Source:</strong> <em>New Delhi, News9Live</em></p>
<img src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/LEDA-22057.jpg?w=802&enlarge=true" alt="The spiral galaxy LEDA 22057." width="802" height="464">
<figcaption>The spiral galaxy LEDA 22057. (Image Credit: ESA/Hubble and NASA, R. J. Foley, UC Santa Cruz).</figcaption>
<p>The Hubble Space Telescope has captured the spiral galaxy LEDA 22057, located 650 million light-years away in the constellation of Gemini. An automated survey spotted a supernova, designated 2024PI, in this galaxy earlier this year. The image, taken about a month after the supernova's discovery, shows the blue dot towards the right of the central bulge, which is the fading supernova.</p>
<ul>
<li>The supernova, SN 2024PI, is a Type Ia supernova, which requires a dense white dwarf and a binary companion.</li>
<li>The white dwarf siphons off material from its companion, leading to a violent explosion when the accumulated material becomes too massive.</li>
<li>In the distant future, about five billion years from now, the Sun is expected to become a red giant and die in a supernova explosion, but it will not produce a Type Ia supernova since it is not part of a binary system.</li>
</ul>
<p>Aditya Madanapalle, a science and technology reporter, wrote this article. He has over 10 years of experience and focuses on space, AI, videogames, cybersecurity, and fundamental research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/hubble-space-telescope-captures-spiral-galaxy-in-aftermath-of-supernova-2785516</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/hubble-space-telescope-captures-spiral-galaxy-in-aftermath-of-supernova-2785516</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:31:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnal Students Recognised by NASA for Discovering Main Belt Asteroid TD40 - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnal Students Get NASA Nod for Asteroid Discovery</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/nB0t6sp9Te8/hqdefault.jpg" alt="NASA Recognition Ceremony"><figcaption>Karnal students recognized by NASA for asteroid discovery</figcaption><p>A group of 12 students and two teachers from Dyal Singh Public School in Karnal have been recognized by NASA's International Astronomical Search Collaboration for discovering a main belt asteroid, designated TD40.</p><ul><li>The discovery was made using data from the Pan-STARRS telescope.</li><li>Certificates were awarded to students for their contributions to this project.</li><li>A ceremony was held to honor the students, attended by notable figures from the scientific community.</li><li>Principal Sushma Devgun highlighted the dedication of the students and their potential future contributions to science.</li></ul><blockquote>“The involvement of students in a NASA project has been a source of motivation for the school community.” - Principal Sushma Devgun</blockquote><p>This achievement underscores the importance of collaborative efforts in education and research, showcasing how young minds can gain international recognition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/karnal-students-receive-nasa-recognition-for-asteroid-discovery-7363018</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/karnal-students-receive-nasa-recognition-for-asteroid-discovery-7363018</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Cities In India Where You Could See 2025's First Meteor Shower 'Quadrantid' - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Cities In India Where You Could See 2025's First Meteor Shower 'Quadrantid'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116798832/116798832.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=96150" alt="10 Cities In India Where You Could See 2025's First Meteor Shower 'Quadrantid'" />
<figcaption>Image Credit: Canva</figcaption>
<p>The Quadrantid Meteor Shower will occur in January 2025, and there are prime locations across India for stargazers to witness this spectacular event. From high-altitude regions to serene deserts, the article explores ten cities that offer the best views.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Leh, Ladakh:</strong> Clear night skies, perfect viewing spots include Nubra Valley and Hanle Observatory.</li>
  <li><strong>Spiti Valley, Himachal Pradesh:</strong> Renowned for its serenity, ideal spots include Dhankar and Langza.</li>
  <li><strong>Auli, Uttarakhand:</strong> Famous for its snow-covered landscapes, with best viewing near Gorson Bugyal.</li>
  <li><strong>Rishikesh, Uttarakhand:</strong> Clear skies and serene views, especially around Neelkanth.</li>
  <li><strong>Kheerganga, Himachal Pradesh:</strong> A secluded spot ideal for stargazing while enjoying hot springs.</li>
  <li><strong>Jaisalmer, Rajasthan:</strong> The clear skies of the Thar Desert make it an excellent viewing location.</li>
  <li><strong>Nainital, Uttarakhand:</strong> Notable for its ARIES, with prime spots at Hanumangarhi.</li>
  <li><strong>Manali, Himachal Pradesh:</strong> Offers a blend of accessibility and remote stargazing spots.</li>
  <li><strong>Srinagar, Jammu & Kashmir:</strong> Scenic landscapes complemented by a clear night sky.</li>
  <li><strong>Alwar, Rajasthan:</strong> An underrated stargazing location with low light pollution near Sariska.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Quadrantid Meteor Shower peaks in the early hours of January 3-4, 2025. Be outside between midnight and dawn."</blockquote>
<p>This meteor shower promises a dazzling display across the country, making these cities perfect for astronomers and enthusiasts alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/travel/10-cities-in-india-where-you-can-see-2025s-first-meteor-shower-quadrantid/photostory/116798826.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/travel/10-cities-in-india-where-you-can-see-2025s-first-meteor-shower-quadrantid/photostory/116798826.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to start learning about space: A beginner’s guide - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How to Start Learning About Space: A Beginner’s Guide</h1>
<p><strong>Date: 2024-12-30</strong> <br> <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/900x1600/Space_1735543873276_1735543873552.jpg" alt="Space" width="300" height="500"><figcaption>Photo Credit: Pexels</figcaption>
<p>Space, the vast and mostly empty region beyond Earth’s atmosphere, is home to stars, planets, and galaxies. This beginner's guide helps you start your journey into understanding and exploring space.</p>
<ol>
<li>Start with our solar system, which consists of the Sun, eight planets, moons, asteroids, and comets.</li>
<li>Use books, documentaries, and online resources to learn more about space.</li>
<li>Explore NASA’s website for educational material and incredible views of distant stars and galaxies through Hubble and James Webb telescopes.</li>
<li>Download space apps to learn about constellations, planets, and space missions in real-time.</li>
<li>Watch documentaries like “Cosmos” or NASA’s “The Planets” to deepen your understanding.</li>
<li>Join local or online astronomy clubs and participate in space-related events.</li>
</ol>
<p>10 colourful space photos by NASA are included to leave you amazed.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/trending/how-to-start-learning-about-space-a-beginner-s-guide-101735543406314.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/trending/how-to-start-learning-about-space-a-beginner-s-guide-101735543406314.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:46:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Confirms Successful Flyby of Parker Solar Probe, Completes Closest Sun Approach - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Confirms Successful Flyby of Parker Solar Probe</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/nB0t6sp9Te8/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>NASA's Parker Solar Probe during its historic flyby.</figcaption><p>NASA's Parker Solar Probe has achieved a milestone by completing its closest approach to the Sun, achieving a record-breaking distance of 3.8 million miles from the solar surface.</p><ul><li>The spacecraft reached speeds of 430,000 miles per hour, the fastest ever for a human-made object.</li><li>This encounter initiates a series of close approaches planned for the future.</li><li>The mission aims to revolutionize our understanding of solar phenomena and their effects across the solar system.</li><li>Future close solar passes are scheduled for March 22 and June 19, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“This mission is pivotal for understanding the Sun's effects across the solar system.” - Nicky Fox, NASA Associate Administrator</blockquote><p>The successful flyby is a testament to decades of technological advancement and the ongoing importance of solar exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/parker-solar-probe-completes-closest-sun-approach-hits-record-430000-mph-7362860</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/parker-solar-probe-completes-closest-sun-approach-hits-record-430000-mph-7362860</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 5 Black Hole Discoveries of 2024: Plasma Jet, Intermediate Black Hole, and More - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNd05SLUJGeS1CWjliMy1PX2gtOGR0V2JablJSV21rYnVENnNETDFUVmFUZExqMFlKZDZFREtyUlFpc0VqVm9LS0RSZjdxMEtZNVVDa1ExM3VuVkM4YjM1cXV4czByVXJPdWZpWE9Bb3dubS1sSUpBMGstVnlCNy1XQkZLR1hrNUlOOVd5MC1ldlhUc1dydVVXUFRWQjNCX3pBQTlPT1dnUjR2Z1hibEHSAa4BQVVfeXFMTXdOUi1CRnktQlo5YjMtT19oLThkdFdiWm5SUldta2J1RDZzREwxVFZhVGRMajBZSmQ2RURLclJRaXNFalZvS0tEUmY3cTBLWTVVQ2tRMTN1blZDOGIzNXF1eHMwclVyT3VmaVhPQW93bm0tbElKQTBrLVZ5QjctV0JGS0dYazVJTjlXeTAtZXZYVHNXcnVVV1BUVkIzQl96QUE5T09XZ1I0dmdYYmxB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxNd05SLUJGeS1CWjliMy1PX2gtOGR0V2JablJSV21rYnVENnNETDFUVmFUZExqMFlKZDZFREtyUlFpc0VqVm9LS0RSZjdxMEtZNVVDa1ExM3VuVkM4YjM1cXV4czByVXJPdWZpWE9Bb3dubS1sSUpBMGstVnlCNy1XQkZLR1hrNUlOOVd5MC1ldlhUc1dydVVXUFRWQjNCX3pBQTlPT1dnUjR2Z1hibEHSAa4BQVVfeXFMTXdOUi1CRnktQlo5YjMtT19oLThkdFdiWm5SUldta2J1RDZzREwxVFZhVGRMajBZSmQ2RURLclJRaXNFalZvS0tEUmY3cTBLWTVVQ2tRMTN1blZDOGIzNXF1eHMwclVyT3VmaVhPQW93bm0tbElKQTBrLVZ5QjctV0JGS0dYazVJTjlXeTAtZXZYVHNXcnVVV1BUVkIzQl96QUE5T09XZ1I0dmdYYmxB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:37:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 5 Black Hole Discoveries of 2024: Plasma Jet, Intermediate Black Hole, and More - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unraveling Black Holes: Major Discoveries of 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Published: December 29, 2024 - Source: Gadgets 360</strong></p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/nB0t6sp9Te8/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Black Hole Discovery"><figcaption>An artist's impression of a black hole ejecting plasma jets.</figcaption>
<p>This year has brought remarkable advancements in understanding black holes, from detecting an intermediate black hole to uncovering plasma jets stretching millions of light-years. Here's a summary of these fascinating developments:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Scientists found a potential intermediate black hole candidate in the IRS 13 star cluster, offering insights into how smaller black holes evolve.</li>
  <li>A black hole named Porphyrion was discovered ejecting plasma jets spanning 23 million light-years, highlighting their ability to shape the cosmos.</li>
  <li>Researchers decoded the mystery behind periodic light pulses, or 'heartbeat' signals, in X-ray flares emitted by black holes, providing a glimpse into their feeding process.</li>
  <li>The Milky Way's central black hole, Sagittarius A*, was found to have an unusual spin, suggesting it resulted from a massive collision between two black holes.</li>
  <li>Astronomers observed a previously dormant black hole springing back to life, offering a rare opportunity to study black hole transitions.</li>
</ul>
<p>These discoveries have significantly expanded our knowledge of black holes and their enigmatic behaviours.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/black-hole-discoveries-2024-7362774</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/black-hole-discoveries-2024-7362774</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Northern Lights Displays Hit A 500-Year Peak In 2024—Here’s Where You Could Catch Aurora Borealis In 2025 - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Northern Lights Displays Hit A 500-Year Peak In 2024—Here’s Where You Could Catch Aurora Borealis In 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Published in October by Forbes.</p>
<img src="https://specials-images.forbesimg.com/imageserve/67092a913967ddeb9d274364/Aurora-borealis-in-NYC/960x0.jpg?cropX1=0&amp;cropX2=1116&amp;cropY1=53&amp;cropY2=681" alt="Aurora borealis in NYC">
<figcaption>Activity on the sun’s surface only recently hit its peak, which NASA expects to persist through early 2026. <small>Getty Images</small></figcaption>
<p>An uptick in solar activity this year has resulted in the strongest displays of aurora borealis in the last 500 years. NASA predicts that this peak will continue through 2025 into early 2026, allowing more opportunities for viewing.</p>
<ul>
<li>The sun’s 11-year cycle reached a “solar maximum,” leading to increased space weather events.</li>
<li>Northern lights are best viewed in Alaska and northern Canada, but severity can pull displays further south.</li>
<li>In 2025, various U.S. states will have opportunities to see the aurora during both “quiet” and “active” displays.</li>
<li>The strongest geomagnetic storm in two decades occurred, leading to unprecedented aurora visibility.</li>
<li>NASA is conducting missions to better understand space weather impacts on Earth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“NASA said it tracked the strongest geomagnetic storm to reach Earth in two decades—resulting in possibly the strongest northern lights displays ‘in the past 500 years.’”</blockquote>
<p>With expected frequent visibility of the aurora, especially during specific solar events, enthusiasts should plan accordingly to witness this natural phenomenon.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/tylerroush/2024/12/30/northern-lights-displays-hit-a-500-year-peak-in-2024-heres-where-you-could-catch-aurora-borealis-in-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/tylerroush/2024/12/30/northern-lights-displays-hit-a-500-year-peak-in-2024-heres-where-you-could-catch-aurora-borealis-in-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Seals strategically occupy icebergs to move across seas - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/seals-strategically-occupy-icebergs-to-move-across-seas-2785340</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/seals-strategically-occupy-icebergs-to-move-across-seas-2785340</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:04:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024 rewind: Major news events as seen from space - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2024 Rewind: Major News Events as Seen from Space</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/baltimore-305922383-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=_jQvV3ddK_KKs2pC1wyIeVtbMxk8jvKm&amp;size=690:388" alt="Photo of a cargo vessel" width="690" height="388"><figcaption>Photo of a 985-foot-long cargo vessel Dali ramming into a pier of Francis Scott Key Bridge in Baltimore, Maryland as seen from space in March.</figcaption><p>As 2024 draws to a close, India Today looks back at the highlights and lowlights of the jam-packed year as seen from space, encompassing domestic and global events.</p><ul><li><strong>January:</strong> Inauguration of Ram Temple in Ayodhya capturing millions' attention.</li><li><strong>February:</strong> Violent protests in Sandeshkhali, West Bengal linked to land grabs and abuse allegations.</li><li><strong>March:</strong> Cargo vessel Dali collided with Francis Scott Key Bridge in Baltimore.</li><li><strong>April:</strong> Severe forest fires in Uttarakhand and Himachal Pradesh resulted in multiple deaths.</li><li><strong>June:</strong> Construction of a humanitarian aid pier in Gaza, critical amidst ongoing conflict.</li><li><strong>July:</strong> Devastating landslides in Wayanad, Kerala, leading to many fatalities.</li><li><strong>August:</strong> The 2024 Summer Olympics held in Paris, capturing iconic landmarks from space.</li><li><strong>September:</strong> Floods in Andhra Pradesh and Telangana killed numerous individuals, analyzed through satellite data.</li><li><strong>October:</strong> New patrolling arrangement announced between India and China post-border tensions.</li><li><strong>November:</strong> Delay in snowfall at Mount Fuji noted, raising environmental concerns.</li><li><strong>December:</strong> Collapse of Assad's regime in Syria as rebel forces took control of Damascus.</li></ul><blockquote>"The initial snowfall on the UNESCO World Heritage site was visible from the southwestern side of the mountain. The absence of snow on Mount Fuji on November 5 broke the previous record for the latest snowfall."</blockquote><p>This year has been pivotal, marked by significant events captured from space, underlining the role of satellite technology in understanding global affairs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/2024-rewind-major-news-events-as-seen-from-space-2657321-2024-12-30</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/2024-rewind-major-news-events-as-seen-from-space-2657321-2024-12-30</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:59:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Keeping Eye on Mysterious Weakening in Earth’s Magnetic Field, Says Report - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxNeEpFSGtabDNONDNmZWVTUTQ1YkZTSXQ4Sk9hVC1pSDBwNjVLU0phZzdiek4zVjlrR0h1aWs4VW1NU2xiekZGcGkwNlR2M181NXE1Z3VaaDJLaUk2Z0lLODdzRW43ZHQxV0djcFVMSGxRZzR3aHlfQ242Z2ZKYXhmVU5Jem5SbVZBUG9CemlhWDRNbmtsYTFsSC0ydEVnMUliVjBvTjY2MGwzTjhpNzh5bDMwMUhXajZPdkE0TjR0WWxnR2FRY1B4Q3RsSU9UdW9NTmFWdWtTMEtfMGPSAeABQVVfeXFMT2tpaWVYV0FDRHV4TFotVUp5MmNHbENSbWF0bFpGVF9KZzVpLWRHVTUxNGxONThCUEFGOXhZTHYzYmpMVFRGMFEtd1NoejUwZ1ZvN1BNaVlGYmd1RGV0akJ0enhrMGw2Y0V5Vlpna29vNEJvSWZYZl9XelFxcUxBRlVhdExIbDBtd3ZtbFVTQUJOMWlTTHQ0MUpXeFNNRTEyNUdkaHFwcllocVdQek5KdF9kbHVKWjVodHVuOWtjRW9DMGVYZmhTckpyMGVScWZoc1UxdEtKLXc5TGJEYl9JTDU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxNeEpFSGtabDNONDNmZWVTUTQ1YkZTSXQ4Sk9hVC1pSDBwNjVLU0phZzdiek4zVjlrR0h1aWs4VW1NU2xiekZGcGkwNlR2M181NXE1Z3VaaDJLaUk2Z0lLODdzRW43ZHQxV0djcFVMSGxRZzR3aHlfQ242Z2ZKYXhmVU5Jem5SbVZBUG9CemlhWDRNbmtsYTFsSC0ydEVnMUliVjBvTjY2MGwzTjhpNzh5bDMwMUhXajZPdkE0TjR0WWxnR2FRY1B4Q3RsSU9UdW9NTmFWdWtTMEtfMGPSAeABQVVfeXFMT2tpaWVYV0FDRHV4TFotVUp5MmNHbENSbWF0bFpGVF9KZzVpLWRHVTUxNGxONThCUEFGOXhZTHYzYmpMVFRGMFEtd1NoejUwZ1ZvN1BNaVlGYmd1RGV0akJ0enhrMGw2Y0V5Vlpna29vNEJvSWZYZl9XelFxcUxBRlVhdExIbDBtd3ZtbFVTQUJOMWlTTHQ0MUpXeFNNRTEyNUdkaHFwcllocVdQek5KdF9kbHVKWjVodHVuOWtjRW9DMGVYZmhTckpyMGVScWZoc1UxdEtKLXc5TGJEYl9JTDU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:55:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Moon: When to watch last celestial event of 2024 - NewsBytes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxNTWw1WmNlaXZ6MEM4dER4VHRna3VMYTdxZEpkaTFZeENhM0V0WHpXZjlfcmcwajVYOE1Ga1RnQkpPYVlyNkpDenRmVlUyQVJXV2Z2MTZUa25pQmMzdk8yTW1IeEF3NjdPWFNwZlVodnRCZmx4RWpoMXdyeC1KZWdYaElEamYtcTdVeHJJamxIbFl0MUJ6d09QcnVDVWZZcmN1TzVORmJJUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxNTWw1WmNlaXZ6MEM4dER4VHRna3VMYTdxZEpkaTFZeENhM0V0WHpXZjlfcmcwajVYOE1Ga1RnQkpPYVlyNkpDenRmVlUyQVJXV2Z2MTZUa25pQmMzdk8yTW1IeEF3NjdPWFNwZlVodnRCZmx4RWpoMXdyeC1KZWdYaElEamYtcTdVeHJJamxIbFl0MUJ6d09QcnVDVWZZcmN1TzVORmJJUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:50:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digital Reconstruction of Dwarf Hippopotamus Skull from Crete Sheds Light on Evolution - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxOT0J4SXlPbGJKZ1cta2U3cERERHpjOUtxeFBXTDRJUVN6SnJxOGdnUmRIVUVUaTNpaXR2OVN2S0pKZEpDSXpROGlGZG9IVU5IbGpWSDlyM3RPNFBVMlR3U0ozNzEyNjgxSm4zd2hVT1YzUm9Mb01vejFqaGh5N3I1a2Z3ZVNmTl92VDBpMzJhZkJpWi1uMGQ3OGhRYVdYSU5ObTVTd3ZaaGFQUHJNczRGbDZqOWYzZnk30gG4AUFVX3lxTE5PQnhJeU9sYkpnVy1rZTdwREREemM5S3F4UFdMNElRU3pKcnE4Z2dSZEhVRVRpM2lpdHY5U3ZLSkpkSkNJelE4aUZkb0hVTkhsalZIOXIzdE80UFUyVHdTSjM3MTI2ODFKbjN3aFVPVjNSb0xvTW96MWpoaHk3cjVrZndlU2ZOX3ZUMGkzMmFmQmlaLW4wZDc4aFFhV1hJTk5tNVN3dlpoYVBQck1zNEZsNmo5ZjNmeTc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxOT0J4SXlPbGJKZ1cta2U3cERERHpjOUtxeFBXTDRJUVN6SnJxOGdnUmRIVUVUaTNpaXR2OVN2S0pKZEpDSXpROGlGZG9IVU5IbGpWSDlyM3RPNFBVMlR3U0ozNzEyNjgxSm4zd2hVT1YzUm9Mb01vejFqaGh5N3I1a2Z3ZVNmTl92VDBpMzJhZkJpWi1uMGQ3OGhRYVdYSU5ObTVTd3ZaaGFQUHJNczRGbDZqOWYzZnk30gG4AUFVX3lxTE5PQnhJeU9sYkpnVy1rZTdwREREemM5S3F4UFdMNElRU3pKcnE4Z2dSZEhVRVRpM2lpdHY5U3ZLSkpkSkNJelE4aUZkb0hVTkhsalZIOXIzdE80UFUyVHdTSjM3MTI2ODFKbjN3aFVPVjNSb0xvTW96MWpoaHk3cjVrZndlU2ZOX3ZUMGkzMmFmQmlaLW4wZDc4aFFhV1hJTk5tNVN3dlpoYVBQck1zNEZsNmo5ZjNmeTc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:50:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Humans think slower than expected, study finds - Salon]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Humans think slower than expected, study finds</h1>
<p><strong>Published December 30, 2024 by Salon</strong></p>
<img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Doctor pointing to brain scan images'>
<figcaption>Doctor pointing to brain scan images (Getty Images/Tom Werner)</figcaption>
<p>A new study in the journal Neuron reveals that human brains process information at roughly 10 bits per second, which is surprisingly slow when compared to modern technology.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Research conducted at the California Institute of Technology.</li>
    <li>Average human information processing speed is around 10 bits per second.</li>
    <li>This speed is much slower than Wi-Fi speeds and the human eye's processing speed.</li>
    <li>Implications for understanding human cognition and brain functionality.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In fact, the 10 bits per second are needed only in worst-case situations, and most of the time our environment changes at a much more leisurely pace.”</blockquote>
<p>Understanding the speed of thought can shed light on evolutionary adaptations and inform future cognitive research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.salon.com/2024/12/30/humans-think-slower-than-expected-study-finds/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.salon.com/2024/12/30/humans-think-slower-than-expected-study-finds/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arctic Waters Boast Earth’s Largest Waterfall - ShiaWaves | Shia World News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arctic Waters Boast Earth’s Largest Waterfall</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Earth.com</p><img src="https://shiawaves.com/english/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-30-111817-599x470.png" alt="Denmark Strait cataract" width="599" height="470"><figcaption>Denmark Strait cataract, the largest waterfall on Earth.</figcaption><p>The Denmark Strait cataract, located deep beneath the Arctic waters, is recognized as Earth’s largest waterfall with a vertical drop of 11,500 feet and a powerful flow that influences global ocean circulation.</p><ul><li>Vertical drop of 11,500 feet (3,500 meters).</li><li>Width of approximately 300 miles (480 kilometers).</li><li>Moves 3.2 million cubic meters of water every second.</li><li>Hidden from the naked eye and detectable only through oceanographic tools.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“The effects of this hidden giant resonate throughout the planet,” - Marine scientist Anna Sanchez Vidal.</p></blockquote><p>This extraordinary underwater feature serves as a reminder of the remarkable wonders hidden in the ocean’s depths and their significant roles in the environment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://shiawaves.com/english/news/world/environment/116226-arctic-waters-boast-earths-largest-waterfall/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shiawaves.com/english/news/world/environment/116226-arctic-waters-boast-earths-largest-waterfall/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:24:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Planet 9: Hypothetical or an Undiscovered World? - Brandsynario]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxQVV9xYjQ2VjFyYWxyLVhqOTFfTkZSdlRwMXNjQXRXcWlpNnVoSllnT0ZtaHlnNFhqYzhjWlZYbm9iSl9LcHVVN0lZaTBXTTktM0ZZellrVHAtUXVRVUFTNmJzbEtPNm1uOUlFUVlHRUtZWjVwczltaHBvTGI0VkFYRHNn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxQVV9xYjQ2VjFyYWxyLVhqOTFfTkZSdlRwMXNjQXRXcWlpNnVoSllnT0ZtaHlnNFhqYzhjWlZYbm9iSl9LcHVVN0lZaTBXTTktM0ZZellrVHAtUXVRVUFTNmJzbEtPNm1uOUlFUVlHRUtZWjVwczltaHBvTGI0VkFYRHNn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:27:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA probe makes closest ever pass by the sun - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Parker Solar Probe Makes Historic Closest Approach to the Sun</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 - <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/i8o9k9/article69033242.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-24T160321Z_1130366850_RC2PB49RD9KK_RTRMADP_3_SPACE-EXPLORATION-SUN.JPG" alt="A 2018 artist’s concept shows the Parker Solar Probe spacecraft flying into the sun’s outer atmosphere on a mission to help scientists learn more about the star." title="A 2018 artist’s concept shows the Parker Solar Probe spacecraft flying into the sun’s outer atmosphere on a mission to help scientists learn more about the star."><figcaption>A 2018 artist’s concept of the Parker Solar Probe. | Photo Credit: NASA/Johns Hopkins APL/Steve Gribben</figcaption><p>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe made history on December 24 by flying closer to the sun than any other spacecraft, enduring scorching temperatures of over 930 degrees Celsius.</p><ul><li>Launched in August 2018, the spacecraft is part of a seven-year mission.</li><li>The probe flew within 6.1 million kilometers of the sun.</li><li>Mission scientists expect confirmation of the flyby on December 28.</li><li>The Parker Solar Probe will encounter two more close passes in March and June 2025.</li><li>The craft can achieve speeds of around 690,000 km/h.</li></ul><blockquote>“Right now, the Parker Solar Probe is flying closer to a star than anything has ever been before.” - Nicky Fox, NASA official</blockquote><p>This groundbreaking flyby is part of a series of missions aimed at understanding solar winds and the mysteries of the sun's atmosphere.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/nasa-probe-makes-closest-ever-pass-by-the-sun/article69042696.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/nasa-probe-makes-closest-ever-pass-by-the-sun/article69042696.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Groundbreaking ironmaking breakthrough in China increases productivity by 3,600 times - Tech Explorist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techexplorist.com/groundbreaking-ironmaking-breakthrough-china-increases-productivity-3600-times/95169/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techexplorist.com/groundbreaking-ironmaking-breakthrough-china-increases-productivity-3600-times/95169/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:55:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Year-ender | Top space exploration moments and discoveries of 2024 - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Space Exploration Moments and Discoveries of 2024</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 31, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Pivotal year in space exploration" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Pivotal year in space exploration</figcaption><p>In 2024, space exploration soared with historic lunar south pole samples, groundbreaking all-civilian spacewalks, and key milestones pushing the boundaries of human and robotic achievements.</p><ul><li><strong>Japan’s Moon Landing:</strong> In January, Japan landed its SLIM spacecraft on the moon, becoming the fifth country to do so.</li><li><strong>First Private Spacecraft on the Moon:</strong> Intuitive Machines’ Odysseus landed in February, marking a milestone for private space exploration.</li><li><strong>First Ever Moon Dust Samples:</strong> China’s Chang’e 6 mission returned unique samples from the moon's far side.</li><li><strong>Ancient Microbial Life on Mars:</strong> NASA’s Perseverance rover in July found evidence suggesting ancient life on Mars.</li><li><strong>First All-Civilian Spacewalk:</strong> SpaceX’s Polaris Dawn mission included a historic civilian spacewalk in September.</li><li><strong>Astronauts Stuck in Space:</strong> Boeing’s Starliner had thruster issues, stranding astronauts until February 2025.</li><li><strong>A Mission to Jupiter’s Icy Moon:</strong> NASA’s Europa Clipper embarked on a six-year journey to Jupiter in October.</li></ul><blockquote>“2024 was a pivotal year in space exploration.”</blockquote><p>This recap illustrates the continuous advancements in space exploration, showcasing remarkable achievements and milestones reached in 2024.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/technology/year-ender-top-space-exploration-moments-and-discoveries-of-2024-19530899.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/technology/year-ender-top-space-exploration-moments-and-discoveries-of-2024-19530899.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:10:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Science News | ⚡Know Dates of Lunar Eclipse, Solar Eclipse Set To Occur in 2025 - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Eclipse Schedule for 2025: Lunar and Solar Eclipse Dates Revealed</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: --, Source: --</strong></p><img src='--' alt='--'><figcaption>--</figcaption><p>In 2025, four major eclipses are set to occur, including two solar and two lunar eclipses. India will witness a full lunar eclipse in September, along with other celestial events such as meteor showers and supermoons.</p><ol><li>Two solar eclipses</li><li>Two lunar eclipses, including one visible in India</li><li>Other celestial events like meteor showers and supermoons</li></ol><blockquote>--</blockquote><p>--</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.latestly.com/quickly/technology/science/know-dates-of-lunar-eclipse-solar-eclipse-set-to-occur-in-2025-6527704.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.latestly.com/quickly/technology/science/know-dates-of-lunar-eclipse-solar-eclipse-set-to-occur-in-2025-6527704.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:47:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2 solar, lunar eclipses in 2025; India to witness only THIS eclipse - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Four Eclipse Events in 2025; India Witnesses Final Lunar Eclipse</h1>
<h2>Date and Source:</h2>
<p><strong>Published: December 30, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: DNA</strong></p>
<h2>Image with Caption:</h2>
<img alt="Four Eclipse Events in 2025; India Witnesses Final Lunar Eclipse" title="Four Eclipse Events in 2025; India Witnesses Final Lunar Eclipse" width="640" height="480" decoding="async" data-nimg="1" src="https://cdn.dnaindia.com/sites/default/files/2669420-phto-2024-12-30t130318.826.png?im=FitAndFill=(1200,900)"><figcaption>Four Eclipse Events in 2025; India Witnesses Final Lunar Eclipse</figcaption>
<h2>Introduction:</h2>
<p>The year 2025 is set to be an exciting one for skywatchers, with no less than four eclipse events scheduled. However, Indians will have to wait until the final lunar eclipse to witness any of these celestial phenomena.</p>
<h2>Key Points:</h2>
<ol>
  <li>The year begins with a full lunar eclipse on March 14, 2025, but unfortunately, it will not be visible from India.</li>
  <li>A second partial solar eclipse on March 29, 2025, will also pass over India.</li>
  <li>Indians will finally get to witness an eclipse on September 7-8, 2025, with a breathtaking full lunar eclipse visible from Asia, Europe, and the Indian Ocean region.</li>
  <li>The year concludes with a partial solar eclipse on September 21-22, visible only in regions such as New Zealand, the South Pacific, and West Antarctica.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics:</h2>
<blockquote>The series of eclipses in 2025 will begin with a full lunar eclipse on March 14, 2025, but unfortunately, it will not be visible in India, according to Dr. Rajendra Prakash Gupt, Superintendent of the observatory. However, he noted that this celestial event will follow a second partial solar eclipse on March 29, 2025, which again India will miss out on. Indians, however, can look forward to the full lunar eclipse between September 7 and September 8, 2025, as the moon transforms into a deep crimson hue, lasting from 8:58 PM to 2:25 AM, according to Mr. Gupt.</blockquote>
<h2>Conclusion:</h2>
<p>While Indians will have to wait for the final lunar eclipse in 2025 to witness any eclipse events, skywatchers around the world can look forward to a series of remarkable celestial phenomena in the coming year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/viral/report-2-solar-lunar-eclipses-in-2025-india-to-witness-only-this-eclipse-3124913</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/viral/report-2-solar-lunar-eclipses-in-2025-india-to-witness-only-this-eclipse-3124913</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My fight with Claude on Big O notation O(1) Time Complexity | by Naveenkumar Murugan | Dec, 2024 - Medium]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>My Fight with Claude on Big O Notation: Understanding O(1) Time Complexity</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Medium</p><figure><img src="https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:700/0*F0WIrrwsAJv9KJ-Q" alt="Illustration for Big O Notation" width="700" height="400"><figcaption>Source: ChatGPT</figcaption></figure><p>This article explores the author's journey to simplify the concept of O(1) time complexity in algorithms, highlighting common confusions and aiming to provide a clearer understanding.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Attempts to provide a simpler definition of time complexity for better understanding.</li><li>Common definition of O(1) as time bounded by a finite value, regardless of input size.</li><li>Author shares personal confusions regarding the meaning of “1” in O(1).</li><li>Quotes important to the author, emphasizing clarity in explanation.</li></ul><blockquote>“If you can’t explain the thing to a 5 year old kid, you haven’t understood the thing enough.”</blockquote><h2>Conclusion:</h2><p>The author encourages readers to rethink traditional definitions and digest complex concepts into simpler explanations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://medium.com/@naveenkumarmurugan/my-fight-with-claude-on-big-o-notation-o-1-time-complexity-a11fd914e38f</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/@naveenkumarmurugan/my-fight-with-claude-on-big-o-notation-o-1-time-complexity-a11fd914e38f</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:26:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Latest Space Pictures Captured By NASA Hubble Space - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Latest Space Pictures Captured By NASA Hubble Space</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116788272/116788272.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=1320221" alt="7 Latest Space Pictures Captured By NASA Hubble Space"><figcaption>Image Credit: Times Now</figcaption><p>This article features a stunning collection of the latest space pictures captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, showcasing various celestial phenomena.</p><ul><li>The Mice NGC 4676: Colliding spiral galaxies indicating star formation.</li><li>Westerlund 2: A star cluster located in a stellar nursery.</li><li>Discovering Protostellar OH 339.88-1.26: A dusty area with bright stars.</li><li>Young Star HH-47: A complex stellar formation.</li><li>XZ Tauri: A multiple star system with gas expulsion.</li><li>Red Giant Star CW Leonis: A stunning carbon star image.</li><li>Ghostly Star Forming Pillar: The Cone Nebula captured in detail.</li></ul><blockquote>“NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope has captured an impressive image of the multiple star system known as XZ Tauri alongside neighbor HL Tauri and several young stellar objects.”</blockquote><p>This article provides a glimpse into the wonders of space explored by the Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting remarkable cosmic phenomena.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-latest-space-pictures-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space/photostory/116788254.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-latest-space-pictures-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space/photostory/116788254.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:55:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>