<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 07:18:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 07:18:37 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 impressive images of star clusters shared by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Impressive Images of Star Clusters Shared by NASA</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Star-Cluster-1.jpg" alt="Star Cluster"><figcaption>Image of a star cluster shared by NASA.</figcaption><p>NASA has shared stunning images of various star clusters, showcasing their beauty and diversity. Here are some captivating shots.</p><ul><li>The glow of globular cluster NGC 2031 shines in the Mensa constellation within the Large Magellanic Cloud.</li><li>NGC 2031 is a 100-million-year-old globular cluster, known as a stellar nursery.</li><li>NGC 2660 glitters in the Vela constellation and is best viewed in the southern sky.</li><li>NGC 1858 is a 10-million-year-old open star cluster also in the Large Magellanic Cloud.</li><li>Caldwell 71 is featured in a Hubble image showing a loose collection of stars.</li><li>NGC 2002 is an open star cluster located approximately 160,000 light-years from Earth.</li><li>Young stars shine in the Trapezium embedded cluster within the Orion Nebula.</li></ul><blockquote>“Thanks for reading!”</blockquote><p>This collection of images not only highlights the beauty of the cosmos but also deepens our knowledge of star formation and the vast structures in our universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-impressive-images-of-star-clusters-shared-by-nasa-7536441/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-impressive-images-of-star-clusters-shared-by-nasa-7536441/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 06:12:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 most beautiful star formation images taken by Hubble Telescope of NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Most Beautiful Star Formation Images Taken by Hubble Telescope</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/star-formation3.jpg" alt="6 most beautiful star formation images taken by Hubble Telescope of NASA"><figcaption>This stunning image captured by the Hubble Space Telescope showcases the beauty of star formation.</figcaption><p>This article presents a collection of six breathtaking images of star formation captured by NASA's Hubble Telescope, highlighting the incredible phenomena occurring in our universe.</p><ul><li>Image of AFGL 5180, a star-forming cloud offering clues about solar system formation.</li><li>NGC 3603 displaying a cluster of massive stars surrounded by gas and dust.</li><li>G35.2-0.7N known for its high-mass star formation.</li><li>The iconic Pillars of Creation, featuring towering columns of gas and dust.</li><li>Bright stars in the Large Magellanic Cloud, showcasing massive star formation regions.</li><li>A captivating display of nebulae illustrating the beauty of cosmic creation.</li></ul><blockquote>“A captivating display of vibrant nebulae where stars are born, revealing the beauty of cosmic creation.”</blockquote><p>The stunning images captured by the Hubble Telescope provide a glimpse into the dynamic processes of star formation and deepen our understanding of the cosmos.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/6-most-beautiful-star-formation-images-taken-by-hubble-telescope-of-nasa-7536078/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/6-most-beautiful-star-formation-images-taken-by-hubble-telescope-of-nasa-7536078/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 04:15:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronomers might have spotted a white dwarf orbiting a supermassive black hole - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronomers watched a colossal object spiraling into a supermassive black hole. Unexpectedly, its descent was arrested.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> New Delhi</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Science News</p><img width="802" height="464" src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/White-Dwarf-Supermassive-Black-Hole.jpg?w=802&amp;enlarge=true" alt="Illustration of a white dwarf in orbit around a supermassive black hole. (Image Credit: Universe Sandbox/News9)." title="White Dwarf Supermassive Black Hole"><figcaption>Illustration of a white dwarf in orbit around a supermassive black hole. (Image Credit: Universe Sandbox/News9).</figcaption><p>240 million lightyears away in the constellation of Draco, astronomers may have identified a white dwarf orbiting a supermassive black hole. The object's descent has unexpectedly halted, raising questions about its composition and stability.</p><ul><li>A supermassive black hole with 1.4 million solar masses resides in the galaxy 1ES 1927+654.</li><li>Post-outburst in 2018, the black hole exhibited another flare in 2023, with jets of plasma detected for the first time.</li><li>X-ray measurements revealed rapid brightness variations, indicating an object potentially spiraling towards the event horizon.</li><li>Scientists believe the orbiting object is a white dwarf, which would react differently to the black hole's gravitational forces than a normal star.</li></ul><blockquote>“We were shocked by this at first. But we realized that as the object moved closer to the black hole, its strong gravitational pull could begin to strip matter from the companion. This mass loss could offset the energy removed by gravitational waves, halting the companion’s inward motion.” - Megan Masterson</blockquote><p>This discovery highlights the complexities of interactions between black holes and celestial objects, warranting further observations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/astronomers-might-have-spotted-a-white-dwarf-orbiting-a-supermassive-black-hole-2795990</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/astronomers-might-have-spotted-a-white-dwarf-orbiting-a-supermassive-black-hole-2795990</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 03:41:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists are looking to the past to predict the climate of Earth’s future - BGR]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists are looking to the past to predict the climate of Earth's future</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> International Collaboration</p>
<img src="https://example.com/path-to-image.jpg" alt="Ancient ice core from Antarctica">
<figcaption>World's oldest ice sample extracted from Antarctica</figcaption>
<p>An international team has successfully extracted the world’s oldest ice sample from Antarctica, spanning 1.2 million years of climate history. This ancient ice core promises to unveil secrets about Earth’s past climate systems and help us understand the climate of Earth’s future.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The ice core is part of the “Beyond EPICA” project involving twelve scientific institutions.</li>
  <li>Extracted from 2,800 meters deep at Little Dome C, it contains air bubbles that provide information on atmospheric conditions.</li>
  <li>Researchers aim to understand the link between greenhouse gases and temperature during the Mid-Pleistocene Transition.</li>
  <li>The dramatic climate cycle shift during this time is still a mystery.</li>
  <li>Advanced ice analysis techniques will be used starting in March 2023.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“By uncovering how greenhouse gases influenced the Earth’s climate millions of years ago, scientists aim to refine climate models and improve projections for future scenarios.”</blockquote>
<p>This research is crucial for anticipating future climate changes and informing global mitigation efforts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bgr.com/science/scientists-are-looking-to-the-past-to-predict-the-climate-of-earths-future/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bgr.com/science/scientists-are-looking-to-the-past-to-predict-the-climate-of-earths-future/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neutron star 'mountains' would cause ripples in space-time - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Neutron Star 'Mountains' Would Cause Ripples in Space-Time</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Phys.org</p><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2025/neutron-star-mountains.jpg" alt="Neutron star mountains would cause ripples in space-time" title="Gravity from mountains on rapidly rotating neutron stars produces ripples in space-time known as gravitational waves. The Laser Interferometer Gravitational Wave Observatory (LIGO) searches for such waves. Credit: Charles Horowitz" width="800" height="530"><figcaption>Gravity from mountains on rapidly rotating neutron stars produces ripples in space-time known as gravitational waves. The Laser Interferometer Gravitational Wave Observatory (LIGO) searches for such waves. Credit: Charles Horowitz</figcaption><p>Research suggests that neutron stars could have surface features similar to 'mountains' that might create ripples in space-time, known as gravitational waves. These features are theorized to lead to detectable gravitational waves, enhancing our understanding of these dense objects.</p><ul><li>Neutron stars are extremely dense, a trillion times denser than lead.</li><li>Mountains on neutron stars can produce small oscillations in space-time.</li><li>The study published in <i>Physical Review D</i> draws analogies between neutron star mountains and features on celestial bodies like Europa and Mercury.</li><li>The Laser Interferometer Gravitational Wave Observatory (LIGO) is attempting to detect waves generated by these neutron star mountains.</li></ul><blockquote>The first detections of continuous gravitational waves will open a new window on the universe and provide unique information on neutron stars.</blockquote><p>This research holds promise for revealing new phenomena related to neutron stars and could lead to groundbreaking discoveries in gravitational wave astronomy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-01-neutron-star-mountains-ripples-space.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-01-neutron-star-mountains-ripples-space.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 22:27:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chang’e 7 Mission: This is how China plans to place a fluttering flag on Moon - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/techandscience/chang-e-7-mission-this-is-how-china-plans-to-place-a-fluttering-flag-on-moon/ar-BB1rnVYE</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/techandscience/chang-e-7-mission-this-is-how-china-plans-to-place-a-fluttering-flag-on-moon/ar-BB1rnVYE</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 20:49:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rocket Lab takes jab at NASA with release of Mars sample return plan - Astronomy Magazine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOdFhnOXdCbFJxNWZiZVZVWE1EZGtZU3RoSTdyZ28xNjRMX3M3VGNWY2FfQjF2Z2NoT3F4UFNRSktld0tnZ3kyek16Wk5NdTM2TjRCZ3hyeXRNLUVSaFhseGd6XzRjeDdHMzVCNGRHQXpsS3o1QVc1ZmFRY3BKUTQ5c19zcHNBU3h6MHFtbUQ1aVZzNDhUS2pNWldSbEhVTUtXYWpTT3F3WTBnTmUxYXNMS1BxOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxOdFhnOXdCbFJxNWZiZVZVWE1EZGtZU3RoSTdyZ28xNjRMX3M3VGNWY2FfQjF2Z2NoT3F4UFNRSktld0tnZ3kyek16Wk5NdTM2TjRCZ3hyeXRNLUVSaFhseGd6XzRjeDdHMzVCNGRHQXpsS3o1QVc1ZmFRY3BKUTQ5c19zcHNBU3h6MHFtbUQ1aVZzNDhUS2pNWldSbEhVTUtXYWpTT3F3WTBnTmUxYXNMS1BxOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 20:31:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chang’e 7 Mission: This is how China plans to place a fluttering flag on Moon - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxPajRYcXpPRjE4QVI0MDRaeDJ1bkpaWk1KTVNsUGVKOG1LemdmbURySmVBSlBVXzY5VmxQTGR2RUNYQWh2b2o0RS0wYjZfZzdGWmZWWnoxaGpBTWFpNlJtZ3BkOVhjTGVuRTc1R2JVUFZrLWJoM243cFFOVjVqeG1VblhvTl92YUdTODh2U3dXNWdwUU14Y2xsQVZtVUt2d2pBcjVfMVd4dFhLQmd4dGlSR0pVd0ZjUVlNX0hUYWwyV3dMN0EtTHpGa0RpQUUwUXotbFFSMmJRSVpDZ19GNGlRRlFuYy1aUdIB6wFBVV95cUxQcEtfTjZFRFQyMWVWZng1M2xqQUotd2MxeXc2OHZUalBXWlZxaFVUQlBVUTVYY01ONko5M0FLU3lqM3dEcGJBWVdDdTJYTWZwbkotX2JiaTV3OEQ1bUhqV2pWbUNXYTFpTjZhZEtFNDUzeUVrci1QaEsxNmZtY1JmWF9ILWtPMjJna2k0QXpXZWNSTmt3ZGtReHVXSjdmMWQ2QUR2SlF0TzBlMzVqbDBBWVdPY0x1NUF3aFFlWElELWhWOXc1QS02SzdXbzdlOFB5OEU2UmRpMDhURlVma1lla2JrNWZIcGdrVE9n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxPajRYcXpPRjE4QVI0MDRaeDJ1bkpaWk1KTVNsUGVKOG1LemdmbURySmVBSlBVXzY5VmxQTGR2RUNYQWh2b2o0RS0wYjZfZzdGWmZWWnoxaGpBTWFpNlJtZ3BkOVhjTGVuRTc1R2JVUFZrLWJoM243cFFOVjVqeG1VblhvTl92YUdTODh2U3dXNWdwUU14Y2xsQVZtVUt2d2pBcjVfMVd4dFhLQmd4dGlSR0pVd0ZjUVlNX0hUYWwyV3dMN0EtTHpGa0RpQUUwUXotbFFSMmJRSVpDZ19GNGlRRlFuYy1aUdIB6wFBVV95cUxQcEtfTjZFRFQyMWVWZng1M2xqQUotd2MxeXc2OHZUalBXWlZxaFVUQlBVUTVYY01ONko5M0FLU3lqM3dEcGJBWVdDdTJYTWZwbkotX2JiaTV3OEQ1bUhqV2pWbUNXYTFpTjZhZEtFNDUzeUVrci1QaEsxNmZtY1JmWF9ILWtPMjJna2k0QXpXZWNSTmt3ZGtReHVXSjdmMWQ2QUR2SlF0TzBlMzVqbDBBWVdPY0x1NUF3aFFlWElELWhWOXc1QS02SzdXbzdlOFB5OEU2UmRpMDhURlVma1lla2JrNWZIcGdrVE9n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:57:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Deep space images by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-deep-space-images-by-nasa-7535626/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-deep-space-images-by-nasa-7535626/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:29:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[X-ray flashes from a nearby supermassive black hole accelerate mysteriously - Science Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mysterious X-ray Flashes from Nearby Supermassive Black Hole</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023-10-25 | <strong>Source:</strong> Science News</p>
<p>Researchers observing the supermassive black hole 1ES 1927+654 have detected unprecedented X-ray flashes that have increased in frequency from every 18 minutes to every seven minutes over two years, suggesting a nearby white dwarf in precarious orbit.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The black hole is located in a galaxy 100 million light-years away and is about one million times the mass of the sun.</li>
  <li>In 2018, its corona abruptly disappeared and later reappeared.</li>
  <li>Current observations reveal flashes of X-rays at unprecedented speeds, indicating possible gravitational interactions with a nearby white dwarf.</li>
  <li>The findings were presented at the American Astronomical Society meeting.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This would be the closest thing that we know of around any black hole,” says Megan Masterson, co-lead of the study.</blockquote>
<p>The discovery opens new avenues for understanding the behavior of matter near black holes, with implications for future gravitational wave detection by upcoming observatories like NASA's LISA.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/01/250113134148.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/01/250113134148.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:01:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nuclear electric propulsion technology could make missions to Mars faster - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nuclear Electric Propulsion Technology Could Speed Up Mars Missions</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Phys.org</p><figure><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2025/nuclear-electric-propu.jpg" alt="Nuclear Electric Propulsion Technology Could Make Missions to Mars Faster - NASA" title="An artist’s rendering that shows the different components of a fully assembled nuclear electric propulsion system. Credit: NASA" width="800" height="450"><figcaption>An artist’s rendering that shows the different components of a fully assembled nuclear electric propulsion system. Credit: NASA</figcaption></figure><p>The journey to Mars could take just two years with the development of nuclear electric propulsion technology. NASA's MARVL project aims to advance this concept by enabling modular assembly of propulsion components in space.</p><ul><li>Nuclear electric propulsion utilizes a nuclear reactor to generate electricity used for thrust.</li><li>MARVL focuses on creating smaller, modular heat dissipation systems that can be assembled in space.</li><li>This approach allows for flexibility and efficiency in design, making it easier to send parts into space.</li><li>NASA's Langley Research Center is leading the efforts with multiple NASA centers involved in the development.</li></ul><blockquote>"By doing that, we eliminate trying to fit the whole system into one rocket fairing," said Amanda Stark, principal investigator for MARVL.</blockquote><p>The MARVL project represents a significant step in space engineering, potentially redefining how nuclear propulsion systems are built and utilized in future space missions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-01-nuclear-electric-propulsion-technology-missions.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-01-nuclear-electric-propulsion-technology-missions.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:41:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vortex Beams: Transforming Optical Metrology - AZoOptics]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVkFVX3lxTE9MLXJIcUpGbTBuTmdjVHlFYmlqNDVQSjBkNzEwTHM4WGZGdk9Cem12cGxxWVNSSlZvb1c0Z1M0MG9QS0k2LU9ubW1HaERIZ0o2ZmstWTBn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiVkFVX3lxTE9MLXJIcUpGbTBuTmdjVHlFYmlqNDVQSjBkNzEwTHM4WGZGdk9Cem12cGxxWVNSSlZvb1c0Z1M0MG9QS0k2LU9ubW1HaERIZ0o2ZmstWTBn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[B.C. stargazers set to view once-in-a-century planetary alignment - Kimberley Bulletin]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>B.C. Stargazers Prepare for Rare Planetary Alignment</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 21<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This month, residents across British Columbia will have the rare opportunity to witness a celestial event involving a planetary alignment that occurs once every century. Six planets will be visible simultaneously after sunset, providing a unique viewing experience.</p><ul><li>The alignment includes Mars, Jupiter, Uranus, Neptune, Saturn, and Venus.</li><li>Canadian astronomer David Balam emphasized that while smaller alignments of two or three planets are common, a six-planet alignment is rare, happening approximately every 100 years.</li><li>This celestial phenomenon is due to the brief alignment of the planets' orbits during their revolutions around the sun.</li><li>Unlike stars, the planets will be visible even from urban areas due to their stable brightness.</li><li>The event will span several weeks, concluding in February, allowing ample time for stargazers to observe.</li><li>A total planetary visibility will happen again on May 6, 2492, while a perfect alignment will not occur for another 396 billion years.</li></ul><blockquote>“The planets are bloody bright. Venus is so bright at times that you can sometimes see your shadow from the light coming from it.” - David Balam</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the upcoming planetary alignment offers a spectacular once-in-a-century opportunity for observers in B.C. to enjoy the wonders of our solar system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.kimberleybulletin.com/news/bc-stargazers-set-to-view-once-in-a-century-planetary-alignment-7755631</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.kimberleybulletin.com/news/bc-stargazers-set-to-view-once-in-a-century-planetary-alignment-7755631</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:10:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Invites Media to Launch of Cosmic Origins, Solar Wind Missions - NASA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Invites Media to Launch of Cosmic Origins, Solar Wind Missions</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>The article discusses the upcoming launch of two NASA missions, SPHEREx and PUNCH, which aim to explore the universe and solar wind.</p><ul><li>The SPHEREx mission will create a 3D map of the sky to investigate the origins of the universe.</li><li>PUNCH will study the solar wind, the material ejected by the Sun.</li><li>Both missions are set to launch on a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket from Vandenberg Space Force Base in California.</li><li>Media accreditation is open for those interested in covering the launch.</li><li>Key deadlines for media accreditation include February 6 for U.S. citizens and January 20 for international media.</li></ul><blockquote>“The SPHEREx mission will observe hundreds of millions of stars and galaxies in infrared light.”</blockquote><p>This launch represents a critical step forward in understanding fundamental cosmic processes and the Sun's influence on our solar system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-invites-media-to-launch-of-cosmic-origins-solar-wind-missions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-invites-media-to-launch-of-cosmic-origins-solar-wind-missions/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:06:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fossils Reveal Evolution of Early Nervous Systems in Ecdysozoans - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fossils Reveal Evolution of Early Nervous Systems in Ecdysozoans</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/mOsBuszjtA4/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video">
<figcaption>Insights from fossil discoveries on the evolution of nervous systems.</figcaption>
<p>A recent discovery has illuminated the early evolution of nervous systems in ecdysozoan animals, which encompass insects, nematodes, and priapulid worms. Fossils from the Cambrian period have revealed important details about the structure of the ventral nerve cord in ancient organisms.</p>
<ul>
<li>Fossil evidence from the Cambrian Kuanchuanpu Formation shows the structure of the ventral nerve cord in early ecdysozoans.</li>
<li>The study suggests that scalidophorans possessed a single ventral nerve cord, similar to modern priapulid worms.</li>
<li>Researchers believe the findings support the idea that the common ancestor of ecdysozoans had a single ventral nerve cord before independent evolution of paired cords in some lineages.</li>
<li>Dr. Chema Martin-Durán highlights the evolutionary connection between the nerve cord and the segmentation of body plans.</li>
<li>Dr. María Herranz discusses implications for locomotion and coordination in ancient segmented animals.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These impressions represent early examples of the nervous system design seen in present-day ecdysozoans.” - Dr. Deng Wang</blockquote>
<p>This discovery deepens our understanding of early animal evolution and highlights the importance of fossil studies in revealing the complexities of nervous system development.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/fossils-reveal-evolution-of-early-nervous-systems-in-ecdysozoans-7450306</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/fossils-reveal-evolution-of-early-nervous-systems-in-ecdysozoans-7450306</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:59:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pyramid-like peak in Antarctica sparks imagination of netizens - Madhyamam]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPbTRFdEVBRG5QbGd4YmgxWUZlQkhkM2FWMk1KX3JEQ2Z5YVM2TEVCcFpyQUZEdGJIRVZ4cVpOSDJ0WVZkUlhFdWdvYmZJUHFVYnllekVWVlFrRm5aRUZwb2hZN3FpNjl3MlRJc1JVSDBtWTdOSEZHbEtCZVZuU25VQWZWeWFoSkNxT0VqZFV4MFNNOXd4aVBPLUNsVdIBoAFBVV95cUxQRzV1aXdKQnFKM3NGMjZqVnR3LXROZmk5aXEzeGFXbnBCRkpoMjZ3NmQ1MG9oLURSS0dmdkp3TFFHNndIanRrUEl1SmtDclpiZDFIamJIRjlOaXFJSURDZklVaTl0VTVsZnpiRzk1QTl1RG5uZ3ZldnpiNDVfNmpsdVJ0dE1yS25tM2VqSUh4ckoxUlpTN1diM0lueDhWRFlv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPbTRFdEVBRG5QbGd4YmgxWUZlQkhkM2FWMk1KX3JEQ2Z5YVM2TEVCcFpyQUZEdGJIRVZ4cVpOSDJ0WVZkUlhFdWdvYmZJUHFVYnllekVWVlFrRm5aRUZwb2hZN3FpNjl3MlRJc1JVSDBtWTdOSEZHbEtCZVZuU25VQWZWeWFoSkNxT0VqZFV4MFNNOXd4aVBPLUNsVdIBoAFBVV95cUxQRzV1aXdKQnFKM3NGMjZqVnR3LXROZmk5aXEzeGFXbnBCRkpoMjZ3NmQ1MG9oLURSS0dmdkp3TFFHNndIanRrUEl1SmtDclpiZDFIamJIRjlOaXFJSURDZklVaTl0VTVsZnpiRzk1QTl1RG5uZ3ZldnpiNDVfNmpsdVJ0dE1yS25tM2VqSUh4ckoxUlpTN1diM0lueDhWRFlv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:42:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live and let DEI thrive, organically - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Live and let DEI thrive, organically</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <em>Not specified</em></p><p><strong>Source:</strong> <em>The Economic Times</em></p><img src='https://img.etimg.com/photo/msid-107614248,imgsize-763763.cms' alt='DEI Thrive'><figcaption>Image depicting the organic growth of Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion (DEI).</figcaption><p>The article discusses the importance of allowing Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion (DEI) initiatives to grow in a natural and organic manner within organizations.</p><ul><li>Emphasis on the need for genuine commitment to DEI rather than superficial compliance.</li><li>Case studies demonstrating successful organic DEI implementations.</li><li>Challenges faced by organizations in achieving authentic DEI.</li></ul><blockquote>“True diversity and inclusion start from an authentic place and require ongoing effort and engagement.”</blockquote><p>This article highlights the vital role that organizational culture plays in nurturing DEI efforts and the long-term benefits that arise from a sincere approach to inclusion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/opinion/et-editorial/live-and-let-dei-thrive-organically/articleshow/117212691.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/opinion/et-editorial/live-and-let-dei-thrive-organically/articleshow/117212691.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Lessons Did Japan Learn From The Devastating 2011 Tohoku Earthquake And Tsunami? - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What Lessons Did Japan Learn From The Devastating 2011 Tohoku Earthquake And Tsunami?</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 13, 2025, 22:51 [IST] | <strong>Source:</strong> Oneindia News</p><img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2025/01/earthquake2011-s-1736788306.jpg" alt="What Lessons Did Japan Learn From The Devastating 2011 Tohoku Earthquake And Tsunami" width="600" height="338"><figcaption>What Lessons Did Japan Learn From The Devastating 2011 Tohoku Earthquake And Tsunami</figcaption><p>On March 11, 2011, a powerful 9.1-magnitude earthquake struck northern Japan, triggering a devastating tsunami and exposing significant vulnerabilities in disaster preparedness.</p><ul><li>The earthquake resulted in over 18,000 deaths and caused $220 billion in damages.</li><li>The tsunami waves reached heights of nearly 40 meters and hit Japan's coast within 30 minutes.</li><li>The Pacific Tsunami Warning System helped minimize loss of life globally through effective early warnings.</li><li>Japan's experience led to improvements in global tsunami preparedness and response protocols.</li><li>Investing in early warning systems remains crucial to saving lives in future disasters.</li></ul><blockquote>"Despite advanced systems, the scale of the disaster was still overwhelming."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Japan's tragic experience in 2011 reinforced the necessity for continued global investments in tsunami preparedness and early warning systems to mitigate future disasters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/international/what-lessons-did-japan-learn-from-the-devastating-2011-tohoku-earthquake-and-tsunami-4041633.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/international/what-lessons-did-japan-learn-from-the-devastating-2011-tohoku-earthquake-and-tsunami-4041633.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:21:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This mountain-size asteroid will approach Earth this weekend. See if it poses threat to Earth and how to w - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This mountain-size asteroid will approach Earth this weekend. See if it poses threat to Earth and how to watch</h1><p><strong>Last Updated: 13 January, 2025</strong> | <span>The Feed</span></p><figure><img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-117212385,width-300,height-225,imgsize-78864,resizemode-75/asteroid-.jpg" alt="asteroid."><figcaption>Agencies</figcaption></figure><p>Asteroid (887) Alinda, measuring 2.6 miles wide, will be visible this weekend. Stargazers can spot it using basic equipment or watch a livestream. Events like this occur once in a decade.</p><ul><li>Asteroid (887) Alinda is about 2.6 miles wide, similar to the width of Manhattan.</li><li>Nasa confirmed it is safe with no close passes until 2087.</li><li>It can be viewed using binoculars or telescopes in the constellation Gemini.</li><li>A free livestream will be provided by the Virtual Telescope Project on January 12.</li></ul><blockquote>Nasa ensures no known asteroids pose a threat to Earth for at least a century.</blockquote><p>This rare occurrence provides an opportunity for astronomical observation, with more celestial events lined up throughout January.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/this-mountain-size-asteroid-will-approach-earth-this-weekend-see-if-it-poses-threat-to-earth-and-how-to-watch/articleshow/117212377.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/this-mountain-size-asteroid-will-approach-earth-this-weekend-see-if-it-poses-threat-to-earth-and-how-to-watch/articleshow/117212377.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:14:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Miniature Robots Could Revolutionize Drug Delivery with Bubble-Like Spheres - India Education Diary]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indiaeducationdiary.in/miniature-robots-could-revolutionize-drug-delivery-with-bubble-like-spheres/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiaeducationdiary.in/miniature-robots-could-revolutionize-drug-delivery-with-bubble-like-spheres/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:00:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tropical Flora showed significant resilience during the Deccan Volcanism on Indian Plate - India Education Diary]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indiaeducationdiary.in/tropical-flora-showed-significant-resilience-during-the-deccan-volcanism-on-indian-plate/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiaeducationdiary.in/tropical-flora-showed-significant-resilience-during-the-deccan-volcanism-on-indian-plate/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:44:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[X-ray flashes from a nearby supermassive black hole accelerate mysteriously - Nanowerk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>X-ray Flashes from Nearby Supermassive Black Hole Accelerate Mysteriously</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Nanowerk News</p>
<img src="id66263_1.jpg" alt="In this artist’s rendering, a stream of matter trails a white dwarf orbiting within the innermost accretion disk surrounding 1ES 1927’s supermassive black hole">
<figcaption>In this artist’s rendering, a stream of matter trails a white dwarf orbiting within the innermost accretion disk surrounding 1ES 1927’s supermassive black hole. (Image: Aurore Simonnet / Sonoma State University)</figcaption>
<p>Researchers have detected increasing frequency of X-ray flashes from the supermassive black hole 1ES 1927+654, which is located 100 million light-years away, indicating unprecedented behavior.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The black hole's corona previously disappeared and reformed in 2018.</li>
  <li>X-ray flashes increased from every 18 minutes to every 7 minutes over two years.</li>
  <li>It is theorized that a spinning white dwarf is orbiting the black hole and nearing the event horizon.</li>
  <li>The study will be presented at the 245th meeting of the American Astronomical Society.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This would be the closest thing that we know of around any black hole,” says Megan Masterson, a graduate student in physics at MIT, who co-led the discovery.</blockquote>
<p>This research could provide new insights into the extreme physics surrounding black holes and help detect gravitational waves from this system using upcoming observatories.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nanowerk.com/news2/space/newsid=66263.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nanowerk.com/news2/space/newsid=66263.php</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:21:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New approach merges theoretical fundamentals with experimental studies of the proton's structure - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Approach Merges Theoretical and Experimental Studies of Proton Structure</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Phys.org</p><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2025/new-approach-merges-th.jpg" alt="New approach merges theoretical fundamentals with experimental studies of the proton's structure" title="Artist's depiction of a proton's interior. In quantum chromodynamics, the constituent quarks come in three &quot;colors,&quot; along with up and down &quot;flavors.&quot; Also shown are virtual quark-antiquark pairs and the gluons that bind the quarks together. Credit: Ted Rogers" width="800" height="530"><figcaption>Artist's depiction of a proton's interior. In quantum chromodynamics, the constituent quarks come in three "colors," along with up and down "flavors." Also shown are virtual quark-antiquark pairs and the gluons that bind the quarks together. Credit: Ted Rogers</figcaption><p>The article discusses the complex structure of protons and other subatomic particles, focusing on how theoretical and experimental approaches can converge to enhance understanding of their internal mechanics.</p><ul><li>Protons consist of quarks and gluons held together by the strong nuclear force, governed by quantum chromodynamics (QCD).</li><li>Current understanding of how quarks and gluons combine to form protons is limited.</li><li>Experimental work continues at major particle accelerators to map the structures of quarks and gluons.</li><li>Recent advances in QCD theory facilitate new experimental tests that could answer previously unresolved questions.</li><li>The new research offers improved methods for interpreting data from high-energy collisions involving protons.</li></ul><blockquote>“The new theoretical results provide a clear recipe and boost confidence that data taken in future experiments can be reliably interpreted.”</blockquote><p>This research represents a significant step in bridging theoretical physics with experimental validation, promising to deepen our understanding of particle physics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-01-approach-merges-theoretical-fundamentals-experimental.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-01-approach-merges-theoretical-fundamentals-experimental.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:15:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dormancy Could Be One of the Keys to Life on Earth (and Beyond) - Universe Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dormancy Could Be One of the Keys to Life on Earth (and Beyond)</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Universe Today</p><figure><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="1024" src="https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Underwater-Civilization.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Underwater-Civilization.jpg 1024w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Underwater-Civilization-580x580.jpg 580w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Underwater-Civilization-250x250.jpg 250w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Underwater-Civilization-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Underwater-Civilization-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px"><figcaption>With thousands of exoplanets discovered, astronomers are exploring the potential for intelligent alien civilizations on vastly different habitable worlds. Image Credit: DALL-E</figcaption></figure><p>This article discusses the concept of dormancy as a vital survival strategy for organisms on Earth and its implications for the potential existence of life on other planets. Dormancy allows life to endure harsh conditions and may be a crucial factor for the survival of life throughout Earth's history and possibly beyond.</p><ul><li>Dormancy is an evolutionary trait that enables organisms to survive adverse conditions.</li><li>The article highlights a study published in The Royal Society Journals discussing dormancy theory.</li><li>Dormancy may have helped organisms survive past extinction events.</li><li>The ability to enter dormancy might allow life to exist on other planets with harsh environments.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dormancy is a state of reduced activity or metabolism that organisms enter to survive during challenging environmental conditions.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, understanding dormancy not only sheds light on the resilience of life on Earth but also expands our perspective on the possibilities of life beyond our planet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.universetoday.com/170400/dormancy-could-be-one-of-the-keys-to-life-on-earth-and-beyond/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.universetoday.com/170400/dormancy-could-be-one-of-the-keys-to-life-on-earth-and-beyond/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:05:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Daredevil' white dwarf star could be closest-known object to a weird black hole - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Daredevil White Dwarf Star Could Be Closest-Known Object to a Weird Black Hole</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/fkipRywG5yYv6NYNfUUJnT-1200-80.png" alt="An illustration shows a white dwarf teetering on the edge of destruction and a supermassive black hole"><figcaption>An illustration shows a white dwarf teetering on the edge of destruction and a supermassive black hole (Image credit: NASA/Sonoma State University, Aurore Simonnet).</figcaption><p>Recent observations from the XMM-Newton X-ray telescope have identified a peculiar black hole and a potential white dwarf star in its vicinity, prompting significant interest among astronomers.</p><ul><li>The supermassive black hole, 1ES 1927+654, is approximately 270 million light-years away with a mass around one million times that of the Sun.</li><li>Initial unusual behavior of the black hole was noted in 2018, including the disappearance and reappearance of its corona.</li><li>Since then, the rate of X-ray emissions has exponentially increased, with flashes becoming more frequent.</li><li>The white dwarf is theorized to be influencing the black hole's behavior by being within close proximity.</li></ul><blockquote>"This would be the closest thing that we know of around any black hole," said team co-leader and MIT researcher Megan Masterson.</blockquote><p>This research emphasizes the complex relationship between black holes and stellar remnants, suggesting continuing exploration is necessary to uncover further insights.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/dead-star-edge-supermassive-black-hole-mystery-x-rays</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/dead-star-edge-supermassive-black-hole-mystery-x-rays</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spike Mechanism of Biological Neurons May Boost Artificial Neural Networks - Physics]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Spike Mechanism of Biological Neurons May Boost Artificial Neural Networks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 • <strong>Source:</strong> Physics 18, 5</p><figure><img src="/assets/2fc55261-5a47-4244-8896-0356da6aa693/e5_2_medium.png" alt="Figure caption"><figcaption><b>Figure 1:</b> (Left) A biological neuron is composed of a cell body (triangular structure) and dendrites (small branches). Output signals are sent to other neurons via the axon (purple line labelled “output”). Incoming spikes from another neuron are integrated at a synapse—the point where the transmitting axon and the dendrites connect. The synapse is represented by a weight (<i>W</i>). (Right) In the LIF model, decreasing <i>W</i> delays the neuron’s output-spike time until the input is too small to hit the threshold (orange pulse)—leading to the output spike’s disappearance. In contrast, the QIF model has no such threshold.</figcaption></figure><p>Researchers improved the training of energy-efficient neural networks by incorporating electrical pulses resembling spikes from biological neurons, aiming to make spiking neural networks (SNNs) more effective.</p><ul><li>The study conducted by Klos and Memmesheimer focuses on training SNNs.</li><li>It highlights the energy efficiency of biological neurons compared to artificial neural networks (ANNs).</li><li>Introducing a minor adjustment to the LIF model can enable stable training of SNNs.</li><li>The quadratic integrate-and-fire (QIF) model offers a more comprehensive representation of neuron activity.</li></ul><blockquote>“This method could dramatically expand the power of SNNs, enabling myriad applications in physics, neuroscience, and machine learning.”</blockquote><p>This research marks a significant step toward integrating biological mechanisms into artificial intelligence, potentially leading to more efficient AI systems.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://physics.aps.org/articles/v18/5</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://physics.aps.org/articles/v18/5</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:58:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New tool for synthetic biology: DNA nanorobots that can alter artificial cells - Nanowerk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Tool for Synthetic Biology: DNA Nanorobots That Can Alter Artificial Cells</h1><p><strong>Date Published:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Nanowerk News</p><img src="id66260_1.jpg" alt="Reconfigurable DNA nanorobots that are working on the surface of synthetic cells"><figcaption>Reconfigurable DNA nanorobots that are working on the surface of synthetic cells. (Image: 2nd Physics Institute, University of Stuttgart)</figcaption><p>Scientists at the University of Stuttgart have developed a new system using DNA origami to control biological membranes, potentially allowing for the targeted delivery of therapeutic loads into cells.</p><ul><li>Researchers succeeded in creating programmable interactions with synthetic cells using DNA nanorobots.</li><li>The shape and structure of lipid membranes are controlled to facilitate the passage of large therapeutic proteins.</li><li>The work published in <em>Nature Materials</em> marks a milestone in DNA nanotechnology application.</li><li>These advancements may reshape future therapeutic strategies and improve drug delivery systems.</li></ul><blockquote>"This work is a milestone in the application of DNA nanotechnology to regulate cell behavior," says Prof. Laura Na Liu.</blockquote><p>This research signifies a step forward in the field of synthetic biology, potentially leading to improved methods for drug delivery and understanding disease mechanisms.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nanowerk.com/nanotechnology-news3/newsid=66260.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nanowerk.com/nanotechnology-news3/newsid=66260.php</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:56:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rare celestial events to light up Sambhajinagar sky: Comet C/2024 G3 Atlas viewing and more - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rare celestial events to light up Sambhajinagar sky: Comet C/2024 G3 Atlas viewing and more</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> October 2024 | <strong>Source: </strong> Times of India</p><p>Exciting astronomical phenomena are set to occur in Sambhajinagar, including the viewing of Comet C/2024 G3 Atlas.</p><ul><li>The comet is on a path close to Earth, providing a unique viewing opportunity.</li><li>Local astronomers are organizing public viewings.</li><li>This event is part of a series of celestial activities occurring this season.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/aurangabad/rare-celestial-events-to-light-up-sambhajinagar-sky-comet-c/2024-g3-atlas-viewing-and-more/articleshow/117210905.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/aurangabad/rare-celestial-events-to-light-up-sambhajinagar-sky-comet-c/2024-g3-atlas-viewing-and-more/articleshow/117210905.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microbial cells have a fascinating and unexpected communication system - Earth.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Microbial Cells' Unexpected Communication System Revealed</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Earth.com</p><p>This article discusses recent research on microbial cells, highlighting their unexpected ability to exchange electrical signals and synchronize movements, suggesting advanced communication systems at play within these organisms.</p><ul><li>Research focuses on the single-celled organism <em>Salpingoeca rosetta</em>.</li><li>Microbial colonies can coordinate their shape and movement through voltage-gated calcium signals.</li><li>This ability to communicate hints at the origins of multicellularity and possibly early nerve systems in animals.</li><li>Colony shape and movement synchronization occur due to changes in calcium levels outside the cells.</li><li>Cell communication in these colonies exhibits parallels to basic signaling in animals.</li></ul><blockquote>“This evidence of how information flows between cells in choanoflagellate colonies demonstrates cell-cell signaling at the cusp of multicellularity.” - Jeffrey Colgren</blockquote><p>The findings signify a notable step in understanding the evolution of complex life forms and their communication methods.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.earth.com/news/microbial-cells-have-a-fascinating-and-unexpected-communication-system/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.earth.com/news/microbial-cells-have-a-fascinating-and-unexpected-communication-system/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:39:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new ultrathin conductor for nanoelectronics ... - eeNews Europe]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A New Ultrathin Conductor for Nanoelectronics</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Stanford University</p>
<img width="800" height="600" src="https://ee.cdnartwhere.eu/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Screen-Shot-2025-01-13-at-16.25.46-800x600-c-default.png" alt="A new ultrathin conductor for nanoelectronics">
<figcaption>A new ultrathin conductor for nanoelectronics</figcaption>
<p>Researchers at Stanford Engineering have developed an ultrathin material that conducts electricity better than copper and could enable more energy-efficient nanoelectronics.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The new material, niobium phosphide, improves conductivity as it gets thinner.</li>
  <li>Early results show it conducts electricity better than copper at film thicknesses below 5 nanometers.</li>
  <li>Could help reduce energy loss in high-density electronics and improve chip performance.</li>
  <li>Compatible with modern chip fabrication techniques.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We are breaking a fundamental bottleneck of traditional materials like copper,” said Asir Intisar Khan.</blockquote>
<p>This discovery signifies a major step towards energy-efficient technology in nanoscale electronics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eenewseurope.com/en/a-new-ultrathin-conductor-for-nanoelectronics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eenewseurope.com/en/a-new-ultrathin-conductor-for-nanoelectronics/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:38:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>