<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:24:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:24:21 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Donald Trump Will Decide How Mars Soil Samples Reach Earth | Explained - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-donald-trump-will-decide-how-mars-soil-samples-reach-earth-explained-ws-ab-9184672.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-donald-trump-will-decide-how-mars-soil-samples-reach-earth-explained-ws-ab-9184672.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:23:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Donald Trump Will Decide How Mars Soil Samples Reach Earth | Explained - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-donald-trump-will-decide-how-mars-soil-samples-reach-earth-explained-ws-ab-9184672.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-donald-trump-will-decide-how-mars-soil-samples-reach-earth-explained-ws-ab-9184672.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:23:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Very Beautiful Images Of Moon Taken By NASA - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Very Beautiful Images Of Moon Taken By NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/117123012/117123012.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=746481" alt="6 Very Beautiful Images Of Moon Taken By NASA">
<figcaption>Credit: Times Now</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases six breathtaking images of the Moon captured by NASA, highlighting the beauty and intrigue of Earth's natural satellite.</p>
<ul>
<li>2017 Total Solar Eclipse image showing the Sun's corona.</li>
<li>Full Moon photo taken from the International Space Station.</li>
<li>Unique perspective of the Moon by NASA's MESSENGER spacecraft.</li>
<li>Tycho Crater captured by the Hubble Space Telescope.</li>
<li>Oblique view of the Copernicus crater taken by Lunar Orbiter 2.</li>
<li>Image of the Moon captured by NASA’s Galileo spacecraft in 1992.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These images aid in understanding the physics and structure of the Moon, showcasing its beauty and our capabilities of capturing it from various spaces.”</blockquote>
<p>This collection of images not only emphasizes the aesthetic appeal of the Moon but also engages audiences in lunar exploration and science.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-very-beautiful-images-of-moon-taken-by-nasa/photostory/117122999.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-very-beautiful-images-of-moon-taken-by-nasa/photostory/117122999.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:22:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jupiter’s Clouds: A Breakthrough Discovery by Combining Old and New Techniques - PUNE.NEWS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amateur Astronomer Challenges Long-Held Assumptions About Jupiter’s Clouds</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <br><strong>Source:</strong> PUNE.NEWS</p><p>An amateur astronomer has provided a new perspective on Jupiter's atmospheric composition, leading to significant revelations that challenge established beliefs regarding the planet's iconic clouds.</p><img src='url_to_image' alt='Jupiter's Clouds'><figcaption>Image of Jupiter's atmosphere.</figcaption><p>This groundbreaking discovery utilized old techniques merging with modern tools, demonstrating the power of collaboration between amateur and professional astronomers.</p><ul><li>Steve Hill used band-depth analysis to study Jupiter's clouds and found limited ammonia ice presence.</li><li>Collaboration with Dr. Patrick Irwin and data from advanced instruments validated Hill's findings.</li><li>Breakthroughs suggest clouds contain ammonium hydrosulfide or photochemical smog instead of primarily ammonia ice.</li></ul><blockquote>“Even seemingly simple observations can push the boundaries of our understanding.” - Dr. Irwin</blockquote><p>The implications of this research extend to Saturn as well, suggesting similar cloud composition due to analogous photochemical processes. Future research is necessary to refine these findings and deepen our understanding of gas giants.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://pune.news/science/jupiters-clouds-a-breakthrough-discovery-by-combining-old-and-new-techniques-288378/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pune.news/science/jupiters-clouds-a-breakthrough-discovery-by-combining-old-and-new-techniques-288378/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:13:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How does Earth look from space? 7 pics that show our planet's beauty from above - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How does Earth look from space? 7 pics that show our planet's beauty from above</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/900x1600/Earth_From_Space_1736495425192_1736495425388.png" alt="Earth from Space"><figcaption>Earth from Space</figcaption><p>This article showcases seven breathtaking images of Earth taken from space, highlighting the planet’s beauty captured by NASA’s satellites.</p><ul><li>The images reveal the stunning oceans, weather patterns, and light from cities at night.</li><li>Each photo emphasizes different aspects of Earth’s environment, including the Great Barrier Reef and storm systems.</li><li>The gallery offers a humbling perspective on our planet’s beauty and fragility.</li></ul><blockquote>“Viewing Earth from space offers a humbling perspective of our planet’s beauty and fragility.”</blockquote><p>These striking visuals serve as a reminder of the connectivity and wonder of our world, encouraging appreciation for Earth's natural landscapes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/trending/how-does-earth-look-from-space-7-pics-that-show-our-planets-beauty-from-above-101736493717284.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/trending/how-does-earth-look-from-space-7-pics-that-show-our-planets-beauty-from-above-101736493717284.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:01:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stargazers in Hong Kong to witness rare alignment of 4 planets - South China Morning Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stargazers in Hong Kong to Witness Rare Alignment of 4 Planets</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> February 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>Hong Kong residents will have the rare opportunity to observe four of the brightest planets in the solar system with the naked eye until the end of February. The city's space museum will host a live stream of the astronomical event on Friday.</p><ul><li>The phenomenon is known as a planetary parade, where several planets are visible in the night sky simultaneously.</li><li>This parade will predominantly feature Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars.</li><li>By the end of February, the public will be able to see six planets, including Neptune and Uranus, but the latter two will require telescopes.</li><li>Currently, alignments with four or more visible planets occur once every few years.</li></ul><blockquote>“Residents can just observe [the planets] with the naked eye,” said Kenneth Chiu Kam-hung, assistant curator at the Hong Kong Space Museum.</blockquote><p>The live stream of the planetary alignment will take place on Friday from 7.30pm to 8.30pm.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3294304/stargazers-hong-kong-witness-rare-planetary-alignment-4-planets</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3294304/stargazers-hong-kong-witness-rare-planetary-alignment-4-planets</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:34:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stargazers in Hong Kong to witness rare planetary alignment of 4 planets - South China Morning Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stargazers in Hong Kong to Witness Rare Alignment of 4 Planets</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> February 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>Hong Kong residents will have the rare opportunity to observe four of the brightest planets in the solar system with the naked eye until the end of February. The city's space museum will host a live stream of the astronomical event on Friday.</p><ul><li>The phenomenon is known as a planetary parade, where several planets are visible in the night sky simultaneously.</li><li>This parade will predominantly feature Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars.</li><li>By the end of February, the public will be able to see six planets, including Neptune and Uranus, but the latter two will require telescopes.</li><li>Currently, alignments with four or more visible planets occur once every few years.</li></ul><blockquote>“Residents can just observe [the planets] with the naked eye,” said Kenneth Chiu Kam-hung, assistant curator at the Hong Kong Space Museum.</blockquote><p>The live stream of the planetary alignment will take place on Friday from 7.30pm to 8.30pm.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3294304/stargazers-hong-kong-witness-rare-planetary-alignment-4-planets</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/3294304/stargazers-hong-kong-witness-rare-planetary-alignment-4-planets</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:34:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iron lines in the X-ray detected from a binary black hole system that can help infer their properties - Department Of Science & Technology]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxNNE85cFU2M2lGb0lMcUxKajZYLUg1YURvWndLQU5iRjJJSzVQRGxQenVWbEZTS3NaWWpBUFZpb28xOTA0X0lFM3lYcWlJVl8yZnJ4eFFKSkNhY2NMNk9SUjBGejlKX3ZaVWhrZHF2eDZ4T1EwWlQwcTVtUHlTLWRKeDhtU1dNNm1zaS0yejdoT05BcGt1UVhvWWhqMS1xZHUxN0Mw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxNNE85cFU2M2lGb0lMcUxKajZYLUg1YURvWndLQU5iRjJJSzVQRGxQenVWbEZTS3NaWWpBUFZpb28xOTA0X0lFM3lYcWlJVl8yZnJ4eFFKSkNhY2NMNk9SUjBGejlKX3ZaVWhrZHF2eDZ4T1EwWlQwcTVtUHlTLWRKeDhtU1dNNm1zaS0yejdoT05BcGt1UVhvWWhqMS1xZHUxN0Mw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:30:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BepiColombo mission to Mercury provides new insights into planet formation - Innovation News Network]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQb3NjVWVHZWI5RDlnT0U1S2NHSHJjdnJuUmRpYXhkNEZHRzVWVnlCTG9uakNRQ2RaYU9fRjRYWkloNGlPemk4aFNDLXNlTk8xdUZZVjlSS0VsTUlsY3VsYVE3Q0plSFhhMjNJN0UweUlGaDNjSTFFSV95MGY5MjExc1poMXMxek5HcC1zalVUUzJYVW50WEtCOEJKcFlLbnFNYTVMcjdCTWhTaGZnOXpzeDNGWlJIWkVaNENV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQb3NjVWVHZWI5RDlnT0U1S2NHSHJjdnJuUmRpYXhkNEZHRzVWVnlCTG9uakNRQ2RaYU9fRjRYWkloNGlPemk4aFNDLXNlTk8xdUZZVjlSS0VsTUlsY3VsYVE3Q0plSFhhMjNJN0UweUlGaDNjSTFFSV95MGY5MjExc1poMXMxek5HcC1zalVUUzJYVW50WEtCOEJKcFlLbnFNYTVMcjdCTWhTaGZnOXpzeDNGWlJIWkVaNENV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:26:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Research discovers new skeletal tissue with potential for regeneration: Study - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Research Discovers New Skeletal Tissue with Potential for Regeneration</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 10, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p><p>An international research team has uncovered a new type of skeletal tissue, known as lipocartilage, which may revolutionize regenerative medicine and tissue engineering.</p><ul><li>The study, led by the University of California, Irvine, identifies lipocartilage found in mammals' ears, nose, and throat, demonstrating unique structural properties.</li><li>Unlike traditional cartilage, lipocartilage is made up of fat-filled cells called lipochondrocytes, providing stability and elasticity.</li><li>The research, published in the journal Science, reveals that lipochondrocytes maintain consistent sizes and can create lipid reservoirs without shrinking in response to food availability.</li><li>Potential applications include creating patient-specific cartilage from stem cells, which could be 3D printed to treat facial defects and various cartilage diseases.</li><li>Findings also include the understanding of genetic processes that regulate fat storage within the cartilage.</li></ul><blockquote>“Lipocartilage's resilience and stability provide a compliant, elastic quality that's perfect for flexible body parts such as earlobes or the tip of the nose,” said Maksim Plikus, the study's corresponding author.</blockquote><p>This discovery opens new avenues for less invasive cartilage reconstruction techniques, promising a future where patients can receive personalized medical solutions for tissue repair.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/health/research-discovers-new-skeletal-tissue-with-potential-for-regeneration-study/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/health/research-discovers-new-skeletal-tissue-with-potential-for-regeneration-study/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:48:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First potential antidote for hydrogen sulfide poisoning created - Chemistry World]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxORFU5V1J6NmMzbFNsaU1QdWlQZ25hQ1FndG1fSk9ndnVyQ0VDY0ItMk80UEJPVC04ZGpMNUprdTNHekloUnNTNVVwY0tsNHlyWWFWMkJJeFBNaURFV2lickVZaGJFcWRzMmhmeDNuX0dMRmhlbjd0cGh0RHVEMEJWSFNud0tPVFpjVmNpc0tnMHU2amgwZUQxSEM1ZmJmTnpjaWgxeTRGSGVEY2RZMXBnMF9CamZMZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxORFU5V1J6NmMzbFNsaU1QdWlQZ25hQ1FndG1fSk9ndnVyQ0VDY0ItMk80UEJPVC04ZGpMNUprdTNHekloUnNTNVVwY0tsNHlyWWFWMkJJeFBNaURFV2lickVZaGJFcWRzMmhmeDNuX0dMRmhlbjd0cGh0RHVEMEJWSFNud0tPVFpjVmNpc0tnMHU2amgwZUQxSEM1ZmJmTnpjaWgxeTRGSGVEY2RZMXBnMF9CamZMZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:03:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 mind-blowing galaxy images captured by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Mind-Blowing Galaxy Images Captured by NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Galaxy-images-2.jpg" alt="Galaxy images (2)"/>
<figcaption>Image of galaxies captured by NASA</figcaption>
<p>NASA has shared multiple stunning images of galaxies that showcase the beauty and complexity of the universe. Each image highlights different features and phenomena associated with various galaxies.</p>
<ul>
<li>Featured images include stunning captures from the Spitzer Space Telescope and Hubble Telescope.</li>
<li>The spiral arms of the nearby galaxy Messier 81 are remarkably showcased.</li>
<li>The immense Andromeda galaxy is presented in spectacular detail.</li>
<li>Nasa’s Spitzer Telescope revealed the Milky Way’s hidden center.</li>
<li>New insights on the magnetic fields of Centaurus A from the SOFIA telescope.</li>
<li>A unique X-ray view of the Milky Way's center reveals superheated gas threads.</li>
<li>NASA’s Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope captured twin bubbles extending from the galactic center.</li>
<li>A recent Hubble image of NGC 6951, a spiral galaxy 78 million light-years away was shared.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>“NASA’s Spitzer Telescope reveals the Milky Way’s hidden center, showing its dense, star-packed core.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This collection of images not only showcases NASA's technological advancements in space observation but also offers a glimpse into the vastness and mystery of our universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-mind-blowing-galaxy-images-captured-by-nasa-7528683/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-mind-blowing-galaxy-images-captured-by-nasa-7528683/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:59:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[300 million-year-old hotspot linked to the formation of the Great Lakes discovered by scientists; where i - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>300 million-year-old hotspot linked to the formation of the Great Lakes discovered by scientists; where is it now?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117114927,imgsize-91182,width-400,resizemode-4/117114927.jpg" alt="300 million-year-old hotspot linked to the formation of the Great Lakes discovered by scientists; where is it now?" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>300 million-year-old hotspot linked to the formation of the Great Lakes</figcaption><p>The discovery of a hotspot beneath the ancient supercontinent Pangaea is a significant advancement in understanding the geological history of the Great Lakes region.</p><ul><li>The Cape Verde hotspot has been linked to the formation of the Great Lakes over 300 million years ago.</li><li>The discovery reveals how tectonic activities and glacial movements contributed to shaping the landscape.</li><li>Seismic anomalies indicate past deformation of the lithosphere beneath the Great Lakes region influenced by the hotspot.</li></ul><blockquote>“The connection between the Cape Verde hotspot and the Great Lakes adds a new layer of understanding to geological processes.”</blockquote><p>This groundbreaking research helps to understand not just the formation of the Great Lakes, but also the broader trends in geological developments influenced by ancient hotspots.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/300-million-year-old-hotspot-linked-to-the-formation-of-the-great-lakes-discovered-by-scientists-where-is-it-now/articleshow/117114546.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/300-million-year-old-hotspot-linked-to-the-formation-of-the-great-lakes-discovered-by-scientists-where-is-it-now/articleshow/117114546.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 09:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Physicists spot 44 stars no one knew existed thanks to ‘cosmic hall of mirrors’ effect - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Physicists spot 44 stars no one knew existed, thanks to ‘cosmic hall of mirrors’ effect</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Tech-feature-images86.jpg?w=640" alt="The discovery was made owing to a scientific phenomenon known as gravitational lensing." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>The discovery was made owing to a scientific phenomenon known as gravitational lensing. (Image credit: NASA, ESA, and J. Lotz, and the HFF team)</figcaption><p>A group of physicists at Durham University in the UK has identified over 44 previously unknown stars located in the Dragon Arc galaxy, nearly 6.5 billion light-years away.</p><ul><li>The stars were hidden behind the Abell 370 cluster of galaxies.</li><li>Identified using images from the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST).</li><li>Discovered stars observed during “cosmic noon,” a peak star birth era.</li><li>Gravitational lensing allowed for magnification of distant light.</li><li>First significant observation of stars at such a distance.</li></ul><blockquote>“This very particular type of star we have detected in the Dragon Arc, called red supergiants, are very difficult to observe...” - Dr. Mathilde Jauzac</blockquote><p>This discovery could enhance understanding of star formation and the universe's evolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/science/physicists-uncover-distant-stars-hidden-behind-galaxy-cluster-9771350/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/science/physicists-uncover-distant-stars-hidden-behind-galaxy-cluster-9771350/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:38:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Catch Venus at its brightest: Last chance to see 'evening star' in full glory until 2026, here's how to... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Catch Venus at its Brightest: Last Chance to See 'Evening Star' in Full Glory Until 2026</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250110081404_Sheetal-Kumari-fi.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431' alt='Evening star, Venus' title='Evening star, Venus' width='770' height='431'><figcaption>Evening star, Venus</figcaption><p>On January 10, 2025, Venus reaches its greatest elongation east, a rare event making the planet exceptionally bright and high in the sky, visible after sunset and throughout the evening.</p><ul><li>Venus will appear most radiant this evening, visible to observers looking west at sunset.</li><li>This event will not occur again until August 2026.</li></ul><blockquote>“Venus will remain visible well into the evening, offering skywatchers an exceptional view.”</blockquote><p>This is a unique opportunity for sky enthusiasts to witness Venus's brilliance before it won't be visible in such a manner for several years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/catch-venus-at-greatest-elongation-east-last-chance-to-see-evening-star-in-full-glory-until-2026-here-s-how-to-view-it-best-article-12907360.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/catch-venus-at-greatest-elongation-east-last-chance-to-see-evening-star-in-full-glory-until-2026-here-s-how-to-view-it-best-article-12907360.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:29:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Firestorm forces emergency evacuation at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Firestorm Forces Emergency Evacuation at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>January 8, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong><a href="https://www.news9live.com/science">Science News</a></p>
<img width="802" height="464" src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/NASA-Jet-Propulsion-Laboratory.png?w=802&amp;enlarge=true" alt="NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory" title="NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory">
<figcaption>NASA Jet Propulsion Lab Under Siege as Wildfires Destroy Everything in Their Path. (Image Credit: NASA)</figcaption>
<p>The Pasadena-based Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) of NASA was ordered to be evacuated due to the advancing Eaton Fire, which threatened to reach the facility.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Residents in the vicinity were also ordered to evacuate.</li>
  <li>The fire lines came within a mile of the lab, causing strong winds that prompted concern, although the lab has not suffered fire damage.</li>
  <li>JPL director Laurie Leshin expressed the impact on local residents, noting that many have lost their homes.</li>
  <li>The Eaton Fire has burned approximately 10,600 acres as of January 8, 2024, with zero percent containment reported.</li>
  <li>The wildfire has resulted in the evacuation of over fifty-one thousand residents and confirmed five fatalities.</li>
  <li>Despite the evacuation, JPL has managed to maintain communication with various NASA spacecraft through its emergency protocols.</li>
  <li>The lab is critical for ongoing planetary missions and will remain closed until further notice.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“No fire damage yet (there is some wind damage), but it is right next to the lab. Hundreds of JPLers have been evacuated from their homes, and many have lost homes.” - Laurie Leshin</blockquote>
<p>As Southern California faces severe wildfire conditions, the well-being of JPL employees and the community remains a top priority.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/firestorm-forces-emergency-evacuation-at-nasas-jet-propulsion-laboratory-2793363</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/firestorm-forces-emergency-evacuation-at-nasas-jet-propulsion-laboratory-2793363</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:47:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why did sabre-toothed predators evolve their deadly teeth? New research may have answers - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why did sabre-toothed predators evolve their deadly teeth? New research may have answers</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 10 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> The Conversation</p><p>New research reveals that the extreme sabre teeth of ancient predators like Smilodon were optimized for puncturing prey and evolved multiple times in history.</p><ul><li>Sabre teeth evolved independently in various mammalian groups, showcasing convergent evolution.</li><li>The study indicates these teeth, while effective for hunting, were weaker and prone to breaking.</li><li>Research involved analyzing over 200 carnivore teeth, incorporating 3D shape measurements and engineering simulations.</li><li>Findings suggest a continuum of sabre-tooth shapes, each suited for different hunting strategies.</li><li>The adaptations reflect a key balance between efficiency in puncturing and structural strength.</li></ul><blockquote>“Their increasing specialisation may have acted as an 'evolutionary ratchet', making them highly effective hunters but also vulnerable to extinction.”</blockquote><p>This research not only sheds light on sabre-toothed predators but also provides insights applicable to engineering and design.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/science/why-did-sabre-toothed-predators-evolve-their-deadly-teeth-new-research-may-have-answers-3349309</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/science/why-did-sabre-toothed-predators-evolve-their-deadly-teeth-new-research-may-have-answers-3349309</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:30:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[International Team Unlocks Secrets of the Universe’s First Light at South Pole Telescope - Business News This Week]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxONEk1eGxIRk8zMW1uVnREa3EwbENTUWowam9tSEdSclJSLTZkdEtFT2FuLUY4bVliZlY0YkFpbDd4V3JPQmNMWjZFLVlYMHNtbXFaalhmWE5vWkxJS0NCbE5NRE4zZk9DWnhudUJRc2xtUm1YejlEQU5XcGdFbGZKVmxGNTlnM3dEMzRhUGtwOHNRMktOYU56aDB5QWQtWmZYSmplaGVzR1ZvbU1uT2FKdFZEbE5QcDdxTkdGTVpqcEI3eU5o?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxONEk1eGxIRk8zMW1uVnREa3EwbENTUWowam9tSEdSclJSLTZkdEtFT2FuLUY4bVliZlY0YkFpbDd4V3JPQmNMWjZFLVlYMHNtbXFaalhmWE5vWkxJS0NCbE5NRE4zZk9DWnhudUJRc2xtUm1YejlEQU5XcGdFbGZKVmxGNTlnM3dEMzRhUGtwOHNRMktOYU56aDB5QWQtWmZYSmplaGVzR1ZvbU1uT2FKdFZEbE5QcDdxTkdGTVpqcEI3eU5o?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 07:06:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[POSTECH and University of Technology Sydney develop quantum LED using graphene - Graphene-Info]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.graphene-info.com/postech-and-university-technology-sydney-develop-quantum-led-using-graphene</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.graphene-info.com/postech-and-university-technology-sydney-develop-quantum-led-using-graphene</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:49:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China Focus: China Launches Advanced Attosecond Laser Infrastructure to Propel Scientific Research and Technology - NewsX]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNbXA0YTJkbHVicmRyZUZEbXpqUE15cWczMGZ0NHVVelVYOXFLQWhnVHdJWkdiUDUyWm1yTzZZQ3Jic1RsX2toblhRbmxibjNXYi1GeHI3TkVudVlmSUdOdDBDa2NFZm5mMHlRajN2SlNBZWI2LWdjby1NNUNnSk1NUXpBSFpvUzREVmhnT1g4T0k0ZXNiNktiQVdIcUJyVTh5eXJXZGtKMFdwbkVfQkpmVW5YNTNZX1Z5NEpQbnNMbzJvTWZHNlZlWFNyTkI2LXNlZVBvX3lVQWgxajNEUTBDVE1MNA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNbXA0YTJkbHVicmRyZUZEbXpqUE15cWczMGZ0NHVVelVYOXFLQWhnVHdJWkdiUDUyWm1yTzZZQ3Jic1RsX2toblhRbmxibjNXYi1GeHI3TkVudVlmSUdOdDBDa2NFZm5mMHlRajN2SlNBZWI2LWdjby1NNUNnSk1NUXpBSFpvUzREVmhnT1g4T0k0ZXNiNktiQVdIcUJyVTh5eXJXZGtKMFdwbkVfQkpmVW5YNTNZX1Z5NEpQbnNMbzJvTWZHNlZlWFNyTkI2LXNlZVBvX3lVQWgxajNEUTBDVE1MNA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists reveal secrets of sharks' sex lives by examining their bloody mating bite marks - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxNU0lBNGxyTk1Gb2xWREhZWDAyMlN4SXhla1FEa2QtcnZFdF9XNWRHWW1tdW1rRGJtaUN4Z3FHMW1KMFY3b2ItMTVrc2RyckVqOUhUdkE2cmpjU3ZwZzI2MWJYQ1hXdlhDZlpZbDdPNVZNR1pRVUdTTWFNR0Juc2lOSWVvRmlGXzJKWkxaMHBZV2RqeW1odGxFN3RsV2xmNHlSUGN4R2JfdzRTNFdoNkUtcnotWnZLY2tUdEwwWDgzZ2hXM2d3MnRTLXQxUnVvNkpWNEJjSklpbldOdXJ5aHQwekZB0gHnAUFVX3lxTE9yVXJzVmx4czhMaUpyd3dneGo0MnNVMmQwWjFGdllwLVhtNlNoWjZRLWk2YXNuVVFqaEFrMVlERGI5NXE1Ty16LWhJRFM1eGpTdkFRY1BNQUpjM3RVZ0RnQlp0UUdlWUNEby1hVXMydWJwQ1FDOVVtVW96cTZFN2R1ZlpmQ2lxcWRHUWp1R3lFZ3RGbHdPQkRKMG9MMnJVYzMtMV9XSnBRc3lKRlpZSHM5VzM2TUQzZmU5eFhDaWc2aERCWTVhTEJtYjVwSnBTd1JVSG43d25HeHVkaXlVSnlTXzVGT3ZlWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxNU0lBNGxyTk1Gb2xWREhZWDAyMlN4SXhla1FEa2QtcnZFdF9XNWRHWW1tdW1rRGJtaUN4Z3FHMW1KMFY3b2ItMTVrc2RyckVqOUhUdkE2cmpjU3ZwZzI2MWJYQ1hXdlhDZlpZbDdPNVZNR1pRVUdTTWFNR0Juc2lOSWVvRmlGXzJKWkxaMHBZV2RqeW1odGxFN3RsV2xmNHlSUGN4R2JfdzRTNFdoNkUtcnotWnZLY2tUdEwwWDgzZ2hXM2d3MnRTLXQxUnVvNkpWNEJjSklpbldOdXJ5aHQwekZB0gHnAUFVX3lxTE9yVXJzVmx4czhMaUpyd3dneGo0MnNVMmQwWjFGdllwLVhtNlNoWjZRLWk2YXNuVVFqaEFrMVlERGI5NXE1Ty16LWhJRFM1eGpTdkFRY1BNQUpjM3RVZ0RnQlp0UUdlWUNEby1hVXMydWJwQ1FDOVVtVW96cTZFN2R1ZlpmQ2lxcWRHUWp1R3lFZ3RGbHdPQkRKMG9MMnJVYzMtMV9XSnBRc3lKRlpZSHM5VzM2TUQzZmU5eFhDaWc2aERCWTVhTEJtYjVwSnBTd1JVSG43d25HeHVkaXlVSnlTXzVGT3ZlWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 06:15:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['1.27 million light-years long': Astronomers spot a new ultra-diffuse galaxy forming in Leo constellation;... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxORnE3UVMxMlc1QkN0d3V3NDZlZkl3T3pvT3ExUGpaZ3dUOWZJYV9mY0M1UkZoOExQWXFNVVhrVHUzRjlyYll1UExGTHlDTnhPMUNtV3FuYnE3dVNUdXNROHZ4TmZZNzk2WWZxbVpXc2VsalJoajZYOVZnNGNKX05kWTRXbmJuUlpqdi0wVDFCMnhSem9sdXlUOTVoeF81a093TU5wZjB4eDM5X0dBOFo2QW54QnBidFBwdFV1Z3duTHBKcEE1cDM3b2FseXcyU2VjMXdWU1FYTTROSHN0WnExS1l2MkFwNHg4clF6dEtRTVUxQ2lsZ1A1NEF1OVdmSThv0gGGAkFVX3lxTE5lVkdLTVF4dVV0WV9KczU1OXp5NlJLajU4TjVUTnNXY0NBLV9iZ3VGR2dYcl9WdENKdGpZb25zZ3FNSEszajlKMWthS0pSZEt1Vi1WbTlBOF9uZDNaMlY0V3F6VUM0QzBxTGFUYmZhUG9LRnp1RE04S3BoZUNLNVVRbnZ2RDN0UGxUdTZ1cHo0R1Y3UC12MjU3QnFNcXhtNlV2Rk9PSmRSV2xjZUd2Vk1sbEwweDNxVTNrUjFiOHA2MWw1M2E4Z1BJYVpmZkV6Uk92TnJtYXZPRFdZanFXekZWVkVhbktnYU85NGlVMXpibXFNM1FRQmNuRkxBREQ0cTdYUkx3N2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxORnE3UVMxMlc1QkN0d3V3NDZlZkl3T3pvT3ExUGpaZ3dUOWZJYV9mY0M1UkZoOExQWXFNVVhrVHUzRjlyYll1UExGTHlDTnhPMUNtV3FuYnE3dVNUdXNROHZ4TmZZNzk2WWZxbVpXc2VsalJoajZYOVZnNGNKX05kWTRXbmJuUlpqdi0wVDFCMnhSem9sdXlUOTVoeF81a093TU5wZjB4eDM5X0dBOFo2QW54QnBidFBwdFV1Z3duTHBKcEE1cDM3b2FseXcyU2VjMXdWU1FYTTROSHN0WnExS1l2MkFwNHg4clF6dEtRTVUxQ2lsZ1A1NEF1OVdmSThv0gGGAkFVX3lxTE5lVkdLTVF4dVV0WV9KczU1OXp5NlJLajU4TjVUTnNXY0NBLV9iZ3VGR2dYcl9WdENKdGpZb25zZ3FNSEszajlKMWthS0pSZEt1Vi1WbTlBOF9uZDNaMlY0V3F6VUM0QzBxTGFUYmZhUG9LRnp1RE04S3BoZUNLNVVRbnZ2RDN0UGxUdTZ1cHo0R1Y3UC12MjU3QnFNcXhtNlV2Rk9PSmRSV2xjZUd2Vk1sbEwweDNxVTNrUjFiOHA2MWw1M2E4Z1BJYVpmZkV6Uk92TnJtYXZPRFdZanFXekZWVkVhbktnYU85NGlVMXpibXFNM1FRQmNuRkxBREQ0cTdYUkx3N2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:29:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Science News | ⚡Rare 'New Year Comet' ATLAS G3 To Shine Bright in the Night Sky - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxQYXNaYjlmZVREbTYxVFVfOW1NZU1XWlFxSnVWd0pGVlhWZnptM2twYzlVT3JoWkM4WTMtLXVjNExrMzBMYU9VRDVRZjFRMlhsaXFzM2g4WVM3QUQwR0tPb29EWnM2aGxuR084endiNEJ1NWprcndZZlktckRBQ29SZ1NkSDVvR2o1c1g4Umc4TFdkM2c2T3VfeUFzVEo4cmlNb3RhWk5fdDh6YkxpZDg2U3NLWnNmUVoxSXp2NzktcFdPSWph0gHEAUFVX3lxTFBhc1piOWZlVERtNjFUVV85bU1lTVdaUXFKdVZ3SkZWWFZmem0za3BjOVVPcmhaQzhZMy0tdWM0TGszMExhT1VENVFmMVEyWGxpcXMzaDhZUzdBRDBHS09vb0RaczZobG5HTzh6d2I0QnU1amtyd1lmWS1yREFDb1JnU2RINW9HajVzWDhSZzhMV2QzZzZPdV95QXNUSjhyaU1vdGFaTl90OHpiTGlkODZTc0tac2ZRWjFJenY3OS1wV09JamE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxQYXNaYjlmZVREbTYxVFVfOW1NZU1XWlFxSnVWd0pGVlhWZnptM2twYzlVT3JoWkM4WTMtLXVjNExrMzBMYU9VRDVRZjFRMlhsaXFzM2g4WVM3QUQwR0tPb29EWnM2aGxuR084endiNEJ1NWprcndZZlktckRBQ29SZ1NkSDVvR2o1c1g4Umc4TFdkM2c2T3VfeUFzVEo4cmlNb3RhWk5fdDh6YkxpZDg2U3NLWnNmUVoxSXp2NzktcFdPSWph0gHEAUFVX3lxTFBhc1piOWZlVERtNjFUVV85bU1lTVdaUXFKdVZ3SkZWWFZmem0za3BjOVVPcmhaQzhZMy0tdWM0TGszMExhT1VENVFmMVEyWGxpcXMzaDhZUzdBRDBHS09vb0RaczZobG5HTzh6d2I0QnU1amtyd1lmWS1yREFDb1JnU2RINW9HajVzWDhSZzhMV2QzZzZPdV95QXNUSjhyaU1vdGFaTl90OHpiTGlkODZTc0tac2ZRWjFJenY3OS1wV09JamE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:12:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Considers Cheaper, Faster Ways To Retrieve Mars Samples - Science Friday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Considers Cheaper, Faster Ways To Retrieve Mars Samples</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Science Friday</p>
<img src="https://www.sciencefriday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/PIA26379-Sol-1295-Navcam-NLF_1295_0781909732_909RZS_N0603852NCAM02295_0A0195J01-e1736465300588.jpg?w=1024" alt="A mars rover on the dusty, pinkish desert surface of Mars, with its tracks zigzagging into the hazy background." width="1024" height="686">
<figcaption>NASA’s Perseverance Rover captured this image of its own tracks in the Jezero Crater on Mars in October 2024. Credit: <a href="https://science.nasa.gov/resource/tracks-tell-tale-of-perseverances-crater-rim-climb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NASA/JPL-Caltech</a></figcaption>
<p>NASA’s Mars Sample Return mission aims to collect Martian materials and deliver them to Earth, but plans have become more complicated and costly. Recently, NASA has proposed two options to expedite the sample return process, which could see the samples arrive by the late 2030s. However, a finalized plan will be left for the next administration.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Mars Sample Return mission is designed to retrieve rocks, sand, and air from Mars.</li>
<li>Initial plans were found to be costly and time-consuming, prompting new proposals.</li>
<li>NASA is considering two alternative strategies for a more cost-effective approach.</li>
<li>The selected plan will be determined by the next administration in about 18 months.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Is the project on the rocks?”</blockquote>
<p>The future of the Mars Sample Return mission hangs in the balance as NASA seeks to balance scientific ambition with cost and practicality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencefriday.com/segments/nasa-mars-sample-return-mission-plan-trump/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencefriday.com/segments/nasa-mars-sample-return-mission-plan-trump/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 05:08:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists drill nearly 2 miles down to pull 1.2 million-year-old ice core from Antarctic - ABC News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://abcnews.go.com/Technology/wireStory/scientists-drill-2-miles-pull-12-million-year-117496776</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://abcnews.go.com/Technology/wireStory/scientists-drill-2-miles-pull-12-million-year-117496776</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 03:39:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spacecraft buzzes Mercury's north pole and beams back stunning photos - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Spacecraft Buzzes Mercury's North Pole and Beams Back Stunning Photos</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/0f0b6414bbf485fb6a8c6cd92e14c552.jpg" alt="Spacecraft image of Mercury">
<figcaption>Image captured by the spacecraft near Mercury's north pole.</figcaption>
<p>The recent mission to Mercury has yielded breathtaking images as the spacecraft passes over the planet's north pole, offering new insights into its surface and composition.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The spacecraft executed a successful flyby of Mercury.</li>
  <li>High-resolution images reveal unique geological features.</li>
  <li>The mission aims to study Mercury's environment and geological history.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The level of detail in these photos is unprecedented.”</blockquote>
<p>This mission marks a significant step forward in our understanding of Mercury and could lead to further discoveries about our solar system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/spacecraft-buzzes-mercurys-north-pole-and-beams-back-stunning-photos/articleshow/117102297.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/spacecraft-buzzes-mercurys-north-pole-and-beams-back-stunning-photos/articleshow/117102297.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 02:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 stunning images of galaxies shared by NASA - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Stunning Images of Galaxies Shared by NASA</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 10, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> DNA</p><img src="https://images1.dnaindia.com/images/DNA-EN/900x1600/2025/1/10/1736471887944_image20250110T064542.677.jpg" alt="10 stunning images of galaxies shared by NASA"><figcaption>A stunning image of a galaxy captured by NASA.</figcaption><p>The article features a selection of breathtaking images of galaxies as shared by NASA, showcasing the beauty and complexity of the universe.</p><ul><li>The James Webb Space Telescope reveals details of the Cartwheel Galaxy.</li><li>Images show star formation in the Carina Nebula highlighting NGC 3324.</li><li>All-sky map from Planck displays our Milky Way galaxy in vivid detail.</li><li>A festive portrait of the Milky Way depicts its various gas and dust components.</li><li>SOFIA captures magnetic field images of Centaurus A.</li><li>The Hubble Telescope presents a colorful view of the evolving universe.</li><li>Spitzer Space Telescope highlights the spiral arms of galaxy Messier 81.</li><li>The article ends with a mention of the Fermi Gamma-ray Space Telescope’s discovery of a gigantic structure in our galaxy.</li></ul><blockquote>“NASA's impressive images expand our understanding of the universe.”</blockquote><p>These stunning visuals not only captivate the imagination but also deepen our knowledge of cosmic phenomena.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/viral/10-stunning-images-of-galaxies-shared-by-nasa-1736471864578</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/viral/10-stunning-images-of-galaxies-shared-by-nasa-1736471864578</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 01:25:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk in 2016 Pitched He’d Colonize Mars by 2022: He Won’t Even Get There by 2028 - flyingpenguin]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk in 2016 Pitched He’d Colonize Mars by 2022: He Won’t Even Get There by 2028</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<img src="/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/spacex-mars-by-2018-500x493.jpeg" alt="" width="474" height="467">
<figcaption>SpaceX's vision for Mars colonization.</figcaption>
<p>This article reflects on Elon Musk's ambitious plans to colonize Mars by 2022, which remain unrealized as the projected timelines have continually shifted since 2016.</p>
<ul>
<li>Musk initially proposed travel to Mars at less than $100,000 per person, with a timeline for colonization starting in 2022.</li>
<li>By 2017, he had revised plans to land cargo on Mars, aiming to introduce humans to the planet by 2024.</li>
<li>The vision escalated from an initial colony of 80,000 to 1 million inhabitants over a span of 40 to 100 years.</li>
<li>Critiques highlight the disconnect between Musk's promises and actual achievements in space exploration.</li>
<li>The piece argues that Musk's approach reflects a pattern of unmet expectations reminiscent of other ventures he leads.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“...recognize Mars as a free planet and that no Earth-based government has authority or sovereignty over Martian activities.”</blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, the article emphasizes the need for accountability in private space ventures, suggesting that misleading promises can erode public trust in legitimate scientific progress.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.flyingpenguin.com/?p=64454</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.flyingpenguin.com/?p=64454</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:46:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Recasts Plan To Return Samples From Mars - Aviation Week]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Recasts Plan To Return Samples From Mars</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified  <strong>Source:</strong> Aviation Week Network</p>
<img src="/sites/default/files/styles/crop_freeform/public/2025-01/samples-1_nasa-esa-jpl-caltech_promo.jpg?itok=XPKZI9D7" alt="Mars Sample Return concept illustration with rovers and rockets">
<figcaption><p>NASA is looking to simplify plans to return a cache of science samples collected by the ongoing Mars Perseverance rover mission. The original architecture, conceptualized here, could cost up to $11 billion and return the samples in 2040.</p><p>Credit: NASA/ESA/JPL-Caltech</p></figcaption>
<p>The departing leadership of NASA outlined a simpler, less expensive plan to return science samples from Mars, hoping the incoming administration of President-elect Donald Trump and the new U.S. Congress will champion the plan to reality. After decades of groundwork, a carefully curated collection of samples awaits their journey back to Earth.</p>
<ul>
<li>Simplification of the original Mars sample return plan.</li>
<li>Cost reduction with a target budget around $11 billion.</li>
<li>The goal is to bring back samples collected by the Perseverance rover.</li>
<li>Need for support from the incoming administration and Congress.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"NASA is looking to simplify plans to return a cache of science samples collected by the ongoing Mars Perseverance rover mission."</blockquote>
<p>This new approach aims to achieve the ambitious goal of returning Martian samples with more efficiency than previous plans without compromising scientific integrity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://aviationweek.com/space/budget-policy-regulation/nasa-recasts-plan-return-samples-mars</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://aviationweek.com/space/budget-policy-regulation/nasa-recasts-plan-return-samples-mars</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 23:11:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New ultra-diffuse galaxy discovered in formation 430 million light years away - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New ultra-diffuse galaxy discovered in formation 430 million light years away</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 09 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p><p>Astronomers have found a new ultra-diffuse galaxy forming at the end of a tidal tail of galaxy NGC 3785, which is located about 430 million light years away in the Leo constellation. This discovery was made by a team from various prestigious institutions.</p><ul><li>The galaxy formation results from gravitational interactions with a neighboring galaxy.</li><li>Ultra-diffuse galaxies are characterized by being less bright and less massive than typical galaxies.</li><li>The tidal tail of NGC 3785 is noted to be the longest ever observed.</li><li>The tidal tail extends over 1.27 million light years.</li></ul><blockquote>“We found that the tidal tail stretches for 1.27 million light years, making it the longest tidal tail ever discovered in an isolated environment.” - Chandan Watts</blockquote><p>This finding could enhance our understanding of galaxy evolution and the processes leading to the formation of ultra-diffuse galaxies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/science/space/new-ultra-diffuse-galaxy-discovered-in-formation-430-million-light-years-away-3348890</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/science/space/new-ultra-diffuse-galaxy-discovered-in-formation-430-million-light-years-away-3348890</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 23:10:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>