<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:25:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 18:25:59 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Planet parade: City witnesses planets with enthusiasm - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Planet Parade: City Witnesses Planets with Enthusiasm</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 20, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> News Agency</p><p>In an extraordinary celestial event, residents of the city gathered to witness the rare alignment of planets in the night sky, creating a spectacular display of cosmic beauty.</p><ul><li>City officials organized public viewings with telescopes provided for attendees.</li><li>Local astronomers gave talks and explanations about the events and importance of such alignments.</li><li>Families and space enthusiasts expressed their excitement and awe at the phenomenon.</li><li>Special events included educational workshops for children to learn about astronomy.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s not just a sight to behold, but a great opportunity for learning and inspiration,” said a local astronomer.</blockquote><p>The event brought together community members, highlighting the importance of astronomy education and public engagement in science.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/guwahati/planet-parade-city-witnesses-planets-with-enthusiasm/articleshow/117309126.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/guwahati/planet-parade-city-witnesses-planets-with-enthusiasm/articleshow/117309126.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cosmologist Rajendra Gupta visits Kerala University - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/cosmologist-rajendra-gupta-visits-kerala-university/article69105490.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/cosmologist-rajendra-gupta-visits-kerala-university/article69105490.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Webb Telescope Tracks Formation and Expansion of Carbon-Rich Dust Shells in Star System - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Webb Telescope Tracks Formation and Expansion of Carbon-Rich Dust Shells in Star System</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/kOPLxpRVCX8/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Video on the study</figcaption><p>Data from the James Webb Space Telescope has revealed the formation and outward expansion of carbon-rich dust shells in the Wolf-Rayet 140 star system, providing insights into cosmic evolution.</p><ul><li>Wolf-Rayet 140 consists of two massive stars in an elongated orbit.</li><li>17 concentric dust shells expanding at around 1% of the speed of light.</li><li>The shells demonstrate rapid movement, expanding visibly over 14 months.</li><li>The larger star may explode as a supernova or collapse into a black hole in the future.</li></ul><blockquote>“The consistent velocities of these shells were confirmed by Webb's detailed observations.” - Emma Lieb, Study Lead Author</blockquote><p>The findings could help understand the processes behind the creation of rocky planets and solar systems.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/nasa-s-hubble-observes-rare-blue-lurker-star-with-unusual-evolution-7474502</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/nasa-s-hubble-observes-rare-blue-lurker-star-with-unusual-evolution-7474502</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:42:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Webb Telescope Spots Swirling Ribbons of Interstellar Medium - ExtremeTech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Webb Telescope Spots Swirling Ribbons of Interstellar Medium</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent Announcement<br><strong>Source:</strong> NASA, ExtremeTech</p><img src="https://i.extremetech.com/imagery/content-types/05pnohmr5QveehPIaSebBhZ/hero-image.fit_lim.v1736981617.png" alt="Webb's image of the interstellar medium." width="2560" height="1440"><figcaption>Credit: NASA, ESA, CSA, STScI, Jacob Jencson (Caltech/IPAC)</figcaption><p>NASA's James Webb Space Telescope has captured a stunning new view of the interstellar medium, showcasing the intricate dust and gas between stars, illuminated by the echoes of a long-gone star. The image reveals previously unseen structures within this elusive material.</p><ul><li>The Webb Telescope provided a unique look at the interstellar medium, typically invisible to observers.</li><li>Light from a collapsed star allowed for visualization of ribbon-like swirls in the interstellar medium.</li><li>The image demonstrates structures within the interstellar medium smaller than ever observed before.</li><li>Webb's NIRCam performed a CT scan-like analysis to create a layered image.</li></ul><blockquote>"We did not know that the interstellar medium had structures on that small of a scale, let alone that it was sheet-like," says Josh Peek, a member of the Webb science team.</blockquote><p>This groundbreaking image enhances our understanding of the interstellar medium and its complex structures, promising further insights as we continue to explore the cosmos.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.extremetech.com/science/webb-telescope-spots-swirling-ribbons-of-interstellar-medium</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.extremetech.com/science/webb-telescope-spots-swirling-ribbons-of-interstellar-medium</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:12:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Very Beautiful Images Of Space Clicked By NASA Hubble Space Telescope - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Very Beautiful Images Of Space Clicked By NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/117305299/117305299.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=1450070" alt="6 Very Beautiful Images Of Space Clicked By NASA Hubble Space Telescope">
<figcaption>Credit: NASA-ESA-and-STScI</figcaption>
<p>The Hubble Space Telescope has captured breathtaking images of the cosmos. Here are 6 of the most beautiful pictures ever taken by this iconic observatory.</p>
<ul>
  <li><h2>Ghost Nebula</h2><p>Located in the constellation Cassiopeia, illuminated by Gamma Cassiopeiae.</p></li>
  <li><h2>Westerlund 2</h2><p>A massive star cluster with 3,000 stars in the star-forming region Gum 29.</p></li>
  <li><h2>NGC 1850</h2><p>A 100-million-year-old globular cluster in the Large Magellanic Cloud.</p></li>
  <li><h2>Mystic Mountain</h2><p>Features a pillar of gas and dust, showcasing dynamic cosmic activity.</p></li>
  <li><h2>M83</h2><p>The Southern Pinwheel Galaxy, rich in active star formation.</p></li>
  <li><h2>NGC 1300</h2><p>A textbook example of a barred spiral galaxy with a distinctive structure.</p></li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Hubble Space Telescope has truly transformed our understanding of the universe.”</blockquote>
<p>This collection showcases the beauty and complexity of the universe, inspiring further exploration and appreciation of space.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-very-beautiful-images-of-space-clicked-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/117305273.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-very-beautiful-images-of-space-clicked-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/117305273.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:38:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams steps out on spacewalk after seven months in orbit - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPcmU0MTU4Y1VvTkZiSHFLQ2pKUlgzRVBiMTJaRW1ESHUzR2RQcGRqTWsyMTNGVXMwT2dYdkdDTjRHV3RkOTRkSHlsZTd5QlRtZkdFd2FfZkFDMFZzeDhrdmJJU0dneVY3ekt5bHpoQUJfUWFYV2k0VjRkVXdhQUZBV3lTU0MxblhpdWl5ajNLV2pKbklISWtSa3VMQWVITXczc0NwRDdtWGpDbEdaRDdyMkRKNDVGLUFBZGw3MjVSc3o1Y1d6ZUFTNENXOFl6RWlRZVRuN2NPbGhrVTdtX1I5b2diVHrSAesBQVVfeXFMUHV1ZkY5VFdqekNOcTF4dkVCNTNNVmlCOE4yejlreXRXV2JvMVVvWnhPeTY5QjJBbVRZRFBxVTlyZnJFaFRrOHpqXzIzQUl0TExET2EwQUhhd0ZSZklNMTJjY2xPdDZhQlFxRFRGV05ibEM5d2l1U0FEbTRmUUxTNkp1VXMwemJqUnVOSEJxSXQyUHZXeE9GQ1BsbWxfNXFubm94TXA1dWFhbk1SQzNYTmVwVDJ1ZFk5YWwzeGlhYnR0czByMWxkUXpXcjJ6TWh6ZnJqWVVmM3lTekxuSkVfZXF5WjZncmQ0WERXMA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPcmU0MTU4Y1VvTkZiSHFLQ2pKUlgzRVBiMTJaRW1ESHUzR2RQcGRqTWsyMTNGVXMwT2dYdkdDTjRHV3RkOTRkSHlsZTd5QlRtZkdFd2FfZkFDMFZzeDhrdmJJU0dneVY3ekt5bHpoQUJfUWFYV2k0VjRkVXdhQUZBV3lTU0MxblhpdWl5ajNLV2pKbklISWtSa3VMQWVITXczc0NwRDdtWGpDbEdaRDdyMkRKNDVGLUFBZGw3MjVSc3o1Y1d6ZUFTNENXOFl6RWlRZVRuN2NPbGhrVTdtX1I5b2diVHrSAesBQVVfeXFMUHV1ZkY5VFdqekNOcTF4dkVCNTNNVmlCOE4yejlreXRXV2JvMVVvWnhPeTY5QjJBbVRZRFBxVTlyZnJFaFRrOHpqXzIzQUl0TExET2EwQUhhd0ZSZklNMTJjY2xPdDZhQlFxRFRGV05ibEM5d2l1U0FEbTRmUUxTNkp1VXMwemJqUnVOSEJxSXQyUHZXeE9GQ1BsbWxfNXFubm94TXA1dWFhbk1SQzNYTmVwVDJ1ZFk5YWwzeGlhYnR0czByMWxkUXpXcjJ6TWh6ZnJqWVVmM3lTekxuSkVfZXF5WjZncmQ0WERXMA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rare planetary parade: Check dates and here's how you can see six or seven planets. Skywatching tips from - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rare planetary parade: Check dates and here's how you can see six or seven planets</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 - <strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p><p>This January, skygazers can look forward to a rare planetary parade where six planets—Venus, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Neptune, and Uranus—will be visible in the night sky at the same time.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>A planetary parade occurs when multiple planets appear aligned from Earth’s perspective.</li><li>The event is set to occur on January 21, with visibility starting from January 15.</li><li>The best viewing time is expected to be just after sunset around 8:30 p.m. local time.</li><li>A telescope may be required to spot Uranus and Neptune.</li><li>The parade will evolve into a seven-planet display when Mercury joins on February 29.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tonight it is a big one, Mars... It is directly opposite the sun, so it's going to rise at sunset, be visible all night...” - Greg Redfern, NASA/JPL Solar System Ambassador</blockquote><p>This spectacular event provides a unique opportunity for astronomy enthusiasts to observe multiple planets in the sky simultaneously, making it a memorable experience for the month.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/global-trends/us-news-rare-planetary-parade-check-dates-and-heres-how-you-can-see-six-or-seven-planets-skywatching-tips-from-nasa/articleshow/117304106.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/global-trends/us-news-rare-planetary-parade-check-dates-and-heres-how-you-can-see-six-or-seven-planets-skywatching-tips-from-nasa/articleshow/117304106.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:58:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rare planetary parade: Check dates and here's how you can see six or seven planets. Skywatching tips from NASA - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgJBVV95cUxNSGt5cms2bFpmcklleXJkVm9kbmpQc2RzdUlDVnFxZmMxZHRfQmFxZVZGTkZYNUZHQUg3TWdWX0R1N0tXaUVLaUxMQzY1TGVtR3pNYU9ySG1BcTFlZkkxOW4ybm01SnFBUk9lMnl0YjZjSi1TdHN1T19WM0xTb0VVenBMMG9nQ0tiTEZMSXVOSTRZVVVqR0dFUmpobUdGWEJQZ2laOTNLSUxQZlpKRy1OVWhZdWl4MlBnWVpQcDM2N3lya3BWcDJzeFVWSF9Jc2NDUWQ2WmwzRTFmVkVNdkUyQ1FJTmc0SnJSZ20wUklSWjdtaF9vazFkaHV4bENXdU54WmlVN05IY2lVQkF6YUROZkhLVnNWT0d0Q1ktSXFIQXlkZUxKb2VIbkhn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgJBVV95cUxNSGt5cms2bFpmcklleXJkVm9kbmpQc2RzdUlDVnFxZmMxZHRfQmFxZVZGTkZYNUZHQUg3TWdWX0R1N0tXaUVLaUxMQzY1TGVtR3pNYU9ySG1BcTFlZkkxOW4ybm01SnFBUk9lMnl0YjZjSi1TdHN1T19WM0xTb0VVenBMMG9nQ0tiTEZMSXVOSTRZVVVqR0dFUmpobUdGWEJQZ2laOTNLSUxQZlpKRy1OVWhZdWl4MlBnWVpQcDM2N3lya3BWcDJzeFVWSF9Jc2NDUWQ2WmwzRTFmVkVNdkUyQ1FJTmc0SnJSZ20wUklSWjdtaF9vazFkaHV4bENXdU54WmlVN05IY2lVQkF6YUROZkhLVnNWT0d0Q1ktSXFIQXlkZUxKb2VIbkhn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:58:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's stuck astronaut steps out on a spacewalk after 7 months in orbit - The Albertan]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Astronaut Suni Williams Completes Spacewalk After Seven Months in Orbit</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> March 21, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Associated Press</p><img src="https://apnews.com/media/image/84ae97630b3fa52536cc977903962a5c171d7f220c2923c517636c9135c72ea8.jpg" alt="Suni Williams evaluating her spacesuit"/><figcaption>In this photo provided by NASA, astronaut Suni Williams tries on and evaluates her spacesuit aboard the International Space Station on Jan. 9, 2025. (NASA via AP)</figcaption><p>NASA astronaut Suni Williams stepped out for her first spacewalk after being in orbit for more than seven months, assisting with overdue outdoor repairs on the International Space Station.</p><ul><li>Williams is the station's commander and completed her eighth spacewalk.</li><li>She performed the spacewalk alongside NASA's Nick Hague.</li><li>Williams and fellow astronaut Butch Wilmore are expected to float back out next week.</li><li>This spacewalk marks the first since an aborted attempt last summer due to a water leak issue.</li><li>NASA has resolved the cooling loop problem that caused the previous delay.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was the first spacewalk by NASA astronauts since an aborted one last summer.”</blockquote><p>This successful spacewalk signifies a positive step forward for NASA's ongoing operations and showcases the resilience of its astronauts during extended missions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thealbertan.com/world-news/nasas-stuck-astronaut-steps-out-on-a-spacewalk-after-7-months-in-orbit-10084096</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thealbertan.com/world-news/nasas-stuck-astronaut-steps-out-on-a-spacewalk-after-7-months-in-orbit-10084096</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:18:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronomers Discover Unusual X-Ray Oscillations From a Black Hole 100 Million Light-Years Away - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronomers Discover Unusual X-Ray Oscillations From a Black Hole 100 Million Light-Years Away</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> phys.org</p>
<p>A supermassive black hole located in a galaxy 100 million light-years away has been observed showing unusual X-ray oscillations, marking a significant discovery in the study of black holes.</p>
<ul>
<li>The frequency of X-ray flashes increased from 18 minutes to seven minutes over two years.</li>
<li>The black hole, named 1ES 1927+654, has drawn attention for its unique behavior.</li>
<li>Researchers from MIT suggest that the oscillations may originate from a compact white dwarf orbiting near the black hole's event horizon.</li>
<li>The white dwarf may shed material into the black hole, affecting its dynamics without crossing the event horizon.</li>
<li>Future observatories like NASA’s LISA could potentially detect the gravitational waves produced by this phenomenon.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Such proximity to a black hole without falling in has not been observed before.” - Megan Masterson</blockquote>
<p>Continued observations are anticipated to shed further light on the interactions between black holes and their surrounding celestial objects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://passionategeekz.com/astronomers-discover-unusual-x-ray-oscillations-from-a-black-hole-100-million-light-years-away/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://passionategeekz.com/astronomers-discover-unusual-x-ray-oscillations-from-a-black-hole-100-million-light-years-away/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:40:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronomers Discover Unusual X-Ray Oscillations From a Black Hole 100 Million Light-Years Away - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronomers Discover Unusual X-Ray Oscillations From a Black Hole</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/kOPLxpRVCX8/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video">
<figcaption>Video Explanation of the Discovery</figcaption>
<p>A supermassive black hole, located 100 million light-years away, has shown unusual behavior with increasing X-ray flash frequencies over two years.</p>
<ul>
<li>Frequency of X-ray flashes started at 18 minutes and accelerated to seven minutes.</li>
<li>The black hole 1ES 1927+654 may have a white dwarf in a precarious orbit.</li>
<li>Discovery presented at the 245th American Astronomical Society meeting.</li>
<li>Potential detection of gravitational waves from the white dwarf's orbit is anticipated.</li>
<li>Further observations planned to understand black hole dynamics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Megan Masterson: “Such proximity to a black hole without falling in has not been observed before.”</blockquote>
<p>This discovery offers new insights into black hole activity and the interactions with surrounding celestial bodies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/unusual-x-ray-oscillations-from-supermassive-black-hole-100-million-light-years-away-7470487</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/unusual-x-ray-oscillations-from-supermassive-black-hole-100-million-light-years-away-7470487</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[University of Warwick: Astronomers Discover Two New Planets, Challenging Theories of Planet Formation - India Education Diary]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indiaeducationdiary.in/university-of-warwick-astronomers-discover-two-new-planets-challenging-theories-of-planet-formation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiaeducationdiary.in/university-of-warwick-astronomers-discover-two-new-planets-challenging-theories-of-planet-formation/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:59:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists leverage AI to develop an opener for a molecular can - INDIAai]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPNnZpQmhuNWJRSXNmbERMN3pCSHNjanZJc0lrcUxPZjdfcDVnMEdQYUhTY19FZHBOcVJVSGlZb29NQ3R3enk0VTFzT2tjc0NiLThWT1AzdHo3NjQ1c25paWVlX0FxeGpFQ2t2eU5FTjRQclBhNDc5MXNiVjZHU2RDOF9qaXVDbkw3TnNfN0owUnFuYnhVdm83ZGJn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPNnZpQmhuNWJRSXNmbERMN3pCSHNjanZJc0lrcUxPZjdfcDVnMEdQYUhTY19FZHBOcVJVSGlZb29NQ3R3enk0VTFzT2tjc0NiLThWT1AzdHo3NjQ1c25paWVlX0FxeGpFQ2t2eU5FTjRQclBhNDc5MXNiVjZHU2RDOF9qaXVDbkw3TnNfN0owUnFuYnhVdm83ZGJn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:56:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A copper catalyst can efficiently convert carbon dioxide into acetaldehyde - Tech Explorist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Copper Catalyst Improves CO2 Conversion to Acetaldehyde</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 03 January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Nature Synthesis</p><p>The article discusses a novel copper-based catalyst that efficiently converts carbon dioxide (CO2) into acetaldehyde, presenting a promising alternative to traditional manufacturing processes. This breakthrough could significantly reduce greenhouse gas emissions while providing a critical industrial chemical.</p><ul><li>The copper catalyst achieves a remarkable 92% selectivity for acetaldehyde, outperforming existing methods.</li><li>This method addresses the limitations of the conventional Wacker process, relying on non-renewable resources and resulting in high carbon emissions.</li><li>The design utilized spark ablation to create small, precise copper clusters, enhancing efficiency and stability.</li><li>The catalyst maintains its performance over extended periods, showcasing its potential for industrial applications.</li><li>Ongoing research could lead to broader applications, transforming chemical production.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Wacker process has remained largely unchanged for the past 60 years. It was time for a green breakthrough,” said Koolen.</blockquote><p>The development of this copper catalyst represents a significant advancement in sustainable chemistry, paving the way for greener industrial practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techexplorist.com/copper-catalyst-efficiently-convert-carbon-dioxide-acetaldehyde/96127/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techexplorist.com/copper-catalyst-efficiently-convert-carbon-dioxide-acetaldehyde/96127/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:25:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new continent and ocean? Earth’s mantle is splitting apart faster than we thought - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxQaG9sc1NuN3BWZlhrLUlMVWlPUkNRSXNKS01tS0d6UWV2NzduWTdTVlFDeFE4TkZSUGl0VjVHcFlhZnRoQ05RWWlLX0NHd25NSGpWTGdyMzZSTnk4YVpyWWtSSlFBejNkRlhLbmhMRFdYcDVpaFNVVTBEOWNBNUx5Vm1PR1dPQ2tzV29CRVJuMXIzTi1KWGo2U3FoT0FMdjF1a0Q1LUF0UTRqeHhCQ21UWkdfem5WWnpwWlhZVDdvd2JaR2NKc1NVaUd5OEpSSkN6ZlpRbUU3RVcxYXZH0gHcAUFVX3lxTFBob2xzU243cFZmWGstSUxVaU9SQ1FJc0pLTW1LR3pRZXY3N25ZN1NWUUN4UThORlJQaXRWNUdwWWFmdGhDTlFZaUtfQ0d3bk1IalZMZ3IzNlJOeThhWnJZa1JKUUF6M2RGWEtuaExEV1hwNWloU1VVMEQ5Y0E1THlWbU9HV09Da3NXb0JFUm4xcjNOLUpYajZTcWhPQUx2MXVrRDUtQXRRNGp4eEJDbVRaR196blZaenBaWFlUN293YlpHY0pzU1VpR3k4SlJKQ3pmWlFtRTdFVzFhdkc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxQaG9sc1NuN3BWZlhrLUlMVWlPUkNRSXNKS01tS0d6UWV2NzduWTdTVlFDeFE4TkZSUGl0VjVHcFlhZnRoQ05RWWlLX0NHd25NSGpWTGdyMzZSTnk4YVpyWWtSSlFBejNkRlhLbmhMRFdYcDVpaFNVVTBEOWNBNUx5Vm1PR1dPQ2tzV29CRVJuMXIzTi1KWGo2U3FoT0FMdjF1a0Q1LUF0UTRqeHhCQ21UWkdfem5WWnpwWlhZVDdvd2JaR2NKc1NVaUd5OEpSSkN6ZlpRbUU3RVcxYXZH0gHcAUFVX3lxTFBob2xzU243cFZmWGstSUxVaU9SQ1FJc0pLTW1LR3pRZXY3N25ZN1NWUUN4UThORlJQaXRWNUdwWWFmdGhDTlFZaUtfQ0d3bk1IalZMZ3IzNlJOeThhWnJZa1JKUUF6M2RGWEtuaExEV1hwNWloU1VVMEQ5Y0E1THlWbU9HV09Da3NXb0JFUm4xcjNOLUpYajZTcWhPQUx2MXVrRDUtQXRRNGp4eEJDbVRaR196blZaenBaWFlUN293YlpHY0pzU1VpR3k4SlJKQ3pmWlFtRTdFVzFhdkc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:13:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Shares Photo Of Bird Staring At Camera; Netizens Wonder Whether Space Agency's Instagram Is Hacked - Here's The Truth Behind Viral Post - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Shares Photo Of Bird Staring At Camera; Netizens Wonder Whether Space Agency's Instagram Is Hacked</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 16, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><img src="https://media.assettype.com/freepressjournal/2025-01-16/6e04y6ff/Swarna-2025-01-16T152538.601.jpg" alt="Sandhill Crane" loading="lazy"><figcaption>A stunning close-up of a sandhill crane near the Kennedy Space Center.</figcaption><p>The recent Instagram post by NASA featured a close-up of a sandhill crane, leading many to speculate if their account had been hacked. However, the post emphasizes the diverse wildlife found at the Kennedy Space Center.</p><ul><li>The post displayed a photo of a redheaded sandhill crane with its large brown eyes.</li><li>This was part of NASA's effort to highlight the wildlife at its facilities.</li><li>Followers were initially confused by the non-space related image.</li><li>The caption clarified the bird is one of 1,500 species residing at Kennedy Space Center.</li><li>No evidence of a cybersecurity breach was found.</li></ul><blockquote>“This sandhill crane is one of the 1,500 different species of plants and animals that make their home at NASA's Kennedy Space Center.”</blockquote><p>This incident highlights NASA's commitment to environmental awareness while engaging with their audience in a creative way.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/viral/nasa-shares-photo-of-bird-staring-at-camera-netizens-wonder-whether-space-agencys-instagram-is-hacked-heres-the-truth-behind-viral-post</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/viral/nasa-shares-photo-of-bird-staring-at-camera-netizens-wonder-whether-space-agencys-instagram-is-hacked-heres-the-truth-behind-viral-post</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:00:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last starlight for ground-breaking Gaia - European Space Agency]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxPdjg2S0hBaWxjY1pIRFF2d2VaM3RQWGI3eWt6ZkN0dkJoMHRoTFFpbElnQUNfa2Z3Zlo5dXFLTjZiSWV2UWlOUWxpTVRsTGEza2dnQVRUTVYtOEotZjRGV09xTU1Ic1VRVmhZSHA4NWNUa1JVUUgxNWRpek9kVDZ2UFFRb0RRY1dQenhtelVHRWZrMWREdVF2eXRIR3lCY0U?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxPdjg2S0hBaWxjY1pIRFF2d2VaM3RQWGI3eWt6ZkN0dkJoMHRoTFFpbElnQUNfa2Z3Zlo5dXFLTjZiSWV2UWlOUWxpTVRsTGEza2dnQVRUTVYtOEotZjRGV09xTU1Ic1VRVmhZSHA4NWNUa1JVUUgxNWRpek9kVDZ2UFFRb0RRY1dQenhtelVHRWZrMWREdVF2eXRIR3lCY0U?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 09:55:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supermassive black hole equal to 700 million suns' mass spotted firing a giant beam at Earth - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxOUkJieDhaM3M2alBGYUtpMnJsVFI4MlZHZTZ3dTVnSTVvdXd6cHhuVzlvNVFyNTNHenNyS3A5RzI1Qll5THo2cDcwQ1g1NkQyZE1EME5rVjhicDllUUJxQVU2U0RMLUNSUzFhVE1WT0ktMEtpYWN3RTNGTWpyS29ZVEhaaUNPNUEwNkdHcHpaYTN5RDhLdGZaSFhKOVhPb1ZFNXFJU0JJR3E1dHRLbW9WUmQ1UU5fcG5fZXRKSjM2VUtJWnZQay1UYjZ2NXZwcGgxWHJlVFdkTWk3RTJraXgxLTU5ZFLSAeoBQVVfeXFMTVFFUjM2WnZhcF9DVncwazlVcnNtaGVLcnl2U3pHUmoyMUFxYVdFYl9zck9ram9GNnlQZllvakFYLU14V0oxd1BFRnVQWkwxXzBVakk3V25HWlB4aWxPamZxSnEyNUdjSU5CaWoxRjA3RXc2dXh4aHBCT1d6SVF2QllaVlh4dmxsOE52MWoxLTd5YUxVSFVwQzBoelVzTXhOemNNdU9uZnU4OTBHbkg2am5od2xhMi1DWjdCMWZzZDlHREVFZFhvUEx5bDdxQ0cxa25kS2VmdjJtWDQ0cVlmQ0tfUExUVEkwNmt3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxOUkJieDhaM3M2alBGYUtpMnJsVFI4MlZHZTZ3dTVnSTVvdXd6cHhuVzlvNVFyNTNHenNyS3A5RzI1Qll5THo2cDcwQ1g1NkQyZE1EME5rVjhicDllUUJxQVU2U0RMLUNSUzFhVE1WT0ktMEtpYWN3RTNGTWpyS29ZVEhaaUNPNUEwNkdHcHpaYTN5RDhLdGZaSFhKOVhPb1ZFNXFJU0JJR3E1dHRLbW9WUmQ1UU5fcG5fZXRKSjM2VUtJWnZQay1UYjZ2NXZwcGgxWHJlVFdkTWk3RTJraXgxLTU5ZFLSAeoBQVVfeXFMTVFFUjM2WnZhcF9DVncwazlVcnNtaGVLcnl2U3pHUmoyMUFxYVdFYl9zck9ram9GNnlQZllvakFYLU14V0oxd1BFRnVQWkwxXzBVakk3V25HWlB4aWxPamZxSnEyNUdjSU5CaWoxRjA3RXc2dXh4aHBCT1d6SVF2QllaVlh4dmxsOE52MWoxLTd5YUxVSFVwQzBoelVzTXhOemNNdU9uZnU4OTBHbkg2am5od2xhMi1DWjdCMWZzZDlHREVFZFhvUEx5bDdxQ0cxa25kS2VmdjJtWDQ0cVlmQ0tfUExUVEkwNmt3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 09:40:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mars Satellite Images Reveal Giant 'Kidney Beans,' Sparking Hints of Water and Life - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mars Satellite Images Reveal Giant 'Kidney Beans,' Sparking Hints of Water and Life</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/kOPLxpRVCX8/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Video on Mars satellite images">
<figcaption>Video discussing the findings on Mars' surface features.</figcaption>
<p>Recent observations of frozen dunes on Mars suggest the potential presence of water and microbial life in the planet's past.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Frozen sand dunes observed by NASA's Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter are stationary due to carbon dioxide frost.</li>
  <li>Understanding these features can help scientists determine if Mars once had conditions suitable for liquid water.</li>
  <li>The Martian axial tilt may have supported a thicker atmosphere in the past, impacting its climate.</li>
  <li>Research on frost patterns aids in uncovering Mars' climatic history and possible habitability.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Studying these frost-covered dunes helps scientists assess whether liquid water was present on Mars for periods long enough to support life.”</blockquote>
<p>These findings deepen our understanding of Mars' climate evolution and its implications for astrobiology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/mars-satellite-images-reveal-giant-kidney-beans-sparking-hints-of-water-and-life-7470368</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/mars-satellite-images-reveal-giant-kidney-beans-sparking-hints-of-water-and-life-7470368</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 08:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian scientists develop wearable devices that can detect stress - indulgexpress]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxPM3JlWUs3MXBjcnNQOHFCQkFVa1JveFgxRjNaaDhYLVRzY0RvRnBHMTRTSzMwM1N1b3BPa3lfRFRiNHN4WF95TUhWU1dqanJicGJmaS1ra0VKZXVfWG82bUpHQ2tWcUxjdDFPWFJxNllBeDdrX05IcVBubGdUdndTbXNPREFReXBjWTdWVGhQTl82bVdlNF9tOTlvQ24zc0JrRTNSRUVLWGFqd2tZLUdLLWUwQjVHNGEzSDBNajhoVWlmMFpEM1NEeTNSTkjSAdoBQVVfeXFMUEdFZWM4NUg3di1xcVc3cWdOQ1E0eG53VkU4aEpOR2pKWmYyY1dTZ0RaQm9vcDVjQWRqakFRS2NRSEZ2YVhXQXhuNHlsWnBVbHlJelVCMjY2RU9PR2ZmX2x0UjBjNnBYNkhlMExfU0Ixbmt1VHRFVlR4R3FaSmNnTm9NOEFpWlI0bmhVTTMwNzQ1R3RSbEJ3c2pFcmZ0TjNHYVVPb0Qxa3hHUk1UTGJmTUc1V3JUMDNob3V5SmEyRzFpcmpybG1iREZyQ1BCcjVnd0E0TUpFZjQzY1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxPM3JlWUs3MXBjcnNQOHFCQkFVa1JveFgxRjNaaDhYLVRzY0RvRnBHMTRTSzMwM1N1b3BPa3lfRFRiNHN4WF95TUhWU1dqanJicGJmaS1ra0VKZXVfWG82bUpHQ2tWcUxjdDFPWFJxNllBeDdrX05IcVBubGdUdndTbXNPREFReXBjWTdWVGhQTl82bVdlNF9tOTlvQ24zc0JrRTNSRUVLWGFqd2tZLUdLLWUwQjVHNGEzSDBNajhoVWlmMFpEM1NEeTNSTkjSAdoBQVVfeXFMUEdFZWM4NUg3di1xcVc3cWdOQ1E0eG53VkU4aEpOR2pKWmYyY1dTZ0RaQm9vcDVjQWRqakFRS2NRSEZ2YVhXQXhuNHlsWnBVbHlJelVCMjY2RU9PR2ZmX2x0UjBjNnBYNkhlMExfU0Ixbmt1VHRFVlR4R3FaSmNnTm9NOEFpWlI0bmhVTTMwNzQ1R3RSbEJ3c2pFcmZ0TjNHYVVPb0Qxa3hHUk1UTGJmTUc1V3JUMDNob3V5SmEyRzFpcmpybG1iREZyQ1BCcjVnd0E0TUpFZjQzY1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 08:15:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA astronaut shares first image of comet G3 Atlas visible only once in 160,000 years - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Astronaut Shares First Image of Comet G3 Atlas Visible Only Once in 160,000 Years</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img decoding="async" src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250113065605_Sheetal-Kumari-fi.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Comet entering Earth's orbit. (Image: Canva)" title="Comet entering Earth's orbit. (Image: Canva)" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Comet entering Earth's orbit. (Image: Canva)</figcaption><p>Astronaut Don Pettit captured breathtaking footage of Comet ATLAS from the International Space Station as it made its closest approach to the Sun.</p><ul><li>The comet, officially named C/2024 G3, is 87 million miles away from Earth.</li><li>Pettit described seeing the comet from orbit as "totally amazing."</li><li>Experts predict Comet ATLAS to be the brightest comet of the year.</li></ul><blockquote>"It is totally amazing to see a comet from orbit. Atlas C2024-G3 is paying us a visit." - Don Pettit</blockquote><p>Comets are ancient remnants that form glowing tails as they approach the Sun, creating spectacular sights in the sky.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-astronaut-shares-first-image-of-comet-g3-atlas-visible-only-once-in-160-000-years-article-12912228.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-astronaut-shares-first-image-of-comet-g3-atlas-visible-only-once-in-160-000-years-article-12912228.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 08:08:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Chinese Academy of Sciences’ 2024 Outstanding Scientific and Technological Achievement Award was announced. Chen Liquan, the founder of my country’s lithium battery, won the Personal Achievement Award - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwJBVV95cUxPVVFKdC1JTnVWMkhlYjU3TU41cDRnNC1CZVRHZWVJbHpyelFXcFQwNEVUQTE1Zk1JS3prbkFjVGUxOXB6MWp0RFZkdW9vdkVkM2o4U1FOSU9WZlVoM0NEcDN3YU4yM2JiZm5reTR5MndNZzdycjRHY0o5UjlHLWZMNWd6T093RWVTVE5jdFo3R096YmlIanNybE5Wc0hkeTFoZG5ZOVc0blpPQmM1ai1nQzkzOHlGdWhsV2RqSHpYeXNWS1I3dU1pS09Wai1RSjhkM09heUlTQUd5djZZd1FYZmpPQklkc3luM1FRVEo4MEcwUE9ieUw4YU9QTkZmUjM0RGtZSER6ZUFQOVZvSVNMb1VhTXlSbm9qNFdrbDNjNmhRVXNVR3RsSk5URWVnR0pxbTJZeWVnSENtNXNON1JtTk1iMjQ2blU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwJBVV95cUxPVVFKdC1JTnVWMkhlYjU3TU41cDRnNC1CZVRHZWVJbHpyelFXcFQwNEVUQTE1Zk1JS3prbkFjVGUxOXB6MWp0RFZkdW9vdkVkM2o4U1FOSU9WZlVoM0NEcDN3YU4yM2JiZm5reTR5MndNZzdycjRHY0o5UjlHLWZMNWd6T093RWVTVE5jdFo3R096YmlIanNybE5Wc0hkeTFoZG5ZOVc0blpPQmM1ai1nQzkzOHlGdWhsV2RqSHpYeXNWS1I3dU1pS09Wai1RSjhkM09heUlTQUd5djZZd1FYZmpPQklkc3luM1FRVEo4MEcwUE9ieUw4YU9QTkZmUjM0RGtZSER6ZUFQOVZvSVNMb1VhTXlSbm9qNFdrbDNjNmhRVXNVR3RsSk5URWVnR0pxbTJZeWVnSENtNXNON1JtTk1iMjQ2blU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 07:48:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian scientists develop wearable devices that can detect stress - DTNEXT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dtnext.in/lifestyle/wellbeing/indian-scientists-develop-wearable-devices-that-can-detect-stress-819446</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dtnext.in/lifestyle/wellbeing/indian-scientists-develop-wearable-devices-that-can-detect-stress-819446</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:23:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA shares a stunning image of a Sandhill Crane with ‘large, brown eyes’; here’s what makes this bird sp - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Shares Stunning Image of a Sandhill Crane</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117288661,imgsize-11540,width-400,resizemode-4/117288661.jpg" alt="Stunning Sandhill Crane" title="Image source: Instagram" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>A Sandhill Crane with large brown eyes, photographed at NASA's Kennedy Space Center.</figcaption><p>NASA recently featured a striking image of a Sandhill Crane on their Instagram, showcasing the beauty of wildlife at their Kennedy Space Center.</p><ul><li>The Sandhill Crane is part of the diverse ecosystem at Kennedy Space Center.</li><li>The region includes the Merritt Island National Wildlife Refuge, known for its shallow freshwater environments.</li><li>NASA's post drew mixed reactions, with many praising the unexpected wildlife feature.</li><li>Sandhill Cranes are known for their resilience, thriving in wetlands.</li><li>The Kennedy Space Center serves as both a space hub and a wildlife refuge.</li></ul><blockquote>“A crane at NASA?” - One astonished social media user.</blockquote><p>This captivating glimpse into NASA's unique relationship with wildlife highlights the beauty of both technology and nature coexisting.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-shares-a-stunning-image-of-a-sandhill-crane-with-large-brown-eyes-heres-what-makes-this-bird-special/articleshow/117288601.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-shares-a-stunning-image-of-a-sandhill-crane-with-large-brown-eyes-heres-what-makes-this-bird-special/articleshow/117288601.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's James Webb Space Telescope Shows 3D Structure Of Dust And Gas Between Stars - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxNODFRTVRFbTRRVFJzbzdlbUE1TnJ6R2R0TGVpS1FpXzRtQ1NDU09UQVA2VE1qTFo1akFCNTAySG94eW9QVmUwT1NvS1h6OS1HUUFvUTliaHBYendnVGdwTzMyN201LXUyZXZUamdneDJHOWhBdU9iY0pYY25WTE83X3NOVFlKaDZ5LTlYTFpaeGtuTGhZMmRQMGxfVThVSmVKMm1xY3U4UXIyMmlqX2dndzVPcVQzY1d2VU1PTm1sVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxNODFRTVRFbTRRVFJzbzdlbUE1TnJ6R2R0TGVpS1FpXzRtQ1NDU09UQVA2VE1qTFo1akFCNTAySG94eW9QVmUwT1NvS1h6OS1HUUFvUTliaHBYendnVGdwTzMyN201LXUyZXZUamdneDJHOWhBdU9iY0pYY25WTE83X3NOVFlKaDZ5LTlYTFpaeGtuTGhZMmRQMGxfVThVSmVKMm1xY3U4UXIyMmlqX2dndzVPcVQzY1d2VU1PTm1sVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:12:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch 2 NASA astronauts repair X-ray telescope on ISS during a spacewalk today - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watch 2 NASA astronauts repair X-ray telescope on ISS during a spacewalk today</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/RYPk8fz_SbE/maxresdefault.jpg" alt="NASA astronauts during spacewalk" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>NASA astronauts during spacewalk</figcaption>
<p>Today, two NASA astronauts, Nick Hague and Suni Williams, will perform the first spacewalk of the year to repair the NICER X-ray telescope aboard the International Space Station (ISS).</p>
<ul>
  <li>The spacewalk is set to begin around 8:00 a.m. EST and last approximately 6.5 hours.</li>
  <li>NASA will stream the spacewalk live, starting at 6:30 a.m. EST.</li>
  <li>The astronauts will patch light leaks in the NICER telescope and prepare the Alpha Magnetic Spectrometer for upgrades.</li>
  <li>This marks the first on-orbit repair of a NASA space telescope since 2009.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The experienced spacewalking duo will also replace advanced engineering hardware to maintain station orientation and provide navigation data.”</blockquote>
<p>In May 2023, NICER developed light leaks that are now set to be fixed during this mission. This demonstrates the ongoing need for maintenance of scientific instruments in space.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/space-exploration/international-space-station/watch-2-nasa-astronauts-repair-x-ray-telescope-on-iss-during-a-spacewalk-today</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/space-exploration/international-space-station/watch-2-nasa-astronauts-repair-x-ray-telescope-on-iss-during-a-spacewalk-today</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 05:03:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA shares photo of a ‘large, brown-eyed’ sandhill crane. This bird is special because… - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Shares Stunning Photo of a Unique Sandhill Crane</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/Viral_NASA_Crane_Photo_Instagram_1736995781518_1736995791520.jpg' alt='NASA shared this image of a sandhill crane on Instagram. (Instagram/@nasa)' title='NASA shared this image of a sandhill crane on Instagram. (Instagram/@nasa)'><figcaption>NASA shared this image of a sandhill crane on Instagram. (Instagram/@nasa)</figcaption><p>The photo shared by NASA showcases a 'large, brown-eyed' sandhill crane, highlighting the beauty and diversity of wildlife at the Kennedy Space Center.</p><ul><li>The sandhill crane is among 1,500 species that inhabit NASA's Kennedy Space Center.</li><li>Known for preferring freshwater habitats, sandhill cranes are omnivorous and can grow up to 6 feet in height.</li><li>The photo captures the crane's large eyes, grey neck, and the Vehicle Assembly Building of NASA in the background.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Space Coast is a particularly favorable environment for sandhill cranes due to the region's shallow freshwater habitats.”</blockquote><p>This post reflects the public's fascination with both wildlife and NASA, encouraging a dialogue about conservation and appreciation for nature.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/nasa-shares-photo-of-a-large-brown-eyed-sandhill-crane-this-bird-is-special-because-101736995669502.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/nasa-shares-photo-of-a-large-brown-eyed-sandhill-crane-this-bird-is-special-because-101736995669502.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 03:01:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India develops new system for wearable devices that can detect stress - Medical Buyer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxNSTRwd2pyWWJBamxpNXdYdDlRWmFLRFoxcklRLU5GYldLU2NfTHZYdXRuOFJLMl9NOU5iWk56S29KNDlLWGo3TGpMR3FudjJjZkdPSVFqUXZJc1U1SnV2d21kN3djdkN2ZHM2UFF1TTlxck0zTVliZnphcVQzeXYtc2Y0Ry1xYlhyYnNGR2ZfMHFkUUY2Nk5uMkl6MmtBZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxNSTRwd2pyWWJBamxpNXdYdDlRWmFLRFoxcklRLU5GYldLU2NfTHZYdXRuOFJLMl9NOU5iWk56S29KNDlLWGo3TGpMR3FudjJjZkdPSVFqUXZJc1U1SnV2d21kN3djdkN2ZHM2UFF1TTlxck0zTVliZnphcVQzeXYtc2Y0Ry1xYlhyYnNGR2ZfMHFkUUY2Nk5uMkl6MmtBZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 02:11:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two private lunar landers head toward the moon in roundabout journey - Daily Excelsior]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxNMF85cTVTTzV6dXAyOFlLQ3g4LTkwVmJCVzZ1T1ludE1QMVpHSjdPSWVveGU2bXRPUjI1UkJfOVFwdEJlcXhuejVreVpfVktBNV9lSUdEWHhsUHJpNEc5ZkRzb3VWSDdaZkVHOGJiaUJzTTE5VEF2dTduOUxRUTdYVUVLRWpZdndWVFhNWWhEVXlCOU84SWtQRll0bWY2TVhYMVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxNMF85cTVTTzV6dXAyOFlLQ3g4LTkwVmJCVzZ1T1ludE1QMVpHSjdPSWVveGU2bXRPUjI1UkJfOVFwdEJlcXhuejVreVpfVktBNV9lSUdEWHhsUHJpNEc5ZkRzb3VWSDdaZkVHOGJiaUJzTTE5VEF2dTduOUxRUTdYVUVLRWpZdndWVFhNWWhEVXlCOU84SWtQRll0bWY2TVhYMVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:22:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JNCASR develops new system for wearable devices that can detect stress - BSI bureau]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxOLUFNeElON2FJUjRsMGk0R2RGMFpjT2xlNm1GTVNwaU1TUmhNTm0tN0VFNW95NmhBSWtZbzV0UjhHN256S3lhS0FucXpWcGFranlTRlhnbmpWQ1pzM1NIblZna1hza0dkbHJZcW8yYjhWVWxSVEcxbUZDUHYzVHVKMTcyZTRsMFh4ZVJxX05fU3JwMnVPV01mY2YyVVBINWptOXFUZHhQOWItMU1rdDBmQWgxV0JJMnA2S1FwbHlNUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxOLUFNeElON2FJUjRsMGk0R2RGMFpjT2xlNm1GTVNwaU1TUmhNTm0tN0VFNW95NmhBSWtZbzV0UjhHN256S3lhS0FucXpWcGFranlTRlhnbmpWQ1pzM1NIblZna1hza0dkbHJZcW8yYjhWVWxSVEcxbUZDUHYzVHVKMTcyZTRsMFh4ZVJxX05fU3JwMnVPV01mY2YyVVBINWptOXFUZHhQOWItMU1rdDBmQWgxV0JJMnA2S1FwbHlNUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:55:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>