<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:22:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:22:52 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 stunning image of star clusters captured by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Stunning Images of Star Clusters Captured by NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Star-Cluster-6.jpg" alt="Star Cluster 6" width="1280" height="768">
<figcaption>Star Cluster 6 captured by NASA.</figcaption>
<p>NASA's Hubble Space Telescope has captured breathtaking images of various star clusters, showcasing the beauty and complexity of these celestial formations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>NASA captured two massive star clusters in 30 Doradus, believed to be merging.</li>
  <li>NGC 1850, a 100-million-year-old globular cluster, resides in the Large Magellanic Cloud.</li>
  <li>Star cluster Liller 1 is 30,000 light-years away and began forming stars over 11 billion years ago.</li>
  <li>The open cluster Trumpler 14, located 8,000 light-years away, contains some of the galaxy's most massive stars.</li>
  <li>Terzan 4, a globular cluster, features hot blue stars at the center and cooler red stars on the edges.</li>
  <li>Caldwell 71 is noted for its loosely bound arrangement of stars.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Thanks For Reading!”</blockquote>
<p>This collection of images illustrates the wonders of star formation and the ongoing research to understand our universe better.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-stunning-image-of-star-clusters-captured-by-nasa-7505954/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-stunning-image-of-star-clusters-captured-by-nasa-7505954/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 02:50:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space Billionaires Count Down To Their Rocket Race To The Moon - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPZE1EaGZNTUhCcmd4Ni1NM3RiUnFzZW1kZVhCOTNOa3hHRk0xbUFsSExvY3VfRzlyU3pzYkpKM1AwRWFxSGVGeXZWMzZRbXJIQUVGY2N4MC12YUJKdktMclpSaTZtVlhUWThUeE01QlFQeFZkYk5OdkJOTmtzUVozN3doU1puUS1CcldnWWFKRUVJUW9EQXNWRWhQNkUyTGdNV2FZcWNoTjlwSFFKRHp2OGtLODhPTnl5V3U0Uw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPZE1EaGZNTUhCcmd4Ni1NM3RiUnFzZW1kZVhCOTNOa3hHRk0xbUFsSExvY3VfRzlyU3pzYkpKM1AwRWFxSGVGeXZWMzZRbXJIQUVGY2N4MC12YUJKdktMclpSaTZtVlhUWThUeE01QlFQeFZkYk5OdkJOTmtzUVozN3doU1puUS1CcldnWWFKRUVJUW9EQXNWRWhQNkUyTGdNV2FZcWNoTjlwSFFKRHp2OGtLODhPTnl5V3U0Uw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 02:22:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to catch the Quadrantids, the first meteor shower of 2025 - CGTN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How to Catch the Quadrantids, the First Meteor Shower of 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>January 2025</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>N/A</p><p>The Quadrantid meteor shower will peak on Friday, offering a chance to see fireballs in the sky as it marks the first meteor shower of the year. Good visibility is expected under clear, dark conditions enhanced by a waning crescent moon.</p><ul><li>The Quadrantids can produce up to 120 meteors per hour at their peak.</li><li>The meteors originate from the asteroid 2003 EH1, and they appear as bright fireballs rather than long trails.</li><li>Ideal viewing conditions include dark skies away from city lights, particularly in the early predawn hours.</li><li>The Quadrantid shower lasts until January 16 and is followed by the Lyrids meteor shower peaking in mid-April.</li></ul><blockquote>“They take their name from a constellation that doesn't exist anymore,” said NASA's William Cooke.</blockquote><p>To maximize your viewing experience, choose a night when the moon is low and the sky is clear.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.cgtn.com/news/2025-01-01/How-to-catch-the-Quadrantids-the-first-meteor-shower-of-2025-1zNHopMeK5y/p.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.cgtn.com/news/2025-01-01/How-to-catch-the-Quadrantids-the-first-meteor-shower-of-2025-1zNHopMeK5y/p.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 02:14:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 colourful images of star clusters captured by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Colourful Images of Star Clusters Captured by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 1, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/FotoJet-2025-01-01T062620.886.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=400&amp;h=800" alt="Hubble Space Telescope Image" />
<figcaption>Main image from the article highlighting star clusters.</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases vibrant images of star clusters taken by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope, revealing the beauty and complexity of these distant celestial formations.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Hubble Space Telescope captures stunning images of various star clusters.</li>
<li>Notable clusters featured include NGC 2210, Terzan 12, NGC 6652, NGC 6355, NGC 376, NGC 6440, and NGC 1850.</li>
<li>These clusters are located in the Milky Way and the Large Magellanic Cloud.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"These stars comprise the open cluster NGC 376, which has a total mass only about 3,400 times that of the Sun."</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the piece highlights the remarkable capabilities of the Hubble Space Telescope in capturing the vivid and dynamic nature of star clusters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-colourful-images-of-star-clusters-captured-by-nasas-hubble-space-telescope-7505925/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-colourful-images-of-star-clusters-captured-by-nasas-hubble-space-telescope-7505925/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 01:20:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX’s 2024 rocket launches concluded: 134 completed, a year-on-year increase of 39.6% - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxNUklyZWVBaVBweHVvUWU1aW90dGt2TTdCRGl2RGZCcHYwbWQ4alhnc3J2YUQ5alZYVGJHd0dnMVpfV2JZUkFKY1NvSUNZSWg2bFFHcHZoMW5oZU9LWVFVbU45OEpTSnFOZjBId29FdFRrVDZzNjNjOXg2a1ZLTS11UFB2aVIwVTc0UVJ4bkEzSUdWckJpUFFvMmR1SEFQeDkwS3hFZGo1anlnTmpzNVoyQnJUVdIBswFBVV95cUxNUklyZWVBaVBweHVvUWU1aW90dGt2TTdCRGl2RGZCcHYwbWQ4alhnc3J2YUQ5alZYVGJHd0dnMVpfV2JZUkFKY1NvSUNZSWg2bFFHcHZoMW5oZU9LWVFVbU45OEpTSnFOZjBId29FdFRrVDZzNjNjOXg2a1ZLTS11UFB2aVIwVTc0UVJ4bkEzSUdWckJpUFFvMmR1SEFQeDkwS3hFZGo1anlnTmpzNVoyQnJUVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxNUklyZWVBaVBweHVvUWU1aW90dGt2TTdCRGl2RGZCcHYwbWQ4alhnc3J2YUQ5alZYVGJHd0dnMVpfV2JZUkFKY1NvSUNZSWg2bFFHcHZoMW5oZU9LWVFVbU45OEpTSnFOZjBId29FdFRrVDZzNjNjOXg2a1ZLTS11UFB2aVIwVTc0UVJ4bkEzSUdWckJpUFFvMmR1SEFQeDkwS3hFZGo1anlnTmpzNVoyQnJUVdIBswFBVV95cUxNUklyZWVBaVBweHVvUWU1aW90dGt2TTdCRGl2RGZCcHYwbWQ4alhnc3J2YUQ5alZYVGJHd0dnMVpfV2JZUkFKY1NvSUNZSWg2bFFHcHZoMW5oZU9LWVFVbU45OEpTSnFOZjBId29FdFRrVDZzNjNjOXg2a1ZLTS11UFB2aVIwVTc0UVJ4bkEzSUdWckJpUFFvMmR1SEFQeDkwS3hFZGo1anlnTmpzNVoyQnJUVQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:40:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX 2024 launch stats: Starship, SLC-40 is king, and more - Space Explored]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaceX 2024 Launch Summary: Highlights and Future Projections</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> September 5, 2024 &bull; <strong>Source:</strong> Space Explored</p>
<figure>
<img width="1600" height="800" src="https://spaceexplored.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/10/2024/09/LA7C3208.jpg?quality=82&strip=all&w=1024" alt="Starship full stack sunset" />
<figcaption>Image: Seth Kurkowski / Space Explored</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>SpaceX launched its final mission of 2024, marking another successful year of space endeavors. The year saw significant achievements and set the stage for what’s to come in 2025.</p>
<ul>
<li>SpaceX executed four Starship test flights in 2024, doubling its performance from the previous year.</li>
<li>The SLC-40 launch pad in Florida became the leader in trip turnaround with 62 Falcon 9 launches.</li>
<li>SpaceX successfully landed 130 boosters, with 106 accomplished on droneships.</li>
<li>Approximately two-thirds of Falcon launches were dedicated to Starlink satellites.</li>
<li>Despite a perfect record prior, SpaceX faced mishaps with multiple grounding incidents of its Falcon 9 rockets.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"America’s reliance on SpaceX might be a bit too much," highlighting the implications of recent launch failures.</blockquote>
<p>Looking ahead, SpaceX is poised for a significant increase in launches with expectations of 25 Starship launches in 2025, which could lead to a launch nearly every other week. The company's commitment to innovation and scalability continues to reshape the landscape of space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://spaceexplored.com/2024/12/31/spacex-2024-launch-stats-starship-slc-40-is-king-and-more/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://spaceexplored.com/2024/12/31/spacex-2024-launch-stats-starship-slc-40-is-king-and-more/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A total eclipse of the Moon, Saturn’s rings ‘disappear’, meteors and more: your guide to the southern sky in 2025 - The Conversation Indonesia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://theconversation.com/a-total-eclipse-of-the-moon-saturns-rings-disappear-meteors-and-more-your-guide-to-the-southern-sky-in-2025-242601</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theconversation.com/a-total-eclipse-of-the-moon-saturns-rings-disappear-meteors-and-more-your-guide-to-the-southern-sky-in-2025-242601</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 21:47:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A total eclipse of the Moon, Saturn’s rings ‘disappear’, meteors and more: your guide to the southern sky in 2025 - The Conversation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://theconversation.com/a-total-eclipse-of-the-moon-saturns-rings-disappear-meteors-and-more-your-guide-to-the-southern-sky-in-2025-242601</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theconversation.com/a-total-eclipse-of-the-moon-saturns-rings-disappear-meteors-and-more-your-guide-to-the-southern-sky-in-2025-242601</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 21:47:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Greek scientists digitally reconstruct skull of 200,000-year-old dwarf hippopotamus - The Jerusalem Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Greek Scientists Digitally Reconstruct Skull of 200,000-Year-Old Dwarf Hippopotamus</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> DECEMBER 31, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Jerusalem Post</p>
<img src="https://images.jpost.com/image/upload/q_auto/c_fill,g_faces:center,h_537,w_822/641522" width="290" height="260" alt="Greek scientists digitally reconstruct skull of 200,000-year-old dwarf hippopotamus. (photo credit: Gerakakis and Makris 2024)" title="Greek scientists digitally reconstruct skull of 200,000-year-old dwarf hippopotamus.">
<figcaption>Greek scientists digitally reconstruct skull of 200,000-year-old dwarf hippopotamus. (photo credit: Gerakakis and Makris 2024)</figcaption>
<p>Researchers from the University of Western Attica have successfully reconstructed the skull of the extinct dwarf hippopotamus, Hippopotamus creutzburgi, using advanced 3D digital imaging techniques. This significant study offers new insights into the species' anatomy and evolution.</p>
<ul>
<li>The skull reconstruction is the first complete model of the species.</li>
<li>Four poorly preserved fossil remains from Crete were used for the digital reconstruction.</li>
<li>Innovative techniques including the retrodeformation methodology were employed.</li>
<li>The study indicates the morphological similarities with other hippopotamus species.</li>
<li>Hippopotamus creutzburgi lived more than 200,000 years ago on Crete before going extinct.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The skull and the flattened lower jaw posed challenges due to their severe distortion, which required innovative digital techniques for reconstruction." - Nikolaos Gerakakis</blockquote>
<p>This groundbreaking research illuminates the evolutionary adaptations of dwarf hippopotamuses and their historical context within the Pleistocene epoch, with ongoing studies aimed at revealing the reasons for their extinction.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jpost.com/archaeology/archaeology-around-the-world/article-835545</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jpost.com/archaeology/archaeology-around-the-world/article-835545</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:50:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starlink launch concludes record-breaking 2024 - NASASpaceflight.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Starlink Launch Concludes Record-Breaking 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024-12-31 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASASpaceFlight.com</p>
<div>
  <img src="https://www.nasaspaceflight.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/vulcan2-scaled.jpg" alt="Vulcan on its launch pad ahead of the Cert-2 mission." />
  <figcaption>Vulcan on its launch pad ahead of the Cert-2 mission. (Credit: Max Evans for NSF)</figcaption>
</div>
<p>With SpaceX’s successful launch of the Starlink Group 12-6 mission on Tuesday, a record 259 orbital launches were completed in 2024, underscoring the continuing trend in global space activity.</p>
<ul>
  <li>2024 saw the retirement of ULA’s Delta IV and the original Vega rocket, alongside the first flights of Ariane 6, Vulcan, and Chang Zheng 12.</li>
  <li>Five launches failed to reach orbit, amidst a dramatic increase in total launches compared to previous years.</li>
  <li>Nine crewed orbital missions occurred, including significant operations by SpaceX’s Dragon and Boeing’s Starliner, which faced challenges.</li>
  <li>Noteworthy lunar missions included JAXA's successful SLIM landing and China's Chang'e-6 sample return.</li>
  <li>The year marked a high for U.S. launches, leading the globe with 154 rocket liftoffs, with SpaceX spearheading the efforts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"SpaceX’s launch cadence shows no sign of abating and 2025 is likely to be even busier than 2024." — NASASpaceFlight.com</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the 2024 space launch activities highlighted significant advancements and challenges in space exploration, setting the stage for even more ambitious missions in the coming years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nasaspaceflight.com/2024/12/record-breaking-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nasaspaceflight.com/2024/12/record-breaking-2024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:39:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's micro-mission Lunar Trailblazer will make macro-measurements of the lunar surface in 2025 - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Lunar Trailblazer: A Micro-Mission for Macro Measurements in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Conversation</p><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2024/nasas-micro-mission-lu-1.jpg" alt="NASA's micro-mission Lunar Trailblazer will make macro-measurements of the lunar surface in 2025"><figcaption>Missions like NASA’s TROPICS use a network of small satellites to take more data than one satellite would be able to do alone. Credit: NASA Applied Sciences</figcaption><p>Nasa's Lunar Trailblazer micro-mission is set to be launched alongside the PRIME-1 lunar lander in January 2025. This mission aims to explore the lunar south pole for resources and enhance understanding of water on the lunar surface.</p><ul><li>Lunar Trailblazer will provide insights into water formation and behavior on rocky celestial bodies.</li><li>The mission features two scientific instruments: the Lunar Thermal Mapper and the High-resolution Volatiles and Minerals Moon Mapper.</li><li>The mission is part of NASA’s Small, Innovative Mission for Planetary Exploration (SIMPLEx) program.</li><li>Despite being slightly over budget at $80 million, the mission is still considered cost-effective compared to traditional missions.</li><li>It will provide valuable measurements about lunar water across various conditions on the lunar surface.</li></ul><blockquote>“Lunar Trailblazer may shed light on these theories and help researchers make progress on several other big science questions.”</blockquote><p>This mission could significantly contribute to our understanding of the moon and its resources, which may aid future human exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-12-nasa-micro-mission-lunar-trailblazer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2024-12-nasa-micro-mission-lunar-trailblazer.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 19:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Northern Lights On New Year’s Eve? - The Weather Channel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Northern Lights On New Year’s Eve?</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>December 31, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source: </strong>Weather News</p>
<img src="https://s.w-x.co/NLNYE1.jpg?crop=16:9&amp;width=320&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;quality=60" alt="Northern Lights" />
<figcaption>Image depicting the northern lights.</figcaption>
<p>A geomagnetic storm could make the northern lights visible in the U.S. on New Year’s Eve. This phenomenon will allow several states to witness a spectacular light show.</p>
<ul>
  <li>A geomagnetic storm is expected on New Year’s Eve.</li>
  <li>The northern lights might be visible in parts of the U.S.</li>
  <li>The best states to view the aurora borealis will be outlined in the report.</li>
  <li>Increased frequency of the northern lights is being observed due to recent geomagnetic activity.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Watch this video to see which states could be in for the light show, the best way to see the aurora borealis.”</blockquote>
<p>This event offers a rare opportunity to witness the northern lights in the U.S., particularly on a festive night like New Year’s Eve.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://weather.com/science/space/video/northern-lights-aurora-borealis-on-new-years-eve-united-states</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://weather.com/science/space/video/northern-lights-aurora-borealis-on-new-years-eve-united-states</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 18:42:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earth's space debris problem is getting so bad it's jeopardizing the internet and astronaut missions - Earth.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Earth's Space Debris Crisis Threatening Internet and Astronaut Missions</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 19 | <strong>Source:</strong> US Space Command</p><p>Recent fragmentation of the Intelsat 33e satellite into about 20 pieces has highlighted growing concerns about the increasing volume of space debris in Low Earth Orbit (LEO) and the potential risk of Kessler Syndrome.</p><ul><li>The Intelsat 33e satellite broke into multiple pieces, adding to the existing space junk crisis.</li><li>Kessler Syndrome could disrupt vital satellite services, including GPS and internet communications.</li><li>The European Space Agency is working on initiatives like Clearsat-1 to mitigate space debris.</li><li>Over 10,000 active satellites are currently in orbit, with plans to launch even more, increasing collision risks.</li><li>Experts emphasize the need for international regulations to manage space traffic.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Kessler Syndrome is going to come true. If the probability of a collision is so great that we can’t put a satellite in space, then we’re in trouble.” — John L. Crassidis, space debris expert</blockquote><p>The crisis demands prompt action to manage and reduce space debris to protect future satellites and essential communications technologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.earth.com/news/space-debris-may-create-a-future-with-no-internet-or-astronaut-missions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.earth.com/news/space-debris-may-create-a-future-with-no-internet-or-astronaut-missions/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 18:03:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HIV Prevention Drug to New Super-Earth and more; unveiled in 2024 - Bizz Buzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Breakthrough Scientific Discoveries and Innovations in 2024</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Science Daily</p><p>As 2024 draws to a close, this year has seen remarkable advancements across various fields, from medicine to space exploration.</p><ul><li><b>HIV Prevention Drug - Lenacapavir:</b> Achieved a 96% success rate in trials, administered semi-annually.</li><li><b>Fruit Fly Brain Mapping:</b> A map of 140,000 neurons released, enhancing neuroscience insights.</li><li><b>New Super-Earth Discovery:</b> TOI-715 b found in a habitable zone, potential for liquid water.</li><li><b>Neanderthal-Human Interbreeding:</b> Studies indicate interbreeding lasted 7,000 years.</li><li><b>CRISPR Advancements:</b> New tools improving the safety and precision of gene-editing.</li><li><b>Oldest Known Reptile Skin Fossil:</b> 20 million-year-old fossil uncovered, providing evolutionary insights.</li><li><b>New Moons of Neptune and Uranus:</b> Three new moons discovered, totaling 30.</li><li><b>Cave Art in Patagonia:</b> 900 ancient cave paintings uncovered, revealing prehistoric cultures.</li><li><b>DermaSensor for Skin Cancer Detection:</b> A light-based device reducing missed skin cancer diagnoses by half.</li><li><b>AI Model for Alzheimer's Prediction:</b> A model predicting Alzheimer's progression with 78.5% accuracy.</li><li><b>Deep-Sea Rocks Generate Oxygen:</b> Polymetallic nodules discovered to produce oxygen through electrolysis.</li><li><b>Space Cloud's Impact on Earth's Climate:</b> Research reveals a past cosmic event affecting Earth's climate.</li></ul><p>Each of these innovations holds great promise for the future, straddling multiple domains of human knowledge.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bizzbuzz.news/technology/hiv-prevention-drug-to-new-super-earth-and-more-unveiled-in-2024-1347328</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bizzbuzz.news/technology/hiv-prevention-drug-to-new-super-earth-and-more-unveiled-in-2024-1347328</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 17:12:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Possibility of Northern Lights for New Year's Eve - Central Alberta Online]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Possibility of Northern Lights for New Year's Eve</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 31, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Central Alberta Online</p>
<p>Mother Nature could provide its own fireworks for New Year's Eve tonight as the U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration’s (NOAA) Space Weather Prediction Center has forecasted a strong possibility for aurora borealis over much of the country.</p>
<ul>
<li>The geomagnetic activity forecast for Dec. 31 is a five on the scale that runs from one to nine.</li>
<li>Aurora displays in Alberta have been captivating the public this year.</li>
<li>Prominent displays occurred on May 10-11 and October 10-11, described as 'top-10-ever-in-your-lifetime kind of shows.'</li>
<li>Solar activity and storms derived from sunspots have heightened the intensity of auroras.</li>
<li>Citizen scientists have contributed significantly to understanding auroras, enhancing scientific observation with technology.</li>
<li>Safety and etiquette for aurora chasing are emphasized, including dressing appropriately and planning routes.</li>
<li>2025 is expected to provide further opportunities to witness the northern lights as Solar Cycle 25 continues.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Dress for the weather, have the right vehicle, and tell someone where you’re going," said Roland Dechesne.</blockquote>
<p>As 2024 draws to a close, the stunning auroras have left a lasting impression, reminding us of the natural beauty of the night sky.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://centralalbertaonline.com/articles/possibility-of-northern-lights-for-new-years-eve</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://centralalbertaonline.com/articles/possibility-of-northern-lights-for-new-years-eve</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:16:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space debris may create a future with no internet or astronaut missions - Earth.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Earth's Space Debris Crisis Threatening Internet and Astronaut Missions</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 19 | <strong>Source:</strong> US Space Command</p><p>Recent fragmentation of the Intelsat 33e satellite into about 20 pieces has highlighted growing concerns about the increasing volume of space debris in Low Earth Orbit (LEO) and the potential risk of Kessler Syndrome.</p><ul><li>The Intelsat 33e satellite broke into multiple pieces, adding to the existing space junk crisis.</li><li>Kessler Syndrome could disrupt vital satellite services, including GPS and internet communications.</li><li>The European Space Agency is working on initiatives like Clearsat-1 to mitigate space debris.</li><li>Over 10,000 active satellites are currently in orbit, with plans to launch even more, increasing collision risks.</li><li>Experts emphasize the need for international regulations to manage space traffic.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Kessler Syndrome is going to come true. If the probability of a collision is so great that we can’t put a satellite in space, then we’re in trouble.” — John L. Crassidis, space debris expert</blockquote><p>The crisis demands prompt action to manage and reduce space debris to protect future satellites and essential communications technologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.earth.com/news/space-debris-may-create-a-future-with-no-internet-or-astronaut-missions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.earth.com/news/space-debris-may-create-a-future-with-no-internet-or-astronaut-missions/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eclipses, meteor showers and more: The must-see skywatching events of 2025 - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Eclipses, meteor showers and more: The must-see skywatching events of 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan. 3, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/igznLywj84bnybuwBvCJqA.jpg" alt="photo of a lunar eclipse, showing most of the moon obscured in reddish-brown shadow">
<figcaption>The moon is seen during a total lunar eclipse, Tuesday, Nov. 8, 2022, at NASA’s Kennedy Space Center in Florida. (Image credit: NASA/Joel Kowsky)</figcaption>
<p>Another year of skywatching is upon us, and there's a lot to look forward to in 2025! This article outlines several noteworthy sky events, including meteor showers, lunar and solar eclipses, and planetary occultations.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jan. 3: Quadrantid meteor shower with up to 120 meteors per hour.</li>
<li>March 13-14: Total lunar eclipse favoring the Americas.</li>
<li>March 29: Partial solar eclipse visible from parts of Europe and Africa.</li>
<li>Nov. 5: Supermoon, the largest of the year.</li>
<li>Dec. 14: Geminid meteor shower with optimal viewing conditions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Joe Rao serves as an instructor and guest lecturer at New York's Hayden Planetarium.</blockquote>
<p>In summary, 2025 presents an array of celestial events worth observing, from meteor showers to eclipses—ideal for both seasoned astronomers and casual skywatchers alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/stargazing/eclipses-meteor-showers-and-more-the-must-see-skywatching-events-of-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/stargazing/eclipses-meteor-showers-and-more-the-must-see-skywatching-events-of-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jupiter’s Great Red Spot isn’t as permanent as we thought | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jupiter’s Great Red Spot isn’t as permanent as we thought</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>Jupiter’s Great Red Spot, a massive storm capable of engulfing Earth, is not as stable as previously believed. Recent research indicates that the storm's size continues to change over time.</p><ul><li>The Great Red Spot is observed to be larger than the one first documented by Giovanni Cassini in 1665.</li><li>New findings challenge the notion of its permanence, suggesting dynamic changes occur.</li><li>Continued observation of this atmospheric phenomenon is critical for understanding planetary storms.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/news/jupiters-great-red-spot-isn-t-as-permanent-as-we-thought-11735655888727.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/news/jupiters-great-red-spot-isn-t-as-permanent-as-we-thought-11735655888727.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 14:42:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space science in 2024: Moon missions, Martian milestones, astrophysics discoveries, and more - NASASpaceflight.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Space Science in 2024: Moon Missions, Martian Milestones, Astrophysics Discoveries, and More</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> NASASpaceFlight.com</p>
<img src="https://www.nasaspaceflight.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/The-Moons-umbra-seen-from-the-ISS-Credit-NASA-scaled.jpeg" alt="The Moon's shadow from the ISS" width="2560" height="1707" />
<figcaption>The Moon’s shadow, or umbra, is pictured covering portions of Canada and the U.S. from the ISS during the solar eclipse. (Credit: NASA)</figcaption>
<p>2024 was a transformative year in space science, marked by multiple successful missions and pivotal discoveries across the solar system. With new lunar endeavors and significant updates from Mars, as well as groundbreaking astrophysical research, the year showcased the dynamic field of space exploration.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Three new lunar missions were launched, although one was canceled; Curiosity and Perseverance continued exploring Mars.</li>
  <li>The Europa Clipper mission to Jupiter launched, aiming to study the moon Europa's potential for life.</li>
  <li>Extreme solar activity led to breathtaking auroras on Earth during two major solar eclipses in North America and South America.</li>
  <li>The Hubble and James Webb Space Telescopes made significant discoveries in exoplanet atmospheres and cosmic events.</li>
  <li>NASA's Parker Solar Probe and Voyager spacecraft continued to send valuable data from their respective journeys.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The significant progress made in 2024 emphasizes our unyielding commitment to exploring and understanding our universe.” - NASASpaceFlight.com</blockquote>
<p>2024 highlighted the importance of international collaboration and technological innovation in achieving monumental space exploration goals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nasaspaceflight.com/2024/12/2024-science-roundup/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nasaspaceflight.com/2024/12/2024-science-roundup/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 14:14:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Planet parade' in January: Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, Mars to align - NewsBytes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Planet parade' in January: Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, Mars to align</h1><p><strong>Published on January 1, 2024 by NewsBytes</strong></p><img alt="'Planet parade' in January: Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, Mars to align" title="'Planet parade' in January: Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, Mars to align" src="https://i.cdn.newsbytesapp.com/images/1422981735649357.jpg"><figcaption>Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars will be visible in January</figcaption><p>The new year will kick-start with a spectacular celestial event where four planets—Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars—will be clearly visible shortly after sunset. This planetary alignment offers a rare opportunity to witness multiple planets together, an event often referred to as a 'planet parade.'</p><ul><li>Venus and Saturn will closely align on January 17 and 18.</li><li>Mars reaches opposition on January 15-16, shining brightly in the constellation Gemini.</li><li>Jupiter will be high in the overhead sky, while Venus and Saturn will be positioned in the southwest.</li><li>Uranus and Neptune are also present but require telescopes to be viewed.</li></ul><blockquote>"The sight of four bright planets together is sure to mesmerize both amateur astronomers and casual observers."</blockquote><p>This unique planetary alignment marks a significant event for skywatchers, making this an ideal time for viewing and potential spacecraft missions to Mars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/science/four-planets-align-what-to-expect-during-january-s-planetary-parade/story</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/science/four-planets-align-what-to-expect-during-january-s-planetary-parade/story</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 13:04:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space time of 2024: Top exploration milestones of the year - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Space Time of 2024: Top Exploration Milestones of the Year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: December 30, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Times of India</strong></p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116831909,imgsize-1845426,width-400,resizemode-4/116831909.jpg" alt="Space time of 2024: Top exploration milestones of the year"><figcaption>Space time of 2024: Top exploration milestones of the year</figcaption><p>The year 2024 proved to be an outstanding time in the realm of space exploration, with several agencies achieving remarkable milestones that captivated the world.</p><ul><li>Nasa's Perseverance rover discovered an organic molecule on Mars, hinting at ancient life.</li><li>SpaceX's Polaris dawn mission marked the first civilian spacewalk.</li><li>India launched its first solar observatory mission, Aditya-L1, which began detailed solar observations.</li><li>China's Chang'e 6 successfully retrieved soil samples from the far side of the Moon.</li><li>The Parker solar probe made a historic dive closer to the sun than any other spacecraft.</li><li>ISRO successfully launched two small satellites as part of the Space Docking Experiment.</li></ul><blockquote>“These achievements also reflected the increasing significance of international alliances and commercial initiatives driving the future of space exploration.”</blockquote><p>The achievements of 2024 have paved the way for more ambitious missions in 2025, continuing humanity's quest to explore the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/space-time-of-2024-top-exploration-milestones-of-the-year/articleshow/116831899.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/space-time-of-2024-top-exploration-milestones-of-the-year/articleshow/116831899.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thorium film can replace crystals in atomic clocks - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Thorium film can replace crystals in atomic clocks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Science News</p><img src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Thorium-Target.jpg?w=802&amp;enlarge=true" alt="The darker circle is a thin thorium film target." title="Thorium Target"><figcaption>The darker circle is a thin thorium film target. (Image Credit: Ye Labs, JILA, NIST and University of Colorado).</figcaption><p>Scientists have developed a new method that reduces the amount of thorium required for atomic clocks, paving the way for more precise measurements of time and gravity.</p><ul><li>The advancement allows for the same precision in atomic clock measurements with less radioactive thorium.</li><li>Thorium-229 film is nearly as radioactive as a banana and is cheaper and easier to produce.</li><li>The research was able to achieve excitation of the atomic nucleus using a laser, something that had been attempted for 50 years.</li><li>This could lead to revolutionary measurements in quantum physics and changes in our understanding of fundamental physics.</li></ul><blockquote>“A key advantage to using a parent material — thorium fluoride — is that all the thorium nuclei are in the same local atomic environments and experience the same electric field at the nuclei.” - Anastassia Alexandrova</blockquote><p>This innovation in thorium film technology could not only improve atomic clocks but also enhance a wide range of quantum optics applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/thorium-film-can-replace-crystals-in-atomic-clocks-2786256</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/thorium-film-can-replace-crystals-in-atomic-clocks-2786256</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:26:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quadrantids Meteor Shower 2025: Date, time, and how to watch it in India? - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/quadrantids-meteor-shower-2025-date-time-and-how-to-watch-it-in-india-nc-124123100654_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/quadrantids-meteor-shower-2025-date-time-and-how-to-watch-it-in-india-nc-124123100654_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:18:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bay Area astronomers say what would actually cause a 'Kessler Syndrome' crisis - SFGATE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxOY1V5V0lEekZMOF9uNHg1QzRNeXhXSHduT2xCY21aUFpDSzNoc0lVQXZVa01FZTZkQVBBX1RpSG05bWhoVlctaWlrTlRpRWFSallDR1l6UjU4ek8yU1BRcV85RHAtMDRpdFlXSXNRdXBxVnRQNGprQ2xyYmdFenFxbDBPQTlhOUlXY0lxb2R1RQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxOY1V5V0lEekZMOF9uNHg1QzRNeXhXSHduT2xCY21aUFpDSzNoc0lVQXZVa01FZTZkQVBBX1RpSG05bWhoVlctaWlrTlRpRWFSallDR1l6UjU4ek8yU1BRcV85RHAtMDRpdFlXSXNRdXBxVnRQNGprQ2xyYmdFenFxbDBPQTlhOUlXY0lxb2R1RQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:12:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parker Solar Probe Survives Record-Breaking Close Encounter With The Sun At 1,377°C - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parker Solar Probe's Record-Breaking Close Encounter With The Sun</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> Tuesday, December 31, 2024, 17:42 [IST] | <strong>Source:</strong> OneIndia News</p>
<img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2024/12/parker-solar-small-1735646994.jpg" alt="Parker Solar Probe Survives" width="600" height="338">
<figcaption>Parker Solar Probe Survives Record-Breaking Close Encounter With The Sun</figcaption>
<p>The Parker Solar Probe achieved a groundbreaking milestone, surviving a close approach to the Sun at a temperature of 1,377°C.</p>
<ul>
<li>The probe passed within 6.1 million kilometers of the Sun.</li>
<li>Dr. Nicola Fox compares the distance to 4 centimeters if the Earth and Sun were 1 meter apart.</li>
<li>It travels at speeds up to 692,000 km/h and features advanced heat-shield technology.</li>
<li>The probe contributes to understanding solar winds and the corona’s high temperatures.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"If the Sun and Earth were placed one meter apart, Parker Solar Probe would be just 4 centimeters away from the Sun." - Dr. Nicola Fox</blockquote>
<p>The mission aims to address the coronal heating problem and solar wind origins, providing insights into the Sun's mysteries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/international/parker-solar-probe-survives-record-breaking-close-encounter-with-the-sun-at-1-377-c-4030205.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/international/parker-solar-probe-survives-record-breaking-close-encounter-with-the-sun-at-1-377-c-4030205.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:12:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronomers build galaxy-sized ‘detector’ to map universe’s vibrations - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronomers Build Galaxy-Sized Detector to Map Universe’s Vibrations</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 31, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Conversation</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/sci-tech/science/5zd5lz/article69044563.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/20241230258L.jpg" alt="Astronomers' Detector" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Astronomers have built the largest gravitational wave detector to measure the vibrations of the universe.</figcaption><p>Using the largest gravitational wave detector ever made, astronomers have confirmed that the universe is constantly vibrating due to collisions between supermassive black holes.</p><ul><li>The detector is an array of rapidly spinning neutron stars across the galaxy.</li><li>The gravitational wave background may be louder than previously thought, revealing a more active universe.</li><li>The study provides the most detailed maps of gravitational waves across the sky, with a notable “hot spot” in the Southern Hemisphere.</li><li>The findings suggest more supermassive black holes may be orbiting each other than previously believed.</li><li>This research is published in the Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society.</li></ul><blockquote>“The gravitational wave background is more powerful than expected, indicating more supermassive black holes than theorized.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the research demonstrates the immense potential of galaxy-sized detectors in studying cosmic phenomena and understanding the fabric of the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/astronomers-build-galaxy-sized-detector-to-map-universes-vibrations/article69046237.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/astronomers-build-galaxy-sized-detector-to-map-universes-vibrations/article69046237.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 11:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get Ready For A Northern Lights Spectacle On New Year’s Eve: What You Need to Know - NewsX]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Get Ready For A Northern Lights Spectacle On New Year’s Eve: What You Need to Know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> NewsX</p><p>This New Year’s Eve, sky gazers across parts of the United States will have the chance to witness the Northern Lights, a stunning aurora borealis effect caused by a powerful geomagnetic storm.</p><ul><li>The geomagnetic storm is attributed to recent coronal mass ejections from the Sun.</li><li>Areas as far south as Illinois and Oregon may experience the auroras due to this G3 classified storm.</li><li>The lights are expected to peak after sunset on December 31, providing an alternative to traditional fireworks.</li><li>Increased solar activity has led to the anticipation of vibrant auroras beyond just New Year’s Eve, extending into January 1.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Sun has really stepped up over the past few days... expected to trigger a strong geomagnetic storm (bringing aurora) on the 31st!” - Ryan French, solar astrophysicist</blockquote><p>This celestial event presents a unique chance for many to ring in the New Year under the enchanting glow of the aurora borealis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newsx.com/world/get-ready-for-a-northern-lights-spectacle-on-new-years-eve-what-you-need-to-know/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newsx.com/world/get-ready-for-a-northern-lights-spectacle-on-new-years-eve-what-you-need-to-know/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 11:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trends for 2025: Bustling space bazaar - Down To Earth Magazine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trends for 2025: Bustling Space Bazaar</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> World Economic Forum, McKinsey and Company</p><p>Space has emerged as the new marketplace, with private players leading a growing economy expected to reach $1.8 trillion by 2035.</p><ul><li>Human presence in low-Earth orbit (LEO) increased significantly in 2024, with Starlink launching over 2,000 satellites.</li><li>By the end of 2024, 280 individuals visited the International Space Station.</li><li>NASA's Juno captured sharp images of Jupiter’s moon Io, and Intuitive Machines achieved a soft landing on the moon.</li><li>China transported lunar samples from the far side of the moon, marking a historic achievement.</li><li>India's Aditya L1 successfully entered orbit around the Sun and plans a mission to Venus.</li></ul><blockquote>The space economy is slated to be worth $1.8 trillion by 2035.</blockquote><p>The changing landscape of space exploration and commercialization is reshaping industries and international collaboration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/science-technology/trends-for-2025-bustling-space-bazaar</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.downtoearth.org.in/science-technology/trends-for-2025-bustling-space-bazaar</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 11:07:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA introduces new Mars helicopter design following Ingenuity's success - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Introduces New Mars Helicopter Design Following Ingenuity's Success</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> WION</p><p>Nasa reveals a new Mars helicopter design aimed at enhancing Mars exploration, building on the success of the Ingenuity helicopter, which was the first aircraft to fly on another planet.</p><img src='path_to_image.jpg' alt='Mars helicopter' /><figcaption>NASA’s new Mars helicopter design, the Mars Chopper.</figcaption><p>Flying on Mars poses several challenges due to its thin atmosphere and fine dust. The new design, the Mars Chopper, is larger and can carry scientific instruments, enhancing exploration capabilities.</p><ul><li>The new helicopter will feature six rotors with six blades for increased lift.</li><li>It can carry up to 5 kilograms of equipment.</li><li>It supports scientific investigations in hard-to-reach areas.</li><li>The collaboration involves NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory and Ames Research Center.</li></ul><blockquote>The Mars Chopper will be a game changer for exploration efforts on Mars.</blockquote><p>This helicopter will play a crucial role in future missions, providing aerial support for robotic and human explorers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/science-tech/nasa-introduces-new-mars-helicopter-design-following-ingenuitys-success-8580942</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/science-tech/nasa-introduces-new-mars-helicopter-design-following-ingenuitys-success-8580942</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 11:03:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aurora alert by NASA: Strong solar geomagnetic storm to bring spectacular northern lights on New Year's... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/europe/?url=https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/aurora-alert-by-nasa-strong-solar-geomagnetic-storm-to-bring-spectacular-northern-lights-on-new-year-s-eve-how-to-watch-it-article-12901114.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/europe/?url=https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/aurora-alert-by-nasa-strong-solar-geomagnetic-storm-to-bring-spectacular-northern-lights-on-new-year-s-eve-how-to-watch-it-article-12901114.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:17:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>