<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 14:16:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 14:16:17 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 mesmerising images of galaxies by NASA - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Mesmerising Images of Galaxies by NASA</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> DNA</p><img src="https://images1.dnaindia.com/images/DNA-EN/900x1600/2024/12/29/1735478811805_3.jpg" alt="10 mesmerising images of galaxies by NASA"><figcaption>10 mesmerising images of galaxies by NASA</figcaption><p>This article showcases stunning images of various galaxies captured by NASA, highlighting their unique features and cosmic beauty.</p><ul><li>Caldwell 5 located in the Camelopardalis constellation.</li><li>The Pinwheel Galaxy, 21 million light-years away in Ursa Major.</li><li>Galaxy M94, 16 million light-years away in Canes Venatici.</li><li>NGC 6744 is a galaxy about 30 million light-years away in the Pavo constellation.</li><li>NGC 1448 features a supermassive black hole at its center.</li><li>The Antennae Galaxies are abundant with black holes and neutron stars.</li><li>This active barred spiral galaxy has experienced three supernovae since 1992.</li><li>The Needle Galaxy is featured among the captivating images.</li></ul><p>Source: NASA</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/viral/10-mesmerising-images-of-galaxies-by-nasa-1735478605263</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/viral/10-mesmerising-images-of-galaxies-by-nasa-1735478605263</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:38:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15 must-see naked-eye skywatching events in 2025 - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>15 Must-See Naked-Eye Skywatching Events in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/jbYLgds7hSgDgRLawETMe6.gif" alt="gif animation of a person looking at the night sky with the text 2025 in the top right corner."><figcaption>(Image credit: Created in Canva Pro by Daisy Dobrijevic)</figcaption><p>In 2025, skywatchers can look forward to a series of stunning celestial events, including a bright Mars occulted by the Wolf Moon, Venus at its brightest, a spectacular "devil's horns" solar eclipse, and plenty of meteor showers peaking under moonless night skies.</p><ul><li>Quadrantid meteor shower: Jan. 3, 2025.</li><li>Mars gobbled up by the Wolf Moon: Jan. 13-14, 2025.</li><li>Mars at opposition: Jan. 15, 2025.</li><li>A crescent Venus at its brightest: Feb. 19, 2025.</li><li>"Devil's horns" at sunrise: March 29, 2025.</li><li>Lyrid meteor shower: April 21-22, 2025.</li><li>Eta Aquarid meteor shower: May 6-7, 2025.</li><li>A crescent moon visiting the Pleiades: July 20, 2025.</li><li>Delta Aquariid meteor shower: July 28-29, 2025.</li><li>Conjunction of Venus and Jupiter: Aug. 12, 2025.</li><li>A second partial solar eclipse: Sept. 21, 2025.</li><li>Saturn at opposition: Sept. 21, 2025.</li><li>Draconid meteor shower: Oct. 8-9, 2025.</li><li>A spectacular supermoon: Nov. 5, 2025.</li><li>Leonid meteor shower: Nov. 17-18, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“Supermoons happen because the moon's orbit is elliptical, so some full moons are closer than others, making them appear bigger and brighter from Earth.”</blockquote><p>Mark your calendars to enjoy these incredible celestial sights in 2025!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/stargazing/15-must-see-naked-eye-skywatching-events-in-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/stargazing/15-must-see-naked-eye-skywatching-events-in-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Careers in Space Technology: What to Expect in 2025 - Analytics Insight]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Careers in Space Technology: What to Expect in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Analysys Mason</p><p>The space industry is booming with new developments in exploration, communication, and commercial ventures. This article discusses the evolving career landscape in space technology as we approach 2025.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>Space engineering remains a high-demand field focusing on spacecraft and satellite design.</li><li>Satellite technology careers will see increased demand due to global communication and GPS reliance.</li><li>New opportunities in space exploration research, including planetary geology and astrobiology.</li><li>The rise of the commercial space industry, including tourism and manufacturing roles.</li><li>Emerging roles like space law and space medicine will become vital as space travel becomes more common.</li></ul><blockquote>“Space technology careers will open many new opportunities by 2025 in fields such as engineering, satellite communications, space exploration, and the commercial space industry.”</blockquote><p>This dynamic industry is set to create numerous opportunities for those passionate about space innovation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.analyticsinsight.net/tech-news/careers-in-space-technology-what-to-expect-in-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.analyticsinsight.net/tech-news/careers-in-space-technology-what-to-expect-in-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 10 most intriguing science breakthroughs of 2024 - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The 10 Most Intriguing Science Breakthroughs of 2024</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 29 December 2024, 10:21 IST</p><p>2024 witnessed remarkable scientific discoveries, often overshadowed by global events. These breakthroughs have the potential to improve health and expand our understanding of the universe.</p><ul><li><h2>Moon rocks from Terra Incognita</h2> Chinese craft Chang’e-6 returned samples from the moon's far side, aiding in planetary formation studies.</li><li><h2>A drug that prevents HIV</h2> Lenacapavir shows 100% efficacy in preventing HIV infections with biannual injections, a significant development in HIV prevention.</li><li><h2>AI delves into the human psyche</h2> AI is being utilized to understand human behavior and improve diagnostic accuracy in healthcare.</li><li><h2>Craft sets off for distant ocean world</h2> The Europa Clipper has launched to explore the potential for life beneath the icy surface of Jupiter's moon Europa.</li><li><h2>The James Webb telescope recalculates universal expansion</h2> New observations from the James Webb Telescope challenge previous assumptions about the rate of the universe's expansion.</li><li><h2>Aging spurts at 44 and 60</h2> Significant biological changes were observed at ages 44 and 60, indicating new targets for aging interventions.</li><li><h2>Reconstructing climate in deep time</h2> A recent study shows Earth's climate has fluctuated dramatically over 485 million years, with implications for future climate predictions.</li><li><h2>The health scare of the year: plastic in your brain</h2> Studies indicate concerning links between plastic exposure and health issues, including microplastics in human brains.</li><li><h2>Best occupations for fighting death and dementia</h2> Research reveals that certain professions are linked to longer lifespans and reduced rates of Alzheimer’s.</li><li><h2>A big step toward quantum computing</h2> Progress in solving error rates in quantum computing could lead to significant advancements in technology.</li></ul><blockquote>“This year saw breakthroughs that could fundamentally shift our understanding and approach towards health and the universe.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, 2024 has showcased a plethora of breakthroughs that not only push the boundaries of science but also offer hope for advancements in health and our understanding of life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/science/the-10-most-intriguing-science-breakthroughs-of-2024-3335435</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/science/the-10-most-intriguing-science-breakthroughs-of-2024-3335435</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:21:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 iconic pictures shared by Nasa in 2024 - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Iconic Pictures Shared by NASA in 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p>
<img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2024/12/cropped-iss072e397366mediumITG-1735466730719.jpg" alt="NASA Image" />
<figcaption>NASA image capturing a scene from Mars.</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases ten remarkable photographs shared by NASA in 2024, highlighting significant events and breathtaking scenes from space and our planet.</p>
<ul>
  <li>NASA's Perseverance rover captured the Jezero Crater on Mars during its mission.</li>
  <li>A total solar eclipse was observed from NASA’s Glenn Research Center in Ohio.</li>
  <li>A partial solar eclipse was documented with the Washington Monument in silhouette.</li>
  <li>Photographs depicting the remnants of Razazah Lake in Iraq were shared.</li>
  <li>Images of the Arabian Peninsula captured from the International Space Station were included.</li>
  <li>National and international impacts of Cyclone Chido in Mayotte were visualized.</li>
  <li>NASA's cargo craft Cygnus successfully delivered supplies to the ISS.</li>
  <li>Russian cosmonaut Alexey Ovchinin was photographed during a spacewalk.</li>
  <li>View of the Large Magellanic Cloud along with Earth's atmosphere was shown.</li>
  <li>Winter ice covering parts of Earth as seen from space was also included.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"NASA continues to capture the wonders of space and our planet, depicting both beauty and peril through stunning imagery."</blockquote>
<p>The images shared by NASA not only showcase the beauty of space and Earth but also highlight the challenges and phenomena impacting our world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/science/large-magellanic-cloud-visible-in-the-southern-hemisphere-with-the-upper-red-orange-part-of-our-atmosphere-called-the-f-region-seen-in-the-lower-part-of-the-photograph-198235-29-12-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/science/large-magellanic-cloud-visible-in-the-southern-hemisphere-with-the-upper-red-orange-part-of-our-atmosphere-called-the-f-region-seen-in-the-lower-part-of-the-photograph-198235-29-12-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:15:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk and back-to-back rocket missions: When and where to watch the last SpaceX launch of 2024 LIVE - The Week]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk and Back-to-Back Rocket Missions: Final SpaceX Launch of 2024</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> SpaceX</p><p>SpaceX is set for its final launch of 2024, featuring 21 Starlink satellites from Kennedy Space Center in Florida.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Launch scheduled for December 30 at 12am ET or 10:30am India time.</li><li>21 Starlink satellites will be deployed one hour after liftoff.</li><li>Live webcast available on SpaceX’s official X account five minutes before launch.</li><li>This will mark SpaceX’s 134th launch of the year and 428th in total.</li><li>Recent launches include a mission from Cape Canaveral and another from Vandenberg Space Force Base.</li></ul><blockquote>“Congrats, SpaceX team, on completing two great orbital missions in 24 hours!” - Elon Musk</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theweek.in/news/sci-tech/2024/12/29/elon-musk-space-rocket-mission-when-where-to-watch-last-spacex-launch-of-2024-live-time.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theweek.in/news/sci-tech/2024/12/29/elon-musk-space-rocket-mission-when-where-to-watch-last-spacex-launch-of-2024-live-time.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:13:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four eclipses predicted for 2025, but only one visible from India, according to Ujjain observatory - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Four Eclipses Predicted for 2025, Only One Visible from India</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p> <div id='story-featured-image'> <img src='https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/eclipses-in-2025-1735466360.webp' alt='Eclipses in 2025' width='1200' height='675'> <figcaption>Eclipses in 2025</figcaption> </div> <p>In 2025, two solar and two lunar eclipses will occur, but only one will be visible from India, as per the Jiwaji Observatory in Ujjain.</p> <ul> <li>The first event is a total lunar eclipse on March 14, not visible in India.</li> <li>A partial solar eclipse on March 29 will also be invisible from India.</li> <li>A full lunar eclipse on September 7-8 will be observable in India.</li> <li>The final event is a partial solar eclipse on September 21-22, which won't be visible from India.</li> </ul> <blockquote>The sun's activity is expected to remain elevated throughout 2025, coinciding with the solar maximum of Solar Cycle 25, associated with an increase in solar flares and geomagnetic storms.</blockquote> <p>This year sees an intriguing mix of astronomical events for enthusiasts, with significant implications due to heightened solar activity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/science/four-eclipses-predicted-for-2025-but-only-one-visible-from-india-according-to-ujjain-observatory-2024-12-29-968489</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/science/four-eclipses-predicted-for-2025-but-only-one-visible-from-india-according-to-ujjain-observatory-2024-12-29-968489</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:03:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Parker Solar Probe makes history with closest pass to Sun - Aerospace Global News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe Makes History with Closest Pass to Sun</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>This unprecedented achievement marks a new chapter in solar exploration, as the Parker Solar Probe flew just 3.8 million miles above the Sun's surface, traveling at 430,000 miles per hour.</p><ul><li>The Parker Solar Probe completed its closest approach to the Sun on December 24, 2023.</li><li>It traveled at a speed of 430,000 miles per hour, the fastest for any human-made object.</li><li>The achievement enables scientists to gather unique data about the Sun.</li><li>Launched in 2018, the probe refines its trajectory with gravitational assists from Venus.</li><li>The spacecraft can endure temperatures exceeding 1 million degrees Fahrenheit with a specialized heat shield.</li></ul><blockquote>“Flying this close to the Sun is a historic moment in humanity’s first mission to a star.” - Nicky Fox, NASA Science Mission Directorate</blockquote><p>This mission sets the stage for a new era of solar research, enhancing our understanding of stellar phenomena.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://aerospaceglobalnews.com/news/nasas-parker-solar-probe-makes-history-with-closest-pass-to-sun/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://aerospaceglobalnews.com/news/nasas-parker-solar-probe-makes-history-with-closest-pass-to-sun/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:21:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subaru Telescope captures optically interacting pair of galaxies - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Subaru Telescope Captures Interacting Galaxies NGC 4496</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi<br><strong>Source:</strong> <a href="https://www.news9live.com/science">Science News</a></p><img width="802" height="464" src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/NGC-4496.jpg?w=802&amp;enlarge=true" alt="The optically interacting pair of galaxies designated as NGC 4496. (Image Credit: NAOJ)."><figcaption>The optically interacting pair of galaxies designated as NGC 4496. (Image Credit: NAOJ).</figcaption><p>The Subaru Telescope has captured a pair of galaxies known as NGC 4496 in the Virgo constellation. NGC 4496A and NGC 4496B are notable for their apparent close interaction from our perspective, despite being well separated in space.</p><ul><li>NGC 4496A is 47 million light-years away; NGC 4496B is 212 million light-years away.</li><li>The galaxies appear merged from Earth's viewpoint but are not physically interacting.</li><li>Green regions in the image indicate star formation activity.</li><li>The Subaru Telescope is located in Hawaii and operated by the National Observatory of Japan.</li><li>William Herschel discovered these galaxies in 1784, mistakenly cataloguing them twice.</li></ul><blockquote>“Such line-of-sight alignments of galaxies benefit astronomers as the background galaxy lights up the gas and dust in the foreground galaxy.”</blockquote><p>The Subaru Telescope's findings on NGC 4496 enhance our understanding of galaxy evolution and star lifecycle.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/subaru-telescope-captures-optically-interacting-pair-of-galaxies-2784518</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/subaru-telescope-captures-optically-interacting-pair-of-galaxies-2784518</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 07:20:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Predict Under Sea Volcano Eruption Near Oregon - Observer Voice]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxOOGcyZk9ITHFIR2t0MkVnN0JESGdyS05xdHE1QlZUQTk5N0c5ZXN1UVBNWGN4eUU4RTdqcC1Wc2IzWG1rODhCaG5McktjT2pvekZfemNFS25OVml0SUItWFpjS1NzdUJhS2hRTmJsYkljcXk4Z2FiMkRxa29EbDdpbG5lWndwU0NWOTFudVFSODg3V1N1?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxOOGcyZk9ITHFIR2t0MkVnN0JESGdyS05xdHE1QlZUQTk5N0c5ZXN1UVBNWGN4eUU4RTdqcC1Wc2IzWG1rODhCaG5McktjT2pvekZfemNFS25OVml0SUItWFpjS1NzdUJhS2hRTmJsYkljcXk4Z2FiMkRxa29EbDdpbG5lWndwU0NWOTFudVFSODg3V1N1?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 06:43:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India to witness just 1 of 4 eclipses in 2025: know the dates - Kalinga TV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India to Witness Only 1 of 4 Eclipses in 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> New Delhi, <strong>Source:</strong> Experts from Ujjain’s Jiwaji Observatory</p>
<p>Buckle up for an thrilling ride in the year 2025! Eclipses are in plenty this year, with four eclipses including two solar and two lunar.</p>
<img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Eclipse Illustration'>
<figcaption>Illustration of a lunar eclipse</figcaption>
<p>The first is a total lunar eclipse on March 14, which will be invisible in India. The second is a partial solar eclipse on March 29, which will also not be seen from India. However, Indian astronomy enthusiasts can look forward to a full lunar eclipse between September 7 and 8, visible in India. The final event is a partial solar eclipse between September 21 and 22, viewable only in New Zealand and surrounding areas.</p>
<ul>
  <li>March 14: Total lunar eclipse (invisible in India)</li>
  <li>March 29: Partial solar eclipse (invisible in India)</li>
  <li>September 7-8: Full lunar eclipse (visible in India)</li>
  <li>September 21-22: Partial solar eclipse (invisible in India)</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Indian astronomy lovers can be thrilled by the fact that the full lunar eclipse between September 7 and 8 will be visible in the country,” said Dr. Rajendra Prakash Gupt.</blockquote>
<p>This year 2024 has already provided four celestial events including a penumbral lunar eclipse, total solar eclipse, partial lunar eclipse, and annular solar eclipse.</p>
<p>In conclusion, while 2025 will showcase several eclipses, Indian viewers will only get to experience one.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://kalingatv.com/miscellany/india-to-witness-just-1-of-4-eclipses-in-2025-know-the-dates/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kalingatv.com/miscellany/india-to-witness-just-1-of-4-eclipses-in-2025-know-the-dates/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 05:37:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[These are the 7 biggest milestones in the aerospace industry so far this millennium: Review 24 years of rockets with us - Softonic EN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>These are the 7 biggest milestones in the aerospace industry so far this millennium: Review 24 years of rockets with us</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Softonic</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://articles-img.sftcdn.net/t_articles/auto-mapping-folder/sites/3/2024/09/newsletter.png" width="100px" height="100px">
<figcaption>Aerospace Milestones Overview</figcaption>
<p>This article reviews significant milestones in the aerospace industry from 2000 to 2024, highlighting advancements and achievements that have marked the progress of space exploration.</p>
<ul>
<li>Artemis I: NASA's mission to send humans back to deep space with significant investment in the Artemis Program.</li>
<li>Return of crewed spaceflight: SpaceX's Dragon capsule restored US capabilities for manned missions to the ISS.</li>
<li>Detection of gravitational waves: Confirmed a century-old theory by detecting gravitational waves from black holes.</li>
<li>Space tourism: The rise of commercial space travel with flights from Virgin Galactic and Blue Origin.</li>
<li>China's Chang’e program: China's advancements in lunar exploration and ambitions to send humans to the Moon.</li>
<li>SpaceX's Starship capture: Technical achievement in rocket recovery and testing.</li>
<li>Falcon Heavy launch: A demonstration of the capabilities of commercial heavy-lift rockets.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This technical achievement demonstrates several important things, including the verification of the radical approach to catching a rocket.”</blockquote>
<p>These milestones reflect the evolving landscape of the aerospace industry, highlighting both competitive advances and international collaboration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://en.softonic.com/articles/these-are-the-7-biggest-milestones-in-the-aerospace-industry-so-far-this-millennium-review-24-years-of-rockets-with-us</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.softonic.com/articles/these-are-the-7-biggest-milestones-in-the-aerospace-industry-so-far-this-millennium-review-24-years-of-rockets-with-us</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:25:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Human brain’s processing speed is far slower than the internet, a study reveals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Human Brain Processes Information Slower Than the Internet, Study Indicates</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Research findings reveal that the human brain's processing speed is significantly slower compared to the instantaneous nature of the internet. This highlights intriguing contrasts between biological and technological information processing.</p><ul><li>The study compares the speed of human cognitive functions with data transmission rates on the internet.</li><li>It suggests that while the brain operates efficiently, it cannot match the speed of data flow in digital networks.</li><li>This difference raises questions about the implications for learning and information retention in an increasingly digital world.</li></ul><blockquote>“Understanding the gap between our cognitive abilities and technology could lead to better educational strategies.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the findings underscore the importance of considering the speed of information processing in both biological and technological contexts, as it affects our learning and interaction with the digital world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/human-brains-processing-speed-is-far-slower-than-the-internet-a-study-reveals/articleshow/116755082.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/health-news/human-brains-processing-speed-is-far-slower-than-the-internet-a-study-reveals/articleshow/116755082.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 23:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A beautiful astronaut stranded in space took photos to celebrate Christmas, prompting netizens to ask: Where did the Santa hat come from? – Passionategeekz - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwJBVV95cUxQWVFGSWpiOTBxWUs1SFRmU25NREFHSXZTOGozZmVEd1A3UV85aTJMdFpCWkVhMFZpUDBNOXpTRG1LN0hQckZSeXYwWmI1aDZWR1dSaFI5WGhpWkdSUGgwZkhLb3EtV2M0WmtpQm5QOF9JTDFXX3ZmbnBsbGdfODVsbnNDUlJyZWhVZXJHeXJpYnRQWWtYeHplU21fMF8wZW5lWXJCNW9ETzJ2anZZcVBJdnVHZkNSTVlXNVlMT1hlVDFqX1cyX0hYb0JwdTZhc2ZJamZxamM2Vk5MSnNNcEFsRWlRelgyUUtyVXIzbFBGVXg4QU5LaW9KRXd4a2lkVTIyQ3RXWnNnTkNKMWPSAYsCQVVfeXFMUFlRRklqYjkwcVlLNUhUZlNuTURBR0l2UzhqM2ZlRHdQN1FfOWkyTHRaQlpFYTBWaVAwTTl6U0RtSzdIUHJGUnl2MFpiNWg2VkdXUmhSOVhoaVpHUlBoMGZIS29xLVdjNFpraUJuUDhfSUwxV192Zm5wbGxnXzg1bG5zQ1JScmVoVWVyR3lyaWJ0UFlrWHh6ZVNtXzBfMGVuZVlyQjVvRE8ydmp2WXFQSXZ1R2ZDUk1ZVzVZTE9YZVQxal9XMl9IWG9CcHU2YXNmSWpmcWpjNlZOTEpzTXBBbEVpUXpYMlFLclVyM2xQRlV4OEFOS2lvSkV3eGtpZFUyMkN0V1pzZ05DSjFj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwJBVV95cUxQWVFGSWpiOTBxWUs1SFRmU25NREFHSXZTOGozZmVEd1A3UV85aTJMdFpCWkVhMFZpUDBNOXpTRG1LN0hQckZSeXYwWmI1aDZWR1dSaFI5WGhpWkdSUGgwZkhLb3EtV2M0WmtpQm5QOF9JTDFXX3ZmbnBsbGdfODVsbnNDUlJyZWhVZXJHeXJpYnRQWWtYeHplU21fMF8wZW5lWXJCNW9ETzJ2anZZcVBJdnVHZkNSTVlXNVlMT1hlVDFqX1cyX0hYb0JwdTZhc2ZJamZxamM2Vk5MSnNNcEFsRWlRelgyUUtyVXIzbFBGVXg4QU5LaW9KRXd4a2lkVTIyQ3RXWnNnTkNKMWPSAYsCQVVfeXFMUFlRRklqYjkwcVlLNUhUZlNuTURBR0l2UzhqM2ZlRHdQN1FfOWkyTHRaQlpFYTBWaVAwTTl6U0RtSzdIUHJGUnl2MFpiNWg2VkdXUmhSOVhoaVpHUlBoMGZIS29xLVdjNFpraUJuUDhfSUwxV192Zm5wbGxnXzg1bG5zQ1JScmVoVWVyR3lyaWJ0UFlrWHh6ZVNtXzBfMGVuZVlyQjVvRE8ydmp2WXFQSXZ1R2ZDUk1ZVzVZTE9YZVQxal9XMl9IWG9CcHU2YXNmSWpmcWpjNlZOTEpzTXBBbEVpUXpYMlFLclVyM2xQRlV4OEFOS2lvSkV3eGtpZFUyMkN0V1pzZ05DSjFj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 23:11:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 amazing cosmology pictures by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Amazing Cosmology Pictures by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ring-of-relativity-Headlines.jpg" alt="Ring of Relativity" />
<figcaption>Ring of Relativity captured by Hubble.</figcaption>
<p>This article features stunning images captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, showcasing the wonders of the universe through cosmology.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Lensing cluster Abell 383:</strong> A giant galaxy cluster showing the effect of dark matter bending light.</li>
  <li><strong>Hubble’s colourful view of the Universe:</strong> A detailed and colorful portrait of the evolving Universe.</li>
  <li><strong>Dark matter ring discovery:</strong> An international team found a ghostly ring formed by colliding galaxy clusters.</li>
  <li><strong>Cosmic Snake:</strong> A galaxy with regions of intense star formation affected by gravitational lensing.</li>
  <li><strong>Rings of Relativity:</strong> A unique cosmic phenomenon featuring a galaxy elegantly curving around another.</li>
  <li><strong>Astronomy in Action:</strong> A rare celestial phenomenon showcased in a striking Hubble image.</li>
  <li><strong>Ghost light from dead galaxies:</strong> Pandoras Cluster captured in a ghostly Hubble view.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Astronomers have utilized Hubble’s capability to capture detailed and colorful images of phenomena that would otherwise remain unseen.</blockquote>
<p>This collection of images serves as a reminder of the incredible capabilities of the Hubble Space Telescope and its contributions to our understanding of the cosmos.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-amazing-cosmology-pictures-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7499920/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-amazing-cosmology-pictures-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7499920/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 20:11:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists talk about dangers of debris in Earth's orbit - AzerNews.Az]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Discuss Growing Dangers of Space Debris in Earth's Orbit</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown<br><strong>Source:</strong> Azernews</p><p>Vishnu Reddy, a professor at the University of Arizona, warns about the increasing dangers of space debris in Earth's orbit, highlighting the risks associated with Kessler Syndrome.</p><ul><li>The increase in objects launched into space has soared over the past four years.</li><li>The greatest threat is space debris around 35,000 kilometers from Earth, where most telecommunications satellites operate.</li><li>No definitive solutions have been proposed for preventing Kessler Syndrome, which could lead to a cascade of debris from satellite collisions.</li><li>The phenomenon could make significant areas of near-Earth orbit unsuitable for future missions.</li></ul><blockquote>“The number of objects we’ve launched into space has increased exponentially over the past four years. A situation we’ve long feared is now becoming a reality.” - Vishnu Reddy</blockquote><p>The potential consequences of Kessler Syndrome underline the urgent need for strategies to manage and mitigate space debris risks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.azernews.az/region/235815.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.azernews.az/region/235815.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Our favorite space stories of 2024 — from lost planets to human-caused meteor showers - Livescience.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Our favorite space stories of 2024 — from lost planets to human-caused meteor showers</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>2024</p>
<p><strong>Source: </strong>Live Science</p>
<img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FeeK8hKVqw2dv9fnEQgTkR.jpg" alt="A stunning, billowing cloud of purple and orange gas in space">
<figcaption>The stunning star nursery Messier 78 was one of the Euclid space telescope's first targets. (Image credit: ESA/Euclid/Euclid Consortium/NASA, image processing by J.-C. Cuillandre (CEA Paris-Saclay), G. Anselmi)</figcaption>
<p>This year saw significant events in space exploration, with notable achievements related to the moon and sun. Japan achieved a remarkable lunar landing, while NASA confirmed the sun's peak activity cycle.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Japan's "Moon Sniper" mission completed the most precise lunar landing in history.</li>
  <li>The first commercial moon landing occurred from a private company.</li>
  <li>China's Chang'e 6 mission successfully brought precious lunar samples back to Earth.</li>
  <li>The sun's solar maximum led to intense solar storms and rare global auroras.</li>
  <li>An anticipated total solar eclipse dazzled millions across North America.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This is truly a landmark year for lunar exploration, with achievements from both government and private missions."</blockquote>
<p>As the year comes to a close, these events highlight the ongoing advancements in our understanding of space, showcasing both collaborations and innovations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livescience.com/space/astronomy/our-favorite-space-stories-of-2024-from-lost-planets-to-human-caused-meteor-showers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livescience.com/space/astronomy/our-favorite-space-stories-of-2024-from-lost-planets-to-human-caused-meteor-showers</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revisiting the biggest moments in the space industry in 2024 - TechCrunch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Revisiting the biggest moments in the space industry in 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> TechCrunch</p>
<figure><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1536" height="1044" src="https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/boeing-starliner-docked-to-iss-e1718849214277.webp?w=680" alt="Boeing Starliner docked to ISS"><figcaption><span><strong>Image Credits:</strong><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nasa.gov/" target="_blank">NASA <span>(opens in a new window)</span></a></span></figcaption></figure>
<p>2024 has marked the dawn of a new space age with significant advancements and milestones in the industry. From SpaceX's notable achievements to international lunar landing attempts, this year has showcased a remarkable array of events.</p>
<ul>
    <li>1. Boeing’s Starliner mission faced technical malfunctions, resulting in NASA's decision to utilize a SpaceX Dragon capsule for astronaut return.</li>
    <li>2. SpaceX successfully caught the Super Heavy booster during a test flight, an engineering first in the industry.</li>
    <li>3. Polaris Dawn led by Jared Isaacman achieved the first private spacewalk, focusing on spacesuit testing.</li>
    <li>4. Multiple nations and companies aimed for lunar landings; mixed results were observed, with China's mission succeeding.</li>
    <li>5. The Space Force awarded significant contracts to commercial providers, indicating a strong partnership between government and the private sector.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This year has been full of historic and ambitious missions,” stated industry experts highlighting the advancements in space travel.</blockquote>
<p>This year has been pivotal in shaping the future of space exploration, with implications for technology, international collaboration, and commercial endeavors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/28/revisiting-the-biggest-moments-in-the-space-industry-in-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/28/revisiting-the-biggest-moments-in-the-space-industry-in-2024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maximum afterburner for NASA’s X-59 engine test run - Aerospace Global News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's X-59 Completes First Maximum Afterburner Test Run</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: November 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: NASA</strong></p><p>NASA's X-59 experimental quiet supersonic aircraft has successfully completed its first maximum afterburner engine test run, paving the way for its anticipated first flight in 2025.</p><ul><li>The test was conducted at Lockheed Martin’s Skunk Works facility in Palmdale, California.</li><li>The modified F414-GE-100 engine produced 22,000 pounds of thrust, allowing the aircraft to reach speeds of Mach 1.4.</li><li>Engine operations demonstrated compliance with temperature limits and airflow requirements.</li><li>The engine is positioned atop the aircraft to minimize noise during supersonic flight, aiming to create a quieter 'thump' instead of a sonic boom.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was an emotional high to see and hear another innovative, boundary-pushing Skunk Works X-plane coming to life.” - Pat LeBeau, Lockheed Martin X-59 Manager</blockquote><p>This successful test marks a crucial step towards the X-59's mission of transforming supersonic flight into a quieter experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://aerospaceglobalnews.com/news/maximum-afterburner-for-nasas-x-59-engine-test-run/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://aerospaceglobalnews.com/news/maximum-afterburner-for-nasas-x-59-engine-test-run/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:27:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Year in Abstracts: Obese Genomes and Banana Galaxies - 404 Media]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Year in Abstracts: Obese Genomes and Banana Galaxies</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 2024, 404 Media</p><figure><img src='https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdq1-hMtjKsdFlJ9oQfUsi3KgJSQicD58tv1Om47MqBs0p75uZwlqr2b_jxdfpDK-UjB2UoTcVTptZwGWwGFlOuupnrmSVwnECrMFeMOFPrm4n1xjHGQ29LxId6gHjKMOlPlguSHA?key=MRdnZrj8ZKe9iTHyKkjG2cuO' alt='Banana-like galaxy shapes' loading='lazy' width='624' height='240'><figcaption><i><em>I have never seen bananas that look like this, but ok. Image: </em></i><a href='https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.3847/1538-4357/ad1a13?ref=404media.co#apjad1a13s6' target='_blank' rel='noreferrer noopener'><u><i><em>Pandya, Viraj et al.</em></i></u></a></figcaption></figure><p>This article highlights five intriguing scientific studies from 2024 that explore captivating phenomena such as banana-shaped galaxies and record-breaking genomes. These discoveries further our understanding of various fields, from astrophysics to evolutionary biology.</p><ul><li>Banana galaxies observed using the James Webb Space Telescope showcase the unique shapes of high-redshift galaxies.</li><li>The quasar J0529−4351 is reported as the most luminous object known, with a black hole consuming one solar mass per day.</li><li>A tropical fork fern, Tmesipteris oblanceolata, has been found to have the largest genome of any eukaryote, with 160 billion base pairs.</li><li>Research on RNA evolution provides insights into the origins of life on Earth through the development of self-replicating RNA enzymes.</li><li>The discovery of a potential cave system on the Moon presents exciting possibilities for future human exploration.</li></ul><blockquote>“The black hole in this quasar accretes around one solar mass per day onto an existing mass of ∼17 billion solar masses.” - Christian Wolf, Australian National University</blockquote><p>This summary encapsulates the exciting scientific advancements made in 2024, suggesting that both our understanding of the universe and the complexities of life on Earth continue to expand.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.404media.co/the-year-in-abstracts-obese-genomes-and-banana-galaxies-3/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.404media.co/the-year-in-abstracts-obese-genomes-and-banana-galaxies-3/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kessler Syndrome Threatens Earth’s Orbit As Space Debris Continues To Builds Up - NewsX]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQOVh3eEpEN0MxXzR0dnFzZnNjOG9jc0VpekowX0JtVmZmSElYU0N4UTZIa0xVWWtXQkZTV3lNQTZXa2dLLWtKSHVEbDN1V1F5czROYUNnTk5jWnU1Y2dIVF9qWFphWkRZQUZjQVRUVGlNbjJray0waWdVRFU5aFhFalFnVlo3WHR3Ui1kRHZFdGlwelk5UmNoOElOT0t5T1ZuRGxzVkl4VW04VGhkVHhrb1Q2SmtZUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxQOVh3eEpEN0MxXzR0dnFzZnNjOG9jc0VpekowX0JtVmZmSElYU0N4UTZIa0xVWWtXQkZTV3lNQTZXa2dLLWtKSHVEbDN1V1F5czROYUNnTk5jWnU1Y2dIVF9qWFphWkRZQUZjQVRUVGlNbjJray0waWdVRFU5aFhFalFnVlo3WHR3Ui1kRHZFdGlwelk5UmNoOElOT0t5T1ZuRGxzVkl4VW04VGhkVHhrb1Q2SmtZUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Predict Under Sea Volcano Eruption Near Oregon Coast in 2025 - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Predict Under Sea Volcano Eruption Near Oregon Coast in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/s0qmkvsC5pE/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Video related to the article</figcaption><p>An undersea volcano off Oregon's coast, Axial Seamount, is showing signs of imminent activity, with predictions of a possible eruption as early as 2025.</p><ul><li>Researchers have detected ground deformation, increased seismic activity, and magma accumulation.</li><li>The volcano has been closely monitored with real-time data collection from the seafloor.</li><li>Advanced predictive models utilizing AI are being developed to improve eruption forecasts.</li><li>While the immediate threat to humans is low, enhanced forecasting could help prepare coastal regions.</li></ul><blockquote>"This prediction represents a significant milestone in volcanic monitoring, as it is rare for scientists to anticipate eruptions with such precision."</blockquote><p>Ongoing monitoring efforts aim to refine strategies for future volcanic activity detection.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/scientists-predict-under-sea-volcano-eruption-near-oregon-coast-in-2025-7349516</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/scientists-predict-under-sea-volcano-eruption-near-oregon-coast-in-2025-7349516</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Organic Molecules in Space: A Key to Understanding Life’s Cosmic Origins - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxPSjdpUm42emkyMV80NFpGOGlyZkQ5SnEzYk1LN2xEcmtRdFpOUnJVLVJjeG5lc0ZXNXhhSWVCWUd5ZGZUX29nUDhDRHNrZTVFQVAtZlRwcDJsLXYtLTJZWjMxY3hXUXB0eEFha2RCSjh1Q2FzMVM0dkUzMGY0eGJaYjczY1Q3cVJ4dTBOYUVvVHZSR1BHbGktcXI3ektYRFgy0gGgAUFVX3lxTE9KN2lSbjZ6aTIxXzQ0WkY4aXJmRDlKcTNiTUs3bERya1F0Wk5SclUtUmN4bmVzRlc1eGFJZUJZR3lkZlRfb2dQOENEc2tlNUVBUC1mVHBwMmwtdi0tMllaMzFjeFdRcHR4QWFrZEJKOHVDYXMxUzR2RTMwZjR4YlpiNzNjVDdxUnh1ME5hRW9UdlJHUEdsaS1xcjd6S1hEWDI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxPSjdpUm42emkyMV80NFpGOGlyZkQ5SnEzYk1LN2xEcmtRdFpOUnJVLVJjeG5lc0ZXNXhhSWVCWUd5ZGZUX29nUDhDRHNrZTVFQVAtZlRwcDJsLXYtLTJZWjMxY3hXUXB0eEFha2RCSjh1Q2FzMVM0dkUzMGY0eGJaYjczY1Q3cVJ4dTBOYUVvVHZSR1BHbGktcXI3ektYRFgy0gGgAUFVX3lxTE9KN2lSbjZ6aTIxXzQ0WkY4aXJmRDlKcTNiTUs3bERya1F0Wk5SclUtUmN4bmVzRlc1eGFJZUJZR3lkZlRfb2dQOENEc2tlNUVBUC1mVHBwMmwtdi0tMllaMzFjeFdRcHR4QWFrZEJKOHVDYXMxUzR2RTMwZjR4YlpiNzNjVDdxUnh1ME5hRW9UdlJHUEdsaS1xcjd6S1hEWDI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:37:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yearender 2024: Asteroids, comets and other celestial events - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yearender 2024: Asteroids, comets and other celestial events</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> WION News</p>
<p>Stargazers experienced a thrilling year in 2024 with a plethora of celestial events, including meteor and asteroid strikes, eclipses, and a variety of comets that lit up the night sky.</p>
<img src="https://example.com/image.jpg" alt="Celestial Events Image">
<figcaption>Stargazers captured stunning views of various celestial events in 2024.</figcaption>
<ul>
  <li>The Great North American Eclipse on April 8 covered many states from Mexico to Newfoundland.</li>
  <li>Comet 12P/Pons–Brooks, known as the Devil Comet, made its closest approach on June 2.</li>
  <li>Comet 13P/Olbers had its closest approach to Earth on July 20, being the brightest comet at that time.</li>
  <li>Comet C/2023 A3 (Tsuchinshan–ATLAS) was highly anticipated and visible to the naked eye in October.</li>
  <li>Asteroids and meteorites struck various locations including South Africa and the Philippines, with significant sightings and reports.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It was similar to a rocky asteroid about the size of a car entering Earth's atmosphere at very high speed.” - Professor Roger Gibson</blockquote>
<p>This year was a remarkable one for astronomy enthusiasts as the multitude of celestial events captured widespread attention and provided stunning sights across the globe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/science-technology/incredible-celestial-events-asteroid-strikes-comets-2024-8573441</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/science-technology/incredible-celestial-events-asteroid-strikes-comets-2024-8573441</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:02:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How NASA's Parker Solar Probe got closer to the Sun than ever before on December 24? - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How NASA's Parker Solar Probe got closer to the Sun than ever before on December 24</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p><figure><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/nasa-3-1735386701.webp" alt="NASA" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>NASA</figcaption></figure><p>NASA's Parker Solar Probe is set to achieve a monumental milestone with its closest approach to the Sun on December 24, 2024, reaching just 6.1 million kilometers from the Sun's surface.</p><ul><li>This flyby marks the 22nd close encounter of the mission.</li><li>The probe will reach speeds of 692,000 kilometers per hour and study the Sun's corona.</li><li>NASA plans to provide updates post-flyby through its channels.</li><li>The mission will conclude in 2025 with a total of 24 solar encounters.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Parker Solar Probe will fly through the Sun's outer atmosphere, known as the corona, at an incredible speed of 692,000 kilometres per hour."</blockquote><p>This landmark flyby paves the way for future data collection during a period of intense solar activity expected throughout 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/science/how-nasa-s-parker-solar-probe-got-closer-to-the-sun-than-ever-before-on-december-24-2024-12-28-968367</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/science/how-nasa-s-parker-solar-probe-got-closer-to-the-sun-than-ever-before-on-december-24-2024-12-28-968367</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:54:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Majestic Images Of Black Holes Captured By NASA - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Majestic Images Of Black Holes Captured By NASA</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116741850/116741850.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=47552" alt="7 Majestic Images Of Black Holes Captured By NASA"><figcaption>Credit: ESA/NASA-the-AVO-project-and-Paolo-Padovani</figcaption><p>This article presents stunning imagery of black holes captured by NASA, highlighting groundbreaking discoveries in the field of astrophysics.</p><ul><li>A Dust-Bound Supermassive Black Hole surrounded by swirling debris.</li><li>A black hole releasing two bubbles of hot gas observed 900 million light-years away.</li><li>Illustration depicting the potential origins of supermassive black hole seeds.</li><li>Hubble imagery capturing ghostly green filaments within the Teacup galaxy.</li><li>An artistic portrayal of a binary black hole in the closest quasar to Earth.</li><li>Quasar energy impacting galaxy structures through high-speed material expulsion.</li><li>NGC 5548 exhibits unique behavior obstructing X-ray emissions from a supermassive black hole.</li></ul><blockquote>“These stunning images shed light on the complex behaviors of black holes and their interactions with surrounding galaxies.”</blockquote><p>These images not only enhance our understanding of black holes but also inspire curiosity and encourage further exploration in space science.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-majestic-images-of-black-holes-capturedbynasa/photostory/116741824.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-majestic-images-of-black-holes-capturedbynasa/photostory/116741824.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:40:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India to witness only one out of four eclipses in 2025 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India to witness only one out of four eclipses in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In 2025, India will only see one of the four solar and lunar eclipses that occur globally, making it a unique celestial event for the region.</p><ul><li>India will experience one out of four total eclipses in 2025.</li><li>This event attracts significant interest in astronomy and celestial phenomena.</li><li>Public awareness and participation in eclipse viewing is expected to increase.</li></ul><blockquote>“Eclipses can have a profound impact on astronomical observations and community engagement.”</blockquote><p>Overall, while the number of eclipses is limited for India in 2025, the anticipation surrounding the sole occurring eclipse presents an opportunity for educational outreach and public engagement in astronomy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-to-witness-only-one-out-of-four-eclipses-in-2025/articleshow/116741476.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-to-witness-only-one-out-of-four-eclipses-in-2025/articleshow/116741476.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Northern Lights Alert For 2025: Where And When To See Aurora In The U.S. And Europe - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/jamiecartereurope/2024/12/28/northern-lights-why-2025-will-be-a-good-year-for-the-us-and-europe/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/jamiecartereurope/2024/12/28/northern-lights-why-2025-will-be-a-good-year-for-the-us-and-europe/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starship, Europa Clipper and more: The top 10 spaceflight stories of 2024 - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Starship, Europa Clipper and more: The top 10 spaceflight stories of 2024</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/62aSz3WeKQNTS2hfiBrJzS.jpg" alt="SpaceX's Starship Flight 5 Super Heavy booster approaches its launch tower for the first-ever landing" /><figcaption>SpaceX's Starship Flight 5 Super Heavy booster approaches its launch tower for the first-ever landing and capture at the pad after launching on a suborbital test flight from Starbase in South Texas on Oct. 13, 2024. (Image credit: SpaceX)</figcaption><p>2024 was a landmark year for space exploration, marked by monumental events and breakthroughs in technology and collaboration.</p><ul><li>SpaceX captured the Super Heavy booster after launch, advancing reusability.</li><li>Intuitive Machines' Odysseus successfully landed on the moon.</li><li>Boeing's Starliner launched astronauts and encountered docking issues.</li><li>China's Chang'e 6 mission returned samples from the moon's far side.</li><li>NASA's Europa Clipper launched to explore Jupiter's icy moon.</li><li>Polaris Dawn executed the first private spacewalk.</li><li>Mars helicopter Ingenuity concluded its mission with significant achievements.</li><li>United Launch Alliance debuted the Vulcan Centaur rocket.</li><li>NASA cancelled the VIPER moon rover mission due to budget concerns.</li><li>Oleg Kononenko broke the record for the most time spent in space.</li></ul><blockquote>“2024 will be remembered as a special year for spaceflight.”</blockquote><p>This year solidified humanity's footprint in space with ambitious plans for the future of exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/space-exploration/missions/starship-europa-clipper-and-more-the-top-10-spaceflight-stories-of-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/space-exploration/missions/starship-europa-clipper-and-more-the-top-10-spaceflight-stories-of-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Northern Lights In 2025: Where And When To See Aurora In The U.S. And Europe - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/jamiecartereurope/2024/12/28/northern-lights-why-2025-will-be-a-good-year-for-the-us-and-europe/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/jamiecartereurope/2024/12/28/northern-lights-why-2025-will-be-a-good-year-for-the-us-and-europe/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>