<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:23:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 14:23:07 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Dragon Cargo Capsule Returns to Earth After CRS-31 Mission - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaceX Dragon Cargo Capsule Returns to Earth After CRS-31 Mission</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Daso04jdMEY/hqdefault.jpg" alt="SpaceX Dragon Cargo Capsule Video"><figcaption>Play Video</figcaption><p>SpaceX's Dragon cargo capsule successfully undocked from the ISS and is set to return to Earth carrying valuable research materials.</p><ul><li>The capsule undocked on December 16 and is expected to splash down on December 17.</li><li>CRS-31's return cargo includes experimental specimens critical for microgravity research.</li><li>The Dragon capsule is the only cargo spacecraft that can safely return scientific materials to Earth.</li><li>The astronauts aboard the ISS have had their mission extended due to technical complications.</li><li>Nasa will rapidly retrieve the Dragon capsule post-splashdown to preserve integral experiments.</li></ul><blockquote>“The recovered cargo will be transported to NASA's Systems Processing Facility for further examination.”</blockquote><p>This mission highlights the ongoing collaboration between commercial spaceflight and scientific research, showcasing significant advancements in space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/spacex-dragon-cargo-capsule-returns-to-earth-after-crs-31-mission-7268683</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/spacex-dragon-cargo-capsule-returns-to-earth-after-crs-31-mission-7268683</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA schedules return of Starliner crew in March - Daily Excelsior]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxQU2tXVzVudUh4Xy1wM2w1S1ltanZxTWt5WUpWZVVtRkFuM3R3NzJvWnc1czF5M01lNnlzNENNeUNGMzA1aDA2ZDk5SFZEWEItdDlQdUZfNi10WFo2RVhwSnRnRE1QUGdnb3RyeFFOZ1o1NnEzOFFoeHJ4cmhrZHdJS0RxSmIyQ1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxQU2tXVzVudUh4Xy1wM2w1S1ltanZxTWt5WUpWZVVtRkFuM3R3NzJvWnc1czF5M01lNnlzNENNeUNGMzA1aDA2ZDk5SFZEWEItdDlQdUZfNi10WFo2RVhwSnRnRE1QUGdnb3RyeFFOZ1o1NnEzOFFoeHJ4cmhrZHdJS0RxSmIyQ1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:09:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A World-First Discovery - Twin Stars Trapped Orbiting Galactic Black Hole - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A World-First Discovery - Twin Stars Trapped Orbiting Galactic Black Hole</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today | <strong>Source:</strong> Nature Communications</p><figure><img src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/638040/original/file-20241212-15-p7npn9.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip" alt="A bright galaxy overlaid with a cutout of a red and black image of a binary star system."><figcaption><small><em><span>This image indicates the location of the newly discovered binary star D9, which is orbiting Sagittarius A*, the supermassive black hole at the centre of our galaxy.</span> <span><a href="https://press.springernature.com/a-binary-system-in-the-s-cluster-close-to-the-supermassive-black/50286972">F. Peißker et al., S. Guisard/ESO</a></span></em></small></figcaption></figure><p>A team of astronomers led by Florian Peißker from the University of Cologne has made a groundbreaking discovery of a binary star system, named D9, orbiting the supermassive black hole Sagittarius A* at the centre of our Milky Way galaxy. This discovery enhances our understanding of the extreme environment surrounding black holes and provides insight into the behavior of hypervelocity stars.</p><ul><li>First detection of a binary star system near a supermassive black hole.</li><li>Binary star D9 orbits Sagittarius A* and is approximately 2.7 million years old.</li><li>Discovery helps explain why some stars move through space faster than others.</li><li>The data gathered could help unravel the nature of black holes.</li></ul><blockquote>“This discovery sheds light on the extreme environment at the centre of our Milky Way galaxy.”</blockquote><p>This discovery not only adds to the understanding of black holes but also aids in solving cosmic mysteries such as the origin of hypervelocity stars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-world-first-discovery-twin-stars-trapped-orbiting-supermassive-black-hole-7277795</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-world-first-discovery-twin-stars-trapped-orbiting-supermassive-black-hole-7277795</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:58:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Binary Star Detected Near Supermassive Black Hole - AZoQuantum]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Binary Star Detected Near a Supermassive Black Hole</h1><p><strong>Date: January 5, 2024 & Source: Nature Communications</strong></p><figure><img src="https://dwg31ai31okv0.cloudfront.net/images/news/ImageForNews_10680_17345189168262459.jpg" alt="First Binary Star Detected Near Supermassive Black Hole" width="1280" height="733"><figcaption><em>Location of binary star D9 in the Milky Way. Image Credit: European Southern Observatory</em></figcaption></figure><p>An international team of researchers has identified a binary star system orbiting near Sagittarius A*, the supermassive black hole at the center of the Milky Way galaxy. This study provides valuable insight into how stars can survive in intense gravitational environments.</p><ul><li>This is the first documented discovery of a stellar pair near a supermassive black hole.</li><li>The newly identified binary star D9 is about 2.7 million years old.</li><li>The D9 system is expected to merge into a single star within one million years due to the gravitational pull of Sagittarius A*.</li><li>This discovery challenges previous beliefs that new stars cannot form near supermassive black holes.</li><li>The identification of young stars suggests that stellar pairs can form even in extreme conditions.</li></ul><blockquote><p><em>“Black holes are not as destructive as we thought.”</em> - Florian Peißker, Study Lead Author</p></blockquote><p>The team used the European Southern Observatory’s Very Large Telescope to make this groundbreaking discovery. Upcoming advancements in telescope technology promise to further explore the nature of these young stellar systems.</p><blockquote><p><em>“Our discovery lets us speculate about the presence of planets since these are often formed around young stars.”</em> - Florian Peißker</p></blockquote><p>This breakthrough lays the groundwork for future research into the surrounding environments of supermassive black holes and the potential existence of planets in these regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.azoquantum.com/News.aspx?newsID=10680</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.azoquantum.com/News.aspx?newsID=10680</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US faces risk of losing to China in second moon race - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Faces Risk of Losing to China in Second Moon Race</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> December 18, 2024 05:02 pm IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Conversation</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/m3js0i/article69000213.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/China_Space_02609.jpg" alt="Chinese astronauts for the Shenzhou-18 mission, from right, Ye Guangfu, Li Cong, and Li Guangsu wave as they attend a send-off ceremony for their manned space mission at the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center in northwestern China, April 25, 2024." title="Chinese astronauts for the Shenzhou-18 mission, from right, Ye Guangfu, Li Cong, and Li Guangsu wave as they attend a send-off ceremony for their manned space mission at the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center in northwestern China, April 25, 2024.">
<figcaption>Chinese astronauts for the Shenzhou-18 mission, from right, Ye Guangfu, Li Cong, and Li Guangsu wave as they attend a send-off ceremony for their manned space mission.</figcaption>
<p>As both the US and China prepare to return humans to the Moon, the US lunar program faces delays, while China is projected to land astronauts by 2030. This article explores the implications of a potential new Moon race and the challenges both nations face.</p>
<ul>
<li>12 Americans landed on the Moon between 1969 and 1972.</li>
<li>The US lunar program is behind schedule due to unprepared equipment.</li>
<li>China intends to land astronauts on the Moon by 2030, backed by a smooth-running space program.</li>
<li>Nasa's Artemis program aims to land humans on the Moon by 2026, with several milestones including Artemis I and II.</li>
<li>Critics suggest Artemis is overly complicated compared to China’s direct approach.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Rushing back to the Moon could be costly, both financially and in the risk to human life.”</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming Moon missions highlight competitive international space efforts and the importance of responsible exploration principles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/us-faces-risk-of-losing-to-china-in-second-moon-race/article69000225.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/us-faces-risk-of-losing-to-china-in-second-moon-race/article69000225.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[InSight Lander studying ‘dust devils’ on Mars, spotted dead by NASA orbiter - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>InSight Lander studying ‘dust devils’ on Mars, spotted dead by NASA orbiter</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116435667,imgsize-18078,width-400,resizemode-4/116435667.jpg" alt="InSight Lander studying ‘dust devils’ on Mars, spotted dead by NASA orbiter"><figcaption>InSight Lander on Mars</figcaption><p>The InSight lander has successfully studied dust devils on Mars before concluding its mission, as observed by NASA’s Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter. The end of its mission was marked by the inability to regain contact due to dust accumulation on its solar panels.</p><ul><li>The InSight lander focused on Mars' internal structure and seismic activity.</li><li>NASA's MRO captured InSight's last images showing dust accumulation on its solar panels.</li><li>Despite attempts, communication has been lost, with efforts to reconnect set to end in 2024.</li><li>Dust devils play a significant role in Martian climate and surface dynamics.</li></ul><blockquote>“Even though we’re no longer hearing from InSight, it’s still teaching us about Mars.” - Ingrid Daubar, Brown University</blockquote><p>The legacy of InSight’s findings on dust and Mars' climate will continue to inform future missions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/insight-lander-studying-dust-devils-on-mars-spotted-dead-by-nasa-orbiter/articleshow/116435187.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/insight-lander-studying-dust-devils-on-mars-spotted-dead-by-nasa-orbiter/articleshow/116435187.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experts reveal new world magnetic model, predict how Earth’s magnetic field will shift in 5 years - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/experts-reveal-new-world-magnetic-model-predict-how-earth-s-magnetic-field-will-shift-in-5-years-article-12892980.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/experts-reveal-new-world-magnetic-model-predict-how-earth-s-magnetic-field-will-shift-in-5-years-article-12892980.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:49:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Primates often gave birth to twins 60M years ago: new research - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxNVFZVZlBnT05DTGxMNXZHU2lkQWlVdElDaDJMajE3UVB2V3Rmc3FNTkFtZ05mM0NoWXZqYnlTZnk0enlnX1YySWNCenJiM1JWT3ZRVS1NVWpHRi1uYmJiRGFmSzZUN1VFT2JzVE1EWlBwdFFqVE9HQURKcVNzVklHY1pWX0JZZlJneUNrc1Rray1RM25vUC1EMnBRbVpLRXJlZjBnTVJwNU1xdm4wS1ByZ3JQeGdMQzBfaWJCX3VxSFDSAccBQVVfeXFMTlBqVlcxTjJueE5UMFE0U0kyQVoxLXZnZ2lSaDNQT0JLZC1BbDRBQ3Itd19UbHl5T2M3UlV5Ym0zMnZpdU9FRW1YR1RjdVNXMDZhY0VIdkd0cWJUSmxoZmtoZFdhVmloYW9FNUxoQlR0QTFhbmRTNTY0SUdkNTVvd0R3OGdBbnlCRUtyYTMzUGlSaGs0aEFHVTZ2VXdLeTN1X1M1RTRmUi1hZGxzeVRuSTRSa0RNa05DVFAtU0RVY1N0MjhDdnFIYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxNVFZVZlBnT05DTGxMNXZHU2lkQWlVdElDaDJMajE3UVB2V3Rmc3FNTkFtZ05mM0NoWXZqYnlTZnk0enlnX1YySWNCenJiM1JWT3ZRVS1NVWpHRi1uYmJiRGFmSzZUN1VFT2JzVE1EWlBwdFFqVE9HQURKcVNzVklHY1pWX0JZZlJneUNrc1Rray1RM25vUC1EMnBRbVpLRXJlZjBnTVJwNU1xdm4wS1ByZ3JQeGdMQzBfaWJCX3VxSFDSAccBQVVfeXFMTlBqVlcxTjJueE5UMFE0U0kyQVoxLXZnZ2lSaDNQT0JLZC1BbDRBQ3Itd19UbHl5T2M3UlV5Ym0zMnZpdU9FRW1YR1RjdVNXMDZhY0VIdkd0cWJUSmxoZmtoZFdhVmloYW9FNUxoQlR0QTFhbmRTNTY0SUdkNTVvd0R3OGdBbnlCRUtyYTMzUGlSaGs0aEFHVTZ2VXdLeTN1X1M1RTRmUi1hZGxzeVRuSTRSa0RNa05DVFAtU0RVY1N0MjhDdnFIYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA alert! Giant 84-foot asteroid 2024 XS3 to pass Earth today; will the asteroid collide? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Alert: Giant 84-Foot Asteroid 2024 XS3 Passes Earth Safely</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116434652,imgsize-49122,width-400,resizemode-4/116434652.jpg" alt="NASA alert! Giant 84-foot asteroid 2024 XS3 to pass Earth today; will the asteroid collide?" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>A giant 84-foot asteroid 2024 XS3 passing Earth.</figcaption><p>Today, the Apollo NEO asteroid, 2024 XS3, will safely pass Earth at a distance of approximately 3.3 million kilometers. Discovered on December 3, 2024, it poses no collision risk.</p><ul><li>The asteroid follows an elliptical orbit with a perihelion of 0.89 AU and an aphelion of 2.58 AU.</li><li>It is part of the Apollo asteroid group, taking approximately 833 days to complete one revolution around the Sun.</li><li>Scientists assure that after today, 2024 XS3 won't come closer than 45 million kilometers until 2027.</li><li>Asteroids like 2024 XS3 hold vital information about the solar system's formation.</li><li>NASA monitors Near-Earth Objects using advanced radar systems to track potential threats.</li><li>Ongoing efforts include missions aimed to detect and deflect hazardous asteroids.</li></ul><blockquote>"Asteroid 2024 XS3 serves as a reminder of the importance of asteroid monitoring and planetary defense."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while this encounter presents no threat, it highlights the ongoing need for monitoring of NEOs to ensure Earth's safety from future cosmic dangers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-alert-giant-84-foot-asteroid-2024-xs3-to-pass-earth-today-will-the-asteroid-collide/articleshow/116434446.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-alert-giant-84-foot-asteroid-2024-xs3-to-pass-earth-today-will-the-asteroid-collide/articleshow/116434446.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA alert: 84-foot asteroid to pass close to Earth today - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Alert: 84-foot Asteroid to Pass Close to Earth Today</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>NASA has issued a warning regarding the imminent close approach of an 84-foot asteroid to Earth.</p><ul><li>The asteroid is expected to pass within a safe distance.</li><li>This event highlights the ongoing monitoring of near-Earth objects by NASA.</li><li>Similar events have occurred before, where asteroids have closely approached Earth without any threat.</li></ul><blockquote>"This demonstrates the importance of our global efforts to monitor and track these objects," stated a NASA spokesperson.</blockquote><p>While the asteroid poses no danger to Earth, this event serves as a reminder of the importance of planetary defense measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/nasa-alert-84-foot-asteroid-to-pass-close-to-earth-today/articleshow/116434559.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/nasa-alert-84-foot-asteroid-to-pass-close-to-earth-today/articleshow/116434559.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 10:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fate of human survival beyond Earth: This mice-sperm experiment could reveal if humans can reproduce in... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/fate-of-human-survival-beyond-earth-this-mice-sperm-experiment-could-reveal-if-humans-can-reproduce-in-space-article-12892952.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/fate-of-human-survival-beyond-earth-this-mice-sperm-experiment-could-reveal-if-humans-can-reproduce-in-space-article-12892952.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 09:50:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Before living on the moon, get ready to call a submarine your home - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Before Living on the Moon, Get Ready to Call a Submarine Your Home</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/living-in-submarine-183305140-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=LxFr_SxMzIOVyl8HVgkGCJbhwXTUu0zh&amp;size=690:388" alt="Living in submarine" title="A scientific team from universities in Germany, Italy and Portugal is studying how stress, mood and crew dynamics evolve in cramped quarters. (Photo: ESA)"><figcaption>A scientific team from universities in Germany, Italy and Portugal is studying how stress, mood and crew dynamics evolve in cramped quarters. (Photo: ESA)</figcaption><p>The first crew of the SubSea project has completed a 60-day underwater expedition aimed at studying human adaptation to extreme environments, mimicking the conditions of space travel.</p><ul><li>The SubSea project is a collaboration involving ESA, the Portuguese Space Agency, and the Portuguese Navy.</li><li>25 volunteers lived in cramped quarters to simulate astronaut conditions.</li><li>The data collected will inform strategies for future human spaceflight missions.</li></ul><blockquote>“SubSea is an essential initiative to understand human resilience in extreme environments.” - ESA astronaut Andreas Mogensen</blockquote><p>This project marks a significant advance in preparing for future explorations to the Moon and Mars, leveraging Portugal's unique research capabilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/before-living-on-the-moon-get-ready-to-call-a-submarine-your-home-2651698-2024-12-18</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/before-living-on-the-moon-get-ready-to-call-a-submarine-your-home-2651698-2024-12-18</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 09:39:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China astronauts script history with world’s longest spacewalk, break US record. Check details - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China astronauts script history with world’s longest spacewalk, break US record</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Tuesday, [Insert Date]</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> South China Morning Post</p><figure><img height="488" width="650" alt="Chinese astronauts complete 9 hour spacewalk" src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116429522,width-650,height-488,imgsize-1794449,resizemode-75/chinese-astronauts-complete-9-hour-spacewalk.jpg"><figcaption>China says two of its astronauts completed a nine-hour spacewalk, a figure that beats the US-held record for the world’s longest spacewalk set in 2001</figcaption></figure><p>In a significant milestone, Chinese astronauts Cai Xuzhe and Song Lingdong have completed a nine-hour extravehicular activity, setting a new world record and surpassing a 22-year-old record held by the United States.</p><ul><li>Chinese astronauts set a new record for the longest single spacewalk at nine hours.</li><li>The previous record of eight hours and 56 minutes was held by US astronauts James Voss and Susan Helms.</li><li>This achievement is part of China’s broader efforts to enhance its space program and compete on a global scale.</li><li>China's space program has recently seen significant advancements, including lunar missions and complex spacewalks.</li></ul><blockquote>“Both the astronauts were supported by crewmate Wang Haozhe, who remained inside the station.”</blockquote><p>This accomplishment marks a significant step forward in China's ambitions in space exploration, showcasing its technological advancements and reinforcing its position in the international space race.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/global-trends/china-astronauts-cai-xuzhe-song-lingdong-script-history-with-worlds-longest-nine-hour-spacewalk-break-us-record/articleshow/116429271.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/global-trends/china-astronauts-cai-xuzhe-song-lingdong-script-history-with-worlds-longest-nine-hour-spacewalk-break-us-record/articleshow/116429271.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 08:16:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronauts celebrating Christmas in space in 10 pictures - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronauts Celebrating Christmas in Space</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p>
<img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2024/12/cropped-Ge8sMAkWcAAA52CITG-1734506816878-scaled-1.jpg" alt="Astronauts in Space Celebrating Christmas">
<figcaption>Astronauts aboard the International Space Station celebrating Christmas.</figcaption>
<p>The Expedition 61 crew is celebrating Christmas aboard the International Space Station (ISS), showcasing festive decorations and camaraderie among astronauts from NASA, ESA, and Roscosmos.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Decked out the ISS with stockings, candles, and tree banners.</li>
  <li>Crew members engage in shared celebrations, including Thanksgiving gatherings.</li>
  <li>Notable images capture memorable moments of astronauts enjoying meals and festivities.</li>
  <li>Expedition crews come together for various holiday celebrations, highlighting the spirit of unity in space.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Expedition 70 astronauts gather for Christmas Eve celebrations inside the ISS Unity module.”</blockquote>
<p>This Christmas celebration showcases not only the festivities of the crew but also symbolizes the spirit of cooperation among international space agencies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/science/astronauts-celebrating-christmas-in-space-in-10-pictures-195399-18-12-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/science/astronauts-celebrating-christmas-in-space-in-10-pictures-195399-18-12-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 07:47:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nasa pushes back Sunita Williams' return, mission now set for Spring 2025 - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/nasa-sunita-williams-space-mission-iss-starliner-spring-2025-124121800464_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/nasa-sunita-williams-space-mission-iss-starliner-spring-2025-124121800464_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:53:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Urgent Asteroid Alert: Huge 84-foot, asteroid is heading towards Earth at high speed today, NASA confirms - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/urgent-asteroid-alert-huge-84-foot-asteroid-is-heading-towards-earth-at-high-speed-today-nasa-confirms-article-12891966.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/urgent-asteroid-alert-huge-84-foot-asteroid-is-heading-towards-earth-at-high-speed-today-nasa-confirms-article-12891966.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 06:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 stunning images of space discoveries captured by NASA James Webb Space Telescope - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Stunning Images of Space Discoveries Captured by NASA's James Webb Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> HT TECH</p>
<img src="https://images.hindustantimes.com/tech/img/2024/12/18/900x1600/gea275a82151bad5d7f3886a458d5314f5b506a7346f42c8e7_1734493957068_1734493957237.jpg" alt="Space Discovery Image" />
<figcaption>NASA's James Webb Space Telescope captures breathtaking images of deep space.</figcaption>
<p>This article highlights five remarkable discoveries made by NASA's James Webb Space Telescope, showcasing the incredible images captured that reveal the beauty and mystery of our universe.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Webb image of quasar RX J1131-1231 located 6 billion light-years away.</li>
  <li>Captures of the inner Orion Nebula and Trapezium Cluster, spanning 4 light years.</li>
  <li>Near-infrared observations of Saturn providing insights into its orbital characteristics.</li>
  <li>Discovery of supernovae SN 1987A located in the Large Magellanic Cloud at a distance of 168,000 light-years.</li>
  <li>Galaxy Pair VV 191 imagery, showcasing the power of Webb and Hubble together.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“NASA James Webb Space Telescope is one such powerful observatory which has been a part of several unique discoveries.”</blockquote>
<p>These stunning images not only demonstrate the capabilities of the James Webb Space Telescope but also highlight the ongoing exploration and discovery in the field of astronomy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tech.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/5-stunning-images-of-space-discoveries-captured-by-nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-71734493711882.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tech.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/5-stunning-images-of-space-discoveries-captured-by-nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-71734493711882.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 04:03:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s InSight Mars lander: New HiRISE image reveals dusty resting place on the red planet - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s InSight Mars Lander Captured in New HiRISE Image Reveals Dusty Resting Place on the Red Planet</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/insight-lander-mars-1734494008.webp" alt="NASA’s InSight Mars lander" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>NASA’s InSight Mars lander</figcaption>
<p>The InSight Mars lander has been observed in a new image captured by the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter, showing it covered in Martian dust, highlighting dust movement and wind patterns on Mars.</p>
<ul>
<li>The InSight lander landed on Mars in November 2018 and studied the planet's seismic activity and internal structure.</li>
<li>The mission officially ended in December 2022 due to dust accumulation on its solar panels.</li>
<li>NASA's monitoring operations are expected to conclude by the end of 2024.</li>
<li>The recent HiRISE image helps researchers understand the Martian dust cycle and wind dynamics.</li>
<li>Dust accumulation has altered surface features, including the fading of geological marks made by InSight's landing thrusters.</li>
<li>The Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter continues to provide crucial data for current and future Mars missions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The latest image of InSight may mark the lander’s silent legacy, but it continues to contribute to our understanding of the dusty mysteries of Mars.” - NASA</blockquote>
<p>This observation not only preserves the legacy of the InSight lander but also plays a critical role in preparing for future exploration missions on Mars.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/science/nasa-s-insight-mars-lander-new-hirise-image-reveals-dusty-resting-place-on-the-red-planet-2024-12-18-966764</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/science/nasa-s-insight-mars-lander-new-hirise-image-reveals-dusty-resting-place-on-the-red-planet-2024-12-18-966764</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 03:55:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US News Live Today December 18, 2024: Bad news for Sunita Williams, Butch Wilmore: Space rescue mission delayed again - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNUEdzQ0pjdk1PZTJvcHBIdFAyQXZ6bWhVWjNOdzVjNUVKcmJqODlMc19WaFRxX1dkVGVKMkRxSlBoYUJUajdKa1U0MWkwZ2tEUzlzZjNfazNqNzFmdTNYc0l1bEg0Q3UtaXBJOWZDbjFwOHFuQkxna3BGYjNCaDZySWUzSlNzcUdUalJIYVNhTkMySUpoMGtuYzFDLTIxbng1R2RWQ2l3X3hEejdBeVdCSVI5QU45Z9IBuwFBVV95cUxPUVNXQWlpRVRGNnpXVUZHLWlBYjBSNmVaOWJIblVuX3Q3dGktVTJoVGhhelhUWHRoV2hOWnc4eHdtTUpuM3Z1MjJHR3AzSU1mSGkwVmhGUmVVVnlXTmJaMlY3NHA1WEtiNDJLeHQ2ZHBMU3dwajE2ZkZBRnRmek4zZ0FUTnExSlcxOUNhSFd0UzBWS3JoU0ItUE9obGsxQ2JVbTZvNUNQeHFpYXk4UnZpZERlZXpWbjJrR0xZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNUEdzQ0pjdk1PZTJvcHBIdFAyQXZ6bWhVWjNOdzVjNUVKcmJqODlMc19WaFRxX1dkVGVKMkRxSlBoYUJUajdKa1U0MWkwZ2tEUzlzZjNfazNqNzFmdTNYc0l1bEg0Q3UtaXBJOWZDbjFwOHFuQkxna3BGYjNCaDZySWUzSlNzcUdUalJIYVNhTkMySUpoMGtuYzFDLTIxbng1R2RWQ2l3X3hEejdBeVdCSVI5QU45Z9IBuwFBVV95cUxPUVNXQWlpRVRGNnpXVUZHLWlBYjBSNmVaOWJIblVuX3Q3dGktVTJoVGhhelhUWHRoV2hOWnc4eHdtTUpuM3Z1MjJHR3AzSU1mSGkwVmhGUmVVVnlXTmJaMlY3NHA1WEtiNDJLeHQ2ZHBMU3dwajE2ZkZBRnRmek4zZ0FUTnExSlcxOUNhSFd0UzBWS3JoU0ItUE9obGsxQ2JVbTZvNUNQeHFpYXk4UnZpZERlZXpWbjJrR0xZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 03:16:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can humans have babies in space? Current mice sperm experiment may provide insights into human life beyon - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can humans have babies in space? Current mice sperm experiment may provide insights into human life beyond Earth</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Not provided]</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> [Not provided]</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116408887,imgsize-45748,width-400,resizemode-4/116408887.jpg" alt="Can humans have babies in space? Current mice sperm experiment may provide insights into human life beyond Earth" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Can humans have babies in space? Current mice sperm experiment may provide insights into human life beyond Earth</figcaption><p>As ambitions for interplanetary colonization grow, researchers are exploring whether humans can reproduce in space. A new experiment involving freeze-dried mouse sperm aims to uncover how space conditions affect reproduction.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Japanese researchers are studying mouse sperm stored on the ISS to analyze its viability after space exposure in 2025.</li><li>The findings could inform human reproduction capabilities in space environments.</li><li>Previous studies have focused on various species, revealing complexities in reproduction in microgravity.</li><li>Challenges include the effects of gravity on development and potential genetic damage from radiation.</li><li>Innovative IVF techniques are being developed for microgravity.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes:</h2><blockquote>“If reproduction works in space, it will reassure humanity. If it doesn’t, we need solutions.” - Professor Teruhiko Wakayama</blockquote><p>Understanding reproduction in space is vital for future human settlements on the moon and Mars, impacting biodiversity preservation and societal survival in extraterrestrial environments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/can-humans-have-babies-in-space-current-mice-sperm-experiment-may-provide-insights-into-human-life-beyond-earth/articleshow/116408793.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/can-humans-have-babies-in-space-current-mice-sperm-experiment-may-provide-insights-into-human-life-beyond-earth/articleshow/116408793.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Viral images of celestial bodies by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxNTXd6TnM3UVRXcVpmVk9LNlpUMm5KU2t1OWFYcnJoQ2FCQ1IxRnppUTRzVEJWU01KNU5OYk42WnBWb3cxaW9rVDg3SVNzb05KaEdxYjl2cFA4VnBTclVILW4wQ2RrNUFwdWpzMkFhRVJ3NGgzQURtay1jRjlMb1g5UnpaWWV4bXFqLVMxTy1id3Z1bVlicDdzeTc0MkZSQ0hKNnZfbm1KeUREMFAwTlBiV0VCd9IBswFBVV95cUxNTXd6TnM3UVRXcVpmVk9LNlpUMm5KU2t1OWFYcnJoQ2FCQ1IxRnppUTRzVEJWU01KNU5OYk42WnBWb3cxaW9rVDg3SVNzb05KaEdxYjl2cFA4VnBTclVILW4wQ2RrNUFwdWpzMkFhRVJ3NGgzQURtay1jRjlMb1g5UnpaWWV4bXFqLVMxTy1id3Z1bVlicDdzeTc0MkZSQ0hKNnZfbm1KeUREMFAwTlBiV0VCdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxNTXd6TnM3UVRXcVpmVk9LNlpUMm5KU2t1OWFYcnJoQ2FCQ1IxRnppUTRzVEJWU01KNU5OYk42WnBWb3cxaW9rVDg3SVNzb05KaEdxYjl2cFA4VnBTclVILW4wQ2RrNUFwdWpzMkFhRVJ3NGgzQURtay1jRjlMb1g5UnpaWWV4bXFqLVMxTy1id3Z1bVlicDdzeTc0MkZSQ0hKNnZfbm1KeUREMFAwTlBiV0VCd9IBswFBVV95cUxNTXd6TnM3UVRXcVpmVk9LNlpUMm5KU2t1OWFYcnJoQ2FCQ1IxRnppUTRzVEJWU01KNU5OYk42WnBWb3cxaW9rVDg3SVNzb05KaEdxYjl2cFA4VnBTclVILW4wQ2RrNUFwdWpzMkFhRVJ3NGgzQURtay1jRjlMb1g5UnpaWWV4bXFqLVMxTy1id3Z1bVlicDdzeTc0MkZSQ0hKNnZfbm1KeUREMFAwTlBiV0VCdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 01:22:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Viral images of celestial bodies by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.Com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Viral Images of Celestial Bodies by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>This article presents stunning viral images captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, showcasing celestial bodies and their intricate details.</p><ul><li>FS Tau is a multi-star system featuring FS Tau A and FS Tau B.</li><li>The bright star-like object FS Tau A is prominently positioned in the center of the image.</li><li>FS Tau B is situated to the right, obscured by a dark vertical lane of dust.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-viral-images-of-celestial-bodies-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7473230/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-viral-images-of-celestial-bodies-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7473230/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 01:12:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why it is time for the Moon - The Federal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxQUnhrS0xVbkZlY3FEdUdYVzdxT3ZXTmpBUjdfN25lckhkN3Z5dkZJWWdxb0JCVUJRYkVkZDFkTVBPVUR4UnNDcGE0UUREMmc2N0t0YmphS0E2dW9TZl8zWExMSTdoNUYtLXJ6NlIzWjlfS2JpYkJNbWplYnViWERTMTlTUy16QlR0NHd6WNIBkgFBVV95cUxQV0NkTUwyZXpTQ21lWHpXb2JPNVZUZm5GbHNleF9CcU1xTWZiWXlibUJUeDloSTNCZ2V5T2JZS3NqZVZrNGhfOXAwSk5JdE5JNDlLdGxZblR4OVFVN2l3M0JJSHMwVUJ1cjRaSVpWUVc2bjEyZFpDZXp3X2lJQjBibEZ3Z0JqSkc0d2xiejcyVHMwQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxQUnhrS0xVbkZlY3FEdUdYVzdxT3ZXTmpBUjdfN25lckhkN3Z5dkZJWWdxb0JCVUJRYkVkZDFkTVBPVUR4UnNDcGE0UUREMmc2N0t0YmphS0E2dW9TZl8zWExMSTdoNUYtLXJ6NlIzWjlfS2JpYkJNbWplYnViWERTMTlTUy16QlR0NHd6WNIBkgFBVV95cUxQV0NkTUwyZXpTQ21lWHpXb2JPNVZUZm5GbHNleF9CcU1xTWZiWXlibUJUeDloSTNCZ2V5T2JZS3NqZVZrNGhfOXAwSk5JdE5JNDlLdGxZblR4OVFVN2l3M0JJSHMwVUJ1cjRaSVpWUVc2bjEyZFpDZXp3X2lJQjBibEZ3Z0JqSkc0d2xiejcyVHMwQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 01:00:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Researchers introduce Boltz-1, a fully open-source model for predicting biomolecular structures - Nanowerk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nanowerk.com/news2/biotech/newsid=66187.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nanowerk.com/news2/biotech/newsid=66187.php</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 22:37:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black hole genealogy: A new way to discover 'ancestors' of cosmic phenomena - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-12-black-hole-genealogy-ancestors-cosmic.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2024-12-black-hole-genealogy-ancestors-cosmic.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 19:11:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX’s 31st Dragon cargo capsule returns to Earth with splashdown off Florida coast - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaceX’s 31st Dragon cargo capsule returns to Earth with splashdown off Florida coast</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p><p>SpaceX's 31st robotic cargo mission has successfully returned to Earth.</p><img src='URL_of_main_image' alt='SpaceX Dragon capsule' /><figcaption>The CRS-31 Dragon capsule splashed down off the Florida coast.</figcaption><p>The Dragon cargo capsule splashed down off the Florida coast at 1:39 p.m. EDT, bringing back thousands of pounds of equipment and experiment specimens from the International Space Station (ISS).</p><ul><li>The capsule is the only ISS cargo spacecraft capable of returning equipment and experiments safely to Earth.</li><li>It launched from NASA's Kennedy Space Center on Nov. 4, delivering about 6,000 pounds of supplies for astronauts aboard the ISS.</li><li>The astronauts onboard include NASA’s Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams, who had extended stays due to complications with the Boeing Starliner mission.</li><li>The delivered cargo included fresh food, research equipment, and personal items for the astronauts.</li></ul><blockquote>NASA will retrieve the CRS-31 Dragon spacecraft relatively quickly to continue research in the post-microgravity environment.</blockquote><p>This successful splashdown reaffirms the reliability of SpaceX's cargo missions and their importance in supporting ISS operations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/space-exploration/international-space-station/spacexs-31st-dragon-cargo-capsule-departs-iss-to-head-home-to-earth</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/space-exploration/international-space-station/spacexs-31st-dragon-cargo-capsule-departs-iss-to-head-home-to-earth</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 19:00:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists warn of ‘unprecedented’ risks of research into mirror life - CNN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/16/science/mirror-bacteria-research-risks/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/16/science/mirror-bacteria-research-risks/index.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 18:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Straight From a Sci-Fi Movie: Scientists Capture First-Ever Close-Up Image of a Dying Star From Another Galaxy! - Indian Defence Review]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Capture First-Ever Close-Up Image of a Dying Star From Another Galaxy</h1> <p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2024-12-17T13:10:51-05:00">December 17, 2024</time> | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Defence Review</p> <figure><img width="1980" height="1200" src="https://indiandefencereview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/An-artists-reconstruction-of-WOH-G64-depicts-the-star-at-the-center-of-its-dusty-gassy-cocoon.jpg" alt="An artist’s reconstruction of WOH G64 depicts the star at the center of its dusty, gassy cocoon."><figcaption>Straight From a Sci-Fi Movie: Scientists Capture First-Ever Close-Up Image of a Dying Star From Another Galaxy! - © Indian Defence Review</figcaption></figure> <p>Astronomers have achieved a groundbreaking milestone by capturing the first-ever close-up image of a star outside of our Milky Way galaxy, <strong>WOH G64</strong>. Located approximately <strong>160,000 light-years away</strong> in the <strong>Large Magellanic Cloud</strong>, this new image reveals details about a star that could be on the verge of a <strong>supernova</strong> explosion.</p> <ul> <li>WOH G64 is a supergiant star, around 1,500 times the size of the Sun.</li> <li>Astronomers suggest it may explode in 10,000 to 100,000 years.</li> <li>Keiichi Ohnaka commented on the slow pace of stellar evolution, noting the star's significant dimming.</li> <li>The image was taken using the European Southern Observatory’s Very Large Telescope Interferometer.</li> <li>This discovery enhances understanding of the lifecycle of stars and the processes leading to supernovae.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“Just before, in an astronomical sense. Not today or next week or next year.” - Keiichi Ohnaka</blockquote> <p>This extraordinary breakthrough allows for observations of <strong>supernova</strong> processes, providing vital clues that may enrich our understanding of stellar deaths and the cosmic elements they create.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indiandefencereview.com/scientists-capture-lose-up-image-of-a-dying-star/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiandefencereview.com/scientists-capture-lose-up-image-of-a-dying-star/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 18:10:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 Stunning Space Images Released by NASA in 2024 - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Stunning Space Images Released by NASA in 2024</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> WION</p><img src="https://images1.wionews.com/images/wion/900x1600/2024/12/17/1734458545909_4.jpg" alt="Stunning Space Images" /><figcaption>A stunning collection of space images released by NASA capturing incredible cosmic phenomena.</figcaption><p>This article presents a selection of breathtaking space images taken by NASA's James Webb Space Telescope, showcasing various astronomical wonders.</p><ul><li><strong>NGC 628:</strong> A spiral galaxy located 32 million light-years away, featuring a densely populated star region amidst bright orange gas.</li><li><strong>Duo of Starbursts in I Zwicky 18:</strong> An irregular dwarf galaxy that highlights two star formation regions surrounded by hot gas bubbles.</li><li><strong>Horsehead Nebula:</strong> A stunning cloud of dust and gas, ideal for studying star interactions.</li><li><strong>The Crab Nebula:</strong> A remnant of a supernova explosion, home to a neutron star radiating energy.</li><li><strong>Orion Nebula:</strong> Captured using both Chandra and Webb telescopes, showcasing a prominent star formation region.</li><li><strong>Rho Ophiuchi:</strong> A composite image illustrating a complex gas and star region located approximately 390 light-years away.</li><li><strong>Pillars of Creation:</strong> A star-forming region with vibrant young stars among pillars of dust and gas.</li><li><strong>Perseus (NGC 1333):</strong> Showcases a nearby star-forming region with large, bright stars surrounded by glowing gas.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science/8-stunning-space-images-released-by-nasa-in-2024-1734458514800</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science/8-stunning-space-images-released-by-nasa-in-2024-1734458514800</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 18:09:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 amazing photos of celestial bodies shared by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - See now - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Amazing Photos of Celestial Bodies Shared by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 2024 by India.com</p><img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/7-amazing-photos-of-celestial-bodies-shared-by-NASA-Hubble-Space-Telescope-See-now.png?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=400&amp;h=800" alt="7 amazing photos of celestial bodies shared by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - See now"><figcaption>7 amazing photos of celestial bodies shared by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</figcaption><p>This article showcases stunning images captured by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting various celestial bodies within and outside our solar system.</p><ul><li>Large Magellanic Cloud, a dwarf galaxy orbiting the Milky Way.</li><li>PIA24380, a swiftly rotating brown dwarf.</li><li>Galaxy Arp 148, taken by NASA's Spitzer and Hubble telescopes.</li><li>LDN 1551, featuring the star system XZ Tauri.</li><li>Overview of our solar system.</li></ul><blockquote>"Our solar system consists of the Sun and celestial bodies bound to it by gravity, including planets, moons, asteroids, and comets."</blockquote><p>This collection of images not only provides awe-inspiring visuals but also deepens our understanding of the universe and its mysteries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-amazing-photos-of-celestial-bodies-shared-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-see-now-7473118/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-amazing-photos-of-celestial-bodies-shared-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-see-now-7473118/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:30:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>