<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 21:18:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 21:18:49 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Springtime on Mars brings frost avalanches, gas geysers and explosions (photos) - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Springtime on Mars brings frost avalanches, gas geysers and explosions (photos)</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 2024-11-12 <strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/NduPFnxJaRoUeedd67wicb-320-80.jpg" alt="Chunks of frost composed of carbon dioxide begin to break apart and crash to the Martian surface."><figcaption>Martian spring involves lots of cracking ice, which led to this 66-foot-wide (20-meter-wide) chunk of carbon dioxide frost captured in freefall by the HiRISE camera aboard NASA’s Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter in 2015.</figcaption>
<p>As spring begins on Mars, the Red Planet experiences dramatic surface changes, including frost avalanches and gas geysers. The Martian New Year, marking the start of the spring season, leads to unique phenomena as temperatures rise, triggering a series of explosive activities.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Martian New Year began on November 12, 2024, marking a seasonal shift from winter to spring.</li>
<li>As the temperature rises, carbon dioxide frost breaks apart, leading to avalanches.</li>
<li>Gas geysers erupt, ejecting dark material to the surface, creating a landscape unique to Mars.</li>
<li>NASA’s Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO) has been crucial for observing these activities since 2005.</li>
<li>Spring phenomena include dirt spiders, wild winds, and the movement of sand dunes across the Martian surface.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Chance observations we get are reminders of just how different Mars is from Earth, especially in springtime, when these surface changes are most noticeable," said Serina Diniega, a researcher at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory.</blockquote>
<p>This season showcases the unpredictable and powerful nature of Mars, highlighting the distinct differences between our planet and the Red Planet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/the-universe/mars/springtime-on-mars-brings-frost-avalanches-gas-geysers-and-explosions-photos</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/the-universe/mars/springtime-on-mars-brings-frost-avalanches-gas-geysers-and-explosions-photos</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Over 40 new stars discovered thanks to this telescopic magnification trick - OC Today-Dispatch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.octodaydispatch.com/news/national/over-40-new-stars-discovered-thanks-to-this-telescopic-magnification-trick/article_d44f7fef-f658-50ae-a61f-0fc2375280ff.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.octodaydispatch.com/news/national/over-40-new-stars-discovered-thanks-to-this-telescopic-magnification-trick/article_d44f7fef-f658-50ae-a61f-0fc2375280ff.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 18:07:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 10 Tech Innovations to Watch Out for in 2025 - Analytics Insight]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top 10 Tech Innovations to Watch Out for in 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Analytics Insight</p>
<img src="//media.assettype.com/analyticsinsight%2F2025-01-06%2Fnz9c8287%2FTop-10-Tech-Innovations-to-Watch-Out-for-in-2025.jpg?w=320&amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;fit=max" alt="Top 10 Tech Innovations">
<figcaption>Top 10 Tech Innovations</figcaption>
<p>The year 2025 is set to be a landmark period for technological advancements, with innovations that will transform industries and enhance daily life. Here are ten groundbreaking technologies set to shape the future:</p>
<ul>
<li><h2>1. Agentic AI</h2><p>Enabling autonomous decision-making to improve efficiency in various sectors.</p></li>
<li><h2>2. Generative AI</h2><p>Creating content and solutions efficiently across industries.</p></li>
<li><h2>3. Quantum Computing</h2><p>Revolutionising industries with unmatched processing power for complex problems.</p></li>
<li><h2>4. 5G Expansion</h2><p>Enhancing connectivity and paving the way for IoT and augmented reality.</p></li>
<li><h2>5. Spatial Computing</h2><p>Integrating AR, VR, and MR for improved collaboration and user experiences.</p></li>
<li><h2>6. Neurological Enhancement</h2><p>Advancements in brain-machine interfaces to boost cognitive abilities.</p></li>
<li><h2>7. Polyfunctional Robots</h2><p>Transforming industries by performing diverse tasks with enhanced efficiency.</p></li>
<li><h2>8. AI-Enhanced Automation</h2><p>Creating smarter infrastructures for competitive advantage.</p></li>
<li><h2>9. Biotechnology Innovations</h2><p>Enhancing human health through innovative biological applications.</p></li>
<li><h2>10. Renewable Energy Technologies</h2><p>Addressing climate change with sustainable energy solutions.</p></li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These ten tech innovations, expected to grab headlines in 2025, show how significant breakthroughs can take center stage every year.”</blockquote>
<p>Embracing these technologies will not only drive the development of new innovations but also help address some of the world's challenges, leading to a smarter future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.analyticsinsight.net/tech-news/top-10-tech-innovations-to-watch-out-for-in-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.analyticsinsight.net/tech-news/top-10-tech-innovations-to-watch-out-for-in-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 17:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nascent galaxy discovered in formation at the end of the longest tidal tail of NGC 3785 galaxy - India Education Diary]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indiaeducationdiary.in/nascent-galaxy-discovered-in-formation-at-the-end-of-the-longest-tidal-tail-of-ngc-3785-galaxy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiaeducationdiary.in/nascent-galaxy-discovered-in-formation-at-the-end-of-the-longest-tidal-tail-of-ngc-3785-galaxy/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 17:06:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is the Wheel of Ghosts an Ancient Observatory? New Study Suggests Otherwise - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is the Wheel of Ghosts an Ancient Observatory? New Study Suggests Otherwise</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<p>The ancient Rujm el-Hiri site, known as the 'Wheel of Ghosts,' has been reassessed, leading researchers to question its identification as an astronomical observatory due to significant geodynamic changes over millions of years.</p>
<h2>Geophysical Insights Challenge Established Theories</h2>
<p>The study reveals that movements over 150 million years have altered the site's alignment, straying from celestial patterns. Led by Dr. Olga Khabarova and Prof. Lev Eppelbaum, the researchers concluded that historical interpretations regarding its orientation do not align with solstices or other astronomical markers.</p>
<h2>Advanced Techniques Reveal Archaeological Landscape</h2>
<p>Through geomagnetic analysis and satellite technology, the team documented archaeological features near the Sea of Galilee. Unique circular structures alongside burial mounds indicate potential agricultural uses rather than ceremonial roles.</p>
<h2>A Broader Perspective on Rujm el-Hiri's Role</h2>
<p>Dr. Michal Birkenfeld stated that this research enriches the understanding of ancient life, encouraging further exploration of community-environment interactions.</p>
<p><img src='https://img.youtube.com/vi/LVQorZMWVwk/hqdefault.jpg' alt='Play Video'>
<figcaption>Video Explanation of Rujm el-Hiri Findings</figcaption></p>
<p>Catch the latest updates at our <a href='https://www.gadgets360.com/ces'>CES 2025</a> hub.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/is-the-wheel-of-ghosts-an-ancient-observatory-new-study-suggests-otherwise-7411764</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/is-the-wheel-of-ghosts-an-ancient-observatory-new-study-suggests-otherwise-7411764</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 16:47:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mathematicians Uncover Science Behind Hula Hooping and Body Dynamics - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mathematicians Uncover Science Behind Hula Hooping and Body Dynamics</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/osRnVeMzLxY/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Video on Hula Hooping Science"><figcaption>Video explaining the science of hula hooping.</figcaption><p>The mechanics of hula hooping have been analyzed by researchers, uncovering how body shapes and motions influence the ability to keep a hoop spinning against gravity. Insights from the study have raised intriguing questions about body dynamics, energy efficiency, and potential engineering applications.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Research conducted at NYU's Applied Mathematics Laboratory used miniature robotic models to study hula hooping mechanics.</li><li>Body curvature and slope significantly impact the ability to maintain the hoop's motion against gravity.</li><li>Mathematical models developed from the study could extend to applications in robotics and energy harvesting.</li><li>Senior researcher Leif Ristroph emphasizes the broader implications of this research for technology and manufacturing.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our findings could lead to significant improvements in robotic systems and innovative energy solutions.” - Leif Ristroph</blockquote><p>This research enhances the understanding of both human and mechanical motion while providing innovative applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/mathematicians-uncover-science-behind-hula-hooping-and-body-dynamics-7411507</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/mathematicians-uncover-science-behind-hula-hooping-and-body-dynamics-7411507</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 16:30:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Einstein and Adam Grant Agree: The Puzzle Principle Will Make You Instantly Smarter - Inc.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxNMnJ4MDVDM0I5WDZFSjkxNVJsVEEzeFJIWkxhTDM2djFQWVFOci05Q1NhU1laLU50ZHBBall1eHhVendENmlrN2dBUXFIVG5WWTBIR25nVXBlcXZGTHZhbzBHVGF5UkNZbHQzUE9IYW5TamZWd0ZROEZLM2FsdjlpblFGWVhWVkgtRzZ0bGUtT0FnQmVuMXc4Z3lLcXFNZWNPMVVNa29rek5ucENKbWpZMl9FZU5OZW5rYTJBb0I1Q2NHQlFUa3ZR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixwFBVV95cUxNMnJ4MDVDM0I5WDZFSjkxNVJsVEEzeFJIWkxhTDM2djFQWVFOci05Q1NhU1laLU50ZHBBall1eHhVendENmlrN2dBUXFIVG5WWTBIR25nVXBlcXZGTHZhbzBHVGF5UkNZbHQzUE9IYW5TamZWd0ZROEZLM2FsdjlpblFGWVhWVkgtRzZ0bGUtT0FnQmVuMXc4Z3lLcXFNZWNPMVVNa29rek5ucENKbWpZMl9FZU5OZW5rYTJBb0I1Q2NHQlFUa3ZR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 16:14:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Humankind set for more giant leaps in space in 2025 - Arab News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Humankind set for more giant leaps in space in 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2025-01-06 | <strong>Source:</strong> Arab News</p>
<img src="https://www.arabnews.com/sites/default/files/styles/n_670_395/public/main-image/opinion/2025/01/06/afp_20250105_36rz87u_v1_highres_firstlaunchofblueoriginsnewglennrocket_1.jpg?itok=9EtCSGJJ" alt="Exciting year for the space sector" />
<figcaption>This year will be more exciting for the space sector, but also concerning for experts and regulators (File/AFP)</figcaption>
<p>2025 is anticipated to be a pivotal year for space exploration, marked by the influence of prominent figures like Elon Musk and Jared Isaacman. With increasing participation from countries worldwide, the landscape of space endeavors is rapidly evolving.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Elon Musk and Jared Isaacman rise to prominence in US space policy.</li>
  <li>2024 was a landmark year for global space exploration, with significant achievements from various countries.</li>
  <li>Private sector involvement in space has surged, bringing new opportunities and challenges.</li>
  <li>SpaceX and other companies are planning numerous launches in 2025, including several moon missions.</li>
  <li>Concerns about space debris are growing as more payloads are launched.</li>
  <li>The dynamic between Musk and the new US administration may shape future space policies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <strong>“This year will be even more exciting for the space sector, but also concerning for regulators and experts.”</strong>
  <p>Dr. Amal Mudallali</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As nations gear up for a busy year, the direction of space exploration, particularly from the US, will be closely watched.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.arabnews.com/node/2585457</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.arabnews.com/node/2585457</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 16:09:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Kiss and capture’: scientists offer new theory on how Pluto got its largest moon - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Kiss and capture’: scientists offer new theory on how Pluto got its largest moon</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 23, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Guardian</p><p>This article discusses a new scientific theory explaining how Pluto's largest moon, Charon, formed. Scientists suggest that a 'kiss-and-capture' event, rather than a collision, led the two bodies to orbit each other.</p><ul><li>Pluto, classified as a dwarf planet, has five known moons.</li><li>Charon is the largest moon, with a diameter of about 754 miles.</li><li>The new theory posits that Charon and Pluto experienced a brief collision before transitioning to their current orbital relationship.</li><li>This theory challenges previous ideas that suggested a large object impact led to Charon's formation.</li><li>Researchers believe the event could explain geological activity on Pluto and Charon.</li><li>Kiss and capture may be a common occurrence among Kuiper Belt objects.</li></ul><blockquote>“The impact dumps a bunch of heat into Pluto, followed by more heating as Charon starts to move away, which could be the start of a new geologic era that culminates in the surface we observed from New Horizons [space probe] in 2015.” - Dr. Adeene Denton</blockquote><p>The theory provides new insights into the formation of celestial bodies in the Kuiper Belt and may change our understanding of their geological evolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/06/new-theory-how-pluto-got-its-largest-moon-charon</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/06/new-theory-how-pluto-got-its-largest-moon-charon</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As the US and China race to the moon, these loopholes in space law could cause conflict - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>As the US and China race to the moon, these loopholes in space law could cause conflict</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Conversation</p>
<img src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/243577/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-advanced" alt="The Conversation" width="1" height="1">
<figcaption>Image from The Conversation</figcaption>
<p>As the US and China prepare for lunar bases, potential disputes over resources and claims could arise due to existing space laws.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Both nations plan to establish long-term bases on the moon.</li>
  <li>Disputes might emerge regarding the location of lunar bases and resource extraction.</li>
  <li>International space law is complex, with various treaties governing exploration rights.</li>
  <li>The Outer Space Treaty states space is free for exploration by all states.</li>
  <li>The Moon Agreement restricts ownership of lunar resources but is not signed by major spacefaring nations.</li>
  <li>The Artemis Accords aim to establish guidelines for lunar resource use.</li>
  <li>Legal responsibility for pollution applies even as spacecraft travel beyond our solar system.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Countries will want to extract this ice because it can be turned into rocket fuel for onward journeys and for life support... the prospect of 'space water wars' is actually nearer..."</blockquote>
<p>This article explores the implications of space law as nations aim for a new space race, highlighting the urgent need for clear regulations to prevent conflict over extraterrestrial resources.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-01-china-moon-loopholes-space-law.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-01-china-moon-loopholes-space-law.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:45:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MIT Technology Review Releases the 2025 list of 10 Breakthrough Technologies - IT News Online]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxOTXVLZ2dFWXV1TW51b0w2SXkwREJXWF9RZjB4enV4Q25Pc195VHV3bUZ6anhuZXB2U01CaHdtaTlNaUtieWQzaHpEUlFHV00yaWlnaFUxdzZMd1lGNGhlc2ZFelBGNmF3SFZCZGNBTklzUk9CRXJZU2xPV1lxbDg1cWNLQUJSdlkzc1dOWTgwa3AxZ0pjM19HeUhtckx4VzFybWNpclhrTFB5MjFzVHBXaDNMWWVQenNESGJsZmhSNFRMUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxOTXVLZ2dFWXV1TW51b0w2SXkwREJXWF9RZjB4enV4Q25Pc195VHV3bUZ6anhuZXB2U01CaHdtaTlNaUtieWQzaHpEUlFHV00yaWlnaFUxdzZMd1lGNGhlc2ZFelBGNmF3SFZCZGNBTklzUk9CRXJZU2xPV1lxbDg1cWNLQUJSdlkzc1dOWTgwa3AxZ0pjM19HeUhtckx4VzFybWNpclhrTFB5MjFzVHBXaDNMWWVQenNESGJsZmhSNFRMUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:36:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Belt It Out - Hackster.io]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Advancements in Robotic Gripping Technology</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2025-01-01 <strong>Source:</strong> TechXplore</p>
<img src="https://techxplore.com/images/multitasking-robotics.jpg" alt="Multi-object grasping efficiency" />
<figcaption>Multi-object grasping increases pick-and-place efficiency (📷: J. Eom et al.)</figcaption>
<p>The development of a new robotic gripper by researchers at Seoul National University promises to enhance the efficiency of robotic operations by allowing robots to handle multiple objects simultaneously.</p>
<ul>
<li>Existing robotic systems struggle with precise manipulation of multiple objects, whereas humans can perform this task effortlessly.</li>
<li>The new robotic hand employs a dual system: fingers for grasping and conveyor belts for transporting items.</li>
<li>Trials demonstrated up to 34% time savings and up to 71% reductions in travel distances for robotic arms.</li>
<li>This design approach focuses on functionality rather than complex mimicry of human movements.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The efficiency gains of this novel robotic system were demonstrated in both commercial and domestic trials."</blockquote>
<p>This development represents a significant step toward creating more functional and versatile robots for various applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hackster.io/news/belt-it-out-e48fa0b393ca</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hackster.io/news/belt-it-out-e48fa0b393ca</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:21:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Ocean Teems With Networks of Interconnected Bacteria - Quanta Magazine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Ocean Teems With Networks of Interconnected Bacteria</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified, <strong>Source:</strong> Not Specified</p><p>Recent research reveals that Prochlorococcus bacteria in the ocean form nanotube networks, enabling communication and nutrient exchange between individual cells. These findings challenge previous notions that these microscopic cells operate in isolation.</p><ul><li>Prochlorococcus, one of the most abundant photosynthetic organisms, contributes significantly to the Earth’s oxygen supply.</li><li>Biologists discovered long, thin tubes known as bacterial nanotubes linking Prochlorococcus and Synechococcus, suggesting a level of interdependence.</li><li>This research marks the first time nanotubes have been observed in these critical oceanic bacteria.</li><li>Nanotubes may facilitate nutrient exchange in the nutrient-scarce ocean environment, promoting cooperation between species.</li><li>The study raises questions about bacterial communication and the ecological roles of these networks.</li></ul><blockquote>“The fact that there can be physical communication between different kind of organisms — I think that changes many, many previous ideas on how the cells work in the ocean.” - María del Carmen Muñoz-Marín</blockquote><p>This groundbreaking discovery suggests that our understanding of marine bacteria and their interactions may need to be significantly revised, highlighting the complexity of life beneath the surface.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/the-ocean-teems-with-networks-of-interconnected-bacteria-20250106/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.quantamagazine.org/the-ocean-teems-with-networks-of-interconnected-bacteria-20250106/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:11:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Citizen science reveals that Jupiter's colorful clouds are not made of ammonia ice - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Citizen science reveals that Jupiter's colorful clouds are not made of ammonia ice</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Journal of Geophysical Research: Planets</p><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2025/citizen-science-reveal.jpg" alt="Citizen science reveals that Jupiter's colorful clouds are not made of ammonia ice" title="Visible appearance of Jupiter and Saturn reconstructed from VLT/MUSE observations on 23 March 2020 and 6 April 2017, respectively. The left-hand column shows the reconstructed colors when no gamma-correction has been applied, while the right-hand column shows the gamma-corrected appearances, which are closer to what the average human observes with their naked eye through a telescope, but have reduced contrast and are less color enhanced. Credit: Journal of Geophysical Research: Planets (2025). DOI: 10.1029/2024JE008622"><figcaption>Visible appearance of Jupiter and Saturn reconstructed from VLT/MUSE observations on 23 March 2020 and 6 April 2017, respectively. The left-hand column shows the reconstructed colors when no gamma-correction has been applied, while the right-hand column shows the gamma-corrected appearances, which are closer to what the average human observes with their naked eye through a telescope, but have reduced contrast and are less color enhanced. Credit: <i>Journal of Geophysical Research: Planets</i> (2025). DOI: 10.1029/2024JE008622</figcaption><p>Collaborative efforts by amateur and professional astronomers have clarified the misunderstanding regarding the composition of Jupiter's clouds. Instead of ammonia ice, these clouds are likely composed of ammonium hydrosulfide mixed with smog.</p><ul><li>Amateur astronomer Dr. Steven Hill’s method helped map the abundance of ammonia in Jupiter’s atmosphere.</li><li>The clouds are found in a deep warm atmosphere, not consistent with ammonia ice formation.</li><li>Observations made using the MUSE telescope provided evidence for deeper, higher pressure clouds.</li><li>Professor Patrick Irwin’s team confirmed results with a new, simplified analytical method.</li><li>Ammonia maps can assist citizen scientists in tracking variations in Jupiter’s atmosphere.</li></ul><blockquote>Professor Irwin stated, "I am astonished that such a simple method is able to probe so deep in the atmosphere and demonstrate so clearly that the main clouds cannot be pure ammonia ice."</blockquote><p>The new insights allow amateur astronomers to contribute to understanding Jupiter's long-standing atmospheric mysteries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-01-citizen-science-reveals-jupiter-clouds.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-01-citizen-science-reveals-jupiter-clouds.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:08:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronomers have pinpointed the origin of mysterious repeating radio bursts from space - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronomers Identify Source of Repeating Radio Bursts from Space</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CFEhh5QhoCKueQZpb2kctj-650-80.jpg" alt="Murchison Widefield Array" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>One element of the Murchison Widefield Array, a radio telescope in Western Australia that observes the sky at low radio frequencies. (Image credit: ICRAR / Curtin University)</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses recent findings by astronomers who have traced the mysterious repeating radio bursts from space back to a red dwarf star, possibly in a binary orbit with a white dwarf.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The repeating radio bursts have puzzled scientists since their discovery in 2022.</li>
  <li>Researchers tracked the bursts to a lightweight red dwarf star located in a binary orbit.</li>
  <li>New observations were made using the Murchison Widefield Array and the MeerKAT telescope in South Africa.</li>
  <li>GLEAM-X J0704-37 is the newly discovered source, emitting radio waves in a unique pattern.</li>
  <li>Possible explanations for the radio wave generation involve stellar winds and magnetic fields between the two stars.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We've learned the power of expecting the unexpected – and we'll keep scanning the skies to solve this cosmic mystery." - Natasha Hurley-Walker</blockquote>
<p>This discovery could contribute to our understanding of star interactions and the mechanisms behind radio wave emissions in space.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/the-universe/astronomers-have-pinpointed-the-origin-of-mysterious-repeating-radio-bursts-from-space</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/the-universe/astronomers-have-pinpointed-the-origin-of-mysterious-repeating-radio-bursts-from-space</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hidden Climate Disruptions: The Surprising Source of the 1831 Eruption - Indian Defence Review]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hidden Climate Disruptions: The Surprising Source of the 1831 Eruption</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-06T10:00:00-05:00">January 6, 2025</time> | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Defence Review</p><figure><img width="960" height="540" src="https://indiandefencereview.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/183120volcanic20eruption-climate20impact-dr.20william20hutchison.jpeg" alt="Unveiling the mystery of the 1831 volcanic eruption"><figcaption>Hidden Climate Disruptions: The Surprising Source of the 1831 Eruption | Indian Defence Review</figcaption></figure><p>Scientists have uncovered the shocking truth behind the 1831 volcanic eruption that dramatically altered our climate. This revelation illuminates past events and raises urgent questions about future volcanic threats.</p><ul><li>The 1831 eruption caused a significant cooling of Earth's climate, dropping average temperatures in the Northern Hemisphere by about 1 degree Celsius.</li><li>Initially believed to originate from a tropical volcano, it was found to come from Zavaritskii, a midlatitude volcano in the Kuril Islands.</li><li>Research involved sampling ice cores and studying sulfur isotopes and volcanic glass.</li><li>This eruption led to famines in regions such as India, Japan, and Europe due to its climatic impacts.</li><li>Dr. William Hutchison described this confirmation as “a genuine eureka moment.”</li></ul><blockquote>“This eruption had global climatic impacts but was wrongly attributed to a tropical volcano for a long time.” - Dr. Stefan Brönnimann</blockquote><p>This study highlights how little we know about remote volcanoes and their potential impact on global climates, urging better preparedness for future volcanic events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indiandefencereview.com/hidden-climate-disruptions-the-surprising-source-of-the-1831-eruption/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiandefencereview.com/hidden-climate-disruptions-the-surprising-source-of-the-1831-eruption/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chang'e-5 samples provide evidence that moon had magnetic field 2 billion years ago - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chang'e-5 samples provide evidence that moon had magnetic field 2 billion years ago</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Science X Network</p>
<img src="https://scx2.b-cdn.net/gfx/news/hires/2025/researchers-find-evide.jpg" alt="Researchers find evidence that the moon had a magnetic field two billion years ago" width="800" height="348">
<figcaption>Distribution of magnetic anomalies at the lunar surface. Credit: <i>Science Advances</i> (2025). DOI: 10.1126/sciadv.adp3333</figcaption>
<p>A large team of researchers at the Chinese Academy of Sciences has found evidence that suggests the moon had a magnetic field around 2 billion years ago, based on studies of rock samples returned by the Chang'e-5 lunar mission.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The research analyzed lunar rock samples to investigate the moon's magnetic field history.</li>
  <li>The moon, currently lacking a global magnetic field, had a weak field generated by thermomechanical convection in its interior.</li>
  <li>Past missions suggested the moon had a magnetic field approximately 4 billion years ago; this study extends the timeline to 2 billion years ago.</li>
  <li>The magnetic field measurements indicated values between 2,000 to 4,000 nanoteslas, suggesting longer volcanic activity and potential for ancient water.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The moon's magnetic field would have shielded water on the surface from solar wind, preserving it in shadowed regions.</blockquote>
<p>This discovery enhances our understanding of the moon's geological history and its internal processes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-01-samples-evidence-moon-magnetic-field.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-01-samples-evidence-moon-magnetic-field.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 striking images of galaxies captured by NASA - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Striking Images of Galaxies Captured by NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 6, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> DNA</p>
<img src="https://images1.dnaindia.com/images/DNA-EN/900x1600/2025/1/6/1736175229684_1717726707817534350873009764a31efdc.jpeg" alt="10 striking images of galaxies captured by NASA" />
<figcaption>Striking image of galaxies taken by NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases breathtaking images of various galaxies captured by NASA, highlighting their beauty and unique characteristics.</p>
<ul>
<li>MCG-01-24-014 is a bright spiral galaxy located about 275 million light-years from Earth.</li>
<li>IC 5332 is captured face-on and is around 30 million light-years away in the Sculptor constellation.</li>
<li>The tranquil spiral galaxy UGC 12295 shows stunning cosmic beauty.</li>
<li>Jellyfish galaxy JO206 exhibits an impressive star-forming disc surrounded by dust.</li>
<li>A galaxy in Pisces dances with filaments spiraling around its supermassive black hole.</li>
<li>A barred spiral galaxy active since 1992 has hosted three supernovae.</li>
<li>Caldwell 5, located in the Camelopardalis constellation, was discovered in 1895.</li>
<li>NASA's work brings these spectacular images to the public eye.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Source: NASA"</blockquote>
<p>The images not only showcase the stunning beauty of galaxies but also deepen our understanding of these magnificent cosmic structures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/viral/10-striking-images-of-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-1736174627812</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/viral/10-striking-images-of-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-1736174627812</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:54:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There’s still time to catch the stunning Quadrantids meteor shower - Digital Trends]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>There’s still time to catch the stunning Quadrantids meteor shower</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Digital Trends</p>
<img src="https://www.digitaltrends.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/lyrid-meteor-shower.jpeg.jpg?resize=1000%2C600&amp;p=1" alt="The Lyrid meteor shower" />
<figcaption>The Lyrid meteor shower - NASA</figcaption>
<p>The Quadrantids meteor shower, one of the finest meteor showers, is visible throughout early January and will end on January 12. This article offers tips on how to catch this stunning display.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The meteor shower is best viewed on the West Coast of the U.S. and in the Pacific region.</li>
  <li>Robert Massey from the Royal Astronomical Society notes that a thin crescent moon allows for better visibility this year.</li>
  <li>The Quadrantids are associated with the near-Earth asteroid 2003 EH1, with debris burning up as meteors.</li>
  <li>During the peak, up to 70 to 80 meteors can be seen per hour, including a notable number of bright fireballs.</li>
  <li>To view the shower, find a dark spot away from city lights and avoid using binoculars or telescopes for a wider view.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“They have a pretty strong intensity if you happen to be in the right place at the right time…” - Robert Massey</blockquote>
<p>Don't miss out on this New Year treat; enjoy the meteor shower with good weather and dark skies!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.digitaltrends.com/space/quadrantids-meteor-shower-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.digitaltrends.com/space/quadrantids-meteor-shower-2024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:49:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An abundant phytoplankton feeds a global network of marine microbes - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-01-abundant-phytoplankton-global-network-marine.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-01-abundant-phytoplankton-global-network-marine.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:47:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Research Shows Twin Births Were Common in Ancient Primate Evolution - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Research Shows Twin Births Were Common in Ancient Primate Evolution</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><div><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/osRnVeMzLxY/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Video explaining the research on twin births in ancient primates.</figcaption></div><p>This article explores a study which reveals that ancient primates predominantly gave birth to twins, a stark contrast to modern patterns of singleton births. Researchers reconstructed primate reproductive history, suggesting this shift occurred due to evolutionary advantages.</p><ul><li>Twin births were once standard among ancient primates.</li><li>The transition to singleton births occurred at least 50 million years ago, coinciding with increased primate brain and body size.</li><li>Understanding this evolution aids in studying modern reproductive dynamics.</li></ul><blockquote>“This historical context can provide insights into the biological and social dynamics of reproduction.”</blockquote><p>The findings emphasize the lasting impact of evolutionary pressures on reproductive strategies over millions of years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/evolution-of-twin-births-in-primates-an-ancient-trait-rediscovered-7411427</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/evolution-of-twin-births-in-primates-an-ancient-trait-rediscovered-7411427</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Awards SpaceX an $843 Million Contract to Decommission the International Space Station - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/techandscience/nasa-awards-spacex-an-843-million-contract-to-decommission-the-international-space-station/ar-AA1x2N4e</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/techandscience/nasa-awards-spacex-an-843-million-contract-to-decommission-the-international-space-station/ar-AA1x2N4e</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:28:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This company of Elon Musk is rattling windows, setting off car alarms, knocking books of shelves and trigg - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This company of Elon Musk is rattling windows, setting off car alarms, knocking books of shelves and triggering chorus of dog barking at the dead of night; here are all details</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 06, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Economic Times</p><figure><img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116998510,width-300,height-225,imgsize-344742,resizemode-75/this-company-of-elon-musk-is-rattling-windows-setting-off-car-alarms-knocking-books-of-shelves-and-triggering-chorus-of-dog-barking-at-the-dead-of-night-here-are-all-details.jpg" alt="Space Force base region seeing revolt from local residents?" height="225" width="300"><figcaption>Space Force base region seeing revolt from local residents?</figcaption></figure><p>SpaceX' rocket launches are increasingly becoming a nuisance for the local residents living near launch sites. The frequent launches reportedly cause disturbances, with many locals expressing their concerns over structural damage and disrupted sleep.</p><ul><li>SpaceX launches from Vandenberg Space Force Base are causing sonic booms that disturb residents.</li><li>Windows rattle, car alarms go off, and dogs bark due to the noise from the launches.</li><li>Residents feel that advance warnings for launches are insufficient, especially during night hours.</li></ul><blockquote>“The intensity of the sonic booms changes based on atmospheric conditions, making the alerts largely ineffective in certain circumstances.”</blockquote><p>Residents are growing increasingly frustrated with the frequency of the launches and the lack of adequate communication regarding their impacts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/this-company-of-elon-musk-is-rattling-windows-setting-off-car-alarms-knocking-books-of-shelves-and-triggering-chorus-of-dog-barking-at-the-dead-of-night-here-are-all-details/articleshow/116998526.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/this-company-of-elon-musk-is-rattling-windows-setting-off-car-alarms-knocking-books-of-shelves-and-triggering-chorus-of-dog-barking-at-the-dead-of-night-here-are-all-details/articleshow/116998526.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:14:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Astronaut's jaw-dropping video of aurora from space will leave you speechless! - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Astronaut's jaw-dropping video of aurora from space will leave you speechless!</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This article highlights an incredible video captured by a NASA astronaut, showcasing the breathtaking beauty of the aurora viewed from space.</p><ul><li>Astronaut shares mesmerizing views of auroras.</li><li>The video emphasizes the stunning colors and movement of the phenomenon.</li><li>The reaction to the video has been overwhelmingly positive.</li></ul><blockquote>"It's a truly remarkable experience to see this from above." - Anonymous NASA Astronaut</blockquote><p>This captivating footage not only showcases natural beauty but also highlights the unique perspective astronauts have while in space.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/nasa-astronauts-jaw-dropping-video-of-aurora-from-space-will-leave-you-speechless/articleshow/116998398.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/nasa-astronauts-jaw-dropping-video-of-aurora-from-space-will-leave-you-speechless/articleshow/116998398.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Light Sensing to Adaptive Learning: Reconfigurable Memcapacitive Devices in Neuromorphic Computing - EIN Presswire]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>From Light Sensing to Adaptive Learning: Reconfigurable Memcapacitive Devices in Neuromorphic Computing</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> EINPresswire.com</p>
<img src="https://img.einpresswire.com/medium/804016/figure-1-neuromorphic-systems.jpeg" alt="Neuromorphic systems based on biological neurons" width="300" height="120">
<figcaption>Neuromorphic systems based on the structure of biological neurons.</figcaption>
<p>Researchers at KAUST have developed reconfigurable metal-oxide-semiconductor capacitors (MOSCaps) that mimic biological neurons and adapt to stimuli, enhancing the potential for energy-efficient computing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Developed by a team led by Professor Nazek El-Atab at KAUST.</li>
<li>Devices exhibit optoelectronic synaptic features and memcapacitive behavior.</li>
<li>Enable dynamic transitions from light sensing to optical data retention.</li>
<li>Can improve applications in adaptive technology and exoplanet detection.</li>
<li>Show strong memory retention and stability under varying conditions.</li>
<li>Highlight potential for innovative computing solutions with lower power consumption.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The memory window of the device remained above the failure threshold for 106 seconds at 60–80 °C.”</blockquote>
<p>This advancement in neuromorphic technology represents a significant step towards integrating sensing, processing, and memory functions in a single device, potentially revolutionizing data processing and adaptive capabilities in future applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.einpresswire.com/article/774480304/from-light-sensing-to-adaptive-learning-reconfigurable-memcapacitive-devices-in-neuromorphic-computing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.einpresswire.com/article/774480304/from-light-sensing-to-adaptive-learning-reconfigurable-memcapacitive-devices-in-neuromorphic-computing</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Single Cell Genomics Market Research Report 2025 with - GlobeNewswire]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Single Cell Genomics Market Research Report 2025 with Executive and Consultant Guides, & Profiles of 55+ Companies</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan. 06, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> GLOBE NEWSWIRE</p><img src="https://ml.globenewswire.com/media/OGRiYWU3ODEtNTYxMC00Y2NiLWIwNTYtOGVjMmU4ZDMyOTczLTEwMjY3Mzc=/tiny/Research-and-Markets.png" alt=""/><figcaption>Research and Markets</figcaption><p>This report provides comprehensive insights into the Single Cell Genomics market, showcasing emerging trends and potential applications within the healthcare sector.</p><ul><li>Single Cell Genomics is revolutionizing scientific research and offers new opportunities in biotechnology.</li><li>Market dynamics are influenced by advancements in immuno-oncology and the convergence of technology sectors.</li><li>Challenges include intense competition and technological limitations impacting diagnostics.</li><li>Recent developments highlight significant innovations from key industry players.</li></ul><blockquote>“The sky just might be the limit on this new approach to capturing genetic information.”</blockquote><p>This report highlights critical developments in the Single Cell Genomics field and offers valuable insights for stakeholders in the market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/01/06/3004702/0/en/Single-Cell-Genomics-Market-Research-Report-2025-with-Executive-and-Consultant-Guides-Profiles-of-55-Companies.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/01/06/3004702/0/en/Single-Cell-Genomics-Market-Research-Report-2025-with-Executive-and-Consultant-Guides-Profiles-of-55-Companies.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:11:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Approach to Neuromorphic Computing - AZoOptics]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A New Approach to Neuromorphic Computing</h1><p><strong>Published on: [Publication Date]</strong><br/><strong>Source: [Source Name]</strong></p><img src="https://d36nqgmw98q4v5.cloudfront.net/images/news/ImageForNews_30113_1736162479866370.png" width="800" height="320" alt="Neuromorphic systems based on the structure of biological neurons."><figcaption><em>Neuromorphic systems based on the structure of biological neurons. Image Credit: Light: Science & Applications</em></figcaption><p>Scientists led by Professor Nazek El-Atab at KAUST have created a MOSCap device that mimics neuron-like adaptive behavior and memory retention using Hafnium diselenide (HfSe<sub>2</sub>). Their study showcases advancements in neuromorphic computing.</p><ul><li>The separation of sensing, processing, and memory in traditional systems causes inefficiencies.</li><li>Neuromorphic computing combines these functions into a single device, enhancing efficiency.</li><li>Incorporation of HfSe<sub>2</sub> nanosheets allows unique data retention and adaptability.</li><li>Real-world tests show memory retention stability under high temperatures.</li><li>Potential applications include astronomy for detecting exoplanets.</li></ul><blockquote>“The memory window of the device remained above the failure threshold for 106 seconds at 60–80 °C.”</blockquote><p>This discovery represents a significant improvement in neuromorphic technology, highlighting its potential to develop systems that mimic the dynamic learning processes of biological neurons.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.azooptics.com/News.aspx?newsID=30113</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.azooptics.com/News.aspx?newsID=30113</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Discover Luminescent Nanocrystals to Enhance AI Efficiency - INDIAai]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPc2xCTzVsYkRvOVgxeGpGdE5kbG84eDFzRVZMcDhScE9UdHppeEJld3gzajJNdkNOYkpSUTI2V21EcUhNRFh6OEhQVmgxVlpVcTJCc1NPc0NUV3diNGJtckZrbjRveDBMTTNfdUNxTnpBb1pPZEU2d1ZFeUdsYkhJMEM0SnFjN3lhM2pVWGxDVEd0enZSQ0hGT3JwR2NmcG43d0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPc2xCTzVsYkRvOVgxeGpGdE5kbG84eDFzRVZMcDhScE9UdHppeEJld3gzajJNdkNOYkpSUTI2V21EcUhNRFh6OEhQVmgxVlpVcTJCc1NPc0NUV3diNGJtckZrbjRveDBMTTNfdUNxTnpBb1pPZEU2d1ZFeUdsYkhJMEM0SnFjN3lhM2pVWGxDVEd0enZSQ0hGT3JwR2NmcG43d0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:31:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[60 million years ago our primate ancestors had twins all the time, finds study - Interesting Engineering]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNNHdKVGhSdzRtTVZkeHRnSUYyVFIyclJlaHJzQXI0OUpwX09lV20wNTUyVjJQcmZUUDRYazhOZUhnV2puNU1Oc1hzc1RJNEV0SzJhQXE5WDBNV1BhcW9JYjR4Y2FFUUJ2MVgwY1NFR0FaMy1tT19JaEF5Q2FHUmdOYVcta3N0c2w1eGZma2FyVFRUZUlZZHFxX3Z2V0d0LXM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNNHdKVGhSdzRtTVZkeHRnSUYyVFIyclJlaHJzQXI0OUpwX09lV20wNTUyVjJQcmZUUDRYazhOZUhnV2puNU1Oc1hzc1RJNEV0SzJhQXE5WDBNV1BhcW9JYjR4Y2FFUUJ2MVgwY1NFR0FaMy1tT19JaEF5Q2FHUmdOYVcta3N0c2w1eGZma2FyVFRUZUlZZHFxX3Z2V0d0LXM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Macroscopic oscillators move as one at the quantum level ... - eeNews Europe]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxNcWp4NGNOR1F1aFlrX2pvRC15aWVBZkl6dzlMaWxqa1g5RVZOTlFHdnZCUVBzUzV2ejBXaTVJR2VQY2JuUkxLbl9QRTdWWkhSMVYzQ2Jlcm1HSmE0cXBEUW5PWWhsMUQ1QURCcUN6OUtaM3RITVN2d3FrZU1NYVRHRFhiYjctRm1STlUtLWhTSS1pT0k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxNcWp4NGNOR1F1aFlrX2pvRC15aWVBZkl6dzlMaWxqa1g5RVZOTlFHdnZCUVBzUzV2ejBXaTVJR2VQY2JuUkxLbl9QRTdWWkhSMVYzQ2Jlcm1HSmE0cXBEUW5PWWhsMUQ1QURCcUN6OUtaM3RITVN2d3FrZU1NYVRHRFhiYjctRm1STlUtLWhTSS1pT0k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:16:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>