<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 13:25:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 13:25:16 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronauts on ISS Share Christmas Cheer with Floating Candy Canes and Festivities - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronauts Celebrate Christmas in Space with Festive Fun and Meaningful Messages</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/aai7trgc9TA/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Astronauts celebrating Christmas in space">
<figcaption>Astronauts celebrating Christmas in space</figcaption>
<p>The crew aboard the International Space Station (ISS) celebrated Christmas by sharing holiday cheer and emphasizing togetherness, even from an orbiting outpost 260 miles above Earth.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Astronauts created a festive atmosphere with floating decorations and a snowman made from storage bags.</li>
  <li>They acknowledged the efforts of mission control teams on Earth who support their work.</li>
  <li>The crew enjoyed a special meal and decorations that reminded them of their families.</li>
  <li>Barry Wilmore highlighted the religious significance of Christmas during their celebrations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Merry Christmas” from our extraordinary vantage point!” - ISS Crew</blockquote>
<p>The celebration highlighted the unity and collaboration that define both their mission and the holiday spirit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/astronauts-celebrate-christmas-on-iss-with-festive-decorations-and-meals-7335970</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/astronauts-celebrate-christmas-on-iss-with-festive-decorations-and-meals-7335970</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 12:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Parker Solar Probe Makes Closest-Ever Approach to the Sun - Observer Voice]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPVXh2OW80MXpDR3lDWExMUFF3THpvdEowSXgwamFCR3gybk1TOGNSNzNwQU5KbEdQb2NMS3I4S3VrMk9XYTUzbWlKYi1UTE9hS3hldDQwSkQ3Qm5nYWtMek9hdEtOWDBFaGc1ejlpaEdMb0h4NzlkZmV0cGtjN3lRd3F6OHRKVjZHSlFXZDJsNmtKSUZBLTcwWDZCMA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPVXh2OW80MXpDR3lDWExMUFF3THpvdEowSXgwamFCR3gybk1TOGNSNzNwQU5KbEdQb2NMS3I4S3VrMk9XYTUzbWlKYi1UTE9hS3hldDQwSkQ3Qm5nYWtMek9hdEtOWDBFaGc1ejlpaEdMb0h4NzlkZmV0cGtjN3lRd3F6OHRKVjZHSlFXZDJsNmtKSUZBLTcwWDZCMA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 12:19:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lumpy universe does not require dark energy - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lumpy universe does not require dark energy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> New Delhi</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Science News</p><img width="802" height="464" src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Earth-Interior-1.jpg?w=802&amp;enlarge=true" alt="The 'timescape' model describes a lumpy universe that does not require dark energy. (Image Credit: Bing Image Creator/News9)." title="Lumpy Universe"><figcaption>The ‘timescape’ model describes a lumpy universe that does not require dark energy. (Image Credit: Bing Image Creator/News9).</figcaption><p>Scientists have proposed a solution to a major cosmological issue: the universe's expansion may not be accelerating as previously thought, leading to a reevaluation of dark energy concepts.</p><ul><li>The 'timescape' model suggests that the universe's uneven expansion creates the illusion of acceleration.</li><li>Local matter density is thought to be lower, leading to perceptions of rapid expansion from our vantage point.</li><li>Future data may clarify the expanding universe mystery within five years.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dark energy is a misidentification of variations in the kinetic energy of expansion, which is not uniform in a universe as lumpy as the one we actually live in.” - David Wiltshire</blockquote><p>This research prompts reconsideration of fundamental cosmological concepts, highlighting gravitational influences on cosmic time perception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/lumpy-universe-does-not-require-dark-energy-2782447</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/lumpy-universe-does-not-require-dark-energy-2782447</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 12:02:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The earth’s largest hidden underwater waterfall: A 11,500-ft giant under the Arctic - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Earth’s Largest Hidden Underwater Waterfall: A 11,500-ft Giant Under the Arctic</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img alt="The earth’s largest hidden underwater waterfall: A 11,500-ft giant under the Arctic" title="The earth’s largest hidden underwater waterfall: A 11,500-ft giant under the Arctic" src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/116682729/Denmark-Strait-cataract.jpg?width=636&amp;height=358&amp;resize=4"><figcaption>Photo courtesy: Canva</figcaption><p>Deep beneath the Arctic waters between Greenland and Iceland lies the world’s largest waterfall—hidden from sight but crucial to Earth's climate. The Denmark Strait cataract, an underwater giant, influences global ocean circulation and shapes ecosystems despite its invisible and silent presence.</p><ul><li>The Denmark Strait cataract has a vertical drop of 11,500 feet, over three times the height of Angel Falls.</li><li>This underwater phenomenon spans 300 miles (480 kilometers) and operates unseen beneath the Arctic waters.</li><li>It is formed from glacial forces and dates back to the last ice age.</li><li>This massive underwater waterfall plays a critical role in regulating ocean circulation and the planet's climate.</li><li>It helps drive thermohaline circulation, distributing heat, nutrients, and energy across oceans.</li><li>The waterfall is essential for maintaining Earth's ecosystems and influences marine life directly.</li></ul><blockquote>Marine geosystems expert Mike Clare mentioned that the water of the Denmark Strait cataract is virtually unnoticed even by those underwater, moving silently without dramatic visual effects.</blockquote><p>The Denmark Strait cataract represents a hidden marvel of nature that plays a crucial role in climate regulation and ocean health, highlighting the importance of our oceans in maintaining planetary equilibrium.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/travel/destinations/the-earths-largest-hidden-underwater-waterfall-a-11500-ft-giant-under-the-arctic/articleshow/116682679.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/travel/destinations/the-earths-largest-hidden-underwater-waterfall-a-11500-ft-giant-under-the-arctic/articleshow/116682679.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 11:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronauts' Best Photos From the Space Station in 2024 - Business Insider]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronauts' most jaw-dropping photos from the International Space Station show what 2024 looked like 250 miles above Earth</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024-12-12 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Business Insider</p><img src="https://i.insider.com/676a518f9de00e389eb32996?width=700" alt="two women astronauts with hair floating in microgravity look out an array of rectangular windows surrounding a circular window over a view of a blue ocean with wispy clouds"><figcaption>Astronauts Suni Williams and Tracy C. Dyson look out the International Space Station's cupola above the Atlantic Ocean.</figcaption><p>This article showcases the breathtaking photographs taken by astronauts aboard the International Space Station (ISS) during 2024, highlighting unique views of Earth and celestial events.</p><ul><li>Astronauts take hundreds of stunning photos from the ISS each year.</li><li>This year's best snapshots reveal both Earth and space in glorious detail.</li><li>Astronauts captured views of eclipses, northern lights, storms, and Earth's grandest landscapes.</li></ul><blockquote>"I've spent a fair amount of time trying to capture what I can see with my eye. I've not been able to achieve it yet," said astronaut Dominick.</blockquote><p>Overall, these photographs not only serve as artistic expressions but also convey valuable scientific insights about our planet and the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/astronauts-best-photos-from-space-station-this-year-2024-12</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.businessinsider.com/astronauts-best-photos-from-space-station-this-year-2024-12</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 10:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bright, elliptically polarized incandescent light - Tech Explorist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bright, elliptically polarized incandescent light</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Tech Explorist</p>
<p>This article discusses groundbreaking research from the University of Michigan that enables the production of bright, twisted light using technology reminiscent of traditional incandescent bulbs.</p>
<ul>
<li>Traditional methods for producing twisted light are challenging; new techniques have been developed based on blackbody radiation.</li>
<li>Photons emitted by heated objects can become polarized depending on the object's shape and size.</li>
<li>Chiral or twisted light is characterized by its unique clockwise and counterclockwise rotations.</li>
<li>The findings could significantly impact technologies like autonomous vehicles, aiding in object identification.</li>
<li>This method could result in light that is 100 times brighter than existing techniques, though it presents challenges in wavelength refinement.</li>
<li>Future research aims to expand the application of twisted light into the infrared spectrum.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The advancements in physics of blackbody radiation by chiral nanostructures are central to this study. Such emitters are everywhere around us.” - Nicholas Kotov</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, these findings not only advance the field of optics but also open avenues for practical applications in technology that relies on visual identification and contrast enhancement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techexplorist.com/bright-elliptically-polarized-incandescent-light/95042/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techexplorist.com/bright-elliptically-polarized-incandescent-light/95042/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 10:16:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronomers unveil stunning new view of NGC 2264, the “Christmas Tree Cluster” - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronomers Unveil Stunning New View of NGC 2264, the 'Christmas Tree Cluster'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Science News</p>
<img src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/X-ray-1.png?w=802&amp;enlarge=true" alt="Located 2,500 light-years away, this cosmic display offers both visual wonder and insights into star formation. (Image Credit: NASA/CXC/SAO/L. Frattare and K. Arcand)" />
<figcaption>Located 2,500 light-years away, this cosmic display offers both visual wonder and insights into star formation. (Image Credit: NASA/CXC/SAO/L. Frattare and K. Arcand)</figcaption>
<p>A stunning new picture of the galaxy NGC 2264, called the ‘Christmas Tree Cluster,’ has been published just in time for the holiday season. This beautiful nebula is approximately 2,500 light years from Earth and is home to stars that are between one and five million years old.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The X-ray data was obtained from the Chandra X-ray Observatory.</li>
  <li>Optical data was captured by Michael Clow in Arizona.</li>
  <li>The image showcases vibrant colors representing star density and gas motion.</li>
  <li>Astronomers gain insights into star formation and the influence of young stars on their environment.</li>
  <li>The visual representation resembles a decorated Christmas tree, highlighting both art and science.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The image is a true art and science combination with a festive message as to how beautiful and intricate the universe is.”</blockquote>
<p>This new image not only captures the beauty of the cosmos but also provides valuable insights into astrophysical processes, celebrating the wonder of the universe as we enter the holiday season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/astronomers-unveil-stunning-new-view-of-ngc-2264-the-christmas-tree-cluster-2782291</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/astronomers-unveil-stunning-new-view-of-ngc-2264-the-christmas-tree-cluster-2782291</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 09:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Perceptein, a protein-based AI in living cells - INDIAai]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNNHZzaVZTbnFfaFBXUV94MlRCUU0wR2haRklKWkx5ZldrQy03TjFOZmhuZlV6bGZIdTViZGM2VF9FbVduXzh1MVY2aS05M3B6MFl6ei1HeTFyXzg5X0ZraGYxWG1hS2pSODhPQUpNekxoV1pwdGp5MkVaSU5FOGlmV2N3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNNHZzaVZTbnFfaFBXUV94MlRCUU0wR2haRklKWkx5ZldrQy03TjFOZmhuZlV6bGZIdTViZGM2VF9FbVduXzh1MVY2aS05M3B6MFl6ei1HeTFyXzg5X0ZraGYxWG1hS2pSODhPQUpNekxoV1pwdGp5MkVaSU5FOGlmV2N3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 09:08:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three years of James Webb Telescope in 10 stunning pictures - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Three Years of James Webb Telescope in 10 Stunning Images</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: December 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: India Today</strong></p><img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2024/12/cropped-52196657049_dea4d9b3d5_kITG-1735199200527.jpg" alt="James Webb Telescope Image" /><figcaption>Stunning view from the James Webb Telescope.</figcaption><p>This article showcases ten exceptional images captured by the James Webb Telescope over the past three years, highlighting its technological advancements and its contributions to our understanding of the universe.</p><ul><li>Webb's view of ice giant Uranus, showcasing its dynamic features.</li><li>The breathtaking Pillars of Creation, revealing newly formed stars.</li><li>Visualization of the dwarf galaxy Wolf-Lundmark-Melotte, filled with countless stars.</li><li>Discovery of a protostar hidden in the hourglass shape of light.</li><li>Galaxies merging with visible star-forming regions connecting them.</li><li>Image of NGC 7469, a galaxy bursting with new stars.</li><li>Southern Ring planetary nebula observed in mid-infrared.</li></ul><blockquote>“Webb’s infrared vision can peer through dust to observe cosmic phenomena like never before.”</blockquote><p>The James Webb Telescope continues to redefine our perspective of the cosmos, revealing exquisite details and contributing significantly to astronomical discoveries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/science/three-years-of-james-webb-telescope-in-10-stunning-pictures-197459-26-12-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/science/three-years-of-james-webb-telescope-in-10-stunning-pictures-197459-26-12-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 08:09:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Equal to a trillion hydrogen bombs: Is the Sun readying for a violent super explosion? - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/techandscience/equal-to-a-trillion-hydrogen-bombs-is-the-sun-readying-for-a-violent-super-explosion/ar-AA1wuYD4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/techandscience/equal-to-a-trillion-hydrogen-bombs-is-the-sun-readying-for-a-violent-super-explosion/ar-AA1wuYD4</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 07:13:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yearly round-up: The biggest science stories of 2024 - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yearly round-up: The biggest science stories of 2024</h1>
<p><strong>Published on 26 December 2024</strong> by Deccan Herald</p>
<img src="https://images.deccanherald.com/deccanherald%2F2024-12-26%2F2j55dsnu%2F2024_07_10T112309Z_1573420465_RC29S8A4XW7G_RTRMADP_5_CZECH_ZOO_ICE.JPG" alt="A polar bear rests on ice cubes that were brought to its enclosure during a heatwave at Prague Zoo in Prague, Czech Republic, July 10, 2024.">
<figcaption>A polar bear rests on ice cubes during a heatwave at Prague Zoo. Credit: Reuters File Photo</figcaption>
<p>As humanity completed another revolution around the Sun, science threw up some fascinating findings this year. Here’s a look at some of the biggest stories in science for 2024.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>The hottest year on record:</strong> 2024 has been declared the hottest year since records began in 1850, with severe heatwaves across the globe.</li>
  <li><strong>HIV prevention drug shows immense promise:</strong> The FDA-approved drug lenacapavir demonstrated 96%-100% success rates in two trials.</li>
  <li><strong>In search of extraterrestrial life:</strong> NASA's Clipper mission targets Jupiter's moon Europa for signs of life.</li>
  <li><strong>A perfect storm:</strong> The northern lights were visible far beyond their typical range due to solar activity.</li>
  <li><strong>Mapping a fruit fly's brain:</strong> Researchers mapped a fruit fly's brain containing over 140,000 neurons.</li>
  <li><strong>Detecting Alzheimer's:</strong> A new blood test for Alzheimer's showed 88%-92% accuracy, simplifying detection.</li>
  <li><strong>Human-Neanderthal breeding timeline:</strong> Interbreeding between humans and Neanderthals determined to have occurred around 50,500 to 43,500 years ago.</li>
  <li><strong>Gene editing with a dash of AI:</strong> CRISPR technology is enhanced with AI, resulting in a new gene editing tool.</li>
  <li><strong>New moons around old planets:</strong> Three new moons were discovered orbiting Uranus and Neptune.</li>
  <li><strong>Oldest reptile skin:</strong> The oldest known fossilized reptile skin was found, dated over 300 million years ago.</li>
</ul>
<p>2024 was a landmark year for scientific discoveries, setting the stage for future advancements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/science/the-biggest-science-stories-of-2024-yearly-round-up-3332303</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/science/the-biggest-science-stories-of-2024-yearly-round-up-3332303</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 07:12:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Equal to a trillion hydrogen bombs: Is the Sun readying for a violent super explosion? - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Equal to a trillion hydrogen bombs: Is the Sun readying for a violent super explosion?</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 26, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/2024-12/solar%20eruption%20b.gif?VersionId=kTg0pEGIDqWgJkJhCamo6Ud9.VxBxTP8" width="690" alt="Sun superflare" title="The findings reveal that sun-like stars are prone to superflares. (Photo: Nasa)" height="388"><figcaption>The findings reveal that sun-like stars are prone to superflares. (Photo: Nasa)</figcaption><p>An international team of researchers has discovered that sun-like stars, including our own Sun, can produce enormous radiation outbursts known as superflares approximately every hundred years. This is a significant increase compared to prior estimations of their frequency.</p><ul><li>Superflares release energy levels surpassing a trillion hydrogen bombs.</li><li>Researchers analyzed data from NASA's Kepler space telescope, identifying 2,889 superflares across 2,527 stars.</li><li>The occurrence rate of these superflares is substantially higher than previously thought.</li><li>Evidence from tree rings and glacial ice indicates past extreme solar activities.</li><li>The study emphasizes the necessity of monitoring sun-like stars for better frequency estimation of superflares.</li></ul><blockquote>“The implications for Earth are significant; a superflare could pose even greater risks to modern infrastructure and satellites.” - Dr. Valeriy Vasilyev</blockquote><p>Monitoring methods will improve with ESA’s upcoming space probe Vigil, set to enhance monitoring capabilities starting in 2031.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/equal-to-a-trillion-hydrogen-bombs-is-the-sun-readying-for-a-superflare-explosion-2655510-2024-12-26</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/equal-to-a-trillion-hydrogen-bombs-is-the-sun-readying-for-a-superflare-explosion-2655510-2024-12-26</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 06:39:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asteroid Alert! Airplane-sized Giant Space Rock Set For Close Encounter With Earth On Dec 28, NASA Issues Warn - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Asteroid Alert! Airplane-sized Giant Space Rock Set For Close Encounter With Earth On Dec 28</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><img loading='lazy' src='https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116672728,thumbsize-873005,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116672728.jpg' alt='Asteroid (AI-Generated Image)' title='Asteroid (AI-Generated Image)'><figcaption>Asteroid (AI-Generated Image)</figcaption><p>This week, NASA confirmed that an 80-foot asteroid named 2024 YQ2 will safely pass by Earth on December 28, 2024, at a speed of 58,360 km/h.</p><ul><li>Asteroid 2024 YQ2 will fly by at a distance of 1,030,000 km, over twice the distance between the Earth and the Moon.</li><li>Despite its size, 2024 YQ2 is not a threat to Earth and is classified as a Near-Earth Object (NEO).</li><li>NASA is monitoring near-Earth asteroids to better understand our solar system and refine planetary defense strategies.</li><li>The NEO Surveyor mission, aimed at improving detection of hazardous asteroids, is set to launch in 2028.</li></ul><blockquote>“For an asteroid to be considered a Potentially Hazardous Object, it must be larger than 150 meters and come within 7.5 million kilometers of Earth.”</blockquote><p>NASA's ongoing efforts to monitor and study asteroids like 2024 YQ2 underscore the importance of planetary defense and preparedness for potential future threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/asteroid-alert-airplane-sized-giant-space-rock-set-for-close-encounter-with-earth-on-dec-28-nasa-issues-warning-article-116672689</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/asteroid-alert-airplane-sized-giant-space-rock-set-for-close-encounter-with-earth-on-dec-28-nasa-issues-warning-article-116672689</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 05:54:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asteroid Alert! Airplane-sized Giant Space Rock Set For Close Encounter With Earth On Dec 28, NASA Issues Warning - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Asteroid Alert! Airplane-sized Giant Space Rock Set For Close Encounter With Earth On Dec 28</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><img loading='lazy' src='https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116672728,thumbsize-873005,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116672728.jpg' alt='Asteroid (AI-Generated Image)' title='Asteroid (AI-Generated Image)'><figcaption>Asteroid (AI-Generated Image)</figcaption><p>This week, NASA confirmed that an 80-foot asteroid named 2024 YQ2 will safely pass by Earth on December 28, 2024, at a speed of 58,360 km/h.</p><ul><li>Asteroid 2024 YQ2 will fly by at a distance of 1,030,000 km, over twice the distance between the Earth and the Moon.</li><li>Despite its size, 2024 YQ2 is not a threat to Earth and is classified as a Near-Earth Object (NEO).</li><li>NASA is monitoring near-Earth asteroids to better understand our solar system and refine planetary defense strategies.</li><li>The NEO Surveyor mission, aimed at improving detection of hazardous asteroids, is set to launch in 2028.</li></ul><blockquote>“For an asteroid to be considered a Potentially Hazardous Object, it must be larger than 150 meters and come within 7.5 million kilometers of Earth.”</blockquote><p>NASA's ongoing efforts to monitor and study asteroids like 2024 YQ2 underscore the importance of planetary defense and preparedness for potential future threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/asteroid-alert-airplane-sized-giant-space-rock-set-for-close-encounter-with-earth-on-dec-28-nasa-issues-warning-article-116672689</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/asteroid-alert-airplane-sized-giant-space-rock-set-for-close-encounter-with-earth-on-dec-28-nasa-issues-warning-article-116672689</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 05:54:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[390 million light-years away: 7 Most beautiful images of interacting galaxies captured by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>390 million light-years away: 7 Most beautiful images of interacting galaxies captured by NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/beautiful-galaxy-1.jpg" alt="390 million light-years away: NASA captures 7 most beautiful images of interacting galaxies">
<figcaption>Stunning image of interacting galaxies captured by NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases seven breathtaking images of interacting galaxies captured by NASA, emphasizing the beauty and complexity of galaxies located approximately 390 million light-years away.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The first image reveals a captivating view of two galaxies with immense gravitational pull.</li>
  <li>Another image highlights the tangled cosmic interaction of the galaxies MCG+05-31-045.</li>
  <li>Arp 148 captures the aftermath of a cosmic encounter between two galaxies.</li>
  <li>Arp 143 features a bright, distorted star-forming spiral galaxy.</li>
  <li>Wild's Triplet showcases an interesting dynamic among three galaxies.</li>
  <li>Arp 142 illustrates a vibrant interaction between a pair of galaxies.</li>
  <li>Lastly, an artistic representation of two galaxies intertwined aurally by gravity is included.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These images provide a glimpse into the dynamic and beautiful nature of our universe.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, this series of images serves to inspire awe and wonder about the vastness of space and the fascinating interactions within it.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/390-million-light-years-away-7-most-beautiful-images-of-interacting-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-7493573/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/390-million-light-years-away-7-most-beautiful-images-of-interacting-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-7493573/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 05:31:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ajey Lele’s Article ‘NASA’s Midas Touch: Parker Probe Touching The Sun’ Published in SSPC - Institute for Defence Studies and Analyses]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNRG5FNzVNSWtmY2p0TWFWOWlSdWJSdGszTGRHWGJ6YkY5NmpKQWE2SmdhLW5tMmlmRTc1WmVQZ1dJVTBhSS14ZHRaVnVFdXVIU0FfNmtHSmZ1NkYtbjFEaGVVOWkyUTZoZlRKejlHU1N5VzdwZjl2bVN0VXd2U0hnamktVUZNNTlsOXQzOVhJdTNMaGIxN1MwbEw2UzNOVWwxVUs3NmhKbXJ2MlNjVlVV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNRG5FNzVNSWtmY2p0TWFWOWlSdWJSdGszTGRHWGJ6YkY5NmpKQWE2SmdhLW5tMmlmRTc1WmVQZ1dJVTBhSS14ZHRaVnVFdXVIU0FfNmtHSmZ1NkYtbjFEaGVVOWkyUTZoZlRKejlHU1N5VzdwZjl2bVN0VXd2U0hnamktVUZNNTlsOXQzOVhJdTNMaGIxN1MwbEw2UzNOVWwxVUs3NmhKbXJ2MlNjVlVV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 05:04:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronauts send Christmas message to Earth from Space Station - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-au/news/australia/astronauts-send-christmas-message-to-earth-from-space-station/vi-AA1wtcW8</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-au/news/australia/astronauts-send-christmas-message-to-earth-from-space-station/vi-AA1wtcW8</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 04:02:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quiz | Easy like Sunday morning: What has science done for us in 2024? - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Quiz | Easy like Sunday morning: What has science done for us in 2024?</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> December 26, 2024 09:03 am IST</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/s92d2l/article69012239.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/iStock-1256999264.jpg" alt="A research at Kenya’s Samburu National Reserve has revealed that elephants can identify 469 distinct calls among themselves." title="A research at Kenya’s Samburu National Reserve has revealed that elephants can identify 469 distinct calls among themselves."><figcaption>A research at Kenya’s Samburu National Reserve has revealed that elephants can identify 469 distinct calls among themselves. | Photo Credit: Getty Images/iStock</figcaption><p>This article presents a quiz highlighting key scientific achievements and discoveries from 2024. It includes intriguing questions that explore topics ranging from space exploration to animal behavior.</p><ul><li>1. 'Odysseus' became the first commercial vehicle to land on the moon, carrying historic information.</li><li>2. New species named <i>E.akayima</i> discovered in the Caribbean.</li><li>3. Three new moons were added to the known list of satellites in our Solar System.</li><li>4. Mosquitoes dubbed 'World’s deadliest animal' with significant engineered interventions.</li><li>5. University of Maine's 'Factory of the Future' debuted a massive 3D printer.</li><li>6. 'Retrowalking' found beneficial for spinal health.</li><li>7. Elephants communicate with 469 distinct calls.</li><li>8. X-59 QueSST aims to achieve supersonic flight without sonic boom disruptions.</li><li>9. Hot baths help combat Chytrid disease affecting frogs.</li><li>10. Artemis 2 is set to take humans back to the Moon.</li></ul><blockquote>“Elephants call each other by specific names.”</blockquote><p>The quiz invites readers to reflect on the fascinating advancements in science and encourages engagement with scientific exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/berty-ashley-easy-like-sunday-morning-quiz/article69012229.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/entertainment/berty-ashley-easy-like-sunday-morning-quiz/article69012229.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 03:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maximum afterburner test successful: NASA’s X-59 silent supersonic aircraft is about to fly for the first time – Passionategeekz - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxQWXJDNzNqVWczMmlFUXpWNXhncy12NlFZeHJlam45UDhGSWdHU2lrSTl6Qm9NSGlIaGNYX05UTTBCSk5ScnZ2OVdpRWNmMjJLU3hjSnNGdkZUUlc0TGwwTUdwc0g5MHZ1ZXhPVVg4VW9qd291cWV3dTYxbGFJZ1NxWW9HbTZOa2ctWGUxX1FOYllpMW1XTHNyMm1YcEhsWF9hV3VEaVhLWkdFMXJ5cXhGbmFZVDNFcmV2Z2VRSDc2Nk9nZU9MRzRoYWdTRjV6aGo5dXZyN2lyUFBGUXpyb3AxbW1oTS1IaElP0gHoAUFVX3lxTFBZckM3M2pVZzMyaUVRelY1eGdzLXY2UVl4cmVqbjlQOEZJZ0dTaWtJOXpCb01IaUhoY1hfTlRNMEJKTlJydnY5V2lFY2YyMktTeGNKc0Z2RlRSVzRMbDBNR3BzSDkwdnVleE9VWDhVb2p3b3VxZXd1NjFsYUlnU3FZb0dtNk5rZy1YZTFfUU5iWWkxbVdMc3IybVhwSGxYX2FXdURpWEtaR0UxcnlxeEZuYVlUM0VyZXZnZVFINzY2T2dlT0xHNGhhZ1NGNXpoajl1dnI3aXJQUEZRenJvcDFtbWhNLUhoSU8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxQWXJDNzNqVWczMmlFUXpWNXhncy12NlFZeHJlam45UDhGSWdHU2lrSTl6Qm9NSGlIaGNYX05UTTBCSk5ScnZ2OVdpRWNmMjJLU3hjSnNGdkZUUlc0TGwwTUdwc0g5MHZ1ZXhPVVg4VW9qd291cWV3dTYxbGFJZ1NxWW9HbTZOa2ctWGUxX1FOYllpMW1XTHNyMm1YcEhsWF9hV3VEaVhLWkdFMXJ5cXhGbmFZVDNFcmV2Z2VRSDc2Nk9nZU9MRzRoYWdTRjV6aGo5dXZyN2lyUFBGUXpyb3AxbW1oTS1IaElP0gHoAUFVX3lxTFBZckM3M2pVZzMyaUVRelY1eGdzLXY2UVl4cmVqbjlQOEZJZ0dTaWtJOXpCb01IaUhoY1hfTlRNMEJKTlJydnY5V2lFY2YyMktTeGNKc0Z2RlRSVzRMbDBNR3BzSDkwdnVleE9VWDhVb2p3b3VxZXd1NjFsYUlnU3FZb0dtNk5rZy1YZTFfUU5iWWkxbVdMc3IybVhwSGxYX2FXdURpWEtaR0UxcnlxeEZuYVlUM0VyZXZnZVFINzY2T2dlT0xHNGhhZ1NGNXpoajl1dnI3aXJQUEZRenJvcDFtbWhNLUhoSU8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 02:40:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["That’s a super siiiick photo!!" — Internet reacts to NASA posting picture of a star cluster in space that looks like a Christmas tree - Sportskeeda]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Internet's Enthusiastic Reaction to NASA's Festive Star Cluster Photo</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Sportskeeda</p>
<figure><img src="https://staticg.sportskeeda.com/editor/2024/12/0f062-17351703011763-1920.jpg?w=640" alt="Docked Shuttle - Source: Getty (Photo by NASA/Space Frontiers/Getty Images)"><figcaption>Docked Shuttle - Source: Getty (Photo by NASA/Space Frontiers/Getty Images)</figcaption></figure>
<p>NASA and ESA recently released a stunning photo of the 'Christmas Tree Cluster,' NGC 2264, which is about 2300 light years away from Earth. This cosmic image has sparked excitement on social media platforms.</p>
<ul>
<li>The gas in the surrounding nebula is shown in green, enhancing the Christmas tree resemblance.</li>
<li>Users on X (formerly Twitter) reacted with enthusiasm, sharing poetic thoughts and celebrating the beauty of the cosmos.</li>
<li>Notable comments included reflections on cosmic artistry and profound connections to the universe.</li>
<li>The photo highlights NASA's ongoing efforts in cosmic exploration and public engagement.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"That’s a super siiiick photo!! 💚💚💚 very Christmas like!!" - User on X</blockquote>
<blockquote>"The beauty of creation is truly limitless. A cosmic Christmas tree thousands of light-years away reminds us how vast and wondrous the universe is." - Another user</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the festive cosmic imagery has inspired awe and connection among viewers, celebrating both the holiday season and the wonders of space.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sportskeeda.com/pop-culture/news-that-s-super-siiiick-photo-internet-reacts-nasa-posting-picture-star-cluster-space-looks-like-christmas-tree</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sportskeeda.com/pop-culture/news-that-s-super-siiiick-photo-internet-reacts-nasa-posting-picture-star-cluster-space-looks-like-christmas-tree</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US News Today Live Updates on December 26, 2024 : Donald Trump’s Border Czar Tom Homan calls for $86 billion to launch mass deportations | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US News Today Live Updates on December 26, 2024: Tom Homan Calls for $86 Billion for Mass Deportations</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 26 Dec, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> LiveMint</p><figure><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2024/12/25/600x338/USA-POLITICS-CONSERVATIVES-10_1735161977697_1735161991556.JPG" alt="Donald Trump’s Border Czar Tom Homan calls for $86 billion to launch mass deportations" /><figcaption>Donald Trump’s Border Czar Tom Homan calls for $86 billion to launch mass deportations</figcaption></figure><p>Tom Homan, the incoming Border Czar, has proposed a significant funding request to Congress for mass deportations, arguing for its importance to national security.</p><ul><li>Homan estimates that $86 billion will be necessary to implement the mass deportation plan.</li><li>The initiative is framed as critical for national security and expected to yield long-term financial benefits.</li></ul><blockquote>“This initiative is critical for national security,” said Homan, emphasizing the financial benefits.</blockquote><p>This plan is part of ongoing discussions regarding immigration and border security policies under the Trump administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/latest-us-news-today-on-december-26-2024-live-updates-11735156334826.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/latest-us-news-today-on-december-26-2024-live-updates-11735156334826.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 21:27:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US News Today Live Updates on December 26, 2024 : How did NASA astronauts get Christmas decorations in space? Social media wants answers | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US News Today Live Updates on December 26, 2024: How did NASA astronauts get Christmas decorations in space? Social media wants answers</h1><p><strong>Published on: 26 Dec, 2024</strong> by <strong>LiveMint</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2024/12/25/600x338/nasa_video_1735155271702_1735155277548.jpeg" alt="US News Today Live Updates: How did NASA astronauts get Christmas decorations in space? Social media wants answers"><figcaption>US News Today Live Updates: How did NASA astronauts get Christmas decorations in space? Social media wants answers</figcaption></figure><p>NASA astronauts Butch Wilmore and Sunita Williams brought Christmas cheer to the International Space Station (ISS), raising questions on social media regarding the logistics of getting festive decorations into space.</p><ul><li>Astronauts Butch Wilmore and Sunita Williams brought Christmas cheer to the ISS, donning Santa hats despite being stranded in orbit since June. Social media buzzed with playful questions about how festive decorations made it on their originally short mission, sparking intrigue about space logistics.</li></ul><blockquote>“In today’s dynamic landscape, staying updated on the latest developments across the United States is essential,” the report states.</blockquote><p>This event highlights the unique blend of human experience and space exploration, reminding us of the personal connections that endure even in the most challenging environments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/latest-us-news-today-on-december-26-2024-live-updates-11735156334826.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/latest-us-news-today-on-december-26-2024-live-updates-11735156334826.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 19:52:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Solar Probe vanishes into the sun after closest flyby, signal awaited - Interesting Engineering]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTFBXTE0wS3pUV09vcGVWbmJZdFJILWoweXljYUlZUUZpMktNeGl1aDZhMjFYckZvZWxERTZDUUNET0RKWjhTVlcxT1Jwd1JrZlhmMG14Qnh1cnBfRWh0eksyY2xpelBWemVwTWhxbGd3VHZDTndTN09kSA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTFBXTE0wS3pUV09vcGVWbmJZdFJILWoweXljYUlZUUZpMktNeGl1aDZhMjFYckZvZWxERTZDUUNET0RKWjhTVlcxT1Jwd1JrZlhmMG14Qnh1cnBfRWh0eksyY2xpelBWemVwTWhxbGd3VHZDTndTN09kSA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 17:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video | Stunning Satellite Imagery Highlights Key Moments Of 2024 In NDTV Reportage - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stunning Satellite Imagery Highlights Key Moments Of 2024 In NDTV Reportage</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>Satellite imagery has revolutionized journalism, enabling global reporters to uncover stories often overlooked or concealed. For NDTV, satellite images have been vital in reporting for years. As 2024 concludes, Maxar Technologies presents some of the most powerful images of the year, capturing defining moments around the world.</p><ul><li>Satellite imagery has changed the landscape of journalism.</li><li>NDTV has relied on satellite images for significant reports.</li><li>Maxar Technologies showcases key moments captured through satellite in 2024.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/video/stunning-satellite-imagery-highlights-key-moments-of-2024-in-ndtv-reportage-878130</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/video/stunning-satellite-imagery-highlights-key-moments-of-2024-in-ndtv-reportage-878130</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 17:10:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experts Raise The Alarm About Incoming Massive Volcanic Eruption: “Humanity Does Not Have Any Plan” - Bored Panda]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Experts Warn of Potential Catastrophic Volcanic Eruption: No Preparedness Plan Exists</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p><img src="https://www.boredpanda.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/volcanic-eruption-676bb91017b8e__700.jpg" alt="Massive Volcanic Eruption Warning" /><figcaption>Experts Raise The Alarm About Incoming Massive Volcanic Eruption: “Humanity Does Not Have Any Plan”</figcaption><p>Scientists warn of a looming massive volcanic eruption, with a one-in-six chance occurring this century. Experts, such as Markus Stoffel from the University of Geneva, emphasize that humanity lacks a plan to manage the potential disaster.</p><ul><li>1-in-6 chance of a catastrophic eruption this century.</li><li>Markus Stoffel: “Humanity does not have any plan.”</li><li>Previous eruptions like the 1815 Mount Tambora resulted in widespread devastation.</li></ul><blockquote>“The effects might be even worse than we saw back in 1815.” – Michael Rampino, NYU Professor</blockquote><p>The potential for climate chaos looms, necessitating immediate preparedness measures to ensure safety and food supply in the event of a major eruption.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.boredpanda.com/next-massive-volcano-eruption-cause-climate-chaos/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.boredpanda.com/next-massive-volcano-eruption-cause-climate-chaos/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:07:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead Galaxies, Mysterious Red Dots: James Webb Telescope's Findings So Far - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxQVVFhc0xBY3NMd250blhDU2tHbTZNM1dZaTZOTzVNWXRGVDlNM2c5MnV0ZWRiWlNwSUIxM3hFYTZhSkhGT29lWklmbDhFX1p3WEl6U3BJRFU4MDBrVmhERE80V25PREZFbGZHb1BsdlM0RDhHMjdnSklHdFUyblc5WmJsRmFENTMweTBabDdMZTB4Y0phYWtGWUZjdzRkTjNyQlZFejI2SGdWSDRHUWV3eNIBuAFBVV95cUxNb0VMREZBY0xvSUxrSlE1OEY3UkN6aV9LbHlYS2dSR3RFN09ZZnNSekVpTmQ0LW9mZ3J0VU1nbEdzV0ZXdmpLQjBkc0JFbVhCeVRWUmtpM0lwc0hzNHpWVkdDRWRZdU5GYmRBX0Z5cGhJVWxlYV9MVTJUSTk3Mms2MWpBRjFET0NUTUV4UFdrd1lHMVA2eVp4Zk5FQWlKSHhhYlYwTGo5TmhBMHM0Z3FXbTNJNWtiLTVj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxQVVFhc0xBY3NMd250blhDU2tHbTZNM1dZaTZOTzVNWXRGVDlNM2c5MnV0ZWRiWlNwSUIxM3hFYTZhSkhGT29lWklmbDhFX1p3WEl6U3BJRFU4MDBrVmhERE80V25PREZFbGZHb1BsdlM0RDhHMjdnSklHdFUyblc5WmJsRmFENTMweTBabDdMZTB4Y0phYWtGWUZjdzRkTjNyQlZFejI2SGdWSDRHUWV3eNIBuAFBVV95cUxNb0VMREZBY0xvSUxrSlE1OEY3UkN6aV9LbHlYS2dSR3RFN09ZZnNSekVpTmQ0LW9mZ3J0VU1nbEdzV0ZXdmpLQjBkc0JFbVhCeVRWUmtpM0lwc0hzNHpWVkdDRWRZdU5GYmRBX0Z5cGhJVWxlYV9MVTJUSTk3Mms2MWpBRjFET0NUTUV4UFdrd1lHMVA2eVp4Zk5FQWlKSHhhYlYwTGo5TmhBMHM0Z3FXbTNJNWtiLTVj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:56:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s cosmic ‘Wreath’ and ‘Christmas Tree’ shed light on stellar birth and evolution - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s cosmic ‘Wreath’ and ‘Christmas Tree’ shed light on stellar birth and evolution</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>December 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source: </strong><a href='https://www.news9live.com/science'>Science News</a></p>
<img width='802' height='464' src='https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Star-clusters.png?w=802&enlarge=true' alt='Valuable insights into star formation and evolution in different cosmic environments. (Image Credit: NASA/CXC/SAO/L. Frattare and K. Arcand)' title='Star clusters'>
<figcaption>Valuable insights into star formation and evolution in different cosmic environments. (Image Credit: NASA/CXC/SAO/L. Frattare and K. Arcand)</figcaption>
<p><strong>New Delhi: </strong>NASA has revealed breathtaking images of two star clusters, NGC 602 and NGC 2264, resembling festive decorations. These clusters allow astronomers to observe stellar birth in contrasting cosmic environments.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The images from NASA's Chandra X-ray Observatory and James Webb Space Telescope show surrounding gas and dust formations.</li>
  <li>NGC 602, located 200,000 light-years away in the Small Magellanic Cloud, displays young stars in an ionised gas region.</li>
  <li>NGC 2264 is known as the “Christmas Tree Cluster” and is about 2,500 light-years away, showcasing a conical shape resembling a Christmas tree.</li>
  <li>The data offers insights into star formation and the life cycle of stars.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These cosmic images paint how beautiful and intricate the process of star formation is.”</blockquote>
<p>NASA's continuous exploration extends our knowledge of the universe's mysteries, shedding light on the processes of star formation and evolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/nasas-cosmic-wreath-and-christmas-tree-shed-light-on-stellar-birth-and-evolution-2781558</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/nasas-cosmic-wreath-and-christmas-tree-shed-light-on-stellar-birth-and-evolution-2781558</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:18:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead galaxies, mysterious red dots: James Webb's groundbreaking finds in 3 years - The Federal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxNWGEwcmdmeXNsSVB0U203TGMxM25pdEJWN0dkcndwRFB5UVFMc2FybHRyWVFuQS1xTC1WZWl5Q2loYlU0a1Z5X0tSZ2VGcENxV19VTVc4c0xuSE0tLV85UzNtRmhvUUtRUzAza2xTU3pWM1JvQTBpTXBFWVUtQUV3dFUxQ1NhWlVJVjRIZ0hzLXhibE5qeWIxTjBHT1RTVlJMRlBlZFBSV2N2SDN3Ni02X0RiNnh3Z2RYQXNfd0o0MTRKNl80MzBzdThR0gHPAUFVX3lxTFBSNElUSVRSMzA2YmFoQzkzMS1BRlhLN1pkaXdtRnh3cW5IcVlLREpvTkpWRU91NnRfUVJLMzVGQmFCNGdLUjUybXpSTkxrZk9SSncwQ0J4Mm5yWDdKYjFTMTdDdVgyVm1VcXhRVGszRGREc05HeE1fdlNxOWh2dk1uS293NG1wQlZjSThfVXVYZUsxYlBmS0tLUEVfVXRfOF81WnVTQWIyV2NBWmdUak4ySk53TXY2SGM2OXZTMXhRb3ktZFllUDJ5UFh6dU9aUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxNWGEwcmdmeXNsSVB0U203TGMxM25pdEJWN0dkcndwRFB5UVFMc2FybHRyWVFuQS1xTC1WZWl5Q2loYlU0a1Z5X0tSZ2VGcENxV19VTVc4c0xuSE0tLV85UzNtRmhvUUtRUzAza2xTU3pWM1JvQTBpTXBFWVUtQUV3dFUxQ1NhWlVJVjRIZ0hzLXhibE5qeWIxTjBHT1RTVlJMRlBlZFBSV2N2SDN3Ni02X0RiNnh3Z2RYQXNfd0o0MTRKNl80MzBzdThR0gHPAUFVX3lxTFBSNElUSVRSMzA2YmFoQzkzMS1BRlhLN1pkaXdtRnh3cW5IcVlLREpvTkpWRU91NnRfUVJLMzVGQmFCNGdLUjUybXpSTkxrZk9SSncwQ0J4Mm5yWDdKYjFTMTdDdVgyVm1VcXhRVGszRGREc05HeE1fdlNxOWh2dk1uS293NG1wQlZjSThfVXVYZUsxYlBmS0tLUEVfVXRfOF81WnVTQWIyV2NBWmdUak4ySk53TXY2SGM2OXZTMXhRb3ktZFllUDJ5UFh6dU9aUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:34:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From dead galaxies to mysterious red dots, here’s what the James Webb telescope has found in just 3 years - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/science/space/from-dead-galaxies-to-mysterious-red-dots-heres-what-the-james-webb-telescope-has-found-in-just-3-years-3331677</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/science/space/from-dead-galaxies-to-mysterious-red-dots-heres-what-the-james-webb-telescope-has-found-in-just-3-years-3331677</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:52:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From dead galaxies to mysterious red dots, here’s what the James Webb telescope has found in just 3 years - Devdiscourse]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_AFBVV95cUxPUFF0d3QyN20wX29CZk8tdlNUdDNUM3ZlREg2M2ZfNFpOY2wzcUxSNTk2OTJYYnJUcmVBSmpFNkM0bFNKZlI4amIwOFQ5SE54OS1zWkZWY2N2WmRoQVR5MTNEcVc5Y2JFNXBLaGNfeldxSlNYbWNiMHJKVnZWUzhCOGdRVVlPczBNdHdYWnU3STBaV25IZVgzX3JJOXZ4aUw2bG1HWmU2VEJKTEIxLV9tWkdoNWhwSXB2dzZDeEtKVy1xZWpWdUt5UUdHNWFVZ0I5Tm16clN5MFFRcF96MjRESzk0b3ZLd1ZYMGJLNC1DNVpuaGVGZXJ5QmtnY1TSAYICQVVfeXFMTl84dWdYcU9RQ2dncXZrUzVLbzVrbEVPU0V0TDc5YzFLbGlOd1c5d1BYSFdqYzN3ZVFoTFRkbmZuUTYzNVZpRXhLMEJaREc0X0MzS1ItaUNTX1B5SFdzOXZDbmdZNDFTSWhBaEpFeHhRZ1V3Unk4Ui1UT3RCX0k5SW0xbHB2ZkltQWZqSDluQXRFSzNjY3hWNkpwTl9QZFRfU2lNZ2xrVmk2SkV0SUF2aExmbXpBRTg0NEZlT21mSUtDWkVHVFFUSnVadm9OeTFFb2NuMEhQYUNyRG1rZnRzOVNKdnZEUzZUQWdyZ3dFWTR0ajhXd21CUjBEYXVNejUyZUpR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_AFBVV95cUxPUFF0d3QyN20wX29CZk8tdlNUdDNUM3ZlREg2M2ZfNFpOY2wzcUxSNTk2OTJYYnJUcmVBSmpFNkM0bFNKZlI4amIwOFQ5SE54OS1zWkZWY2N2WmRoQVR5MTNEcVc5Y2JFNXBLaGNfeldxSlNYbWNiMHJKVnZWUzhCOGdRVVlPczBNdHdYWnU3STBaV25IZVgzX3JJOXZ4aUw2bG1HWmU2VEJKTEIxLV9tWkdoNWhwSXB2dzZDeEtKVy1xZWpWdUt5UUdHNWFVZ0I5Tm16clN5MFFRcF96MjRESzk0b3ZLd1ZYMGJLNC1DNVpuaGVGZXJ5QmtnY1TSAYICQVVfeXFMTl84dWdYcU9RQ2dncXZrUzVLbzVrbEVPU0V0TDc5YzFLbGlOd1c5d1BYSFdqYzN3ZVFoTFRkbmZuUTYzNVZpRXhLMEJaREc0X0MzS1ItaUNTX1B5SFdzOXZDbmdZNDFTSWhBaEpFeHhRZ1V3Unk4Ui1UT3RCX0k5SW0xbHB2ZkltQWZqSDluQXRFSzNjY3hWNkpwTl9QZFRfU2lNZ2xrVmk2SkV0SUF2aExmbXpBRTg0NEZlT21mSUtDWkVHVFFUSnVadm9OeTFFb2NuMEhQYUNyRG1rZnRzOVNKdnZEUzZUQWdyZ3dFWTR0ajhXd21CUjBEYXVNejUyZUpR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:07:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>