<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 05:24:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 05:24:45 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 breathtaking NASA Hubble images unveiling wonders of the universe | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/news/5-breathtaking-nasa-hubble-images-unveiling-wonders-of-the-universe-11734410175044.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/news/5-breathtaking-nasa-hubble-images-unveiling-wonders-of-the-universe-11734410175044.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 05:08:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA captures stunning image of dust-covered InSight Lander on Mars: See how dust shapes the red planet - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-captures-stunning-image-of-dust-covered-insight-lander-on-mars-see-how-dust-shapes-the-red-planet-article-12891490.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-captures-stunning-image-of-dust-covered-insight-lander-on-mars-see-how-dust-shapes-the-red-planet-article-12891490.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:15:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX’s second-generation starship launch enters countdown, S33 completes static ignition - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxNR2lUR1JVVjRYN2Q4MUpBMHBhQzhMcnFWcmxVbUh0cnhRQnVIaEd0WmZmYmxSM1hrNGN5WEtHbWdzS25rTEZkcWpnNWtmWWJkc3V4VndKMXVkdExFUEl4cmVLNW10SFNMbVJSTW0xTTVYNDU0cTdacXRmaFFBTWRPV0dGZlVSMk1FNWxEYjl2SUhqdExTTW9PeGRsdDVrOHUwYUUtTXhhT3RsUGhHdnZZVW1YemlLMVRGcDN6Tk1ETzVXaGx2cFI2Z1JoQUgxUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxNR2lUR1JVVjRYN2Q4MUpBMHBhQzhMcnFWcmxVbUh0cnhRQnVIaEd0WmZmYmxSM1hrNGN5WEtHbWdzS25rTEZkcWpnNWtmWWJkc3V4VndKMXVkdExFUEl4cmVLNW10SFNMbVJSTW0xTTVYNDU0cTdacXRmaFFBTWRPV0dGZlVSMk1FNWxEYjl2SUhqdExTTW9PeGRsdDVrOHUwYUUtTXhhT3RsUGhHdnZZVW1YemlLMVRGcDN6Tk1ETzVXaGx2cFI2Z1JoQUgxUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:07:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jupiter's Hellish Moon Isn't Powered by a Hidden Ocean of Magma, Study Finds - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jupiter's Moon Io Powered by Localized Magma Chambers, Not a Global Ocean</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Science Alert</p><figure><img decoding="async" src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/12/IoCutout.jpg" alt="Io interior" width="642" height="642" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Artist's illustration showing the internal structure of Io: a mostly solid mantle (green hues), with substantial melt (yellows and oranges), overlying a liquid core (red/black). (NASA/Caltech-JPL/SwRI)</figcaption></figure><p>New research indicates that the volcanic activity on Jupiter's moon Io is not driven by a hidden ocean of magma, as previously suggested. Instead, scientists have found that the volcanoes are fed by a network of small magma chambers within a primarily solid mantle.</p><ul><li>The study used NASA's Juno spacecraft images and gravitational data.</li><li>It counters previous theories suggesting a global magma ocean under Io’s surface.</li><li>The findings have implications for understanding planetary formation and evolution.</li><li>Io's surface is covered with volcanic remnants from its numerous eruptions.</li><li>This research provides insights into tidal heating processes in celestial bodies.</li></ul><blockquote>“This constant flexing creates immense energy, which literally melts portions of Io's interior,” says Scott Bolton, a space physicist involved in the study.</blockquote><p>The research highlights the complexity of tidal heating effects and broadens the understanding of volcanic processes on other celestial bodies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/jupiters-hellish-moon-isnt-powered-by-a-hidden-ocean-of-magma-study-finds</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/jupiters-hellish-moon-isnt-powered-by-a-hidden-ocean-of-magma-study-finds</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 02:45:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Earth at risk? James Webb Space Telescope discovered many tiny asteroids in the asteroid belt between - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>James Webb Space Telescope Detects Numerous Tiny Asteroids Between Mars and Jupiter</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116373906,imgsize-10526,width-400,resizemode-4/116373906.jpg" alt="Is Earth at risk? James Webb Space Telescope discovered many tiny asteroids in the asteroid belt between Jupiter and Mars" title="Image source: Space.com" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Image source: Space.com</figcaption><p>Astronomers using the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) have discovered a large number of tiny asteroids in the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter, raising concerns about their potential risk to Earth.</p><ul><li>Discovery of an unexpectedly high number of tiny asteroids in the asteroid belt.</li><li>The asteroids are significantly smaller than those that caused the extinction of the dinosaurs but pose a greater risk due to their higher collision frequency with Earth.</li><li>A new computational method developed by astronomers allows for improved detection of these small asteroids using GPU technology.</li><li>Among the discoveries, six asteroids have orbits that could potentially intersect with Earth's orbit.</li><li>The JWST's infrared capabilities enhance the detection of faint and fast-moving asteroids.</li><li>Future observations using JWST and other advanced telescopes, like the Vera C. Rubin Observatory, will enhance tracking and identification of small asteroids.</li></ul><blockquote>“This newfound ability to detect small asteroids ... is a critical step toward improving planetary defense.”</blockquote><p>The advancements made by the JWST in detecting small asteroids highlight the growing importance of planetary defense strategies and monitoring potential threats to Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/is-earth-at-risk-james-webb-space-telescope-discovered-many-tiny-asteroids-in-the-asteroid-belt-between-jupiter-and-mars/articleshow/116373808.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/is-earth-at-risk-james-webb-space-telescope-discovered-many-tiny-asteroids-in-the-asteroid-belt-between-jupiter-and-mars/articleshow/116373808.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Laser beam casts a shadow in a ruby crystal - physicsworld.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTE10TElvTF9fZzNzZEMtUHVlV3VuUzRlMEJjM2x2T2FwWjM3WkE4Q2pXeTBYWlRET0V3WDNWTWNVSENsbzc2QW5uMlZSdEpWa0ZTSHFlaUViV24xcldSeDlFelNxU2tUaHVrVE4tdjY2N0NSSnplc3ZaQ2ZzMA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTE10TElvTF9fZzNzZEMtUHVlV3VuUzRlMEJjM2x2T2FwWjM3WkE4Q2pXeTBYWlRET0V3WDNWTWNVSENsbzc2QW5uMlZSdEpWa0ZTSHFlaUViV24xcldSeDlFelNxU2tUaHVrVE4tdjY2N0NSSnplc3ZaQ2ZzMA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 01:05:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Perseverance Rover Completes Its Epic Climb to Crater Rim - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Perseverance Rover Completes Its Epic Climb to Crater Rim</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 12, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Universe Today</p><figure><img decoding="async" src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/12/perserverence_journey_map.jpg" alt="perseverance journey on Mars" width="642" height="486" loading="lazy"><figcaption>The route NASA's Perseverance Mars rover took (in blue) as it climbed the western rim of Jezero Crater. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/University of Arizona)</figcaption></figure><p>NASA's Perseverance rover has successfully reached the top of Jezero Crater's rim, a significant milestone achieved after three and a half months of climbing. This journey enhances the rover's ability to explore a new geological area on Mars.</p><ul><li>The Perseverance rover climbed 500 vertical meters (1,640 vertical feet) to reach Lookout Hill.</li><li>The upcoming Northern Rim campaign will see the rover drive 6.4 kilometers (4 miles) to investigate up to four locations for geological samples.</li><li>Perseverance has completed four prior science campaigns since landing in February 2021, focusing on different aspects of Jezero Crater's geology.</li><li>Significant geological features and potential ancient life evidence are present in the new targeted area.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Northern Rim campaign brings us completely new scientific riches as Perseverance roves into fundamentally new geology." - Ken Farley, Caltech</blockquote><p>This achievement is crucial for furthering our understanding of Mars's geology and potential for past life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/nasas-perseverance-rover-completes-its-epic-climb-to-crater-rim</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/nasas-perseverance-rover-completes-its-epic-climb-to-crater-rim</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:24:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA releases long-term strategy for robotic Mars exploration - SpaceNews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA releases long-term strategy for robotic Mars exploration</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 11, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p>
<p>The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) has unveiled a new strategy to enhance robotic exploration of Mars, proposing a series of smaller, science-driven missions to prepare for future human exploration.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nasa's 20-year plan encourages low-cost missions at each launch opportunity.</li>
<li>The strategy introduces three key science themes: searching for life, supporting human exploration, and understanding Mars as a dynamic planetary system.</li>
<li>Smaller missions are expected to cost between $100 million and $300 million each and will focus on specific scientific questions.</li>
<li>The plan emphasizes collaboration with commercial and international partners.</li>
<li>Nasa's 2025 budget proposal includes $40 million for Mars robotic exploration technologies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We want to do that with lower-cost missions that are science driven and has the capability of providing flexible, rapid response to discoveries.” - Becky McCauley Rench</blockquote>
<p>This strategy is aimed at expanding our understanding of Mars and lays the groundwork for future human missions to the planet, emphasizing scientific inquiry and innovative partnerships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://spacenews.com/nasa-releases-long-term-strategy-for-robotic-mars-exploration/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://spacenews.com/nasa-releases-long-term-strategy-for-robotic-mars-exploration/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:54:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Finalizes Strategy for Sustaining Human Presence in Low Earth Orbit - IT News Online]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQdll3LWdYWXJOanN2MGlVS21nZ1BKaHY0RnhPZTFOenU5LWdRdXNTRjdwNVZKZk92SVlqb3JvSktfY0V1el90N3U3WDFDUmhZWDRmXzhNRFhiTi1BQmRRN2FtNXg4dWV4Z3ZKVmNuLVVWMmVnMGc1OVlVcmkxTXk0MnlxRHBJVFlqWUdCWXFWWm03aDl1cGVrbkR3VU5TYUhrYVpWcHVoLWpVdmRoSWU0M2VEYmp1SlpXeG14Tg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQdll3LWdYWXJOanN2MGlVS21nZ1BKaHY0RnhPZTFOenU5LWdRdXNTRjdwNVZKZk92SVlqb3JvSktfY0V1el90N3U3WDFDUmhZWDRmXzhNRFhiTi1BQmRRN2FtNXg4dWV4Z3ZKVmNuLVVWMmVnMGc1OVlVcmkxTXk0MnlxRHBJVFlqWUdCWXFWWm03aDl1cGVrbkR3VU5TYUhrYVpWcHVoLWpVdmRoSWU0M2VEYmp1SlpXeG14Tg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:57:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new method to detect dehydration in plants - MIT News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A New Method to Detect Dehydration in Plants</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 1, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Nature Communications</p>
<p>Researchers at the Singapore-MIT Alliance for Research and Technology (SMART) have developed a breakthrough sensor technology that can detect drought stress in plants in real-time, allowing for timely interventions to prevent crop loss.</p>
<ul>
<li>Development of the world's first covalent organic framework (COF) sensors integrated within silk fibroin microneedles for in-planta detection of physiological pH changes.</li>
<li>The sensors can detect early signs of drought stress, providing warnings up to 48 hours in advance compared to traditional methods.</li>
<li>This technology aims to enhance agricultural practices amidst challenges such as climate change and reduced resources.</li>
<li>The integration of COF-based sensors and biomaterials facilitates seamless monitoring of plant health.</li>
<li>The findings are published in an open-access paper titled “Chromatic Covalent Organic Frameworks Enabling In-Vivo Chemical Tomography.”</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This type of sensor can be easily attached to the plant and queried with simple instrumentation. It can therefore bring powerful analyses into the hands of farmers and researchers alike.” - Professor Michael Strano</blockquote>
<p>This new sensor technology represents a significant advancement in precision agriculture, potentially optimizing crop production and resilience to drought.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.mit.edu/2024/new-method-detect-dehydration-plants-1216</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.mit.edu/2024/new-method-detect-dehydration-plants-1216</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Finalizes Strategy for Sustaining Human Presence in Low Earth Orbit - StreetInsider.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.streetinsider.com/PRNewswire/NASA+Finalizes+Strategy+for+Sustaining+Human+Presence+in+Low+Earth+Orbit/24110769.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.streetinsider.com/PRNewswire/NASA+Finalizes+Strategy+for+Sustaining+Human+Presence+in+Low+Earth+Orbit/24110769.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:41:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Finalizes Strategy for Sustaining Human Presence in Low Earth Orbit - NASA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Finalizes Strategy for Sustaining Human Presence in Low Earth Orbit</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>NASA has released its final goals and objectives to sustain a human presence in low Earth orbit, paving the way for advancements in microgravity science and international collaboration.</p><ul><li>The strategy outlines 13 goals and 44 objectives for low Earth orbit.</li><li>It aims to ensure the U.S. leadership in space as the ISS approaches retirement in 2030.</li><li>Stakeholder engagement included over 1,800 comments and workshops to refine the strategy.</li><li>The goals span commercial infrastructure, scientific research, and international cooperation.</li><li>The initiative supports deep space exploration efforts toward missions to the Moon and Mars.</li></ul><blockquote>“As we near the retirement of the International Space Station in 2030, these objectives are a pivotal next step in solidifying U.S. leadership in space.” - Pam Melroy, NASA Deputy Administrator</blockquote><p>The finalized objectives will help NASA navigate the transition to commercial space stations and maintain continuous human presence, essential for future deep space missions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-finalizes-strategy-for-sustaining-human-presence-in-low-earth-orbit/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-finalizes-strategy-for-sustaining-human-presence-in-low-earth-orbit/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:04:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISRO’s latest Space Feat—PSLV-C59 /Proba-3 Mission - Brighter Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxORHFSajQ5ejBldzk4VUhiUHRyb1dDeEVLTHU4MjBXVVRmSWZELU0tRnZ2cm1PeWp4Y0xYTlBiS2tyUVdaX09SdVNRSHpzRE4wMTVXSlJzM1o5azh3X2lHUUxwTm9FT2h0dnp1SnNCQkpia1Exa3p5NGxmZE52RzkwZg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxORHFSajQ5ejBldzk4VUhiUHRyb1dDeEVLTHU4MjBXVVRmSWZELU0tRnZ2cm1PeWp4Y0xYTlBiS2tyUVdaX09SdVNRSHpzRE4wMTVXSlJzM1o5azh3X2lHUUxwTm9FT2h0dnp1SnNCQkpia1Exa3p5NGxmZE52RzkwZg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:58:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 spectacular images of space captured by NASA Hubble Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>9 Spectacular Images of Space Captured by NASA Hubble Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/QT-Antennae-Galaxies-reloaded.jpg" alt="QT Antennae Galaxies reloaded">
<figcaption>Antennae Galaxies reloaded: The NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope has snapped the best ever image of the Antennae Galaxies.</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases stunning images taken by the Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting significant celestial phenomena and features.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Antennae Galaxies reloaded - best image captured by Hubble.</li>
  <li>Extreme star cluster reveals a huge cavity shaped by hot blue stars.</li>
  <li>Galaxy NGC 2525 - located 70 million light-years from Earth.</li>
  <li>Hubble’s 31st anniversary celebrated with a view of AG Carinae.</li>
  <li>Lagoon Nebula - Hubble's colorful image for its 28th anniversary.</li>
  <li>Magnetic monster NGC 1275 captured in stunning detail.</li>
  <li>New stars blowing a cavity in a fascinating star-forming region.</li>
  <li>Rings of Relativity depicting GAL-CLUS-022058.</li>
  <li>The Eagle nebula resembling a winged creature.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Thanks For Reading! Next: 5 Birds with razor sharp memory.”</blockquote>
<p>The images from Hubble not only demonstrate the advancements in space observation but also inspire awe and curiosity about the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/9-spectacular-images-of-space-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-7470444/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/9-spectacular-images-of-space-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-7470444/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:33:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Distinguishing Albino Zebras from Elephants | by Avi Loeb | Dec, 2024 - Medium]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://medium.com/@avi-loeb/distinguishing-albino-zebras-from-elephants-0116cee91e7a</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/@avi-loeb/distinguishing-albino-zebras-from-elephants-0116cee91e7a</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:06:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First-Ever Black Hole Image Sharpened Using Machine Learning - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 19:51:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Performs First Air Crash Investigation on a World Located 100 Million Miles Away - autoevolution]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.autoevolution.com/news/nasa-performs-first-air-crash-investigation-on-a-world-located-100-million-miles-away-244245.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.autoevolution.com/news/nasa-performs-first-air-crash-investigation-on-a-world-located-100-million-miles-away-244245.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 19:18:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronomers Uncover Explosive Mystery as Enormous Gamma-Ray Flare Erupts from M87's Black Hole - The Debrief]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxOcHh5RzRfdm1VOVBGMGhEbjR2TlZPVjN2eGFoeFNyYmRXbjNCWndEamlqWHdEVkZDbTAtZ1BlVVd5RkVGa2lCNWNPSFNZVEROV0UtdDdnMVlQaTgxTG5EV0ZiZmlXUy1nMnhYUXhQTnU3dlpteVFXbDBXeU9jal9tRTREdEhYbzd0TTcyS0FsSHhvdFpEMlJjYlFVY3IyZ2phUE1TZ3VWdnNzQmR5UHdFWXJaamRPVG0z?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxOcHh5RzRfdm1VOVBGMGhEbjR2TlZPVjN2eGFoeFNyYmRXbjNCWndEamlqWHdEVkZDbTAtZ1BlVVd5RkVGa2lCNWNPSFNZVEROV0UtdDdnMVlQaTgxTG5EV0ZiZmlXUy1nMnhYUXhQTnU3dlpteVFXbDBXeU9jal9tRTREdEhYbzd0TTcyS0FsSHhvdFpEMlJjYlFVY3IyZ2phUE1TZ3VWdnNzQmR5UHdFWXJaamRPVG0z?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 19:00:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Discovered: Batch of asteroids between Mars, Jupiter - ummid.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Batch of Asteroids Discovered Between Mars and Jupiter</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Science</p>
<img src="asteroids.webp" width="800" height="534" alt="Discovered: Batch of asteroids between Mars, Jupiter">
<figcaption>Discovered: Batch of asteroids between Mars, Jupiter</figcaption>
<p>Astronomers have discovered a vast population of small asteroids in the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter using archival images from the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST).</p>
<ul>
  <li>The newly discovered asteroids range in size from that of a bus to several stadiums.</li>
  <li>These asteroids, termed “decametre,” collide with Earth 10,000 times more often than larger asteroids.</li>
  <li>A total of 138 new decametre asteroids were found, along with eight previously known asteroids.</li>
  <li>NASA has identified two asteroids, 2024 XY5 and 2024 XB6, passing near Earth on December 16, 2024.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“An asteroid just tens of metres in size exploded over Chelyabinsk, Russia, releasing 30 times more energy than the atomic bomb detonated over Hiroshima.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, this discovery enhances the understanding and tracking of smaller asteroids that may approach Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://ummid.com/news/2024/december/16-12-2024/discovered-batch-of-asteroids-between-mars-jupiter.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ummid.com/news/2024/december/16-12-2024/discovered-batch-of-asteroids-between-mars-jupiter.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How mouse sperm in space could shape humanity's cosmic future - Interesting Engineering]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How Mouse Sperm in Space Could Shape Humanity's Cosmic Future</h1><p><strong>Updated:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 01:30 PM EST</p><img alt="Radiation-proof sperm: How space mouse semen could help humans thrive on Moon, Mars" loading="lazy" width="584" height="421" src="https://cms.interestingengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/httpscms.interestingengineering.comwp-adminpost.phppost87133actionedit-14.png"><figcaption>Representative image of a mouse. iStock</figcaption><p>The challenges of human survival beyond Earth involve more than just breathable air; it's crucial to ensure life can reproduce in the harsh conditions of space. Scientists are exploring how freeze-dried mouse sperm could aid interplanetary colonization.</p><ul><li>Experiments show that freeze-dried mouse sperm can remain viable in space for up to 200 years.</li><li>Recent studies indicate that sperm stored on the ISS produced healthy offspring after rehydration.</li><li>Researchers aim to extend sperm preservation using advanced radiation protection devices.</li><li>Future plans include creating biobanks on the Moon or Mars to safeguard genetic materials.</li><li>Understanding reproduction in space is essential for transporting food and pets to other planets.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our aim is to establish a system for safely and permanently preserving Earth’s genetic resources somewhere in space.”</blockquote><p>The research could prove vital for ensuring humanity's survival beyond Earth, laying the groundwork for life even in extreme environments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://interestingengineering.com/science/space-mouse-sperm-humans-cosmic-future</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://interestingengineering.com/science/space-mouse-sperm-humans-cosmic-future</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISRO’s latest space feat-PSLV-C59/Proba-3 Mission - State Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ISRO Successfully Launches PSLV-C59/Proba-3 Mission</h1><p><strong>Last Updated: Dec 16, 2024</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Omkar Dattatray</strong></p><p>Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) has achieved another significant milestone with the successful launch of the PSLV-C59 rocket carrying the European Space Agency’s Proba-3 mission. This launch marks the world’s first precision formation-flying demonstration in space.</p><img src='image_url' alt='PSLV-C59 Launch' /><figcaption>ISRO's PSLV-C59 Launch.</figcaption><p>The mission, which took place on December 5, 2024, aims to study the solar corona and the solar wind using two spacecraft operating in tandem.</p><ul><li>PSLV-C59 launched from Satish Dhawan Space Centre at 4:04 PM.</li><li>Proba-3 is designed for precision formation flying, creating artificial solar eclipses for extended observations.</li><li>The mission demonstrates collaborative efforts between ISRO, ESA, and New Space India Ltd.</li><li>Launch postponed due to anomalies but was executed successfully after rescheduling.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am grateful to ISRO for this picture-perfect ascent to orbit.” - Damien Galano, Proba-3 Mission Manager</blockquote><p>This launch underscores the advancements in international collaboration in space exploration and paves the way for future scientific opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://statetimes.in/isros-latest-space-feat-pslv-c59-proba-3-mission/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://statetimes.in/isros-latest-space-feat-pslv-c59-proba-3-mission/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:29:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA solves 44-year-old mystery of why Jupiter's Io is so volcanically active - Livescience.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Solves 44-Year-Old Mystery of Io's Volcanic Activity</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 12, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Science</p><p>NASA scientists have resolved a decades-old question regarding why Jupiter's moon, Io, is so volcanically active, concluding that its volcanoes are fed by localized underground magma chambers rather than a global magma ocean.</p><ul><li>Io, slightly larger than Earth's moon, is home to an estimated 400 volcanoes.</li><li>NASA's Juno spacecraft made close flybys of Io to study its geology.</li><li>The research indicates that tidal flexing of Io is responsible for its volcanic activity, heating its interior.</li></ul><blockquote>“Juno's discovery that tidal forces do not always create global magma oceans does more than prompt us to rethink what we know about Io's interior,” said Ryan Park, Juno co-investigator.</blockquote><p>This newfound understanding of Io's geology sheds light on volcanic processes not just in our solar system but also on exoplanets, enhancing our knowledge of planetary evolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livescience.com/space/nasa-solves-mystery-of-why-jupiters-io-is-so-volcanically-active</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livescience.com/space/nasa-solves-mystery-of-why-jupiters-io-is-so-volcanically-active</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX’s 31st Dragon cargo capsule departs ISS to head home to Earth - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaceX's 31st Dragon Cargo Capsule Departs ISS to Head Home to Earth</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<p>SpaceX's 31st robotic cargo mission is on its way back to Earth, after successfully undocking from the International Space Station (ISS) this morning.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Dragon cargo capsule undocked at 11:05 a.m. EST, beginning deorbit burns to complete its mission.</li>
  <li>It will splash down off the coast of Florida tomorrow, December 17, with thousands of pounds of equipment and samples from ISS research.</li>
  <li>The spacecraft is currently the only cargo craft capable of safely returning cargo to Earth, while others incinerate upon reentry.</li>
  <li>CRS-31 delivered 6,000 pounds of supplies for NASA's astronauts at the ISS in November.</li>
  <li>NASA can quickly retrieve the Dragon after splashdown to continue research on the returned experiments.</li>
  <li>Today's undocking was delayed from its original schedule due to bad weather in the splashdown zone.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“NASA will be able to retrieve the CRS-31 Dragon spacecraft relatively quickly after splashdown tomorrow, reaping the benefits of any experiments in need of quick attending following atmospheric reentry.”</blockquote>
<p>This mission is crucial for ongoing research and supply to astronauts on the ISS, highlighting the importance of commercial partnerships in space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/space-exploration/international-space-station/spacexs-31st-dragon-cargo-capsule-departs-iss-to-head-home-to-earth</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/space-exploration/international-space-station/spacexs-31st-dragon-cargo-capsule-departs-iss-to-head-home-to-earth</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:37:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Mirror life forms’ may sound like science fiction, but scientists warn they could be deadly to humans and destroy the environment - Yahoo News UK]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Understanding Yahoo's Family of Brands and Privacy Practices</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Yahoo</p><p>Yahoo reiterates its identity as part of the Yahoo family of brands, explaining the use of cookies for various functionalities across its sites and apps.</p><ul><li>Yahoo is part of a broader family of brands, including AOL.</li><li>Their services utilize cookies for authentication, security, and usage analytics.</li><li>Users have the option to accept or reject the use of personal data and cookies for targeted advertising.</li><li>Privacy settings can be managed at any time through their privacy dashboard.</li></ul><blockquote>“When you use our sites and apps, we use cookies to provide our services.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Yahoo emphasizes the importance of cookies for user experience while providing options for privacy management.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://consent.yahoo.com/v2/collectConsent?sessionId=2_cc-session_7ab05482-bf7b-4dfd-adb6-738275b7d8a2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://consent.yahoo.com/v2/collectConsent?sessionId=2_cc-session_7ab05482-bf7b-4dfd-adb6-738275b7d8a2</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:29:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Our Martian heritage must be preserved, say leading scientists - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Preserving Our Martian Heritage: A Call from Leading Scientists</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date Not Provided <strong>Source:</strong> The Guardian</p>
<p>Leading researchers emphasize the importance of preserving human artifacts on Mars as part of our species' historical record of space exploration. They warn that current and future missions must consider the impact on existing sites.</p>
<ul>
<li>Scientists assert that artifacts and debris left on Mars represent significant historical markers.</li>
<li>Natural weathering and potential disturbances from missions threaten these sites.</li>
<li>Preservation of these items is crucial for documenting humanity's history of exploration.</li>
<li>Past significant missions like Apollo 11 and Venera 7 also warrant protection due to their heritage status.</li>
<li>Experts suggest a need for a systematic approach to record and map space heritage across different celestial bodies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Each dispersal event represents key moments in our species’ long history of migration.” - Dr. Justin Holcomb</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, safeguarding our Martian heritage is deemed vital for future generations' understanding of our exploratory legacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2024/dec/16/our-martian-heritage-must-be-preserved-say-leading-scientists</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/science/2024/dec/16/our-martian-heritage-must-be-preserved-say-leading-scientists</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Mars Orbiter Spots Retired InSight Lander to Study Dust Movement - NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPUThjUGFVTnoyN0w4c0VDTE04blVDMGkyRWtnRHJwMGVFQU5sSGdzamRkczdJNDhVRHNMOEZqbFk3NDdLWF9OeVBKSzRoNVVoMnNRZWJocnhPTWtlRGhUb2NQcHpPcC1YZVN2a2xMa0FsRktCazhHUHdCZEgtRm1xdmpUX3paNG8yS0FHOWdZc3l4bHFOSGZjNk5SMUZubFVMZ1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxPUThjUGFVTnoyN0w4c0VDTE04blVDMGkyRWtnRHJwMGVFQU5sSGdzamRkczdJNDhVRHNMOEZqbFk3NDdLWF9OeVBKSzRoNVVoMnNRZWJocnhPTWtlRGhUb2NQcHpPcC1YZVN2a2xMa0FsRktCazhHUHdCZEgtRm1xdmpUX3paNG8yS0FHOWdZc3l4bHFOSGZjNk5SMUZubFVMZ1E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:03:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is a dark comet? A quick guide to the 'new' kids in the solar system - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-12-dark-comet-quick-kids-solar.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2024-12-dark-comet-quick-kids-solar.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1st monster black hole ever pictured erupts with surprise gamma-ray explosion - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>1st Monster Black Hole Pictured Erupts with Surprise Gamma-Ray Explosion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Astronomy & Astrophysics</p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/5GTRdfkwkPcEE3pwZr85UD.png" alt="The first image of a black hole, the supermassive black hole at the heart of the galaxy M87"><figcaption>(Main) the first image of a black hole, the supermassive black hole at the heart of the galaxy M87. Light curve of the gamma-ray flare and collection of quasi-simultaneous images of the M87 jet at various scales obtained in radio and X-rays during the 2018 campaign. (Image credit: EHT Collaboration, Fermi-LAT Collaboration, HESS Collaboration, MAGIC Collaboration, VERITAS Collaboration, EAVN Collaboration)</figcaption><p>The Event Horizon Telescope has captured an unexpected gamma-ray explosion from the supermassive black hole M87*, revealing new insights into the structure surrounding black holes.</p><ul><li>The flare lasted for about three days, marking the first flare of M87* since 2010.</li><li>M87* has a mass of about 5.4 billion suns, significantly larger than the Milky Way's central black hole, Sagittarius A*.</li><li>The eruption was significantly more energetic compared to previous flares.</li><li>This event has implications for understanding cosmic rays and high-energy particle acceleration.</li></ul><blockquote>“Together with the EHT's submillimeter observations, this offers a unique opportunity to understand the properties of gamma-ray emission and link it to potential changes in the M87 jet.” — Giacomo Principe, project leader</blockquote><p>This discovery highlights the collaborative nature of modern astronomy, utilizing multiple observatories to enhance our understanding of the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/m87-black-hole-unexpected-gamma-rays</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/m87-black-hole-unexpected-gamma-rays</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mirror bacteria may constitute ‘radical departure from known life,’ scientists warn - Yahoo News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxOa2xHaTFCWWtiTkIwVkZQVUx6dnJKUmRMbVFVR1ZxS3JVb1RkcWhFeTlpTTM2MVlnRDMtZHRONjlGQ05uRnVTaVpqUUM4S1lXOWIwazdtb25ReGtiTGlEcGN4dWUzR0NmU3FZc0t3OU5vemNJVkV5a2FXYXE1NnhXajdB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxOa2xHaTFCWWtiTkIwVkZQVUx6dnJKUmRMbVFVR1ZxS3JVb1RkcWhFeTlpTTM2MVlnRDMtZHRONjlGQ05uRnVTaVpqUUM4S1lXOWIwazdtb25ReGtiTGlEcGN4dWUzR0NmU3FZc0t3OU5vemNJVkV5a2FXYXE1NnhXajdB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 16:49:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Solar superflares dangerous than atomic bombs to hit Earth, scientists warn - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Solar Superflares: More Dangerous Than Atomic Bombs, Scientists Warn</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Scientific Community</p><p>Scientists are raising alarms about the potential threat of solar superflares to Earth, comparing their potential damage to that of atomic bombs.</p><ul><li>Recent studies suggest that solar superflares could have catastrophic effects on Earth's electrical infrastructure.</li><li>The energy released by these solar events may disrupt satellites and communication systems.</li><li>There is an increasing need for preparedness to mitigate the risks posed by these natural phenomena.</li></ul><blockquote>“The impact of a solar superflare could be equivalent to a large-scale nuclear disaster,” experts warn.</blockquote><p>As our reliance on technology grows, understanding and preparing for solar flares becomes increasingly vital for societal safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/solar-superflares-dangerous-than-atomic-bombs-to-hit-earth-scientists-warn/articleshow/116375727.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/solar-superflares-dangerous-than-atomic-bombs-to-hit-earth-scientists-warn/articleshow/116375727.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 16:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>