<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:21:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:21:11 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Apocalyptic Theories About the End of the Universe - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxPcXRXMGR0UkVlLVRmUkVPYzYyREVCclFHZkZvLWp2TUN6VVBHZ09RRHhlWFA1V0txYTJIVzEzTjRCWTgyajN4eklaVUtiWDhXRTBwWEpkUk53TXUzd3ZxUjhJeGJIY0IxbzNsS0FmU1lUeGN1ZmQ1Q1M4LWp0SEVVTVB1Yk5fUnFMZ2NJdm1SOUV5R2pzUVNqb0pNSG9Fb2VjT0hXX3VKQlFzN21NRkc0UzRZWFBUMUnSAbcBQVVfeXFMT3F0VzBkdFJFZS1UZlJFT2M2MkRFQnJRR2ZGby1qdk1DelVQR2dPUUR4ZVhQNVdLcWEySFcxM040Qlk4MmozeHpJWlVLYlg4V0UwcFhKZFJOd011M3d2cVI4SXhiSGNCMW8zbEtBZlNZVHhjdWZkNUNTOC1qdEhFVU1QdWJOX1JxTGdjSXZtUjlFeUdqc1FTam9KTUhvRW9lY09IV191SkJRczdtTUZHNFM0WVhQVDFJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxPcXRXMGR0UkVlLVRmUkVPYzYyREVCclFHZkZvLWp2TUN6VVBHZ09RRHhlWFA1V0txYTJIVzEzTjRCWTgyajN4eklaVUtiWDhXRTBwWEpkUk53TXUzd3ZxUjhJeGJIY0IxbzNsS0FmU1lUeGN1ZmQ1Q1M4LWp0SEVVTVB1Yk5fUnFMZ2NJdm1SOUV5R2pzUVNqb0pNSG9Fb2VjT0hXX3VKQlFzN21NRkc0UzRZWFBUMUnSAbcBQVVfeXFMT3F0VzBkdFJFZS1UZlJFT2M2MkRFQnJRR2ZGby1qdk1DelVQR2dPUUR4ZVhQNVdLcWEySFcxM040Qlk4MmozeHpJWlVLYlg4V0UwcFhKZFJOd011M3d2cVI4SXhiSGNCMW8zbEtBZlNZVHhjdWZkNUNTOC1qdEhFVU1QdWJOX1JxTGdjSXZtUjlFeUdqc1FTam9KTUhvRW9lY09IV191SkJRczdtTUZHNFM0WVhQVDFJ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:41:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New ultrathin conductor promises more efficient, cooler electronics - Tech Explorist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techexplorist.com/new-ultrathin-conductor-promises-more-efficient-cooler-electronics/95551/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techexplorist.com/new-ultrathin-conductor-promises-more-efficient-cooler-electronics/95551/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:40:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's LEXI Mission Will Explore Earth’s Magnetic Shield from the Moon - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's LEXI Mission Will Explore Earth’s Magnetic Shield from the Moon</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Science</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/zowpbPSVSEQ/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Video on LEXI Mission</figcaption><p>NASA is preparing to deploy the Lunar Environment Heliospheric X-ray Imager (LEXI) to the moon, aiming to provide groundbreaking observations of Earth's magnetic field.</p><ul><li>LEXI will capture images of the magnetosphere's movements in response to solar wind.</li><li>The mission seeks to enhance understanding of space weather and its impact on satellites and electronics.</li><li>LEXI will monitor Earth's magnetosphere for six days, using low-energy X-rays.</li><li>Findings may improve predictions of geomagnetic storms affecting technological systems.</li></ul><blockquote>“Stronger solar winds cause the magnetosphere to compress, while weaker winds allow it to expand.” - Hyunju Connor, NASA</blockquote><p>Understanding the interactions of Earth's magnetosphere is crucial for protecting terrestrial and space-based assets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/nasas-lexi-mission-lunar-x-ray-imaging-for-earth-s-magnetic-field-insights-7441645</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/nasas-lexi-mission-lunar-x-ray-imaging-for-earth-s-magnetic-field-insights-7441645</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japan's Wooden Satellite LignoSat Launched: Everything You Need to Know - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Japan's Wooden Satellite LignoSat Launched: Everything You Need to Know</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/UMlvIT42km4/hqdefault.jpg" alt="LignoSat Wooden Satellite" />
<figcaption>LignoSat, the world's first wooden satellite.</figcaption>
<p>In a significant milestone for space exploration, the world's first wooden satellite, LignoSat, has been successfully launched into Earth's orbit by the Japanese Aerospace Exploration Agency (JAXA).</p>
<ul>
  <li>LignoSat aims to explore the feasibility of wood as a sustainable material in satellite construction.</li>
  <li>The satellite was developed using honoki magnolia wood, known for its durability and resistance to environmental stresses.</li>
  <li>LignoSat was launched aboard SpaceX-31's Dragon Cargo Vehicle from the International Space Station.</li>
  <li>The satellite is equipped with sensors to monitor stress, temperature variations, and radiation exposure.</li>
  <li>The initiative could lead to more eco-friendly solutions in satellite technology.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If successful, this initiative could set a precedent for the adoption of sustainable practices in the global space industry.”</blockquote>
<p>The development of sustainable materials for satellite construction is crucial as concerns over the environmental impact of space missions grow.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/japans-wooden-satellite-lignosat-explores-sustainability-in-space-technology-7434946</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/japans-wooden-satellite-lignosat-explores-sustainability-in-space-technology-7434946</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:13:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA warns: China’s Three Gorges Dam could slow Earth’s rotation by 0.06 seconds; here’s how - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA warns: China’s Three Gorges Dam could slow Earth’s rotation by 0.06 seconds; here’s how</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117014398,imgsize-56310,width-400,resizemode-4/117014398.jpg" alt="NASA warns: China’s Three Gorges Dam could slow Earth’s rotation by 0.06 seconds; here’s how" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>The Three Gorges Dam</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses NASA's findings about the Three Gorges Dam in China, noting that its construction and operation have led to a measurable change in the Earth's rotation, specifically a slowdown by 0.06 microseconds per day.</p>
<ul>
  <li>NASA's study indicates that the dam's large water reservoir redistributes Earth's mass, affecting rotational dynamics.</li>
  <li>The Three Gorges Dam is the world's largest hydroelectric dam, significantly contributing to renewable energy production.</li>
  <li>Human activities, such as constructing dams, have broader implications for Earth's physical properties and dynamism.</li>
  <li>The article highlights the growing human capacity to influence the Earth's natural systems.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The effect of the Three Gorges Dam on Earth's rotation is tantamount to the immense and often invisible power that human ingenuity has over planetary systems.”</blockquote>
<p>The findings emphasize the interdependence of human engineering and the natural world, urging responsible environmental stewardship due to the long-term effects of such large projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-warns-chinas-three-gorges-dam-could-slow-earths-rotation-by-0-06-seconds-heres-how/articleshow/117012416.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-warns-chinas-three-gorges-dam-could-slow-earths-rotation-by-0-06-seconds-heres-how/articleshow/117012416.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Stunning Images Of Nebulas Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Stunning Images Of Nebulas Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/117192558/117192558.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=725443" alt="7 Stunning Images Of Nebulas Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope">
<figcaption>Credit: Times Now</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases breathtaking images of various nebulas captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, celebrating the beauty and complexity of star formation across the universe.</p>
<ul>
<li>The article features the Orion Nebula, a nearby star-forming region.</li>
<li>Highlights include stunning images of the Tarantula Nebula and Little Dumbbell Nebula.</li>
<li>Each section provides details on the significance of the showcased nebulae.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Hubble’s colorful capture bursts with color and energy.”</blockquote>
<p>The article emphasizes Hubble's role in advancing our understanding of the universe and the remarkable visuals it provides.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-stunning-images-of-nebulas-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/117192528.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-stunning-images-of-nebulas-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/117192528.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:03:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starwatch: Mars at its brightest, closest to Earth and in conjunction with moon - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Starwatch: Mars at its Brightest and Closest to Earth</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2023  <strong>Source:</strong> The Guardian</p><p>Currently, Mars is at its closest approach to Earth and is set to experience a spectacular conjunction with the moon. This astronomical event will provide an excellent opportunity for skywatchers.</p><ul><li>Mars has recently reached its closest distance to Earth, separated by 59.7 million miles (96.1 million kilometers).</li><li>This proximity occurs every two years, similar to Earth lapping Mars.</li><li>The next significant event occurs on January 16, with Mars reaching “opposition,” making it appear at its brightest.</li><li>The moon will pass near Mars on January 14, providing an additional highlight for observers.</li></ul><blockquote>“Mars reflects the most light that it can, meaning the planet will be at its brightest.”</blockquote><p>This celestial event underlines the dynamic relationship between Earth and Mars, providing a unique spectacle for astronomy enthusiasts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/13/starwatch-mars-at-its-brightest-closest-to-earth-and-in-conjunction-with-moon</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/13/starwatch-mars-at-its-brightest-closest-to-earth-and-in-conjunction-with-moon</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Once-in-a-lifetime comet visible tonight. It won't return for 1,60,000 years - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Once-in-a-lifetime comet visible tonight. It won't return for 160,000 years</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 13, 2025<br><strong>Published By:</strong> Sibu Kumar Tripathi</p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/comet-g3-atlas-c2024-135531400-16x9_0.jpeg?VersionId=qOvQpxAiub7xpvukRWjEi5Lp3FFilNpH&amp;size=690:388" alt="Comet G3 ATLAS (C/2024)" title="Comet G3 ATLAS (C/2024) seen from the Space Station. (Photo: X/@astro_Pettit)"><figcaption>Comet G3 ATLAS (C/2024) seen from the Space Station. (Photo: X/@astro_Pettit)</figcaption><p>Tonight, skywatchers around the world can witness Comet G3 ATLAS (C/2024) at its peak brightness, an event that occurs once every 160,000 years.</p><ul><li>The comet will come within 8.7 million miles of the Sun.</li><li>It is expected to shine at around -3.2 magnitude, visible to the naked eye under good conditions.</li><li>Best viewing opportunities are in the Southern Hemisphere shortly after sunset.</li><li>Astronaut Don Pettit captured images of the comet from the International Space Station.</li><li>Recent observations show a dramatic increase in brightness following a January 2, 2025 outburst.</li></ul><blockquote>Astronomers are closely monitoring G3 ATLAS as it approaches perihelion, raising questions about the comet's stability.</blockquote><p>This once-in-a-lifetime event is generating excitement among stargazers and scientists alike as it makes its historic pass through our skies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/once-in-a-lifetime-comet-g3-atlas-c2024-visible-tonight-it-will-not-return-for-160000-years-2663880-2025-01-13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/once-in-a-lifetime-comet-g3-atlas-c2024-visible-tonight-it-will-not-return-for-160000-years-2663880-2025-01-13</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:59:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Once-in-a-lifetime Comet G3 ATLAS (C/2024) visible tonight. It won't return for 1,60,000 years - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Once-in-a-lifetime comet visible tonight. It won't return for 160,000 years</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Published By:</strong> Sibu Kumar Tripathi</p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/comet-g3-atlas-c2024-135531400-16x9_0.jpeg?VersionId=qOvQpxAiub7xpvukRWjEi5Lp3FFilNpH&amp;size=690:388" alt="Comet G3 ATLAS (C/2024)" title="Comet G3 ATLAS (C/2024) seen from the Space Station. (Photo: X/@astro_Pettit)" width="690" height="388">
<figcaption>Comet G3 ATLAS (C/2024) seen from the Space Station. (Photo: X/@astro_Pettit)</figcaption>
<p>Skywatchers are in for a spectacular treat tonight as Comet G3 ATLAS (C/2024) reaches its peak brightness, an event expected only once every 160,000 years.</p>
<ul>
<li>Discovered on April 5, 2024, by the ATLAS in Chile.</li>
<li>The comet is approaching its perihelion, coming within 8.7 million miles of the Sun.</li>
<li>Recent brightness increases predict it could outshine Venus and Jupiter, with a visibility magnitude of around -3.2.</li>
<li>The best viewing opportunities are in the Southern Hemisphere shortly after sunset.</li>
<li>Astronomers are monitoring for potential fragmentation as the comet approaches the Sun.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It promises to leave an indelible mark on the astronomical calendar.”</blockquote>
<p>It's a unique opportunity for observers, particularly those equipped with binoculars, to witness the brilliance of this historic comet.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/once-in-a-lifetime-comet-g3-atlas-c2024-visible-tonight-it-will-not-return-for-160000-years-2663880-2025-01-13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/once-in-a-lifetime-comet-g3-atlas-c2024-visible-tonight-it-will-not-return-for-160000-years-2663880-2025-01-13</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:59:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can astronauts have sex in space, how will a child born in space look like? - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can astronauts have sex in space, how will a child born in space look like?</h1>
<p><strong>Published Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/birth-in-space.png?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Can astronauts have sex in space, how will a child born in space look like?">
  <figcaption>Can astronauts have sex in space, how will a child born in space look like?</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><strong>Life Beyond Earth:</strong> Humans have always been curious about life beyond Earth, fueling explorations like sending rovers to Mars. This curiosity leads to questions about human reproduction and childbirth in space.</p>
<h2>Pregnancy in Space</h2>
<p>Female astronauts can potentially become pregnant in space, but factors such as zero gravity and radiation can adversely affect fetal development. NASA has no clear policy on intimate relationships in space.</p>
<h2>Challenges of Childbirth</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Zero gravity causes astronauts to lose up to 12% bone density in six months, complicating childbirth.</li>
  <li>Radiation exposure can lead to genetic abnormalities in newborns.</li>
  <li>A child born in space may have physical differences, such as larger skulls due to the absence of gravity.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Animal Reproduction in Space</h2>
<p>Experiments have been conducted on animals, such as sending freeze-dried mouse sperm to space for six years, resulting in healthy offspring back on Earth. However, implications for human reproduction remain uncertain.</p>
<p>The journey to establishing human life in space continues with many challenges to overcome, especially concerning reproduction.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/viral/can-astronauts-have-sex-in-space-how-will-a-child-born-in-space-look-like-7534054/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/viral/can-astronauts-have-sex-in-space-how-will-a-child-born-in-space-look-like-7534054/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:26:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why practical summer courses in neuroscience matter - The Transmitter: Neuroscience News and Perspectives]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxQelpDUVJBaXpPakptekVaR0c1bTBFUWlreld4SFBTdWc2NUd2dmlGQ0QxYkZKNWVPcm42TjJsbk9vR21nWlNyTUF3eWdleUlHWUkxS2dCdHBCZGpRd1RINm1OS3ZUS0NvZHJZanV3TWpScnFYY2l3VTRkUUcyaG4zM203VlBBZXNxbEFTaTdiRGcxaEhOYjdVczdNOVR6OXI5U19J?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxQelpDUVJBaXpPakptekVaR0c1bTBFUWlreld4SFBTdWc2NUd2dmlGQ0QxYkZKNWVPcm42TjJsbk9vR21nWlNyTUF3eWdleUlHWUkxS2dCdHBCZGpRd1RINm1OS3ZUS0NvZHJZanV3TWpScnFYY2l3VTRkUUcyaG4zM203VlBBZXNxbEFTaTdiRGcxaEhOYjdVczdNOVR6OXI5U19J?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:00:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space Agriculture Market Expected to Grow at 18.20% CAGR, Reaching USD 12.7 Billion by 2030 - openPR]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Space Agriculture Market Expected to Grow at 18.20% CAGR, Reaching USD 12.7 Billion by 2030</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> openPR</p><p><img src="https://cdn.open-pr.com/L/1/L113201983_g.jpg" alt="Space Agriculture Market"><figcaption>Space Agriculture Market</figcaption></p><p>The Space Agriculture Market is projected to grow at a robust CAGR of 18.20%, from USD 5.32 billion in 2023 to approximately USD 12.7 billion by 2030, driven by advancements in agricultural technology and increasing investments in space exploration.</p><ul><li>The market growth is influenced by the need for self-sustaining life support systems in long-duration space missions.</li><li>Technologies like hydroponics, aeroponics, and AI-enabled automation are transforming agricultural practices in microgravity.</li><li>Countries such as Vietnam, Thailand, Japan, and South Korea are emerging as key players in the space agriculture sector.</li><li>The US remains a leader due to its significant investments and advancements, particularly through NASA and private companies.</li></ul><blockquote>“Space agriculture plays a critical role in providing food, oxygen, and psychological benefits for sustainable colonization on celestial bodies.”</blockquote><p>This sector not only aims to enhance food production in space but also opens avenues for agricultural innovation on Earth, aligning with the growing consumer desire for sustainability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.openpr.com/news/3811356/space-agriculture-market-expected-to-grow-at-18-20-cagr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.openpr.com/news/3811356/space-agriculture-market-expected-to-grow-at-18-20-cagr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Missions Highlight Groundbreaking Discoveries at AAS Meeting - News Karnataka]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQQW84a2NtUV9rYnhpLS1XNExOQzZLeWR2N2JCTXcwYkQyVDBMMTU3bXNFaDVqbm1mYTMybVZKeENhM19XbTBWbjlmV2QyVGdtWTViQmRuVTNyTnFmR0tQUlJ3ejdFblpXNWh5ek9UT1VtUXhfNFlRT19nS3VhLXRBemswTHNnSXlBUk15X3dOYTU5UUs4Q0w2VmNqVTRKSWJSSkw4WG9jZUk2RVc5MWo0QkNn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxQQW84a2NtUV9rYnhpLS1XNExOQzZLeWR2N2JCTXcwYkQyVDBMMTU3bXNFaDVqbm1mYTMybVZKeENhM19XbTBWbjlmV2QyVGdtWTViQmRuVTNyTnFmR0tQUlJ3ejdFblpXNWh5ek9UT1VtUXhfNFlRT19nS3VhLXRBemswTHNnSXlBUk15X3dOYTU5UUs4Q0w2VmNqVTRKSWJSSkw4WG9jZUk2RVc5MWo0QkNn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:20:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Full Wolf Moon: When and how to see 2025's brightest night - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/techandscience/full-wolf-moon-when-and-how-to-see-2025-s-brightest-night/ar-BB1rkhvh</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/techandscience/full-wolf-moon-when-and-how-to-see-2025-s-brightest-night/ar-BB1rkhvh</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:01:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BepiColombo Just Completed its Sixth Flyby of Mercury. Here are the Best Images - Universe Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BepiColombo Completes Sixth Flyby of Mercury with Stunning Images</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> <a href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/BepiColombo/Top_three_images_from_BepiColombo_s_sixth_Mercury_flyby">ESA</a></p>
<img decoding="async" width="1024" height="1024" src="https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Mercury_in_true_color-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Mercury_in_true_color-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Mercury_in_true_color-580x580.jpg 580w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Mercury_in_true_color-250x250.jpg 250w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Mercury_in_true_color-768x768.jpg 768w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Mercury_in_true_color-100x100.jpg 100w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Mercury_in_true_color.jpg 1040w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px">
<figcaption>Image of Mercury taken by NASA’s MESSENGER mission. Credit: NASA/JHUAPL/ASU/Carnegie Institution of Washington</figcaption>
<p>BepiColombo has successfully completed its sixth flyby of Mercury, capturing remarkable images of the planet as it prepares for its final orbit, set for 2026. This mission, a collaboration between ESA and JAXA, is crucial for understanding the characteristics of Mercury.</p>
<ul>
<li>BepiColombo is maneuvering closer to Mercury with each flyby.</li>
<li>The spacecraft captured stunning images from just a few hundred kilometers above Mercury's surface.</li>
<li>Mercury is the smallest and closest planet to the Sun, with extreme temperature variations.</li>
<li>Two orbiters, the ESA’s Mercury Planetary Orbiter and JAXA’s Mercury Magnetospheric Orbiter, are involved in this mission.</li>
<li>First images from the flyby revealed craters, volcanic plains, and evidence of frozen water.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The craters Prokofiev, Kandinsky, Tolkien, and Gordimer can be seen with their permanently dark floors.</blockquote>
<p>The successful sixth flyby marks a significant step in BepiColombo's mission, bringing us closer to understanding Mercury's geology and history as it edges towards its final orbit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.universetoday.com/170394/bepicolombo-just-completed-its-sixth-flyby-of-mercury-here-are-the-best-images/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.universetoday.com/170394/bepicolombo-just-completed-its-sixth-flyby-of-mercury-here-are-the-best-images/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 23:52:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Says Spacecraft Made Closest-Ever Pass to Sun - VOA Learning English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Says Spacecraft Made Closest-Ever Pass to Sun</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>December 24, 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>VOA Learning English</p><figure><img alt="This artist's impression depicts the Parker Solar Probe on a flight around the Sun. (Image Credit: NASA/Johns Hopkins APL/Steve Gribben)" src="https://gdb.voanews.com/64cc5979-1a36-4ccc-9eab-ad712ec595b0_cx0_cy7_cw100_w250_r1_s.png" height="36" width="684"></figure><figcaption>This artist's impression depicts the Parker Solar Probe on a flight around the Sun. (Image Credit: NASA/Johns Hopkins APL/Steve Gribben)</figcaption><p>The Parker Solar Probe has made history by passing within 6.1 million kilometers of the Sun, the closest any spacecraft has ever approached.</p><ul><li>The probe, launched in August 2018, studies the Sun's corona and solar wind.</li><li>NASA confirmed the spacecraft is safe and successfully communicated after the pass.</li><li>Speed records were set, with the probe traveling at up to 692,000 kilometers per hour.</li><li>This mission aids in understanding solar impacts on technology and search for habitable worlds.</li><li>Data from the Parker Solar Probe has provided insights on solar wind speeds, reaching up to 1.6 million kilometers per hour.</li></ul><blockquote>“Flying this close to the sun is a historic moment in humanity’s first mission to a star.” - Nicky Fox, NASA’s Associate Administrator</blockquote><p>This achievement marks a significant advancement in solar exploration, enhancing our understanding of solar phenomena and their effects on our solar system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://learningenglish.voanews.com/a/nasa-says-spacecraft-made-closest-ever-pass-to-sun/7932240.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://learningenglish.voanews.com/a/nasa-says-spacecraft-made-closest-ever-pass-to-sun/7932240.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 22:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Satellite mission will closely monitor changes on Earth's surface - Earth.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxQVGNKOWVmaGh6a19OdEFIRWNFdV9UTDFaMVZVYnpGV190M2EwWWoyOGFuNjN1eEtYMEUzelBqVG5vTVRKc1hKVUhCeWlCRFJCbzUxTzRIWVZCdkdBTGQ2cVlTdUREUlVYMjRZYVp2SFllQTZQQUlYeGo2RlF5VWtrOEtLN3BLR1NnbmluTU5VVjNFelF4dk80?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxQVGNKOWVmaGh6a19OdEFIRWNFdV9UTDFaMVZVYnpGV190M2EwWWoyOGFuNjN1eEtYMEUzelBqVG5vTVRKc1hKVUhCeWlCRFJCbzUxTzRIWVZCdkdBTGQ2cVlTdUREUlVYMjRZYVp2SFllQTZQQUlYeGo2RlF5VWtrOEtLN3BLR1NnbmluTU5VVjNFelF4dk80?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 21:02:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Find New Galaxy Forming At Tip Of Tidal Tail Stretching 1.27 Million Light-Years - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/scientists-find-new-galaxy-forming-at-tip-of-tidal-tail-str-hing-1-27-million-light-years-aa-9185533.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/scientists-find-new-galaxy-forming-at-tip-of-tidal-tail-str-hing-1-27-million-light-years-aa-9185533.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 20:32:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fossil uncovers early evolution of animal nervous system - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fossil Uncovers Early Evolution of Animal Nervous System</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [date not provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article discusses a significant fossil discovery that sheds light on the early evolution of the animal nervous system, providing insights into how complex neural structures have developed over millions of years.</p><ul><li>The fossil, dating back over 500 million years, was found in [location not provided].</li><li>It shows the first evidence of a centralized nervous system in primitive animals.</li><li>This finding helps scientists understand the ecological and evolutionary context of early animal life.</li></ul><blockquote>“This discovery challenges previous assumptions about the development of nervous systems in early animals,” said [quote from a researcher not provided].</blockquote><p>This fossil represents an important piece of the puzzle in understanding the evolution of complex organisms and their nervous systems, influencing future research directions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/fossil-uncovers-early-evolution-of-animal-nervous-system/articleshow/117181616.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/fossil-uncovers-early-evolution-of-animal-nervous-system/articleshow/117181616.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Say They've Figured Out What Turned the Sun Blue - Futurism]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Identify Volcano That Turned the Sun Blue in 1831</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified. <strong>Source:</strong> Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</p><p>The study reveals that the Zavaritskii volcano in the Kuril Islands caused the Sun to appear blue after a volcanic eruption in 1831, which cooled the planet significantly and led to social upheaval.</p><img src='https://www.example.com/image.jpg' alt='The Sun Blue' /><figcaption>The blue Sun phenomenon caused by the 1831 eruption.</figcaption><p>This finding came from detailed analyses of ash found in polar ice cores.</p><ul><li>In 1831, a volcanic eruption dropped global temperatures by nearly two degrees Fahrenheit.</li><li>The Zavaritskii volcano was identified through ash fingerprinting.</li><li>Scientists utilized samples from ice cores to make this determination.</li><li>The Kuril Islands continue to be under-monitored for volcanic activity.</li></ul><blockquote>“If this eruption were to happen today, I don't think we'd be much better off than we were in 1831,” said study lead author Will Hutchinson.</blockquote><p>This research highlights the need for monitoring volcanic activity to prepare for potential climate-impacting eruptions in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://futurism.com/the-byte/scientists-turned-sun-blue</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://futurism.com/the-byte/scientists-turned-sun-blue</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China test-fires 5 new rocket engines in a single day. But what are they for? (video) - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Test-Fires 5 New Rocket Engines in a Single Day</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/7iPoNY79Pa8m5KvAAULh9H-320-80.jpg" alt="closeup image of a rocket engine firing, producing a streak of orange flame during a ground-based test" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>On Jan. 2, 2025, China tested five new rocket engines, which could help power a variety of space missions. (Image credit: CCTV)</figcaption>
<p>China successfully tested five different rocket engines on January 2, 2025, as part of preparations for future space missions. These tests were conducted by the China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation (CASC).</p>
<ul>
  <li>Tests were carried out at two locations: Beijing and Laiyuan County in Hebei Province.</li>
  <li>One of the engines tested was a new hydrogen-oxygen engine designed for an unspecified rocket.</li>
  <li>A methane-liquid oxygen engine was also successfully test-fired.</li>
  <li>The tests were part of CASC's ongoing research into engines for deep-space exploration.</li>
  <li>CASC plans to debut new Long March and commercial rockets later in 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The just-completed experiment tested an upper-stage liquid hydrogen-liquid oxygen engine. It tested the overall coordination of the engine and obtained performance data. After assessment, we concluded that the test was a complete success," - Xia Wei, CASC engineer.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, China's recent rocket engine tests mark significant progress in their space exploration efforts, and the forthcoming developments could enhance their rocket capabilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/space-exploration/launches-spacecraft/china-test-fires-5-new-rocket-engines-in-a-single-day-but-what-are-they-for-video</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/space-exploration/launches-spacecraft/china-test-fires-5-new-rocket-engines-in-a-single-day-but-what-are-they-for-video</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Historic planet parade on Jan 25: NASA's 2025 sky guide and how to watch - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPVVd0VUtTeDRtV19DY0FCNkdjVzRoNVlIVTZRSUY3MHpFdWxMZl91M2Y2NzVTa3NoQjY0V2lFZ1dfS3ZBQVk4Sk05cUdyUjdqZEFaM2xKSDIyTXRxVS1uSTd3SGJkeHpfRk5GN25GV3AtQllfRVJKcFhnVWNZaGFtZVg0NmgxdXpfdUJvdlVDbjNaSmVObnZfOG5OTEVIT1duNGdVdEU0eUZEd01mVUpOVUVXLWxGekZOVW5jbzUwd1EyYzJxMGfSAcsBQVVfeXFMTkNLRzhrZHBraEUxRG9xeTROSWl6VWdVYm1kVDVWdHZGY19fNjhtczlGdDFXclZ2ajdPbUpmWFl2RE5IR1UyMmpzaGJKN2pOOVBRSFVqeHBJVFFKcXhuMXdUeElGSnpxZmxSSnlGMlFtZHpCWjY3NzFkWl9DTzNVLVllckVlamlpRE4xYW1iZjczQkh6X1JLZTc5a2JDMjBWWkhvWktHVjJIZUZ6ZWNGdFJSSGg3a0w3Q3l4emFGRlg3azM5MXpEY3p5aEU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPVVd0VUtTeDRtV19DY0FCNkdjVzRoNVlIVTZRSUY3MHpFdWxMZl91M2Y2NzVTa3NoQjY0V2lFZ1dfS3ZBQVk4Sk05cUdyUjdqZEFaM2xKSDIyTXRxVS1uSTd3SGJkeHpfRk5GN25GV3AtQllfRVJKcFhnVWNZaGFtZVg0NmgxdXpfdUJvdlVDbjNaSmVObnZfOG5OTEVIT1duNGdVdEU0eUZEd01mVUpOVUVXLWxGekZOVW5jbzUwd1EyYzJxMGfSAcsBQVVfeXFMTkNLRzhrZHBraEUxRG9xeTROSWl6VWdVYm1kVDVWdHZGY19fNjhtczlGdDFXclZ2ajdPbUpmWFl2RE5IR1UyMmpzaGJKN2pOOVBRSFVqeHBJVFFKcXhuMXdUeElGSnpxZmxSSnlGMlFtZHpCWjY3NzFkWl9DTzNVLVllckVlamlpRE4xYW1iZjczQkh6X1JLZTc5a2JDMjBWWkhvWktHVjJIZUZ6ZWNGdFJSSGg3a0w3Q3l4emFGRlg3azM5MXpEY3p5aEU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:46:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chelsea 5-0 Morecambe: Enzo Maresca post-match press conference - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/sports/football/chelsea-5-0-morecambe-enzo-maresca-post-match-press-conference/vi-BB1rjqmh</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/sports/football/chelsea-5-0-morecambe-enzo-maresca-post-match-press-conference/vi-BB1rjqmh</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX will launch 2 private lunar landers this week, kicking off busy year for moon missions - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaceX will launch 2 private lunar landers this week, kicking off busy year for moon missions</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/LohZTkTdLVUDAVeNP8jc93-320-80.jpg" alt="An image of earth and the moon with a blue line looping between them to show stages of a space mission." loading="lazy">
<figcaption>The Ghost Riders in the Sky mission will last 60 Earth days from launch to its expected loss of power following sunset on the lunar surface. (Image credit: Firefly Aerospace)</figcaption>
<p>This week, the SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket is scheduled to launch two private lunar landers, kicking off a busy year for moon missions.</p>
<ul>
<li>The launch window starts early Wednesday morning at 1:11 a.m. EST from NASA's Kennedy Space Center in Florida.</li>
<li>The two landers, Blue Ghost and Resilience, will embark on their missions after being delivered to Earth orbit by the Falcon 9 rocket.</li>
<li>Blue Ghost, part of NASA's Commercial Lunar Payload Services (CLPS) program, aims to land in Mare Crisium after a 60-day mission, prioritizing scientific research.</li>
<li>Resilience, operated by the Japanese company ispace, follows a more extended trajectory with an expected landing four to five months post-launch.</li>
<li>Both missions highlight the growing collaboration between private companies and NASA in lunar exploration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This week’s Falcon 9 launch to the moon will be followed, in relatively short order, by that of another lunar lander."</blockquote>
<p>These missions are significant steps towards establishing a sustainable human presence on the moon.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/space-exploration/launches-spacecraft/spacex-will-launch-2-private-lunar-landers-this-week-kicking-off-busy-year-for-moon-missions</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/space-exploration/launches-spacecraft/spacex-will-launch-2-private-lunar-landers-this-week-kicking-off-busy-year-for-moon-missions</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Electrical synapses are key to decision-making in animal brains - Earth.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Electrical Synapses: Key Players in Animal Decision-Making</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Earth.com</p><p>Recent research from Yale and the University of Connecticut reveals the significant role of electrical synapses in shaping decision-making processes in animal brains, moving beyond the traditional focus on chemical synapses.</p><ul><li>The study was led by Dr. Daniel Colon-Ramos.</li><li>It centers on the worm C. elegans, which shows advanced behavior in temperature selection.</li><li>Electrical synapses help filter sensory information and guide actions.</li><li>Findings suggest implications for understanding human cognition.</li></ul><blockquote>“Altering this electrical conduit in a single pair of cells can change what the animal chooses to do,” said Dr. Colón-Ramos.</blockquote><p>This research enhances our understanding of how electrical synapses contribute to decision-making in various species, including humans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.earth.com/news/electrical-synapses-are-key-to-decision-making-in-animal-brains/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.earth.com/news/electrical-synapses-are-key-to-decision-making-in-animal-brains/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:17:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Melting Antarctic ice sheets may be causing larger volcanic eruptions - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Melting Antarctic ice sheets may be causing larger volcanic eruptions</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Science X Network</p>
<img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2025/melting-antarctic-ice-3.jpg" alt="Melting Antarctic ice sheets may be causing larger volcanic eruptions" width="800" height="530">
<figcaption>Schematic of the thermomechanical magma chamber model with simulated ice unloading from this study. Credit: <i>Geochemistry, Geophysics, Geosystems</i> (2024). DOI: 10.1029/2024GC011743</figcaption>
<p>Research indicates that the melting of Antarctic ice sheets may be causing volcanic eruptions to occur with greater frequency and intensity. During deglaciation, the reduction of weight from thick ice sheets allows magma chambers beneath the Earth’s surface to expand and potentially trigger eruptions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The melting ice reduces the pressure on underlying magma chambers, altering their dynamics.</li>
  <li>Studies reveal that significant mass unloading can lead to more explosive volcanic activity, especially in the West Antarctic Rift System.</li>
  <li>Research indicates that ice mass unloading can speed up the process leading to an eruption by decades.</li>
  <li>Evidence from volcanic deposits in the Andes supports the correlation between ice mass unloading and increased volcanic activity.</li>
  <li>Melting ice may create a feedback loop, where eruptions cause further ice melt and subsequent eruptions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Understanding the sensitivity of this ice mass unloading of the West Antarctic Ice Sheet on magma chambers has important implications for being able to accurately predict future consequences on Earth's interconnected geological systems.” - A. N. Coonin et al.</blockquote>
<p>This research underscores the connection between climate change and geological activity, highlighting that even if human-caused warming stopped now, the effects of previous melting will continue to impact volcanic behavior for thousands of years to come.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-01-antarctic-ice-sheets-larger-volcanic.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-01-antarctic-ice-sheets-larger-volcanic.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Six-planet system discovered that moves in perfect mathematical harmony - Earth.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Six-planet system discovered that moves in perfect mathematical harmony</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Earth.com</p>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Researchers have identified a fascinating six-planet system around a single star, known as HD110067, that demonstrates synchronized orbits in a configuration called resonance.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The system is located approximately 100 light-years away in the northern constellation Coma Berenices.</li>
  <li>NASA's TESS and ESA's Cheops satellites revealed this unique arrangement of six sub-Neptune planets.</li>
  <li>Resonant systems are rare, with only about one percent of multi-planet systems maintaining this stable configuration.</li>
  <li>The discovery promotes understanding of how planets form and the conditions necessary for liquid water existence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This discovery is going to become a benchmark system to study how sub-Neptunes form, evolve, what are they made of...” — Rafael Luque</blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The discovery of this six-planet system could provide essential insights into planet formation and the dynamics of celestial bodies over time.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.earth.com/news/six-planet-system-hd110067-discovered-that-moves-in-perfect-mathematical-harmony/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.earth.com/news/six-planet-system-hd110067-discovered-that-moves-in-perfect-mathematical-harmony/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:35:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Carbon storage mystery emerges in the Southern Ocean - Earth.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.earth.com/news/carbon-storage-mystery-emerges-in-the-southern-ocean/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.earth.com/news/carbon-storage-mystery-emerges-in-the-southern-ocean/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:07:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smart robot helps out astronauts on China's Tiangong space station (video) - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Smart robot helps out astronauts on China's Tiangong space station (video)</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 29, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/ypLBuXQE5DuWPMvKEGvRRd-320-80.jpg" alt="an astronaut in a blue jumpsuit tests a flying robot aboard a white-walled space station">
  <figcaption>China's Shenzhou 19 astronauts have been testing a smart robotic assistant aboard the Tiangong space station. (Image credit: CCTV)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Astronauts aboard China's Tiangong space station are being assisted by an intelligent robot named Xiao Hang. The crew, part of the Shenzhou 19 mission, is utilizing human-robot collaboration software to enhance mission efficiency.</p>
<ul>
<li>The astronauts are conducting various experiments regarding human-robot interaction, spatial relationships, and robot behavior.</li>
<li>Xiao Hang can move in microgravity and respond to commands, including taking photos.</li>
<li>Future upgrades are planned to enable the robot to perform in-cabin inspections and resource management.</li>
<li>The crew has also been involved in experiments like assessing the impacts of microgravity on fruit flies.</li>
<li>China's Tiangong is intended to be operational for at least 10 years with plans for expansion.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"In the future, it will also be able to perform various functions such as in-cabin inspections and resource management through upgrades," said Wang Haoze, China's first female spaceflight engineer.</blockquote>
<p>This collaboration between astronauts and robotics marks a significant advancement in space exploration, aiming to improve the effectiveness and safety of long-duration missions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/space-exploration/human-spaceflight/smart-robot-helps-out-astronauts-on-chinas-tiangong-space-station-video</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/space-exploration/human-spaceflight/smart-robot-helps-out-astronauts-on-chinas-tiangong-space-station-video</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Red flags' raised over ancient sea monster pulled from Moroccan mine - Livescience.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Concerns Over Authenticity of Ancient Mosasaur Fossil from Morocco</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Science</p><p>Researchers are questioning the authenticity of a mosasaur fossil described in 2021, suggesting it may be based on forged specimens. CT scans are being recommended to verify the fossil's legitimacy.</p><ul><li>The species <em>Xenodens calminechari</em> was first identified from a jaw bone found in Morocco.</li><li>A new study raises doubts about the tooth arrangement and structure, which diverges from known mosasaur characteristics.</li><li>Concerns about the fossil's provenance stem from the phosphate mine's reputation for forged fossils.</li><li>The lead author of the original study has not responded to inquiries regarding the new claims.</li></ul><blockquote>“If this fossil is indeed a forgery, it should be established in the published literature that this is a fake.” - Henry Sharpe, University of Alberta</blockquote><p>The discussion surrounding this fossil highlights the need for stringent verification processes in paleontology to ensure the integrity of scientific findings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livescience.com/animals/extinct-species/red-flags-raised-over-ancient-sea-monster-pulled-from-moroccan-mine</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livescience.com/animals/extinct-species/red-flags-raised-over-ancient-sea-monster-pulled-from-moroccan-mine</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>