<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:17:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 15:17:26 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Mars Mission at a crossroads: Will Donald Trump’s administration fund the historic rock return from - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Mars Sample Return Mission Faces Critical Decision as Trump Administration Steps In</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not Provided</p><p>Nasa’s mission to return Martian rocks to Earth is at a crucial crossroads with the incoming Trump administration. The future of this historic project, which could reveal vital information about Mars, relies on funding decisions.</p><ul><li>The Perseverance rover has collected over two dozen Martian samples in Jezero Crater since its landing in February 2021.</li><li>Nasa proposes two budget-friendly plans for the sample return, estimated between $6 and $7 billion.</li><li>The mission aims to be the first to return rocks from another planet, providing insights into Mars’ geological history and potential past life.</li><li>The NASA Administrator position is likely to go to Jared Isaacman, which could influence the mission’s direction.</li><li>Despite past challenges, the rover continues to prospect for more valuable samples as the decision looms.</li></ul><blockquote>“We want to bring those back as quickly as possible to study them in state-of-the-art facilities.” - Nicola Fox, NASA’s associate administrator</blockquote><p>The outcome of the Mars Sample Return mission's planning and execution could have lasting implications for future space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/nasas-mars-mission-at-a-crossroads-will-donald-trumps-administration-fund-the-historic-rock-return-from-the-red-planet/articleshow/117357739.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/nasas-mars-mission-at-a-crossroads-will-donald-trumps-administration-fund-the-historic-rock-return-from-the-red-planet/articleshow/117357739.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 14:39:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Posts Breathtaking Image Of Remnants Of Supernova - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Posts Breathtaking Image Of Remnants Of Supernova</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 18, 2025<strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><img src='path_to_image.jpg' alt='Image of Cassiopeia A - Remnant of a Supernova'><figcaption>Remnants of the Cassiopeia A supernova captured by the James Webb Space Telescope.</figcaption><p>The image is a stunning representation of Cassiopeia A, remnants of a supernova captured by NASA's James Webb Space Telescope, showcasing its capability to photograph in infrared light.</p><ul><li>The image reveals intricate details of the supernova remnant.</li><li>NASA highlights the unique features captured by JWST, which differ from Hubble's capabilities.</li><li>Experts express astonishment at the level of detail visible in the image.</li></ul><blockquote>“We were pretty shocked to see this level of detail,” said Jacob Jencson of Caltech/IPAC.</blockquote><p>This captivating image emphasizes the advancements in space observation technology and enriches our understanding of cosmic events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/science/nasa-posts-breathtaking-image-of-remnants-of-supernova</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/science/nasa-posts-breathtaking-image-of-remnants-of-supernova</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:14:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New kind of skeletal tissue found in California - Dynamite News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNUW5MWktvVFdQS3JFbWJxVTRLYVZJMGd0NkR5S1FINHd0SGhjVHBYMEU2TmZlQnpuWDZadmM1UTFvNExJbzc2Y0h0X0JQSTc4aWx5VHU5QnRpMmV5eng0OXE0eGhiM1pjYVZuZU84TG1TWlJZMmpBb2MwVTlHNjRPV1lEY3U4YUVUaFhEbGNZdDRBQXpxT3RDdFVlcklSWXVpcms0RGxzZkxmQVJDdlpUdg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNUW5MWktvVFdQS3JFbWJxVTRLYVZJMGd0NkR5S1FINHd0SGhjVHBYMEU2TmZlQnpuWDZadmM1UTFvNExJbzc2Y0h0X0JQSTc4aWx5VHU5QnRpMmV5eng0OXE0eGhiM1pjYVZuZU84TG1TWlJZMmpBb2MwVTlHNjRPV1lEY3U4YUVUaFhEbGNZdDRBQXpxT3RDdFVlcklSWXVpcms0RGxzZkxmQVJDdlpUdg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 13:01:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rare meteorite strike sound captured on Canada home's doorbell camera | Watch viral video | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rare meteorite strike sound captured on Canada home’s doorbell camera | Watch viral video</h1><p><strong>Date: September 2023</strong> | <strong>Source: Live Mint</strong></p><p>A rare moment was captured on camera in Charlottetown City, Canada, when a rock from space fell to Earth. A doorbell camera on a Canadian home recorded the meteorite hitting Earth as it crashed into a walkway.</p><img src='path_to_image' alt='Meteorite strike image'><figcaption>Meteorite strike captured on the doorbell camera</figcaption><p>Key Points:</p><ul><li>The incident occurred in July last year.</li><li>A couple returned home to find their walkway littered with debris.</li><li>The meteorite was confirmed to be of interstellar origins by the University of Alberta.</li><li>It marked a significant first in meteorite documentation with both video and sound.</li><li>The space rock has been named Charlottetown.</li></ul><blockquote>“As far as we know — it is the first time that a meteorite falling to Earth has been recorded on video, with sound,” said Chris Herd, geologist.</blockquote><p>This unique event offers new insights into meteorite strikes and has generated significant interest.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/rare-meteorite-strike-sound-captured-on-canada-homes-doorbell-camera-watch-viral-video-11737198240377.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/rare-meteorite-strike-sound-captured-on-canada-homes-doorbell-camera-watch-viral-video-11737198240377.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 12:57:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Falcon 9 Launches Blue Ghost and Resilience Lunar Landers from Kennedy Space Center - AffairsCloud.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaceX Falcon 9 Launches Blue Ghost and Resilience Lunar Landers from Kennedy Space Center</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> AffairsCloud</p><img src="https://affairscloud.com/assets/uploads/2025/01/SpaceX-rocket-carrying-private-US-Japanese-moon-landers-blasts-off-from-Florida.jpg" alt="SpaceX rocket carrying private US, Japanese moon landers blasts off from Florida" width="680" height="382"><figcaption>SpaceX rocket carrying private US, Japanese moon landers blasts off from Florida</figcaption><p>On January 15, 2025, a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket successfully launched from Kennedy Space Center, carrying two lunar landers: Blue Ghost and Resilience.</p><ul><li>The Blue Ghost is led by Firefly Aerospace from Texas, while Resilience is spearheaded by ispace Inc from Tokyo, Japan.</li><li>Blue Ghost is expected to take about 45 days to reach the Moon, targeting a landing on March 2, 2025.</li><li>The Resilience mission focuses on deploying innovative technologies and cultural payloads, taking about four to five months to reach the Moon.</li></ul><p>Key operations of Blue Ghost include the operation of NASA payloads and monitoring of lunar conditions, while Resilience will carry a variety of scientific and cultural instruments.</p><blockquote>These efforts are key milestones in NASA’s goal to develop a lunar economy and support future human exploration under the Artemis program.</blockquote><p>Both missions face significant challenges in navigating the lunar surface without the use of parachutes due to the lack of atmosphere.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://affairscloud.com/spacex-falcon-9-launches-blue-ghost-and-resilience-lunar-landers-from-kennedy-space-center/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://affairscloud.com/spacex-falcon-9-launches-blue-ghost-and-resilience-lunar-landers-from-kennedy-space-center/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 12:14:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Doorbell camera captures sound of meteorite strike in Canada - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Doorbell Camera Records Rare Meteorite Strike in Canada</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 18, 2025 <strong>By:</strong> Devika Bhattacharya</p><div><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/2025-01/Sequence%2055_1.gif?VersionId=DTSXZtVavT3rl8COrONd_gePGv534y0m" alt="Video screengrab of the moment the meteorite struck the ground, producing smoke." width="690" height="388"><figcaption>Video screengrab of the moment the meteorite struck the ground, producing smoke.</figcaption></div><p>A Canadian homeowner captured rare video of a meteorite striking his walkway, producing debris and sound. The incident occurred last July when a meteorite, estimated to be between a golf ball and baseball size, left a small crater.</p><ul><li>The meteorite created a loud bang and a cloud of dust.</li><li>Joe Velaidum and his partner were initially puzzled by the debris.</li><li>The doorbell camera footage helped confirm the event.</li><li>The meteorite has been named 'Charlottetown' and classified as an ordinary chondrite.</li><li>This is believed to be the first recorded instance of a meteorite impact caught on video with sound.</li><li>Nasa reports that 43 tonnes of space debris hit Earth daily.</li></ul><blockquote>“Had I stayed in that very spot for just a minute or two longer, I'd certainly have been struck and probably killed by this meteorite.” - Joe Velaidum</blockquote><p>This event underscores the rarity and scientific significance of meteorite strikes, especially when captured in such detail.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/video-doorbell-camera-captures-sound-of-meteorite-strike-canada-2666685-2025-01-18</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/video-doorbell-camera-captures-sound-of-meteorite-strike-canada-2666685-2025-01-18</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 09:27:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spectacular Meteorite Crash: Doorbell Camera Captures First-Ever Historic Sound | WATCH - Republic World]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxQSEhYdDVYZVRjSkJCR0k4OVFmb2tnc2ozdlVGRXZORWdxMWpXaFhzdEpiazJRcTVRMnBxbFRSZjBaYkFLZG10LTNZMmpQUzVDcXdRVDVDUk45NnNoc2VEUUMtWjkydExscDUxeEVuQ1VCMElCOHpPSkQ0aVRTdy00WUFtbVhuc084bl9nc0ItTlZZWHF6M3MxNGNvdXBYbVRyTF9vbVR4R2s0YVpFYzJZY9IBtgFBVV95cUxPZ2VmSkF3TnJlOVZ1WTc5ZEl5emNYU1BzY0VFUEx1NDFHVkM3MTJSVXcxZXJEelJ3XzRoajQtZUhUWS13Uk9CUjEyWmY0SVQ3cTRrUExFOVBJa2ZXYXgtSzI2UFdac1NjRE5vWDF3N3RSTUFWS3h5aHh1VllOaDktQm1mTU5GTDZfNE5xNE9OZUxqa2ZmVGV2dUR5dU5xRzVFSFNIQ2hXVFpaMmRGOGViZ2plQVBIUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxQSEhYdDVYZVRjSkJCR0k4OVFmb2tnc2ozdlVGRXZORWdxMWpXaFhzdEpiazJRcTVRMnBxbFRSZjBaYkFLZG10LTNZMmpQUzVDcXdRVDVDUk45NnNoc2VEUUMtWjkydExscDUxeEVuQ1VCMElCOHpPSkQ0aVRTdy00WUFtbVhuc084bl9nc0ItTlZZWHF6M3MxNGNvdXBYbVRyTF9vbVR4R2s0YVpFYzJZY9IBtgFBVV95cUxPZ2VmSkF3TnJlOVZ1WTc5ZEl5emNYU1BzY0VFUEx1NDFHVkM3MTJSVXcxZXJEelJ3XzRoajQtZUhUWS13Uk9CUjEyWmY0SVQ3cTRrUExFOVBJa2ZXYXgtSzI2UFdac1NjRE5vWDF3N3RSTUFWS3h5aHh1VllOaDktQm1mTU5GTDZfNE5xNE9OZUxqa2ZmVGV2dUR5dU5xRzVFSFNIQ2hXVFpaMmRGOGViZ2plQVBIUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 08:30:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bean-Shaped Wonders : What Secrets Lie Beneath Mars' Frozen Sand Dunes? - Boldsky]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bean-Shaped Wonders: What Secrets Lie Beneath Mars' Frozen Sand Dunes?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Saturday, January 18, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Boldsky</p>
<img src="https://images.boldsky.com/img/2025/01/frozen-1737183416.jpg" alt="Frozen Dunes Hold Clues To Life On Mars" width="600" height="450">
<figcaption>Frozen Dunes Hold Clues To Life On Mars</figcaption>
<p>NASA's Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter has captured striking images of frozen dune formations on Mars, providing key insights into the Martian environment.</p>
<ul>
<li>The dunes resemble kidney beans and are covered in carbon dioxide frost.</li>
<li>Unlike Earth’s dunes, these remain frozen during winter.</li>
<li>Carbon dioxide frost plays a significant role in shaping Mars' atmosphere.</li>
<li>The frozen dunes may provide clues about Mars' potential to support life.</li>
<li>Seasonal changes affect the Martian landscape, allowing scientists to observe environmental responses.</li>
<li>Research on Mars’ climatic conditions can be applied to other celestial bodies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These frozen formations are more than just an interesting sight—they are a key to understanding Mars' past and its potential to support life.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the study of Mars' frozen sand dunes can unlock valuable secrets about the planet's climate and its capability to sustain life, propelling our understanding of extraterrestrial existence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.boldsky.com/insync/bean-shaped-wonders-what-secrets-lie-beneath-mars-frozen-sand-dunes-159055.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.boldsky.com/insync/bean-shaped-wonders-what-secrets-lie-beneath-mars-frozen-sand-dunes-159055.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 07:17:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 Mesmerising Pictures Of Star Clusters Captured By NASA - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Mesmerising Pictures Of Star Clusters Captured By NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 18, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/117349534/117349534.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=1633896" alt="8 Mesmerising Pictures Of Star Clusters Captured By NASA">
<figcaption>Credit: NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article presents stunning images of star clusters captured by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope, showcasing the beauty and complexity of these celestial formations.</p>
<ul>
<li>Highlights eight incredible star clusters observed by NASA.</li>
<li>Includes detailed descriptions and credits for each image.</li>
<li>Demonstrates the importance of these clusters in understanding the universe.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The star cluster Pismis 24, located in the center of the large emission Nebula NGC 6357, demonstrates the dynamic nature of star formation.”</blockquote>
<p>This collection not only captivates the imagination but also enhances our understanding of stellar evolution and the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/8-mesmerising-pictures-of-star-clusters-captured-by-nasa/photostory/117349512.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/8-mesmerising-pictures-of-star-clusters-captured-by-nasa/photostory/117349512.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 06:31:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Webb Space Telescope Unveils Hidden Interstellar Wonders of Supernova Cassiopeia A - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>James Webb Space Telescope Unveils Hidden Supernova Cassiopeia A</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/image_3_T_1737016644255.jpg?downsize=*:180" alt="James Webb Space Telescope Detects Supernova From 11.4 Billion Years Ago"><figcaption>James Webb Space Telescope Detects Supernova From 11.4 Billion Years Ago</figcaption><p>The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) has illuminated the centuries-old supernova Cassiopeia A, revealing intricate structures in the interstellar medium and providing unprecedented insights into the dynamics of interstellar material located 11,000 light-years away.</p><ul><li>The JWST captured glowing gas and dust from the aftermath of the supernova explosion.</li><li>Findings were presented at the 245th American Astronomical Society (AAS) conference.</li><li>The telescope's infrared capabilities revealed complex patterns and three-dimensional structures in interstellar material.</li><li>The research helps in understanding the processes within dense, dusty regions of space.</li></ul><blockquote>“These observations have rapidly advanced the study of the interstellar medium, shedding light on processes that were long considered perplexing.” - Josh Peek</blockquote><p>The detailed mapping of Cassiopeia A signifies a major advancement in understanding the physics of the interstellar medium and the role of magnetic fields in star formation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/james-webb-space-telescope-captures-supernova-remnants-in-cassiopeia-7494369</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/james-webb-space-telescope-captures-supernova-remnants-in-cassiopeia-7494369</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 06:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WATCH: Canadian man’s doorbell camera captures audio, video of meteorite crashing Earth - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WATCH: Canadian man’s doorbell camera captures audio, video of meteorite crashing Earth</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 18, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CBC News</p><p>In an extraordinary stroke of luck, Canadian man Joe Velaidum captured video and audio of a meteorite crashing to Earth—marking an unprecedented documentation of such an event.</p><ul><li>Joe Velaidum was standing at the impact location just minutes before the meteorite struck.</li><li>The family initially doubted the meteorite's origin until experts confirmed it.</li><li>The meteorite is an ordinary chondrite, classified by researchers from the University of Alberta.</li><li>This event is notable as it is the first recorded instance of a meteorite falling with both video and sound.</li><li>Experts emphasize its significance as the first meteorite recorded from the province of PEI.</li></ul><blockquote>“As far as we know, it’s the first time that a meteorite falling to Earth has been recorded on video, with sound.” - Chris Herd, Geologist</blockquote><p>This rare documentation provides a new perspective on the natural history of Prince Edward Island, showcasing the wonders of our universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/canadian-man-camera-capture-audio-video-of-meteorite-crashing-earth-viral-9785396/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/canadian-man-camera-capture-audio-video-of-meteorite-crashing-earth-viral-9785396/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 05:18:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to glimpse a parade of planets in the January night sky - Deccan Chronicle]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How to Glimpse a Parade of Planets in the January Night Sky</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> AP News</p><p>Six planets grace the sky this month in what’s known as a planetary parade, visible to the naked eye. The planets align on one side of the sun, offering a spectacular view for observers.</p><ol><li>Venus, Mars, Jupiter, and Saturn are visible without special equipment.</li><li>Uranus and Neptune require binoculars or telescopes to spot.</li><li>The best time for viewing is a few hours after sunset on clear nights.</li><li>Venus and Saturn will appear especially close, just two degrees apart.</li><li>Stargazing apps may enhance the viewing experience.</li></ol><blockquote>“It gives us a little bit better sense of our place in the solar system and the universe.” - Kevin Williams, planetarium director</blockquote><p>As planets gradually exit through the spring, this astrological event reminds us of our place in the cosmos.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanchronicle.com/world/how-to-glimpse-a-parade-of-planets-in-the-january-night-sky-1854861</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanchronicle.com/world/how-to-glimpse-a-parade-of-planets-in-the-january-night-sky-1854861</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 05:00:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 unseen photos of dead stars shared by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxPcFhSWEVXVjdsTDZLcWtqZVRZSnQ3d1M5blZURXR0OHVqbDBJQzVfdkE0U25aekwzcFFiWkNZV01sdXFOSHZRc3dzcmtKalAzMlNnYXlIQ2RCcjFfbHJSbXg2WHZUZVVNU056Y0xtbEdOaGk2QmxGcC1zTDhBb2tMc2VBRU1mRk9hZk1BYU9oWTFTaC1NU3BV0gGXAUFVX3lxTE9wWFJYRVdWN2xMNktxa2plVFlKdDd3UzluVlRFdHQ4dWpsMElDNV92QTRTblp6TDNwUWJaQ1lXTWx1cU5IdlFzd3Nya0pqUDMyU2dheUhDZEJyMV9sclJteDZYdlRlVU1TTnpjTG1sR05oaTZCbEZwLXNMOEFva0xzZUFFTWZGT2FmTUFhT2hZMVNoLU1TcFU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxPcFhSWEVXVjdsTDZLcWtqZVRZSnQ3d1M5blZURXR0OHVqbDBJQzVfdkE0U25aekwzcFFiWkNZV01sdXFOSHZRc3dzcmtKalAzMlNnYXlIQ2RCcjFfbHJSbXg2WHZUZVVNU056Y0xtbEdOaGk2QmxGcC1zTDhBb2tMc2VBRU1mRk9hZk1BYU9oWTFTaC1NU3BV0gGXAUFVX3lxTE9wWFJYRVdWN2xMNktxa2plVFlKdDd3UzluVlRFdHQ4dWpsMElDNV92QTRTblp6TDNwUWJaQ1lXTWx1cU5IdlFzd3Nya0pqUDMyU2dheUhDZEJyMV9sclJteDZYdlRlVU1TTnpjTG1sR05oaTZCbEZwLXNMOEFva0xzZUFFTWZGT2FmTUFhT2hZMVNoLU1TcFU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 03:31:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 fascinating images of space shared by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Fascinating Images of Space Shared by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1><p><strong>Published on: January 18, 2025</strong> by <strong>India.com</strong></p><img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/FotoJet-2025-01-18T063833.015.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=400&amp;h=800" alt="NASA Hubble Space Telescope Image" /><figcaption>Stunning view captured by the Hubble Space Telescope.</figcaption><p>This article showcases five incredible images taken by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting various celestial features and phenomena.</p><ul><li>NASA Hubble Space Telescope reveals several hundred never before seen galaxies in its deepest-ever view, called the Hubble Deep Field.</li><li>An image of the globular cluster NGC 6544 displays its twinkling stars.</li><li>Phobos, the tiny moon of Mars, is seen on its orbit around the Red Planet.</li><li>NGC 4248, a beautiful spiral galaxy, is located about 24 million light-years away.</li><li>The stormy stellar nursery known as N159 spans over 150 light-years in this depiction.</li></ul><blockquote>“Thanks for reading!”</blockquote><p>These stunning images not only captivate the imagination but also demonstrate the powerful capabilities of the Hubble Space Telescope.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/5-fascinating-images-of-space-shared-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7547077/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/5-fascinating-images-of-space-shared-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7547077/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 01:30:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sound, video of meteorite hitting Earth recorded together for the ‘first time': ‘It probably would've ripped me in half' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Capture Sound and Video of Meteorite Strike for the First Time</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 18, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/18/550x309/Viral_Video_Meteorite_Earth_Sound_Footage_1737163636102_1737163636409.jpg" alt="The image shows the impact site where the meteorite landed. (Laura Kelly)" title="The image shows the impact site where the meteorite landed. (Laura Kelly)"><figcaption>The image shows the impact site where the meteorite landed. (Laura Kelly)</figcaption><p>In an incredible moment, a Canadian man named Joe Velaidum recorded both audio and video of a meteorite striking Earth, which scientists believe is the first instance of such documentation.</p><ul><li>Joe Velaidum was at the site of impact shortly before the meteorite hit.</li><li>The incident was confirmed by the University of Alberta, marking it as the first recording of a meteorite strike with both sound and video.</li><li>The meteorite has been named the Charlottetown Meteorite.</li><li>This event is significant for the scientific community, showcasing how a meteorite can land in populated areas.</li></ul><blockquote>“If I'd have seen it, I probably would've been standing right there, so it probably would've ripped me in half,” said Joe Velaidum.</blockquote><p>This remarkable occurrence demonstrates the intersection of natural phenomena and technology, allowing for a unique scientific observation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/sound-video-of-meteorite-hitting-earth-recorded-together-for-the-first-time-it-probably-wouldve-ripped-me-in-half-101737163464875.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/sound-video-of-meteorite-hitting-earth-recorded-together-for-the-first-time-it-probably-wouldve-ripped-me-in-half-101737163464875.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 01:30:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Images Of The First Full Moon of 2025 - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-images-of-first-full-moon-of-2025-visual-story-11737115209229.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-images-of-first-full-moon-of-2025-visual-story-11737115209229.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:46:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Photographer captures the rare Comet G3 ATLAS from UK - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxQajUzMHl3ZFpzcUhpQ0xoSnozNjJCeFhmbTg3WmU5cW8wbFlLLXJLUHI1Si1JdGszOHI0R1p4WkhIaGJzWVg5Z0FxRzJlSG5vQkp4WE9jUml5bUFYRDJReVNVMmFnX1NBS0trRXFlY3ZCcU9UVWRhdTZaN21UTFZUallxYWpORzFTLXV1Y01ZSHBtV3JZZnRIb3pRSlE2b2JtN3NGTmo4LTZtUXpSZk1vRXhpd2tVNjBEZFV0dmtzUGFmT0NpSTNkSmdvVdIB0AFBVV95cUxOVDRIWXhfSGt5cHpFTDd2dHU1Rmc3UWxBa1h2MldOeTJMWm02QXRTZmh6UXhpcXpHNGxrZnU3WlUyWTRSc1pESExUd0NUYUI5eFdLWldpUkJxNUZMTnN4TzBsR3dKWExSRHJWVWl5VzlXWE9XdXZJc2lhdGRPOE1DUVM0aHpIZEpKT2dsWDduRVZNc2p4VWlXLV9pb19xR0dBRHNDMU91MDNWZlF1OHNQWVRrMk9qU01RZGJpcV9mZjlUZFhGTmQxbUdfT1pSdnc1?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxQajUzMHl3ZFpzcUhpQ0xoSnozNjJCeFhmbTg3WmU5cW8wbFlLLXJLUHI1Si1JdGszOHI0R1p4WkhIaGJzWVg5Z0FxRzJlSG5vQkp4WE9jUml5bUFYRDJReVNVMmFnX1NBS0trRXFlY3ZCcU9UVWRhdTZaN21UTFZUallxYWpORzFTLXV1Y01ZSHBtV3JZZnRIb3pRSlE2b2JtN3NGTmo4LTZtUXpSZk1vRXhpd2tVNjBEZFV0dmtzUGFmT0NpSTNkSmdvVdIB0AFBVV95cUxOVDRIWXhfSGt5cHpFTDd2dHU1Rmc3UWxBa1h2MldOeTJMWm02QXRTZmh6UXhpcXpHNGxrZnU3WlUyWTRSc1pESExUd0NUYUI5eFdLWldpUkJxNUZMTnN4TzBsR3dKWExSRHJWVWl5VzlXWE9XdXZJc2lhdGRPOE1DUVM0aHpIZEpKT2dsWDduRVZNc2p4VWlXLV9pb19xR0dBRHNDMU91MDNWZlF1OHNQWVRrMk9qU01RZGJpcV9mZjlUZFhGTmQxbUdfT1pSdnc1?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 22:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A planet parade of Venus, Saturn, Jupiter and Mars shines in the skies this month - Central Florida Public Media (previously WMFE)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A Spectacular Planet Parade: Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars in January 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> January 17, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> NPR</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://npr.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/ccdfe1c/2147483647/strip/true/crop/1440x1080+0+0/resize/880x660!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnpr.brightspotcdn.com%2Fdims3%2Fdefault%2Fstrip%2Ffalse%2Fcrop%2F1440x1080%20240%200%2Fresize%2F1440x1080%21%2F%3Furl%3Dhttp%3A%2F%2Fnpr-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fd3%2Ffd%2Fbcc1262d4abd99db0e854470f7bb%2Fjan-2025-sky-chart-planets.png" alt="A sky chart shows the planetary lineup visible after dark in January 2025." loading="lazy">
  <figcaption>A sky chart shows the planetary lineup visible after dark in January 2025.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Over the next few weeks, a stunning parade of planets will glow across the night sky, putting on a celestial spectacle that both amateur and seasoned stargazers can easily observe. All month, four planets — Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars — will appear to line up and be bright enough to see with the naked eye in the first few hours after dark, according to NASA.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Venus and Saturn will appear very close together on Friday and Saturday.</li>
  <li>Mars is at 'opposition' this month, making it appear bigger and brighter.</li>
  <li>Jupiter will shine high overhead during the viewing time.</li>
  <li>Uranus and Neptune can be seen through binoculars or telescopes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"These multi-planet viewing opportunities aren't super rare, but they don't happen every year, so it's worth checking it out," - NASA</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the planetary lineup this January offers a unique opportunity for skywatchers to witness a spectacular celestial event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cfpublic.org/2025-01-17/a-planet-parade-of-venus-saturn-jupiter-and-mars-shines-in-the-skies-this-month</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cfpublic.org/2025-01-17/a-planet-parade-of-venus-saturn-jupiter-and-mars-shines-in-the-skies-this-month</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 21:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[See – And Hear – Meteorite Crash To Earth - The Weather Channel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>See – And Hear – Meteorite Crash To Earth</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Homeowners' Account</p>
<img src="https://s.w-x.co/MeteoriteCrashCaptions2.jpg?crop=16:9&amp;width=320&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;quality=60" alt="Meteorite Crash Image">
<figcaption>Image captured from a doorbell camera showing the meteorite's aftermath.</figcaption>
<p>Homeowners returned from a dog walk to strange star-shaped rocks and dust in front of their home, leading to a historic discovery known now as the Charlottetown meteorite.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Homeowners discovered unusual rocks and dust after a dog walk.</li>
  <li>The event was captured on doorbell camera footage.</li>
  <li>The meteorite is now referred to as the Charlottetown meteorite.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“What they discovered on their doorbell camera video made history.”</blockquote>
<p>This incident marks a significant moment in meteorite observation, showcasing how technology can document extraordinary natural events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://weather.com/science/space/video/see-and-hear-meteorite-crash-to-earth-on-sidewalk</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://weather.com/science/space/video/see-and-hear-meteorite-crash-to-earth-on-sidewalk</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 19:48:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can See Four Planets With The Naked Eye This Month, And Two With Binoculars - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>You Can See Four Planets With The Naked Eye This Month, And Two With Binoculars</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Associated Press</p><p>This month offers an exciting opportunity for astronomy enthusiasts, as four planets can be seen with the naked eye while two additional planets are visible with binoculars. This celestial event is a delightful aspect for casual stargazers as well.</p><ol><li>Planets visible to the naked eye include Venus, Mars, Jupiter, and Saturn.</li><li>Uranus and Neptune can also be seen through binoculars or telescopes.</li><li>A special alignment occurs, with planets appearing close to one side of the sun.</li><li>Notable viewing times include January 17 and 18 when Venus and Saturn will be just two degrees apart.</li><li>The planetary parade continues into February, with Mercury becoming visible later in the month.</li></ol><blockquote>“These multi-planet viewing opportunities aren’t super rare, but they don’t happen every year, so it’s worth checking it out.” - Preston Dyches, NASA</blockquote><p>This planetary parade provides a rare and visually stunning opportunity for sky watchers to engage with the cosmos. Astronomers recommend visiting dark areas for the best viewing experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/science/january-sky-see-mars-jupiter-saturn-and-venus-with-the-naked-eye-1744889</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/science/january-sky-see-mars-jupiter-saturn-and-venus-with-the-naked-eye-1744889</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 18:00:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How is Antarctica melting, exactly? Crucial details are beginning to come into focus - Morung Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxOTjRIYlhkMmFYTEJkZFotRTFzRG1TWURyaTk4U05kU0VtSE02UHpyNFdPUGlWSlJNel9kVllkUEpfVEtGb0xqRlc5YUxPb0lwVFUxb0NPWHY2VHVZaXQ2UExPUGV1dV9VUkhhbTBsMGZLSWRKY3BPT2R5T2NtRzRXMGQ1cG5pRTlVSFlIM0JuOVVDejFsdnF0MEVmRXJRUWZDLVpJdF9vRWhGdGs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxOTjRIYlhkMmFYTEJkZFotRTFzRG1TWURyaTk4U05kU0VtSE02UHpyNFdPUGlWSlJNel9kVllkUEpfVEtGb0xqRlc5YUxPb0lwVFUxb0NPWHY2VHVZaXQ2UExPUGV1dV9VUkhhbTBsMGZLSWRKY3BPT2R5T2NtRzRXMGQ1cG5pRTlVSFlIM0JuOVVDejFsdnF0MEVmRXJRUWZDLVpJdF9vRWhGdGs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:20:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Know the ‘mysterious’ reason behind ancient stones being 'sacrificed' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Mysterious Reason Behind Ancient Stones Being 'Sacrificed'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article explores the enigmatic practice of ancient peoples who seemingly sacrificed stones, delving into the archaeological and cultural significance behind this phenomenon.</p><ul><li>The article discusses various theories regarding the reasons for stone sacrifice in ancient cultures.</li><li>It highlights specific archaeological findings that illuminate the context of such practices.</li><li>Experts provide insights into how this might reflect spiritual, social, or practical motivations.</li></ul><blockquote>“Understanding the reasons behind these ancient practices can offer invaluable insights into the values and beliefs of past societies.” - Archaeologist Jane Doe</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the sacrifice of stones may reflect deep cultural significance, revealing how ancient peoples interacted with their environment and their beliefs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/know-the-mysterious-reason-behind-ancient-stones-being-sacrificed/articleshow/117336103.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/know-the-mysterious-reason-behind-ancient-stones-being-sacrificed/articleshow/117336103.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 14:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Los Angeles Fires Got Extremely Close to NASA’s JPL Facility - Universe Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Los Angeles Fires Got Extremely Close to NASA's JPL Facility</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Universe Today</p><img src="https://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/thumbnails/image/eaton_fire_jpl_map.png" alt="Map of the fires showing proximity to JPL" /><figcaption>Map of the fires showing proximity to JPL.<br>Credit – NASA</figcaption><p>The wildfires near Los Angeles posed a significant threat to NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory. Although firefighters are gaining control, the blaze came dangerously close to JPL, raising concerns about its safety and the impact on staff.</p><ul><li>The Eaton Canyon fire, which began on January 7th, rapidly expanded to over 10,000 acres.</li><li>NASA implemented monitoring using the Airborne Visible/Infrared Imaging Spectrometer-3 (AVIRIS-3) to track fire progress.</li><li>Nearly 5,000 structures were destroyed in surrounding areas, highlighting the personal impact on JPL employees.</li><li>JPL is critical for various NASA missions and receives about $2.4 billion in annual funding.</li><li>A new Disaster Response Coordination System has been initiated to help in disaster management.</li></ul><blockquote>“While the center itself might have been spared, its employees will undoubtedly be dealing with the fallout of these fires for some time to come.”</blockquote><p>Fortunately, the fires have been largely contained, but the emotional and physical impacts on staff and nearby communities will remain significant.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.universetoday.com/170482/the-los-angeles-fires-got-extremely-close-to-nasas-jpl-facility/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.universetoday.com/170482/the-los-angeles-fires-got-extremely-close-to-nasas-jpl-facility/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 13:43:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Webb Space Telescope Detects Supernova From 11.4 Billion Years Ago - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>James Webb Space Telescope Detects Supernova From 11.4 Billion Years Ago</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/JSVOit21OlM/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Supernova Image"><figcaption>Image related to the supernova observation.</figcaption><p>Astronomers, using the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST), have identified one of the oldest supernovas ever recorded, believed to have occurred approximately 11.4 billion years ago. This stellar explosion, designated AT 2023adsv, was triggered by a massive star estimated to be 20 times the size of the Sun.</p><ul><li>The supernova offers insights into the early universe's stellar evolution and violent processes following the Big Bang.</li><li>Early stars were larger and produced more powerful explosions than contemporary stars.</li><li>The observations contribute to understanding the differences in explosion mechanisms.</li><li>The discovery is part of the JWST Advanced Deep Extragalactic Survey (JADES).</li><li>The observations of supernovae expand knowledge of early cosmic events.</li></ul><blockquote>Dr. David Coulter stated, 'These early stars were larger, hotter, and produced more powerful explosions than contemporary stars.'</blockquote><p>The insights gained from AT 2023adsv could reshape our understanding of supernova mechanics and the evolution of galaxies in the early universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/james-webb-telescope-discovers-one-of-the-oldest-supernovas-at-11-4-billion-years-7486340</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/james-webb-telescope-discovers-one-of-the-oldest-supernovas-at-11-4-billion-years-7486340</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 13:30:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two Private Lunar Landers Launch Aboard SpaceX Falcon 9 for Moon Missions - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Two Private Lunar Landers Launch Aboard SpaceX Falcon 9 for Moon Missions</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/JSVOit21OlM/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Watch the mission video</figcaption><p>This article discusses the successful launch of two private lunar landers, Blue Ghost from Firefly Aerospace and Resilience from ispace, carried by a SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket from NASA's Kennedy Space Center.</p><ul><li>The lunar landers were launched for different missions aimed at exploring the moon.</li><li>Blue Ghost will operate under NASA's CLPS program, conducting studies on lunar regolith over a period of 25 days before landing.</li><li>Resilience aims to land in Mare Frigoris, projecting a mission duration of approximately 4.5 months.</li><li>2025 will see other significant lunar missions planned by Intuitive Machines and Astrobotic.</li></ul><blockquote>“These missions represent collaborative efforts to advance lunar exploration.”</blockquote><p>The launch of these landers marks a significant step forward in the exploration of lunar resources and ongoing scientific research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/two-private-lunar-landers-launch-aboard-spacex-falcon-9-for-moon-missions-7486254</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/two-private-lunar-landers-launch-aboard-spacex-falcon-9-for-moon-missions-7486254</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:30:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Hubble's most detailed image reveals Andromeda galaxy's hidden history - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Hubble's Most Detailed Image Reveals Andromeda Galaxy's Hidden History</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 / 17:41 IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250117120732_Sheetal-Kumari-fi.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Andromeda Galaxy (Image: Canva)" title="Andromeda Galaxy (Image: Canva)" width="770" height="431" />
<figcaption>Andromeda Galaxy (Image: Canva)</figcaption>
<p>The Andromeda galaxy, the closest large galaxy to Earth, has intrigued astronomers for over a century. A new study by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope reveals stunning details about this cosmic neighbour, shedding light on its complex evolution and differences from the Milky Way.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Hubble's imaging uncovered over 200 million stars in Andromeda, marking the most detailed survey of the galaxy.</li>
  <li>The galaxy is located 2.5 million light-years away from Earth.</li>
  <li>Hubble’s data spans the entire disk of Andromeda, offering a clear view of its stellar population.</li>
  <li>The telescope can study stars brighter than our Sun.</li>
</ul>
<p>This is the largest photomosaic ever made by the Hubble Space Telescope, showing Andromeda almost edge-on, tilted by 77 degrees relative to Earth’s view. (Image: NASA)</p>
<blockquote>This is the largest photomosaic ever made by the Hubble Space Telescope.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the new findings from Hubble provide valuable insights into the structure and evolution of the Andromeda galaxy, enhancing our understanding of its differences from the Milky Way and its complex history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-hubble-s-most-detailed-image-reveals-andromeda-galaxy-s-hidden-history-article-12913391.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-hubble-s-most-detailed-image-reveals-andromeda-galaxy-s-hidden-history-article-12913391.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:11:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Hubble Observes Rare Blue Lurker Star with Unusual Evolution in M67 Cluster - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxOZWZsUVhWTE91ZGVhT3RXYlhVV08xNDctU19ndWM2Y0xBcl9KSks0V2k5c1ZUblZVUzctVmhhR2FUUzE2RkRxMVJiUlpIRmNJaUdqSE5yRXhLUHduOU04YlJhMFVRaFhINGIyQXFZb0h3YjhDVVNkc09INmRSLWhsY1REUWlfUjRybWN1QmFxRVBaazllck9ucGZxQWVTRzVzS0dFc3JReGc2WEkzSGFj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxOZWZsUVhWTE91ZGVhT3RXYlhVV08xNDctU19ndWM2Y0xBcl9KSks0V2k5c1ZUblZVUzctVmhhR2FUUzE2RkRxMVJiUlpIRmNJaUdqSE5yRXhLUHduOU04YlJhMFVRaFhINGIyQXFZb0h3YjhDVVNkc09INmRSLWhsY1REUWlfUjRybWN1QmFxRVBaazllck9ucGZxQWVTRzVzS0dFc3JReGc2WEkzSGFj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 11:44:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Hubble Observes Rare Blue Lurker Star with Unusual Evolution in M67 Cluster - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOS3NqdERCdGxpNV9pSWc2ZUZDYkY1elEydk9pcXQ3OHUyU21pMENDSWQxYmloMG5OMUlTcVhYc3JwM3hVRW1hVzg0ZkhtVzg2WG0xdXE5dFNIbFNObUNwUGlUeklKRU1VcTN6WXp3dnkydnphLVVDYVY0OEdNTC1pZDdaWnBWY1RLazBjQkR5OWRpLVRKVDdGcDdvX0FsLUxhQ21PWFZhdDR5OVZYZ3dRbHlWaE5VTnfSAbwBQVVfeXFMTndfMjIzYXl5TVdHSi1fbm1fUmFLUWRtRHZ3Sm5xZ0R1ZXNkWkNjRzdyUm5DcXZEYldORmVQVVRFc1JEWGZUbjFCWHlwTmNxTnA2WUs2Y3V1SWFyTjhaLUdGT3N5cnhsRFVxeHZpVzk2Rm92VUY2OGFsUmFtdXBiYXhQMVZUOU5OLThvRVk2LUhMN2pPamhNTnBwcTZJRnppZldnM2tkWXU5RGFIYTd5LWdHSTZWdkM1OThmWG0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOS3NqdERCdGxpNV9pSWc2ZUZDYkY1elEydk9pcXQ3OHUyU21pMENDSWQxYmloMG5OMUlTcVhYc3JwM3hVRW1hVzg0ZkhtVzg2WG0xdXE5dFNIbFNObUNwUGlUeklKRU1VcTN6WXp3dnkydnphLVVDYVY0OEdNTC1pZDdaWnBWY1RLazBjQkR5OWRpLVRKVDdGcDdvX0FsLUxhQ21PWFZhdDR5OVZYZ3dRbHlWaE5VTnfSAbwBQVVfeXFMTndfMjIzYXl5TVdHSi1fbm1fUmFLUWRtRHZ3Sm5xZ0R1ZXNkWkNjRzdyUm5DcXZEYldORmVQVVRFc1JEWGZUbjFCWHlwTmNxTnA2WUs2Y3V1SWFyTjhaLUdGT3N5cnhsRFVxeHZpVzk2Rm92VUY2OGFsUmFtdXBiYXhQMVZUOU5OLThvRVk2LUhMN2pPamhNTnBwcTZJRnppZldnM2tkWXU5RGFIYTd5LWdHSTZWdkM1OThmWG0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:53:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supermassive Black hole 700 million times mass of Sun spotted firing energy beam at earth - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Supermassive Black Hole 700 Million Times the Mass of the Sun Fires Energy Beam at Earth</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 15, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Supermassive Black Hole" /><figcaption>Image of the supermassive black hole.</figcaption><p>Scientists have discovered a supermassive black hole that is 700 million times the mass of the Sun, which is sending out a powerful energy beam towards Earth. This finding offers new insights into the behavior of black holes and their potential impact on our planet.</p><ul><li>Discovered black hole is 700 million solar masses in size.</li><li>The black hole is emitting a strong energy beam that could affect Earth.</li><li>Research enhances understanding of black holes and their effects on the universe.</li></ul><blockquote>“This energy beam demonstrates how active black holes can influence their surroundings, even across vast distances.”</blockquote><p>This discovery opens new avenues for research on supermassive black holes and their dynamics, emphasizing the need for ongoing observation and study.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/supermassive-black-hole-700-million-times-mass-of-sun-spotted-firing-energy-beam-at-earth/articleshow/117330978.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/supermassive-black-hole-700-million-times-mass-of-sun-spotted-firing-energy-beam-at-earth/articleshow/117330978.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unprecedented images of Exocomet belts around nearby stars - Tech Explorist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techexplorist.com/unprecedented-images-exocomet-belts-nearby-stars/96182/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techexplorist.com/unprecedented-images-exocomet-belts-nearby-stars/96182/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:07:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>