<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 14:21:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 14:21:10 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[KAUST And EPFL Conduct Groundbreaking Study On Microbiomes In Glacier-Fed Streams - OneArabia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>KAUST And EPFL Conduct Groundbreaking Study On Microbiomes In Glacier-Fed Streams</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 9, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> SPA</p>
<img src="https://images.onearabia.me/img/2025/01/microbiomes-1736430135353-600x340.jpg" alt="KAUST Studies Microbiomes in Glacier Streams" width="600" height="338">
<figcaption>KAUST Studies Microbiomes in Glacier Streams</figcaption>
<p>King Abdullah University of Science and Technology (KAUST), in partnership with the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL), has completed a groundbreaking study on microbiomes in glacier-fed streams.</p>
<ul>
<li>Researchers gathered samples from 170 glacier-fed streams in regions like New Zealand, the Himalayas, and the Andes over five years.</li>
<li>The study published findings in <i>Nature</i>, creating the first global reference for these ecosystems.</li>
<li>Half of the bacterial species found are endemic to specific mountain ranges.</li>
<li>Glacier-fed streams are vulnerable to climate change, necessitating a baseline understanding of their microbiomes.</li>
<li>The research resulted in the first global atlas of microorganisms in glacier-fed streams, essential for conservation efforts.</li>
<li>The study highlights the importance of these streams as vital water reservoirs for major rivers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Understanding these dynamics is crucial for future conservation efforts.” - Dr. Ramona Marasco, KAUST</blockquote>
<p>This collaboration has set a new standard for microbiome studies in extreme environments and emphasizes the urgent need to protect these ecosystems from climate impacts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.onearabia.me/local/kaust-research-on-microbiomes-in-glacier-fed-streams-011-92421.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.onearabia.me/local/kaust-research-on-microbiomes-in-glacier-fed-streams-011-92421.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 13:45:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 beautiful images of Moon captured by NASA - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Beautiful Images of Moon Captured by NASA</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 9, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> DNA</p><img src="https://images1.dnaindia.com/images/DNA-EN/900x1600/2025/1/9/1736429551591_1.jpg" alt="10 beautiful images of Moon captured by NASA"><figcaption>NASA's captivating images of the moon showcase human exploration and its wonders.</figcaption><p>This article presents a collection of magnificent images of the Moon captured by NASA over the years, highlighting key moments from various missions.</p><ul><li>Images from the Apollo missions displaying iconic moments.</li><li>Highlights of the Galileo spacecraft's journey towards Jupiter.</li><li>Visually stunning snapshots of the Moon's surface and phenomena.</li></ul><blockquote>“These images reflect the triumphs of human exploration and the beauty of our lunar neighbor.”</blockquote><p>The collection serves as a reminder of the significant achievements in space exploration and the beauty of our Moon.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/viral/10-beautiful-images-of-moon-captured-by-nasa-1736429196305</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/web-stories/viral/10-beautiful-images-of-moon-captured-by-nasa-1736429196305</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 13:35:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch the moon hide the 'Seven Sisters' of the Pleiades star cluster tonight - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watch the moon hide the 'Seven Sisters' of the Pleiades star cluster tonight</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 9, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/vvfrLt4aWr5h8j5JdEaF5b-320-80.jpg" alt="An illustration of the sky on Jan. 9, 2025 showing the moon passing in front of the Pleiades star cluster."><figcaption>An illustration of the sky on Jan. 9, 2025 showing the moon passing in front of the Pleiades star cluster. (Image credit: Chris Vaughan/Starry Night)</figcaption><p>On the night of January 9, skywatchers in North America will be able to view the moon as it passes in front of the Pleiades star cluster, known as the 'Seven Sisters'. This event, termed an occultation, presents a rare opportunity to see the celestial phenomenon.</p><ul><li>The moon is expected to cover several stars in the Pleiades and will be most visible from the central and western US.</li><li>This series of occultations began in November 2023 and will continue until July 2029, with another opportunity occurring on February 6, 2025.</li><li>Specific times for viewing vary by location; for example, in New York, key timings include 7:06 p.m. for Electra and 8:18 p.m. for Alcyone.</li><li>Observing with binoculars or a telescope can enhance visibility of the event as the moon obscures the stars.</li></ul><blockquote>“Watching the moon cover or uncover bright stars gives a visceral sense of the moon's orbital motion.” — Alan MacRobert, Senior Editor of Sky & Telescope magazine</blockquote><p>While the phenomenon may seem simple, the visual spectacle of the celestial dance between the moon and the stars is both captivating and scientifically significant.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/stargazing/watch-the-moon-hide-the-seven-sisters-of-the-pleiades-star-cluster-tonight</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/stargazing/watch-the-moon-hide-the-seven-sisters-of-the-pleiades-star-cluster-tonight</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronomers discover new galaxy forming in space’s longest ‘tail’ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronomers Discover New Galaxy Forming in Space’s Longest ‘Tail’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117086982,imgsize-988320,width-400,resizemode-4/117086982.jpg" alt="Astronomers discover new galaxy forming in space’s longest ‘tail’" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Astronomers discover a new galaxy forming in its nascent stages in the longest tidal tail observed.</figcaption><p>BENGALURU: A new galaxy has been discovered by astronomers and scientists located approximately 430 million light-years away in the Leo constellation, offering unprecedented insights into galaxy evolution and formation.</p><ul><li>The galaxy, NGC 3785, features a tidal tail stretching 1.27 million light-years.</li><li>This tidal tail is formed by gravitational interactions between galaxies.</li><li>The discovery highlights the birth of an ultra-diffuse galaxy at the tail's furthest reach.</li><li>Researchers from the Indian Institute of Astrophysics (IIA) and National Centre for Radio Astrophysics (NCRA) contributed to the findings.</li></ul><blockquote>“This extraordinary tidal tail stretches for 1.27 million light-years, making this the longest tidal tail discovered so far,” said Chandan Watts, Ph.D student at IIA.</blockquote><p>This discovery significantly enhances our understanding of how faint and diffuse galaxies come into existence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/astronomers-discover-new-galaxy-forming-in-spaces-longest-tail/articleshow/117086944.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/astronomers-discover-new-galaxy-forming-in-spaces-longest-tail/articleshow/117086944.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 12:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Was there ever life on Mars? NASA may have found evidence, but retrieving it could cost $7.7 billion - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgJBVV95cUxPa3dGTWdYdW1MLUFoaWM1N0pXSDlyRVVNSk1FVDBRX2xnREVuY3I0cVI0WlZfR2xkVVVVd3MtX0lrR0pvUEJ0Z0JRNnlPOEc0VG9hUXE5QkxuOXFvYUJCVXFYNGlqeWR2U0FjaXhOaTlIcGtpeW9iYjBxMmpDcmZIM3d0elRVcm5vZ29wWG1TTE9RTjFRVGNlTjZmSkVoWWZ6Zmw3dFRHTlZhUnNEMGNmM090QXFTSDhLWHF3R1FEVVUyMlNXSmt4ZFExbGp5OWxTT3B0Z0w5NVZmeHhCSnF6VkN5SGlfVlJrazZMa1QyRllvcEhnRUdiNmxGaEtGTzJKMFFYcTRvSWVSVGYxOWFnd3hR0gGXAkFVX3lxTE96V0puYkNacE1FU0tXejdlNEctR01lUThDamswVENjWjNmVjUxQ3c5cWY1RlBDZ0Jkb3hsNmkySTE4YjAtbFdLTEF4UXp2Vklmb0M5M2wxeXMzUy1QdmxUZkotT1ZqVktVeVNHak90d3JCZWtpR21ZRm5xeldfa3k1Tk9ob09wcldjdDNfVUpVUzFiVHloc2RBRk5Gb3ZmZnhzTW1yTEJOQkhVcUxwU1BsdVdyWWYwaXpkR1d2T2xiSzZmNEJtQU15cVNkT1lDUUhsekczOGpxN0VUR1FkYURqSDAyUHBJMldWdWNxV2dXbFlVM0l2RGdBSmsyTDBGZ1dIc0pQeTRpNHFlRk1wZ3ZGTjE4TWtBYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgJBVV95cUxPa3dGTWdYdW1MLUFoaWM1N0pXSDlyRVVNSk1FVDBRX2xnREVuY3I0cVI0WlZfR2xkVVVVd3MtX0lrR0pvUEJ0Z0JRNnlPOEc0VG9hUXE5QkxuOXFvYUJCVXFYNGlqeWR2U0FjaXhOaTlIcGtpeW9iYjBxMmpDcmZIM3d0elRVcm5vZ29wWG1TTE9RTjFRVGNlTjZmSkVoWWZ6Zmw3dFRHTlZhUnNEMGNmM090QXFTSDhLWHF3R1FEVVUyMlNXSmt4ZFExbGp5OWxTT3B0Z0w5NVZmeHhCSnF6VkN5SGlfVlJrazZMa1QyRllvcEhnRUdiNmxGaEtGTzJKMFFYcTRvSWVSVGYxOWFnd3hR0gGXAkFVX3lxTE96V0puYkNacE1FU0tXejdlNEctR01lUThDamswVENjWjNmVjUxQ3c5cWY1RlBDZ0Jkb3hsNmkySTE4YjAtbFdLTEF4UXp2Vklmb0M5M2wxeXMzUy1QdmxUZkotT1ZqVktVeVNHak90d3JCZWtpR21ZRm5xeldfa3k1Tk9ob09wcldjdDNfVUpVUzFiVHloc2RBRk5Gb3ZmZnhzTW1yTEJOQkhVcUxwU1BsdVdyWWYwaXpkR1d2T2xiSzZmNEJtQU15cVNkT1lDUUhsekczOGpxN0VUR1FkYURqSDAyUHBJMldWdWNxV2dXbFlVM0l2RGdBSmsyTDBGZ1dIc0pQeTRpNHFlRk1wZ3ZGTjE4TWtBYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 12:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pluto's 'kiss and capture' of its largest moon Charon 4.5 billion years ago could change how we teach abo - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/education/news/plutos-kiss-and-capture-of-its-largest-moon-charon-4-5-billion-years-ago-could-change-how-we-teach-about-moons-and-planetary-systems-in-us-schools/articleshow/117076924.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/education/news/plutos-kiss-and-capture-of-its-largest-moon-charon-4-5-billion-years-ago-could-change-how-we-teach-about-moons-and-planetary-systems-in-us-schools/articleshow/117076924.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pluto's 'kiss and capture' of its largest moon Charon 4.5 billion years ago could change how we teach about moons and planetary systems in US schools - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pluto's 'kiss and capture' of its largest moon Charon 4.5 billion years ago could change how we teach about moons and planetary systems in US schools</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Pluto and Charon" />
<figcaption>Pluto's encounter with Charon redefines our understanding of moon formation.</figcaption>
<p>The article discusses the significance of Pluto's historical gravitational relationship with its largest moon Charon, suggesting it may influence educational curricula regarding planetary systems in the US.</p>
<ul>
<li>Pluto's capture of Charon occurred approximately 4.5 billion years ago.</li>
<li>This phenomenon provides insights into moon formation and dynamics in planetary systems.</li>
<li>Educational materials may be updated to reflect these new findings.</li>
<li>The research emphasizes the importance of considering gravity's role in celestial relationships.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The interaction between Pluto and Charon is a perfect case study for understanding moons and their parent planets.”</blockquote>
<p>This new perspective is a breakthrough for educators aiming to engage students in astronomy and planetary science more effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/education/news/plutos-kiss-and-capture-of-its-largest-moon-charon-4-5-billion-years-ago-could-change-how-we-teach-about-moons-and-planetary-systems-in-us-schools/articleshow/117076924.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/education/news/plutos-kiss-and-capture-of-its-largest-moon-charon-4-5-billion-years-ago-could-change-how-we-teach-about-moons-and-planetary-systems-in-us-schools/articleshow/117076924.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New study of supernovae calls dark energy’s existence into question - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New study of supernovae calls dark energy’s existence into question</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Conversation</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/4vtgs3/article69080472.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-06T144522Z_264392299_RC29JBA6FAN6_RTRMADP_3_YEAR-END-SPACE.JPG" alt="The Crab Nebula" title="The Crab Nebula, the result of a bright supernova explosion seen by Chinese and other astronomers in the year 1054, 6,500 light-years from Earth, is seen in an image taken by the James Webb Telescope on June 3, 2024." />
<figcaption>The Crab Nebula, the result of a bright supernova explosion seen by Chinese and other astronomers in the year 1054, 6,500 light-years from Earth, is seen in an image taken by the James Webb Telescope on June 3, 2024.</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses a recent study that challenges the existence of dark energy, suggesting an alternative known as the Timescape model, which could significantly alter our understanding of the universe's expansion.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Astronomers have used supernova data to conclude that dark energy may not be necessary to explain the universe’s accelerating expansion.</li>
  <li>The Timescape model suggests that the uneven distribution of matter in the universe influences the perceived rate of expansion.</li>
  <li>The study utilized the Pantheon+ dataset, revealing that the Timescape model could better describe nearby supernova observations compared to the traditional Lambda-CDM model.</li>
  <li>Further research is needed to address potential measurement biases and test the robustness of the Timescape model.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>This would represent a revolutionary paradigm shift in cosmology.</blockquote>
<p>If confirmed, this theory could reshape our understanding of cosmic evolution and the foundational principles of modern physics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/new-study-of-supernovae-calls-dark-energys-existence-into-question/article69080375.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/new-study-of-supernovae-calls-dark-energys-existence-into-question/article69080375.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 11:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top three images from BepiColombo's sixth Mercury flyby - European Space Agency]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top three images from BepiColombo's sixth Mercury flyby</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 09/01/2025 <strong>Source:</strong> European Space Agency</p><figure><img src="/var/esa/storage/images/esa_multimedia/images/2025/01/bepicolombo_s_sixth_mercury_flyby/26525911-1-eng-GB/BepiColombo_s_sixth_Mercury_flyby_article.jpg" alt="BepiColombo's sixth Mercury flyby"><figcaption><a href="/ESA_Multimedia/Images/2025/01/BepiColombo_s_sixth_Mercury_flyby">BepiColombo's sixth Mercury flyby</a></figcaption></figure><p>On 8 January 2025, the ESA/JAXA BepiColombo mission successfully completed its sixth flyby of Mercury, providing stunning images that reveal icy craters and vast sunlit plains.</p><ul><li>The spacecraft flew just 295 km above Mercury's surface on its dark night side.</li><li>The close-up images unveil icy craters at the planet's north pole, possibly containing frozen water.</li><li>This flyby marks the end of the M-CAM cameras' close views of Mercury before the mission's orbiters separate in late 2026.</li></ul><blockquote>“BepiColombo's main mission phase may only start two years from now, but all six of its flybys have given us invaluable new information about Mercury.” - Geraint Jones, ESA</blockquote><p>The successful flyby enhances our understanding of Mercury's surface and sets the stage for further exploration once the spacecraft enters orbit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/BepiColombo/Top_three_images_from_BepiColombo_s_sixth_Mercury_flyby</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/BepiColombo/Top_three_images_from_BepiColombo_s_sixth_Mercury_flyby</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:40:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA shuts down JPL lab due to raging fire in LA - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Shuts Down JPL Lab Due to Raging Fire in LA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Wion</p>
<img src="https://img-cdn.thepublive.com/fit-in/0x0/filters:format(webp)/wion/media/media_files/2025/01/09/UtfyoqiSnb2V9edwLxMa.jpg" alt="NASA shuts down JPL lab due to raging fire in LA">
<figcaption>NASA Laboratory Closure Due to Eaton Fire</figcaption>
<p>The Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) near Los Angeles has been temporarily closed due to the Eaton Fire, which broke out near Altadena. This event has affected critical NASA missions and led to evacuations in the surrounding areas.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Eaton Fire has burned over 1,000 acres north of Pasadena.</li>
  <li>Operations at JPL, including the Perseverance rover, are disrupted.</li>
  <li>Evacuations are underway but the lab itself has not suffered fire damage.</li>
  <li>Experts are on site to safeguard the area and assess damage from the wildfire.</li>
  <li>The fire is part of a larger trend of wildfires affecting the Los Angeles area.</li>
  <li>This incident compounds challenges for JPL following recent layoffs due to funding issues.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"While the lab has not suffered fire damage, nearby evacuations are underway. Many staff members have fled their homes, with some reporting losses." - JPL Director Laurie Leshin</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing wildfire situation highlights the vulnerability of vital infrastructure and ongoing challenges faced by NASA in its operations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-technology/nasa-shuts-down-jpl-lab-due-to-raging-fire-in-la-8604290</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-technology/nasa-shuts-down-jpl-lab-due-to-raging-fire-in-la-8604290</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:54:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fire Meets Zero Gravity As NASA Preps for Major Spacewalks - SciTechDaily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fire Meets Zero Gravity As NASA Preps for Major Spacewalks</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p>
<img src="https://scitechdaily.com/images/Spherical-Flame-in-Space-777x550.jpg" alt="Spherical Flame in Space" width="777" height="550">
<figcaption>A spherical flame created in space (left), and a candle flame burning on Earth (right). Credit: NASA</figcaption>
<p>The article discusses recent activities aboard the International Space Station (ISS) as NASA prepares for upcoming spacewalks and conducts important research on fire behavior in microgravity and exercise effects on astronauts.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The crew on the ISS is focused on microgravity research related to fire safety and exercise science.</li>
  <li>A spacewalk is planned to repair and enhance scientific hardware on the ISS.</li>
  <li>NASA Flight Engineers Don Pettit and Nick Hague are involved in both experiments and preparations for the spacewalks.</li>
  <li>Pettit is working with combustion experiments to improve fire safety protocols for future missions.</li>
  <li>Training for the astronauts includes using advanced exercise equipment to monitor physical health in space.</li>
  <li>Two spacewalks are scheduled for January 16 and January 23 to address specific maintenance and upgrades on the ISS.</li>
  <li>International collaboration takes place among NASA and Roscosmos engineers to prepare for future missions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>NASA managers will hold a preview briefing of the upcoming spacewalks on NASA+.</blockquote>
<p>This preparation showcases not only the ongoing work within the ISS but also the dedication of NASA and international partners to advancing space exploration even amidst challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/fire-meets-zero-gravity-as-nasa-preps-for-major-spacewalks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scitechdaily.com/fire-meets-zero-gravity-as-nasa-preps-for-major-spacewalks/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:05:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pluto ‘kissed’ its moon and captured it in orbit - Tech Explorist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techexplorist.com/pluto-kissed-moon-captured-orbit/95576/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techexplorist.com/pluto-kissed-moon-captured-orbit/95576/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:21:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Highest Jumping Animals in the World - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Highest Jumping Animals in the World</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 9, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2025/01/09/900x1600/froghopper-jumping_1736424059917_1736424062806.jpg" alt="NATURE'S HIGH FLYERS"><figcaption>NATURE'S HIGH FLYERS</figcaption><p>Jumping is a remarkable skill in animals, aiding in hunting and escaping predators. Some leap several times their body length.</p><ul><li><h2>Hare</h2><p>Hares can jump up to 10 feet vertically, thanks to their strong hind legs, enabling them to evade obstacles and predators effectively.</p></li><li><h2>Kangaroo Rat</h2><p>Kangaroo rat, native to North America's deserts, can jump up to 9 feet to evade predators using strong hind legs.</p></li><li><h2>Jumping Spider</h2><p>Jumping spiders, despite their small size, can leap up to 50 times their body length with remarkable precision.</p></li><li><h2>Impala</h2><p>The agile African impala can jump up to 10 feet high and 30 feet long, adeptly clearing obstacles and evading predators swiftly.</p></li><li><h2>Red Kangaroo</h2><p>The red kangaroo, Australia's largest marsupial, can jump up to 6 feet high and 25 feet far, using powerful legs for energy-efficient movement.</p></li></ul><blockquote>Jumping is a remarkable skill in animals, aiding in hunting and escaping predators.</blockquote><p>The ability to jump is a fascinating adaptation found in various animal species, showcasing nature's ingenuity in survival strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-highest-jumping-animals-in-the-world-visual-story-11736423161220.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-highest-jumping-animals-in-the-world-visual-story-11736423161220.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:09:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JAXA deploys first ever wooden satellite in space from ISS - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JAXA Deploys First Ever Wooden Satellite in Space from ISS</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 9, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Wion</p><img src="https://img-cdn.thepublive.com/fit-in/0x0/filters:format(webp)/wion/media/media_files/2025/01/09/qSf5KCFekWQqVjuRziqh.jpg" alt="First Wooden Satellite"><figcaption>First Wooden Satellite deployed into Earth's orbit.</figcaption><p>LignoSat, the world’s first wooden satellite, launched into orbit last month to explore the potential of wood in space applications.</p><ul><li>LignoSat was delivered to the International Space Station aboard a SpaceX Dragon cargo capsule in November 2024.</li><li>The satellite is made from honoki magnolia wood and uses a traditional Japanese wood-joining technique.</li><li>Over its six-month mission, it will assess wood's performance versus traditional materials like aluminum and titanium.</li><li>LignoSat will monitor the effects of extreme temperatures and radiation in space.</li><li>The project aims to inform future designs for habitats on the Moon or Mars using sustainable materials.</li><li>It also aims to reduce space debris impact by ensuring complete combustion upon re-entry.</li></ul><blockquote>“With timber, a material we can produce ourselves, we could build habitats and work in space indefinitely,” said Takao Doi, an astronaut and researcher.</blockquote><p>This innovative project marks a significant step towards utilizing sustainable materials in space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-technology/jaxa-deploys-first-ever-wooden-satellite-in-space-from-iss-8603695</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-technology/jaxa-deploys-first-ever-wooden-satellite-in-space-from-iss-8603695</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:05:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Blazing a trail for sustainable space exploration': World’s first wooden satellite deployed into... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>World’s First Wooden Satellite Deployed into Earth’s Orbit</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 09, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250109060959_Sheetal-Kumari-fi.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431' alt='Artist’s impression of LignoSat' title='Artist’s impression of LignoSat (Image: Kyoto University)' width='770' height='431'>
<figcaption>Artist’s impression of LignoSat (Image: Kyoto University)</figcaption>
<p>The world’s first wooden satellite, LignoSat, has been successfully deployed into orbit, aiming to explore the sustainability of materials used in space technology.</p>
<ul>
  <li>LignoSat orbits 400 kilometers above Earth, launched alongside four other CubeSats.</li>
  <li>Constructed using magnolia wood, weighing 900 grams, showcasing traditional Japanese joinery techniques.</li>
  <li>The satellite aims to test the durability of wood in space, potentially replacing conventional materials like aluminium.</li>
  <li>This innovation could reduce the environmental impact of space technology by utilizing more sustainable materials.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The satellite's findings could offer alternatives to conventional materials like aluminium or titanium, promoting sustainability in space technology.</blockquote>
<p>This pioneering effort represents a significant step toward sustainable practices in space exploration, with potential long-term benefits for the environment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/blazing-a-trail-for-sustainable-space-exploration-world-s-first-wooden-satellite-deployed-into-earth-s-orbit-article-12906382.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/blazing-a-trail-for-sustainable-space-exploration-world-s-first-wooden-satellite-deployed-into-earth-s-orbit-article-12906382.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:25:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Fire emergency at NASA's lab': Jet Propulsion Laboratory closed due to raging LA wildfire - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fire Emergency at NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory Due to LA Wildfire</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250109055209_Sheetal-Kumari-fi.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Jet Propulsion Laboratory (Image: NASA)" title="Jet Propulsion Laboratory (Image: NASA)" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Jet Propulsion Laboratory (Image: NASA)</figcaption><p>A raging wildfire has disrupted operations at NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL), located at the foothills of the San Gabriel Mountains near Los Angeles. The Eaton Fire has brought the centre to a halt, forcing closure and evacuations while threatening critical robotic space missions.</p><ul><li>The Eaton Fire ignited on January 7, scorching over 1,000 acres and is being fueled by strong winds.</li><li>JPL is temporarily closed, with all non-emergency personnel evacuated.</li><li>Director Laurie Leshin confirmed no fire damage yet, but evacuations are ongoing in the area.</li><li>Robotic missions such as Perseverance rover and Europa Clipper are currently at risk.</li></ul><blockquote>“JPL is closed except for emergency personnel,” - Laurie Leshin</blockquote><p>The ongoing wildfire poses a significant threat to operations at JPL, emphasizing the vulnerability of significant scientific infrastructure to natural disasters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/fire-emergency-at-nasas-lab-jet-propulsion-laboratory-closed-due-to-raging-la-wildfire-article-12906398.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/fire-emergency-at-nasas-lab-jet-propulsion-laboratory-closed-due-to-raging-la-wildfire-article-12906398.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:04:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Fire emergency at NASA's lab': Jet Propulsion Laboratory closed due to raging wildfire - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxOOGU0RnZxWGdrT0dxbE5uVUluUWxybEF4cEFlUk1BcUNTQkFjb3g5YnhyNkFiMWdRQjdPNUN0OHhVaTlxd1Q1UFZWUE5LaG5vWmwzVlItdlpCNWlZSUxUYzEtVUt3Zzh6eHZuLWczNEgzV0lMSjZoZnB0X2Zxb1Q5cnN6NzU5Rm9PUzMzMUFoZ2RmT2lNb19yVnJBWG53VmNvV2pWYjMyZS05UVE5YTFSY3UzWml0dmVmWUdlTjZqV3RlblQzUTA4dU9DOEhLSDdaVFR0TnhVRjY1dTjSAeABQVVfeXFMTjZMNzFXV3NQTFQ4WUswZnVNQnctZEtUeHMwaVlSTVRTdmtMWkNtalBGY0hCV3hOdkNJM1JpSUtxbC1JdGZnV1R5ZVQteklSdGlsc0hKU2Fkb1R2VnNKMEtpRFRQbEhNdS1pZU0zNzZwM2d0OFhpOVZvOG1Fd0o4dkhldnhkN3NQMHEzck93Wl90R1EyeGFuUHhnSVEtbVFIU2tmRkhBcU5YeUU2UENLMjFLYVJWWTZ5d0tRelZidFBHNGw2Nldab09vTWJOZE5uaWtUYnM4cWg3djhDNElQQUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxOOGU0RnZxWGdrT0dxbE5uVUluUWxybEF4cEFlUk1BcUNTQkFjb3g5YnhyNkFiMWdRQjdPNUN0OHhVaTlxd1Q1UFZWUE5LaG5vWmwzVlItdlpCNWlZSUxUYzEtVUt3Zzh6eHZuLWczNEgzV0lMSjZoZnB0X2Zxb1Q5cnN6NzU5Rm9PUzMzMUFoZ2RmT2lNb19yVnJBWG53VmNvV2pWYjMyZS05UVE5YTFSY3UzWml0dmVmWUdlTjZqV3RlblQzUTA4dU9DOEhLSDdaVFR0TnhVRjY1dTjSAeABQVVfeXFMTjZMNzFXV3NQTFQ4WUswZnVNQnctZEtUeHMwaVlSTVRTdmtMWkNtalBGY0hCV3hOdkNJM1JpSUtxbC1JdGZnV1R5ZVQteklSdGlsc0hKU2Fkb1R2VnNKMEtpRFRQbEhNdS1pZU0zNzZwM2d0OFhpOVZvOG1Fd0o4dkhldnhkN3NQMHEzck93Wl90R1EyeGFuUHhnSVEtbVFIU2tmRkhBcU5YeUU2UENLMjFLYVJWWTZ5d0tRelZidFBHNGw2Nldab09vTWJOZE5uaWtUYnM4cWg3djhDNElQQUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:04:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unraveling the Cosmos: Timescape Model Challenges Dark Energy Paradigm - Devdiscourse]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unraveling the Cosmos: Timescape Model Challenges Dark Energy Paradigm</h1><p><strong>Updated: 09-01-2025</strong> | Source: Devdiscourse News Desk</p><p>A new cosmological model, known as the Timescape model, is posing an intriguing challenge to the widely accepted Lambda-CDM model of universal expansion, suggesting that cosmic expansion's acceleration may be an illusion due to varying expansion rates.</p><ul><li>The Timescape model accounts for the uneven distribution of matter across the universe.</li><li>It questions the role of dark energy in the universe's accelerated growth.</li><li>Recent studies utilizing supernova data support the hypothesis that cosmic voids expand faster than denser regions.</li><li>This new perspective could shift current paradigms in cosmology, pending further evidence.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.devdiscourse.com/article/science-environment/3219787-unraveling-the-cosmos-timescape-model-challenges-dark-energy-paradigm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.devdiscourse.com/article/science-environment/3219787-unraveling-the-cosmos-timescape-model-challenges-dark-energy-paradigm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 05:28:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Intensely Fake': NASA astronaut's recent aurora video from space sparks authenticity debate online - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Intensely Fake': NASA astronaut's recent aurora video from space sparks authenticity debate online</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250107051100_Sheetal-Kumari-fi.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Aurora From Space (Image: @astro_Pettit/X)" title="Aurora From Space (Image: @astro_Pettit/X)" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Aurora From Space (Image: @astro_Pettit/X)</figcaption><p>NASA astronaut Don Pettit has shared a mesmerizing video showcasing vibrant green auroras from the International Space Station, sparking debate about its authenticity.</p><ul><li>The nine-second video features the green glow of auroras caused by solar particles interacting with Earth's magnetic field.</li><li>There is a mix of awe and skepticism in the comments on social media platforms.</li></ul><blockquote>“Flying over aurora; intensely green.” - Don Pettit (@astro_Pettit)</blockquote><p>The video has stirred a wide range of reactions, with viewers expressing amazement and curiosity about the phenomena.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/intensely-fake-nasa-astronaut-s-recent-aurora-video-from-space-sparks-authenticity-debate-online-article-12906349.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/intensely-fake-nasa-astronaut-s-recent-aurora-video-from-space-sparks-authenticity-debate-online-article-12906349.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 05:14:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['China vs NASA': A billion dollar battle to bring 1st Martian sample - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-technology/china-vs-nasa-a-billion-dollar-battle-to-bring-1st-martian-sample-back-to-earth-8603343</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-technology/china-vs-nasa-a-billion-dollar-battle-to-bring-1st-martian-sample-back-to-earth-8603343</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 03:11:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Truly Remarkable” – Scientists Discover Record-Breaking Super-Earth That Is As Dense as Lead - SciTechDaily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>“Truly Remarkable” – Scientists Discover Record-Breaking Super-Earth That Is As Dense as Lead</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date & Source:</strong> November 8, 2024, <em>Scientific Reports</em></p>
<img src="https://scitechdaily.com/images/K2-360-System-777x550.jpg" alt="K2 360 System" width="777" height="550">
<figcaption>Artist’s conception of the K2-360 system, showing the ultra-dense super-Earth K2-360 b (red) in its extremely close orbit around its Sun-like star, with the more distant companion K2-360 c (blue) in the background. Credit: Astrobiology Center</figcaption>
<p>An international research team has identified a new multi-planet system orbiting a Sun-like star, featuring an ultra-short period planet with one of the highest densities ever recorded, K2-360 b.</p>
<ul>
  <li>K2-360 b: A rocky “super-Earth” about 1.6 times the size of Earth, completing an orbit in just 21 hours and weighing 7.7 times more than Earth.</li>
  <li>K2-360 c: A larger outer planet with a minimum mass of 15 Earth masses, which orbits every 9.8 days but does not transit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“K2-360 b is truly remarkable – it’s as dense as lead, packing nearly 8 Earth masses into a ball only slightly larger than our planet,” says John Livingston, lead author.</blockquote>
<p>The K2-360 system provides insights into extreme planetary evolution and is crucial for understanding how planets form under extreme conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/truly-remarkable-scientists-discover-record-breaking-super-earth-that-is-as-dense-as-lead/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scitechdaily.com/truly-remarkable-scientists-discover-record-breaking-super-earth-that-is-as-dense-as-lead/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 01:33:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japan: JAXA And Kyoto University Launch ‘LignoSat’, First Wooden Satellite - NewsX]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxPdHI5UkdBQm1fcWYxd05zd0dRbW9mUHNFNjAxdk1hNEEwU18yR0RkSXFuOWx3WGlRQ0xQNXc2VnRtLXN5QkgyQlU4Y3B5VGI1YWRpeWd0YjRGdTVVSDlQUF90ZXdzSzdkdEN4c0xzZTcyUWlLbzlhN3U4TmRJNlRRVGJ5dTFUWkJKdFVaT1kxVWpnM3ZRQzduTFBSRmlmWDg0ZGg4eWFsV1ZYMDA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxPdHI5UkdBQm1fcWYxd05zd0dRbW9mUHNFNjAxdk1hNEEwU18yR0RkSXFuOWx3WGlRQ0xQNXc2VnRtLXN5QkgyQlU4Y3B5VGI1YWRpeWd0YjRGdTVVSDlQUF90ZXdzSzdkdEN4c0xzZTcyUWlLbzlhN3U4TmRJNlRRVGJ5dTFUWkJKdFVaT1kxVWpnM3ZRQzduTFBSRmlmWDg0ZGg4eWFsV1ZYMDA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 23:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Volcano that cooled Earth in 1831 identified, scientists say - WORLD News Group]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Volcano That Cooled Earth in 1831 Identified, Scientists Say</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</p><p>The source of a massive volcanic eruption in 1831 has been identified as the Zavaritskii caldera in the Kuril Islands near Japan, revealing how it contributed to significant Earth cooling.</p><img src='link-to-image' alt='Image of the Zavaritskii caldera'><figcaption>Image of the Zavaritskii caldera in the Kuril Islands</figcaption><ul><li>1831 eruption was one of the largest in the 19th century.</li><li>Eruption spewed sulfur dioxide into the stratosphere, cooling the planet by 1 degree Celsius.</li><li>Researchers dated layers of tephra glass in ice cores to confirm the volcano as the eruption source.</li></ul><blockquote>“The cloud of sulfur dioxide deflected enough sunlight to cool the planet by 1 degree Celsius.”</blockquote><p>This discovery provides insight into the impact of volcanic eruptions on global climate change.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://wng.org/sift/volcano-that-cooled-earth-in-1831-identified-scientists-say-1736367634</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://wng.org/sift/volcano-that-cooled-earth-in-1831-identified-scientists-say-1736367634</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 22:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Brains Filter Sensory Noise to Make Better Decisions - Neuroscience News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How Brains Filter Sensory Noise to Make Better Decisions</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not Specified <strong>Source: </strong>Yale</p><figure><img src="https://neurosciencenews.com/files/2025/01/brain-noise-decisions-neuroscinece.jpg" alt="This shows a head and a brain."><figcaption>For the new study, the researchers investigated a specific type of connection between neuronal cells, called electrical synapses, which differs from the more widely studied chemical synapses. Credit: Neuroscience News</figcaption></figure><p>A new study reveals how electrical synapses help animals, including worms, filter sensory inputs and make context-appropriate decisions. Researchers found that these synapses, mediated by the protein INX-1, connect specific neurons in worms, dampening irrelevant signals and prioritizing essential ones.</p><p>The mechanism enables worms to navigate temperature gradients effectively, avoiding distractions. In worms without functioning INX-1, hypersensitivity to minor temperature changes disrupts their ability to choose context-appropriate behaviors.</p><p>Since electrical synapses exist in many animals, including humans, the findings may offer insights into how brains process sensory information for decision-making.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li><strong>Neural Filtering:</strong> Electrical synapses dampen weak signals, allowing worms to prioritize relevant sensory inputs for efficient navigation.</li><li><strong>Protein INX-1 Role:</strong> INX-1-mediated electrical synapses in AIY neurons enable context-specific behavior in worms.</li><li><strong>Broader Implications:</strong> Similar mechanisms may regulate sensory processing in other animals, including humans, influencing decision-making and perception.</li></ul><blockquote>“Altering this electrical conduit in a single pair of cells can change what the animal chooses to do,” said Daniel Colón-Ramos, the Dorys McConnell Duberg Professor of Neuroscience and Cell Biology at Yale School of Medicine and corresponding author of the study.</blockquote><p>These findings highlight the importance of precise neural connections in filtering sensory inputs and guiding behavior.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://neurosciencenews.com/sensory-noise-decision-making-28337/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://neurosciencenews.com/sensory-noise-decision-making-28337/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 21:56:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How electrical synapses fine-tune sensory information for better decisions - Science Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How Electrical Synapses Fine-Tune Sensory Information for Better Decisions</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Journal Cell</p><p>Scientists at Yale and the University of Connecticut have discovered how electrical synapses play a key role in filtering sensory information, aiding animal decision-making processes.</p><ul><li>Research highlights the importance of electrical synapses in enabling context-appropriate choices.</li><li>The study used the <em>C. elegans</em> worm as a model organism to explore action selection mechanisms.</li><li>Worms display behaviors such as gradient migration and isothermal tracking based on temperature preferences.</li><li>Electrical synapses, mediated by the protein INX-1, help dampen signals from thermosensory neurons.</li><li>Impairment of INX-1 leads to hypersensitivity, resulting in ineffective behavioral responses in worms.</li></ul><blockquote>“Altering this electrical conduit in a single pair of cells can change what the animal chooses to do.” - Daniel Colón-Ramos</blockquote><p>This research suggests that understanding electrical synapse configurations can inform broader studies on sensory processing across various species.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/01/250108143451.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/01/250108143451.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 21:38:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Latest Space Pictures Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/5-latest-space-pictures-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/117064571.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/5-latest-space-pictures-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/117064571.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 19:53:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA astronauts stuck on International Space Station say they 'don't feel like castaways' - Sky News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQVFY5MFFoYzlvYXlJRVdRU1pZekxnZzdxVEZyZmNpSE9WekZzdDNhMjlpOGlqaUZhOUM5dUpuWUZCOFJnMW1zMUdyQTlHRHlwQ3ZwUTZQRzlKSmV4endKSUxKa04yRHBBRERldkVOc2hYSXNCcDNGQWxjYzdXUFRKSE50N3BPS1lDamtMM29WTGVqZGMyQXE3UHV3bThlMFU1Q1R2ek41eS1uT05FTzR0djJSS0lTZUZPdnA1VS1rSdIBxAFBVV95cUxQTVktTjByZGNiQ2dDUUhiaHpwOTZ4czhGcGw0d3RDOWhzb3hJMkx5Z0wtOVlEZ1VZME5mc0JXREhMdjhyaXZhWXg1Z01yck1rWFRTNl9QR2Y2V1lEQm5yTi1CVE5kakJiTXpuaDY4b0MtUDVYbFdiYWpaSC1KZ2w4RzVEdFY5WnlIMnhKVWRLY2hkWGQ3eWszYVZUM050eHRjdElYclpmYWhRVFVHZ1c1cjFWN2h2SHU4MWV6UTlVQjlRell6?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxQVFY5MFFoYzlvYXlJRVdRU1pZekxnZzdxVEZyZmNpSE9WekZzdDNhMjlpOGlqaUZhOUM5dUpuWUZCOFJnMW1zMUdyQTlHRHlwQ3ZwUTZQRzlKSmV4endKSUxKa04yRHBBRERldkVOc2hYSXNCcDNGQWxjYzdXUFRKSE50N3BPS1lDamtMM29WTGVqZGMyQXE3UHV3bThlMFU1Q1R2ek41eS1uT05FTzR0djJSS0lTZUZPdnA1VS1rSdIBxAFBVV95cUxQTVktTjByZGNiQ2dDUUhiaHpwOTZ4czhGcGw0d3RDOWhzb3hJMkx5Z0wtOVlEZ1VZME5mc0JXREhMdjhyaXZhWXg1Z01yck1rWFRTNl9QR2Y2V1lEQm5yTi1CVE5kakJiTXpuaDY4b0MtUDVYbFdiYWpaSC1KZ2w4RzVEdFY5WnlIMnhKVWRLY2hkWGQ3eWszYVZUM050eHRjdElYclpmYWhRVFVHZ1c1cjFWN2h2SHU4MWV6UTlVQjlRell6?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:54:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 planets will be visible in the night sky in January, 4 to the naked eye - The National Desk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Visibility of 6 Planets in January: A Stargazer's Guide</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> WKRC</p><img src="/resources/media2/16x9/1536/648/center/90/27a36e64-d1fb-47e5-8288-3d44a58d1b24-Jan_2025_skychart_Planets.png" alt="Skychart of visible planets"/><figcaption>(NASA/JPL-Caltech)</figcaption><p>Nasa has announced that January will be an exciting month for stargazers with six planets visible in the night sky, four of which can be observed without a telescope.</p><ul><li>Peak of the Quadrantid meteor shower on Jan. 3.</li><li>The moon will pass in front of Mars on Jan. 13.</li><li>Venus and Saturn will appear close together on Jan. 17 and 18.</li><li>The planets visible to the naked eye include Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars.</li><li>Uranus and Neptune will require a telescope to be seen.</li></ul><blockquote>Nasa states that seeing so many bright planets at once is a notable event.</blockquote><p>This January presents a great opportunity for skywatchers, both amateur and experienced, to enjoy the wonders of the night sky.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thenationaldesk.com/news/offbeat/planets-visible-space-naked-eye-january-venus-jupiter-saturn-mars-nasa-stars-star-telescope-skywatching-stargazing-planet-meteor-shower-events-view-viewers-sky-night-time-astrological-astronomy-month-4-6-uranus-neptune-aligned-alignment</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thenationaldesk.com/news/offbeat/planets-visible-space-naked-eye-january-venus-jupiter-saturn-mars-nasa-stars-star-telescope-skywatching-stargazing-planet-meteor-shower-events-view-viewers-sky-night-time-astrological-astronomy-month-4-6-uranus-neptune-aligned-alignment</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:41:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronaut set to patch NASA's X-ray telescope aboard space station - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-01-astronaut-patch-nasa-ray-telescope.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-01-astronaut-patch-nasa-ray-telescope.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:10:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This is how NASA aims to bring Mars rock and soil samples at a cheaper and faster rate - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This is how NASA aims to bring Mars rock and soil samples at a cheaper and faster rate</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>Nasa is developing new strategies to collect samples from Mars more efficiently and cost-effectively.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nasa plans to utilize advanced technologies to streamline the collection process.</li>
<li>Collaborations with international partners aim to enhance the mission's feasibility and effectiveness.</li>
<li>Cost reduction strategies include using existing infrastructure instead of building new equipment.</li>
<li>Timelines for sample collection have been accelerated to expedite research and analysis.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Our new approach will enable us to achieve more with less, ensuring our Mars missions are both ambitious and affordable." - NASA Official</blockquote>
<p>This initiative reflects Nasa's commitment to pushing the boundaries of space exploration while maintaining fiscal responsibility.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/this-is-how-nasa-aims-to-bring-mars-rock-and-soil-samples-at-a-cheaper-and-faster-rate/articleshow/117062646.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/this-is-how-nasa-aims-to-bring-mars-rock-and-soil-samples-at-a-cheaper-and-faster-rate/articleshow/117062646.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>