<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 19:17:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 19:17:09 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 planets will be visible in the night sky in January, 4 to the naked eye - The National Desk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Visibility of 6 Planets in January: A Stargazer's Guide</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> WKRC</p><img src="/resources/media2/16x9/1536/648/center/90/27a36e64-d1fb-47e5-8288-3d44a58d1b24-Jan_2025_skychart_Planets.png" alt="Skychart of visible planets"/><figcaption>(NASA/JPL-Caltech)</figcaption><p>Nasa has announced that January will be an exciting month for stargazers with six planets visible in the night sky, four of which can be observed without a telescope.</p><ul><li>Peak of the Quadrantid meteor shower on Jan. 3.</li><li>The moon will pass in front of Mars on Jan. 13.</li><li>Venus and Saturn will appear close together on Jan. 17 and 18.</li><li>The planets visible to the naked eye include Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars.</li><li>Uranus and Neptune will require a telescope to be seen.</li></ul><blockquote>Nasa states that seeing so many bright planets at once is a notable event.</blockquote><p>This January presents a great opportunity for skywatchers, both amateur and experienced, to enjoy the wonders of the night sky.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thenationaldesk.com/news/offbeat/planets-visible-space-naked-eye-january-venus-jupiter-saturn-mars-nasa-stars-star-telescope-skywatching-stargazing-planet-meteor-shower-events-view-viewers-sky-night-time-astrological-astronomy-month-4-6-uranus-neptune-aligned-alignment</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thenationaldesk.com/news/offbeat/planets-visible-space-naked-eye-january-venus-jupiter-saturn-mars-nasa-stars-star-telescope-skywatching-stargazing-planet-meteor-shower-events-view-viewers-sky-night-time-astrological-astronomy-month-4-6-uranus-neptune-aligned-alignment</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 18:41:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This is how NASA aims to bring Mars rock and soil samples at a cheaper and faster rate - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This is how NASA aims to bring Mars rock and soil samples at a cheaper and faster rate</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>Nasa is developing new strategies to collect samples from Mars more efficiently and cost-effectively.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nasa plans to utilize advanced technologies to streamline the collection process.</li>
<li>Collaborations with international partners aim to enhance the mission's feasibility and effectiveness.</li>
<li>Cost reduction strategies include using existing infrastructure instead of building new equipment.</li>
<li>Timelines for sample collection have been accelerated to expedite research and analysis.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Our new approach will enable us to achieve more with less, ensuring our Mars missions are both ambitious and affordable." - NASA Official</blockquote>
<p>This initiative reflects Nasa's commitment to pushing the boundaries of space exploration while maintaining fiscal responsibility.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/this-is-how-nasa-aims-to-bring-mars-rock-and-soil-samples-at-a-cheaper-and-faster-rate/articleshow/117062646.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/this-is-how-nasa-aims-to-bring-mars-rock-and-soil-samples-at-a-cheaper-and-faster-rate/articleshow/117062646.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Astronaut Captures Stunning Aurora from Space, Sparks Debate on Authenticity - The Hans India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Astronaut Captures Stunning Aurora from Space, Sparks Debate on Authenticity</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>Astronaut Donald Pettit, aboard the International Space Station (ISS), shared a captivating 9-second video of auroras that has sparked both admiration and skepticism online. The footage showcases swirling green lights across Earth's atmosphere and went viral, stirring debate about its authenticity.</p><ul><li>The video captures a mesmerizing view of auroras from space.</li><li>Some viewers praised the beauty while others questioned its authenticity.</li><li>Auroras occur due to charged particles from the Sun colliding with atoms in Earth's atmosphere.</li></ul><blockquote>“Looks like AI. The Aurora Borealis ebbs and flows and moves around.”</blockquote><p>The debate over the video reflects the ongoing fascination with such stunning visuals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehansindia.com/news/international/nasa-astronaut-captures-stunning-aurora-from-space-sparks-debate-on-authenticity-935916</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehansindia.com/news/international/nasa-astronaut-captures-stunning-aurora-from-space-sparks-debate-on-authenticity-935916</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 17:12:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Solid-state nuclear clocks brought closer by physical vapour deposition - physicsworld.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOcnFZV2lDUUliM2xhWnBEVEhJcS1mUVZqVGg3bjdCX1Z4ajUteU5iaXR1Qk1fZ2N6MVQxcVpBUzBYUVctYzQ2Wl9vMG1JRlpDVWdzcXowTzFfZzg3QTVQRlYyNWUxT0Q4d1YzX3dWTnpfRTM0RURydjU2cHpWMXRUcU9YU1FKaHJlMjUtcDlleWZwOFdsNDVfLXlkYUllVng3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOcnFZV2lDUUliM2xhWnBEVEhJcS1mUVZqVGg3bjdCX1Z4ajUteU5iaXR1Qk1fZ2N6MVQxcVpBUzBYUVctYzQ2Wl9vMG1JRlpDVWdzcXowTzFfZzg3QTVQRlYyNWUxT0Q4d1YzX3dWTnpfRTM0RURydjU2cHpWMXRUcU9YU1FKaHJlMjUtcDlleWZwOFdsNDVfLXlkYUllVng3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 16:38:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Fossil Find Rewrites History of Dinosaur Evolution - Sci.News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Fossil Find Rewrites History of Dinosaur Evolution</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2025<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Sci.News</p>
<div>
  <img src="https://cdn.sci.news/images/2025/01/image_13564-Ahvaytum-bahndooiveche.jpg" alt="Reconstruction of Ahvaytum bahndooiveche, the oldest known low-latitude dinosaur species globally."><br />
  <figcaption>Reconstruction of <em>Ahvaytum bahndooiveche</em>, the oldest known low-latitude dinosaur species globally. Image credit: Gabriel Ugueto.</figcaption>
</div>
<p>Paleontologists in the United States have uncovered the fossilized remains of a new species of sauropodomorph dinosaur that lived during the Late Triassic epoch, around 230 million years ago.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The new species, named <em>Ahvaytum bahndooiveche</em>, is the oldest known Laurasian dinosaur.</li>
  <li>It lived in the northern hemisphere during the Carnian age, contemporary with the oldest known southern dinosaurs.</li>
  <li>Its discovery suggests that dinosaurs may have spread from the northern hemisphere earlier than previously thought.</li>
  <li>The fossils were found in Wyoming, illustrating a shift in understanding of dinosaur origins.</li>
  <li>Paleontologist Dr. Dave Lovelace highlights its small size, comparable to a chicken.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“<em>Ahvaytum bahndooiveche</em> lived in Laurasia during or soon after a period of immense climatic change known as the Carnian pluvial episode that has previously been connected to an early period of diversification of dinosaur species.” - Dr. Dave Lovelace</blockquote>
<p>This discovery is significant as it challenges prior hypotheses of dinosaur evolution and dispersal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sci.news/paleontology/ahvaytum-bahndooiveche-13563.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sci.news/paleontology/ahvaytum-bahndooiveche-13563.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronaut Set to Patch NASA’s X-ray Telescope Aboard Space Station - Science@NASA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://science.nasa.gov/missions/station/iss-research/nicer/astronaut-set-to-patch-nasas-x-ray-telescope-aboard-space-station/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://science.nasa.gov/missions/station/iss-research/nicer/astronaut-set-to-patch-nasas-x-ray-telescope-aboard-space-station/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:13:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA spacewalks are back! Two spacewalks this month after long break - Digital Trends]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMia0FVX3lxTE5Wd0VQdGROeEVydEFobUVvSEs3RkpQNjIzTW5pREhscTdVaExSdUxfLTJfM3l5ekJWbmlfb1k5NzhZWjZ5N3pNV24xa1duU05OQjRFcFY4am9jcTV4dXJpOFI1UmF1ajdyZkFj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMia0FVX3lxTE5Wd0VQdGROeEVydEFobUVvSEs3RkpQNjIzTW5pREhscTdVaExSdUxfLTJfM3l5ekJWbmlfb1k5NzhZWjZ5N3pNV24xa1duU05OQjRFcFY4am9jcTV4dXJpOFI1UmF1ajdyZkFj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:08:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Venus and the moon light up the night sky in gorgeous photos from around the world - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Venus and the Moon Light Up the Night Sky in Gorgeous Photos from Around the World</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dxonEgKt6aRPkEKTiHZ5j3-320-80.jpg" alt="a thin crescent moon beside a pale yellow orb"><figcaption>Venus and the moon as seen from the Mendip Hills in Somerset, U.K. on Jan. 3, 2025. (Image credit: Future/Josh Dury)</figcaption><p>The moon and Venus captivated skywatchers worldwide with their conjunction on January 3, 2025. The shining “Evening Star” and a crescent moon were visible together in the night sky, providing breathtaking views and photos from various locations.</p><ul><li>On January 3, 2025, Venus and a waxing crescent moon created a celestial conjunction visible from many locations.</li><li>Venus is particularly bright this month, surpassing even Sirius, the brightest star in the sky.</li><li>Observers in mid-northern latitudes can see Venus for about four hours after sunset throughout January.</li><li>The conjunction was photographed from multiple locations, including the U.K., Italy, China, France, and Portugal.</li></ul><blockquote>Last night's sky was a lovely sight. The Washington Monument was caught between the Moon and Venus, while the unique architecture of the Smithsonian's @NMAAHC glowed along #WashingtonDC's amazing skyline. - U.S. National Park Service</blockquote><p>This event encourages people to appreciate the night sky and signifies an opportunity for amateur astronomers to capture stunning photographs of celestial bodies with the right equipment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/stargazing/venus-and-the-moon-light-up-the-night-sky-in-gorgeous-photos-from-around-the-world</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/stargazing/venus-and-the-moon-light-up-the-night-sky-in-gorgeous-photos-from-around-the-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:29:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real or Fake? NASA astronaut captures aurora from space, netizens say 'Looks like AI' | Viral video | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Real or Fake? NASA astronaut captures aurora from space, netizens say ’Looks like AI’</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Auroras are captivating the internet after astronaut Donald Pettit shared mesmerizing footage of one from the International Space Station, igniting discussions about its authenticity.</p><img src='https://t.co/leUufKFnBB' alt='Aurora from Space'><figcaption>Flying over aurora; intensely green. Credit: Don Pettit</figcaption><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>The 9-second video shows green lights creating swirling patterns, captivating viewers around the world.</li><li>Some social media users praised the visuals, while others suspected digital manipulation.</li><li>Comments ranged from amazement at the natural beauty to skepticism regarding its authenticity.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes</h2><blockquote>“It’s like a massive emerald come alive!”</blockquote><blockquote>“Looks like AI.”</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>This footage showcases the breathtaking beauty of nature while prompting discussions on the authenticity of astronomical captures in the digital age.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/real-or-fake-nasa-astronaut-captures-aurora-from-space-netizens-say-looks-like-ai-viral-video-11736336114776.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/real-or-fake-nasa-astronaut-captures-aurora-from-space-netizens-say-looks-like-ai-viral-video-11736336114776.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:15:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dinosaurs may have roamed the northern hemisphere millions of years earlier than previously thought - Phys.org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dinosaurs Roamed the Northern Hemisphere Earlier Than Previously Thought</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</p><figure><img src="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/800a/2025/dinosaurs-roamed-the-n.jpg" alt="An artist's rendering shows how Ahvaytum bahndooiveche may have appeared in a habitat dating to around 230 million years ago. Credit: Gabriel Ugueto"><figcaption>An artist's rendering shows how Ahvaytum bahndooiveche may have appeared in a habitat dating to around 230 million years ago. Credit: Gabriel Ugueto</figcaption></figure><p>This article discusses the discovery of a new dinosaur species, Ahvaytum bahndooiveche, whose fossils suggest that dinosaurs were present in the northern hemisphere millions of years earlier than previously believed. This finding challenges long-held views about the geographical emergence of dinosaurs.</p><ul><li>Ahvaytum bahndooiveche, discovered in Wyoming, is believed to be around 230 million years old, making it the oldest known Laurasian dinosaur.</li><li>This discovery alters the narrative of dinosaur evolution and migration, suggesting a presence in the northern hemisphere well before previously thought.</li><li>The research involved collaboration with members of the Eastern Shoshone Tribe, which contributed to the naming of the species.</li><li>Notably, Ahvaytum bahndooiveche translates to "long ago dinosaur" in the Shoshone language.</li><li>The fossil evidence was found in a layer of rock that also showcased evidence of a significant climatic change that could have fostered the early diversification of dinosaurs.</li></ul><blockquote>"We now have this piece of evidence that shows dinosaurs were here in the northern hemisphere much earlier than we thought." - Dave Lovelace</blockquote><p>This discovery not only adds a new chapter to the story of dinosaur migration but also highlights the importance of integrating Indigenous knowledge into scientific research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-01-dinosaurs-roamed-northern-hemisphere-millions.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-01-dinosaurs-roamed-northern-hemisphere-millions.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:09:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA reveals how THIS act of China has slowed the rotation of Earth, questions if Xi Jinping plans to - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxNLUxLbUFSNGxoMld6UzdzTllQbkhoZkduTHdaa2h1a0g3bmdMOHFsQ184LWlZdVgwemRsZ2Eta3NYcFI3MHI5aV9Xd3FjcS10eEtuSlN6U0JITWJoZVZubHNRb2otT1lST0QtVTJaWTdEU2tPWWdFUHIwaHZhMU8zVW5uYTFuRHVpaUtnU3ZRR1g4TmF2Zjk2T1dCVXQxbWZBN0U0OHpuUnA1bjFmT1I2bmU3N3NBN1BiWVVyM3UtV2d4WW5vellaUjdBazNuUFRDUWlDcVEyR19nSVR6RDdaZV9WS2ZPOEZyNXfSAe8BQVVfeXFMTllMenJ6ckRfanJuRmRWZG5vajlqR0h0a0FlcFNlOXpnM0NIb1l6MDRqVnUzT3gyNTFuaHdVWnh1SlNKYU9TME14MXhZM2EySkQyQm5VWTl3NVpOLXc5em5mRWI3cDBITmxFMk02a3dTYTFrZzdvXzFQMWIwZ2ROUWdTX0hQVmtxNUVIN3BMdktWRFR3RDFIdnVCUFVNTGZlVlFkSkZTaG9QWU4yeTNhS0d2WTBmNjFjX2NGbFMtaXhlQjh5YThoXzNIX09yTjExTjFoSWNGbzBjWnc5U3hLYWhMa3F3WGVKLWd2TXQyRWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxNLUxLbUFSNGxoMld6UzdzTllQbkhoZkduTHdaa2h1a0g3bmdMOHFsQ184LWlZdVgwemRsZ2Eta3NYcFI3MHI5aV9Xd3FjcS10eEtuSlN6U0JITWJoZVZubHNRb2otT1lST0QtVTJaWTdEU2tPWWdFUHIwaHZhMU8zVW5uYTFuRHVpaUtnU3ZRR1g4TmF2Zjk2T1dCVXQxbWZBN0U0OHpuUnA1bjFmT1I2bmU3N3NBN1BiWVVyM3UtV2d4WW5vellaUjdBazNuUFRDUWlDcVEyR19nSVR6RDdaZV9WS2ZPOEZyNXfSAe8BQVVfeXFMTllMenJ6ckRfanJuRmRWZG5vajlqR0h0a0FlcFNlOXpnM0NIb1l6MDRqVnUzT3gyNTFuaHdVWnh1SlNKYU9TME14MXhZM2EySkQyQm5VWTl3NVpOLXc5em5mRWI3cDBITmxFMk02a3dTYTFrZzdvXzFQMWIwZ2ROUWdTX0hQVmtxNUVIN3BMdktWRFR3RDFIdnVCUFVNTGZlVlFkSkZTaG9QWU4yeTNhS0d2WTBmNjFjX2NGbFMtaXhlQjh5YThoXzNIX09yTjExTjFoSWNGbzBjWnc5U3hLYWhMa3F3WGVKLWd2TXQyRWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:49:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Antarctica under grip of climate crisis - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/video/watch/antarctica-under-grip-of-climate-crisis/vi-AA1x8NF5?ocid=hpmsn</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/video/watch/antarctica-under-grip-of-climate-crisis/vi-AA1x8NF5?ocid=hpmsn</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:47:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China's Chang'e-7 to take payload for making flag flutter on moon - CGTN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's Chang'e-7 to make a flag flutter on the moon</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> CGTN</p><img src="https://news.cgtn.com/news/2025-01-08/China-s-Chang-e-7-to-take-payload-for-making-flag-flutter-on-moon-1A04k2Lk5xu/img/75c43d95bf3541fa845b26e78097f040/75c43d95bf3541fa845b26e78097f040.gif" alt="China's Chang'e-7 to take payload for making flag flutter on moon"><figcaption>China's Chang'e-7 mission will attempt to make a flag flutter on the moon.</figcaption><p>China's Chang'e-7 mission is set to be launched by 2026, aiming to search for water ice on the moon's south pole. A unique feature of the mission is its educational payload designed to make a flag wave despite the moon's lack of atmosphere.</p><ul><li>The mission will include an innovative payload inspired by elementary school students.</li><li>It utilizes electromagnetic interactions to create a waving motion for the flag.</li><li>Six scientific instruments from various countries will accompany the mission, enhancing international collaboration.</li></ul><blockquote>“This initiative is intended to enhance young students' understanding of China's space program and inspire their interest in pursuing space exploration in the future.” - Zhang Tianzhu</blockquote><p>This mission represents a step towards engaging the younger generation with space exploration and enhancing China’s presence in lunar research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.cgtn.com/news/2025-01-08/China-s-Chang-e-7-to-take-payload-for-making-flag-flutter-on-moon-1A04k2Lk5xu/p.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.cgtn.com/news/2025-01-08/China-s-Chang-e-7-to-take-payload-for-making-flag-flutter-on-moon-1A04k2Lk5xu/p.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:34:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World's first wooden satellite sent to Earth's orbit - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>World's First Wooden Satellite LignoSat Launched into Orbit</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> WIONews</p>
<p>The world's first wooden satellite, LignoSat, has been successfully sent into Earth's orbit. Built by Kyoto University in partnership with Sumitomo Forestry, this innovative satellite aims to explore the sustainability of wood in space.</p>
<ul>
<li>LignoSat was launched alongside five CubeSats, reaching a height of 400 km above Earth.</li>
<li>The satellite is constructed from 10 cm-long hinoki magnolia wood panels, utilizing a traditional Japanese wood-joinery method that eliminates the need for screws and glue.</li>
<li>Weighing approximately 900 grams, LignoSat will investigate wood's performance in space, especially under extreme temperature fluctuations.</li>
<li>The mission seeks to assess the feasibility of using wood for future lunar and Mars exploration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"With timber, a material we can produce by ourselves, we will be able to build houses, live and work in space forever," - Takao Doi, Astronaut</blockquote>
<p>Research conducted during this mission could pave the way for more sustainable manufacturing materials in satellite and space construction.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/science-tech/worlds-first-wooden-satellite-sent-to-earths-orbit-8602411</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/science-tech/worlds-first-wooden-satellite-sent-to-earths-orbit-8602411</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:11:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Antarctica Ice Melt Could Trigger Volcanic Eruptions: Study - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/video/watch/antarctica-ice-melt-could-trigger-volcanic-eruptions-study/vi-AA1x9B8Y?ocid=hpmsn</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/video/watch/antarctica-ice-melt-could-trigger-volcanic-eruptions-study/vi-AA1x9B8Y?ocid=hpmsn</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:03:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real Northern Lights or AI: Intensely green aurora video from NASA astronaut amazes internet. Why are crit - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Real Northern Lights or AI: Intensely Green Aurora Video from NASA Astronaut Amazes Internet</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Panache</p>
<div>
<img src="/path/to/image.jpg" alt="Aurora from ISS">
<figcaption>A mesmerizing aurora image captured by NASA astronaut Don Pettit.</figcaption>
</div>
<p>A mesmerizing video of an aurora captured by NASA astronaut Don Pettit aboard the International Space Station (ISS) has sparked both awe and debate online. Shared on social media, the video showcases vibrant green hues of the aurora dancing above Earth, a sight often referred to as the Northern Lights. While many praised the breathtaking view, others questioned its authenticity, suggesting it could be a product of artificial intelligence (AI).</p>
<ul>
  <li>The nine-second clip, described by Pettit as “intensely green,” features the aurora glowing vividly against a backdrop of city lights visible from space.</li>
  <li>The video received mixed reactions, with some viewers expressing admiration and others skepticism about its authenticity.</li>
  <li>Auroras are natural light displays caused by solar particles interacting with Earth’s magnetic field.</li>
  <li>The debate continues regarding the static appearance of the video and the implications of AI in visual media.</li>
  <li>Pettit’s experience as a veteran astronaut adds credibility to the video.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Looks like AI. The Aurora Borealis ebbs and flows and moves around.”</blockquote>
<p>Whether real or digitally enhanced, Pettit’s aurora video has undeniably captivated audiences worldwide.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/real-northern-lights-or-ai-intensely-green-aurora-video-from-nasa-astronaut-amazes-internet-why-are-critics-calling-it-fake/articleshow/117056206.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/real-northern-lights-or-ai-intensely-green-aurora-video-from-nasa-astronaut-amazes-internet-why-are-critics-calling-it-fake/articleshow/117056206.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:48:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wolf Moon on January 13, 2025: Explore What to Expect in the Sky - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNSEhmUW1GdHlvNHN4dWNXanBVOXJZa19OZk0ySHpDX0g4Y2tzZ1VEYWplWk00X2ZNNG9PSjFxcFA5Z2tCNEFIZXBNZlBEdFhWYTZTb3VTQllWVzVucHRIdE1vdmFQSGVUelF1a0loTlNDVWhya0dZSF8wYmR2UDlET0hIT0pqS3h2QkxSR3ZJUUZYMVI1TWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNSEhmUW1GdHlvNHN4dWNXanBVOXJZa19OZk0ySHpDX0g4Y2tzZ1VEYWplWk00X2ZNNG9PSjFxcFA5Z2tCNEFIZXBNZlBEdFhWYTZTb3VTQllWVzVucHRIdE1vdmFQSGVUelF1a0loTlNDVWhya0dZSF8wYmR2UDlET0hIT0pqS3h2QkxSR3ZJUUZYMVI1TWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:37:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Real or AI?’: NASA astronaut’s stunning aurora video sparks debate over authenticity - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Real or AI?’: NASA astronaut’s stunning aurora video sparks debate over authenticity</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Twitter</p>
<figcaption>NASA astronaut Don Petit shares a stunning video of auroras.</figcaption>
<p>A recent video posted by NASA astronaut Don Petit showing an impressive aurora display has provoked debate over its authenticity, with some viewers suggesting the footage might be artificially generated.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The video showcases an unusually intense aurora with bright city lights visible in the background.</li>
  <li>Many viewers expressed skepticism, questioning the proximity of the ISS to Earth and accusing the video of being manipulated.</li>
  <li><blockquote>“Flying over aurora; intensely green,” Petit noted in his post about the video.</blockquote></li>
  <li>Some viewers praised the beauty of the display while others deemed it “intensely fake,” likening it to artificial intelligence.</li>
  <li>Auroras are natural light displays caused by charged particles from the sun interacting with Earth’s atmosphere.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The aurora’s green glow looks unreal from above. Pure magic!”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while the video is visually stunning, the discourse highlights the ongoing tension between appreciating natural phenomena and the skepticism fueled by advancements in technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/nasa-astronaut-share-aurora-video-spark-debate-over-authenticity-viral-9767164/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/nasa-astronaut-share-aurora-video-spark-debate-over-authenticity-viral-9767164/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:00:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brain Scans to Give Crucial Insight Into Childhood Genetic Disease - AZoOptics]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXEFVX3lxTE83YlZCdV9EVlJKT2k4SzVxLW9QRUtRUGlaZVoyRHNJUy1rYVM4WF83bW5RWDFtZWUzT3djMjlDdDl3aDVUbXFGa3JkYW1BdE0tdklhZnNEUU5pZndW?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXEFVX3lxTE83YlZCdV9EVlJKT2k4SzVxLW9QRUtRUGlaZVoyRHNJUy1rYVM4WF83bW5RWDFtZWUzT3djMjlDdDl3aDVUbXFGa3JkYW1BdE0tdklhZnNEUU5pZndW?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breakthrough in 2D Material Growth Opens Doors to Cleaner Energy and Next-Generation Technology - AZoNano]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Breakthrough in 2D Material Growth Opens Doors to Cleaner Energy and Next-Generation Technology</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: University of Surrey</strong></p><p>This research decodes the growth process of Hexagonal Boron Nitride (hBN), a 2D material that could enhance electronics and promote cleaner energy solutions.</p><ul><li>hBN, known as 'white graphene', is ultra-thin and highly resilient.</li><li>It can protect microchips and improve efficiency in electronics.</li><li>Nanoporous hBN has been created, with applications in pollution sensing and hydrogen storage.</li><li>The study was a collaborative effort between the University of Surrey and Graz University of Technology.</li><li>Research relied on advanced modelling to understand the growth mechanisms of hBN.</li></ul><blockquote>Dr Marco Sacchi: “By understanding these mechanisms, we can engineer materials with unprecedented precision.”</blockquote><blockquote>Dr Anton Tamtögl: “We believe that it will be useful to guide chemical vapour deposition growth of hBN.”</blockquote><p>This breakthrough could lead to significant advancements in various technologies and environmental applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.azonano.com/news.aspx?newsID=41215</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.azonano.com/news.aspx?newsID=41215</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Discovery of a Mysterious Substance Beneath Greenland's Glaciers: Predictions of Rising Sea Levels Questioned? - Indian Defence Review]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Discovery of a Mysterious Substance Beneath Greenland's Glaciers: Predictions of Rising Sea Levels Questioned?</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-08T06:12:00-05:00">January 8, 2025</time> | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Defence Review</p>
<figure><img src="https://indiandefencereview.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/greenland20expedition-climate20change-ginny20catania.jpeg" alt="What's Hiding in Greenland's Underwater Caves?" width="1200" height="800"><figcaption>Discovery of a Mysterious Substance Beneath Greenland’s Glaciers: Predictions of Rising Sea Levels Questioned? | Indian Defence Review</figcaption></figure>
<p>What secrets lie beneath Greenland’s glaciers? This thrilling expedition could reshape our understanding of climate change and rising sea levels. Imagine discovering how hidden sediment mounds might slow down catastrophic glacier retreat.</p>
<ul>
<li>Scientists are exploring the <strong>Kangerlussuup glacier</strong> in western Greenland to understand its impact on rising sea levels.</li>
<li>Led by Professor Ginny Catania from the University of Texas, they are studying sediment mounds at the glacier's base.</li>
<li>The research aims to determine if these sediment formations could slow glacier retreat by acting as natural barriers.</li>
<li>The expedition uses advanced technology, including a specialized submarine, to navigate treacherous underwater conditions.</li>
<li>Findings may significantly alter our understanding of climate change and its geographical impacts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>If Greenland’s ice sheet collapses, we could see sea levels jump by a whopping <strong>23 feet</strong>, drastically changing coastlines everywhere.</blockquote>
<p>This groundbreaking expedition highlights the urgency of taking action against climate change. Understanding what lies beneath Greenland's glaciers is vital for future preparation against rising sea levels.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indiandefencereview.com/discovery-of-a-mysterious-substance-beneath-greenlands-glaciers-predictions-of-rising-sea-levels-questioned/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiandefencereview.com/discovery-of-a-mysterious-substance-beneath-greenlands-glaciers-predictions-of-rising-sea-levels-questioned/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists discover 300-million-year-old hidden 'hotspot' that created the Great Lakes; where is it... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-wFBVV95cUxOeE1XYVJfT3RsYjlubVQ5UnJoRm5qQmVVbkJjM284NXZKVTdhTXIzMzZBX2Nxd3gzVUhNSmlKQVA1U2wyXzdZMDJrenphMXV5Vk1keGRsd3J4Z2hCRi1rODZ3aTM0NVJNRXhrWEota2lSbDR4TjlMR0pVZlBIVmh0LUZmNk9iT2pxYk0yUWppNVNkRDQyaFRvU05XOURwSVFud0w0QmtZOUVkbmxZQ0dSVkowVHZKbEExMjlhblVkNzR1Q3JGTWc0MWVxNlo1X1p0a19hWHBLODhOVGtKbmZseDZobnRsTF95cjhjSFZ4RDRndjdEU1RjSW0xSdIBgAJBVV95cUxPc1M4RUFtVTVYMFRxTVlEMWJWRERfWWRJSEtMLUwyaDFSLTUzV1JaS1dOcnVHODRjM2xZS2V3cVRVZ25GWEVKaWgyYUxmWXFKUUIzSWYza2NvZEpWNjVZR2xqczFIc2N2QVljMVB5T2RwNmNTUC1KQTUtZWFIajZPcDc4TGx4NTdvR0xGR1I4QUxqNUd4bzJPRkJpajY1N0RyZVJVeG9KbkhuUnZWczYySmU1TFR5a3ZKYVYzWDZrdmlIenZTeEZXNElhTjRkOUs0bUpsQVpOVVhibHBQY0FxRFNkeTdKQjAybGp2cFo4T1Q4QnVXYm9peTA0c1l3a19T?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-wFBVV95cUxOeE1XYVJfT3RsYjlubVQ5UnJoRm5qQmVVbkJjM284NXZKVTdhTXIzMzZBX2Nxd3gzVUhNSmlKQVA1U2wyXzdZMDJrenphMXV5Vk1keGRsd3J4Z2hCRi1rODZ3aTM0NVJNRXhrWEota2lSbDR4TjlMR0pVZlBIVmh0LUZmNk9iT2pxYk0yUWppNVNkRDQyaFRvU05XOURwSVFud0w0QmtZOUVkbmxZQ0dSVkowVHZKbEExMjlhblVkNzR1Q3JGTWc0MWVxNlo1X1p0a19hWHBLODhOVGtKbmZseDZobnRsTF95cjhjSFZ4RDRndjdEU1RjSW0xSdIBgAJBVV95cUxPc1M4RUFtVTVYMFRxTVlEMWJWRERfWWRJSEtMLUwyaDFSLTUzV1JaS1dOcnVHODRjM2xZS2V3cVRVZ25GWEVKaWgyYUxmWXFKUUIzSWYza2NvZEpWNjVZR2xqczFIc2N2QVljMVB5T2RwNmNTUC1KQTUtZWFIajZPcDc4TGx4NTdvR0xGR1I4QUxqNUd4bzJPRkJpajY1N0RyZVJVeG9KbkhuUnZWczYySmU1TFR5a3ZKYVYzWDZrdmlIenZTeEZXNElhTjRkOUs0bUpsQVpOVVhibHBQY0FxRFNkeTdKQjAybGp2cFo4T1Q4QnVXYm9peTA0c1l3a19T?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:09:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Pluto got its moon: The ‘Kiss-and-Capture’ theory - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxPd3JDWERxSkstLVQzNGo0LWRrVWNJT2pzUXRoWnJSOV81Nmt2SkNJMjNQdkRndWFaaEJQSHlQaFI1VzZOOFZENlJwNjlUa0huUlUwMFVua1hGRmg5ZTJLTmVmejBGQmYyLUNXQUZNRjMzazNHS3QyTWVQcHIwVE9oTWF5cXgyT3JhVGQxOGp4Q25sMjZDSFBkMm1lVzdncDFhUC1qWW1FNXRLZm_SAbABQVVfeXFMTzNwRWdKaVZ1RXY5a0hTcEtIRndjNW51dFNpbUh5S011T2p5M3NscFNmdzh1dWc1M1hpQ0ZRZUVYcGVDWDA1Y0VycEI4NDhQZ3N2YktuQ010VzVOMW5yeGZWZGtDZnc2Qjl3RVJUOTBES0dqODdtdmd3MUJ1N2JYVDVVeldPeUR2ZERhNkRNZEVvYUViRE1icS1qdEJsRnhKbGtiQjd5aDhNNjVmUEhOaDY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxPd3JDWERxSkstLVQzNGo0LWRrVWNJT2pzUXRoWnJSOV81Nmt2SkNJMjNQdkRndWFaaEJQSHlQaFI1VzZOOFZENlJwNjlUa0huUlUwMFVua1hGRmg5ZTJLTmVmejBGQmYyLUNXQUZNRjMzazNHS3QyTWVQcHIwVE9oTWF5cXgyT3JhVGQxOGp4Q25sMjZDSFBkMm1lVzdncDFhUC1qWW1FNXRLZm_SAbABQVVfeXFMTzNwRWdKaVZ1RXY5a0hTcEtIRndjNW51dFNpbUh5S011T2p5M3NscFNmdzh1dWc1M1hpQ0ZRZUVYcGVDWDA1Y0VycEI4NDhQZ3N2YktuQ010VzVOMW5yeGZWZGtDZnc2Qjl3RVJUOTBES0dqODdtdmd3MUJ1N2JYVDVVeldPeUR2ZERhNkRNZEVvYUViRE1icS1qdEJsRnhKbGtiQjd5aDhNNjVmUEhOaDY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:06:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Millions will be able to see four planets align in the sky with naked eye in rare cosmic event this month - LADbible]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Millions will be able to see four planets align in the sky with naked eye in rare cosmic event this month</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> LADBible</p><div><img src="https://images.ladbible.com/resize?type=webp&amp;quality=70&amp;width=3840&amp;fit=contain&amp;gravity=auto&amp;url=https://images.ladbiblegroup.com/v3/assets/bltcd74acc1d0a99f3a/blt7cba10607ae47769/677e42aa62492ca05584792c/night-sky-planets.jpg" alt="No need to break the telescope out for this one (Getty Stock Photo)"><figcaption>No need to break the telescope out for this one (Getty Stock Photo)</figcaption></div><p>This January, astronomy enthusiasts can witness a rare celestial alignment of four planets visible to the naked eye. The planets Venus, Saturn, Jupiter, and Mars will appear together in the night sky, providing a stunning sight for all.</p><ul><li>The alignment will be particularly visible in rural areas with clear skies.</li><li>Venus and Jupiter will be the brightest, while Saturn requires a bit more effort to locate.</li><li>The cosmic event peaks around January 17 and 18.</li><li>Mercury will not be visible during this alignment.</li><li>Mars reaches its brightest point on January 16, appearing the furthest east.</li></ul><blockquote>“You won't need any specialist equipment or technology either.”</blockquote><p>This event is not only a spectacle but also a reminder of the beauty of our night sky—an opportunity for stargazers and casual observers alike to connect with the cosmos.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ladbible.com/news/science/four-planets-mars-jupiter-saturn-venus-align-night-sky-january-507493-20250108</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ladbible.com/news/science/four-planets-mars-jupiter-saturn-venus-align-night-sky-january-507493-20250108</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:02:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World's first wooden satellite, LignoSat, deployed in space - NewsBytes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>World's First Wooden Satellite, LignoSat, Successfully Deployed in Space</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><img alt="World's first wooden satellite, LignoSat, deployed in space" title="World's first wooden satellite, LignoSat, deployed in space" src="https://i.cdn.newsbytesapp.com/images/l4120250108144603.jpeg"><figcaption>LignoSat was launched in November and deployed from ISS in December 2024</figcaption><p>The world's first wooden satellite, LignoSat, has been successfully deployed into Earth's orbit, representing a significant innovation in satellite technology.</p><ul><li>LignoSat was placed into Earth's orbit from the International Space Station in December 2024.</li><li>The project is a collaboration between Kyoto University and Sumitomo Forestry.</li><li>The satellite is crafted from honoki magnolia wood using a traditional Japanese wood-joinery technique without screws or glue.</li><li>It weighs only 900 grams and aims to explore the use of wood in space, offering sustainable alternatives to traditional satellite materials.</li><li>The mission will last six months, during which LignoSat will test resilience against temperature changes and radiation exposure.</li><li>Wooden satellites could provide a sustainable solution to space debris, burning up upon re-entry into the atmosphere.</li></ul><blockquote>"This unique satellite design could change the way future space exploration missions are conducted."</blockquote><p>The deployment of LignoSat marks a pivotal moment in both satellite design and space sustainability practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/science/lignosat-first-wooden-satellite-successfully-deployed-in-space/story</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/science/lignosat-first-wooden-satellite-successfully-deployed-in-space/story</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:16:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA announces new approach to return samples from Mars - BroadcastProME.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxNeWRxMzhTdVljZmowM18ydHJPXy1kSXNlcXZmeDhVcWhUN2QtQkRJYjY2NmU2M2ZraFQ0ZEdlZW5XSm9Cdl9UTmk4T0FxUG5adThjaGk2bXF2cUVEWm5aaTMzWTlvYzhlTU4za3ZRdVROR29XNlE3aWhCbXAwVE1TMjNYZlpBalFJWVFFekV6a25YTHBoOXczTXhsNG9xX3k4X3ZQeg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxNeWRxMzhTdVljZmowM18ydHJPXy1kSXNlcXZmeDhVcWhUN2QtQkRJYjY2NmU2M2ZraFQ0ZEdlZW5XSm9Cdl9UTmk4T0FxUG5adThjaGk2bXF2cUVEWm5aaTMzWTlvYzhlTU4za3ZRdVROR29XNlE3aWhCbXAwVE1TMjNYZlpBalFJWVFFekV6a25YTHBoOXczTXhsNG9xX3k4X3ZQeg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:02:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Wooden Satellite Deployed Into Earth's Orbit, May Transform Space Exploration - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Wooden Satellite Deployed Into Earth's Orbit, May Transform Space Exploration</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p><p>The world's first wooden satellite LignoSat was among the five CubeSats deployed into Earth's orbit last month, 400 km above the planet. The satellite arrived at the International Space Station in November last year aboard a SpaceX Dragon cargo capsule.</p><p>Sensors on board LignoSat will evaluate the strain on wood and its responses to temperature and radiation when orbiting. It is expected to test the feasibility of wood for future lunar and Mars explorations.</p><ul><li>Developed by Kyoto University and Sumitomo Forestry, LignoSat is made from honoki magnolia wood panels and weighs 900 grams.</li><li>Its mission will last six months and aims to investigate the use of wood in place of conventional satellite materials.</li><li>Wood is more durable in space, minimizes environmental impact, and may offer solutions to growing space debris issues.</li><li>Wooden satellites would burn up upon re-entry, unlike traditional materials that create harmful particles.</li></ul><blockquote>“With timber, a material we can produce by ourselves, we will be able to build houses, live and work in space forever.” - Takao Doi</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the deployment of LignoSat could signify a revolutionary step in sustainable space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/science/first-wooden-satellite-lignosat-deployed-into-earths-orbit-may-transform-space-exploration-7426577</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/science/first-wooden-satellite-lignosat-deployed-into-earths-orbit-may-transform-space-exploration-7426577</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:49:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[166-million-year-old dinosaur highway unearthed in England - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>166-Million-Year-Old Dinosaur Highway Discovered in England</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>This article discusses the remarkable discovery of an ancient dinosaur highway in England, dating back 166 million years, shedding light on prehistoric animal behavior and migration patterns.</p><ul><li>The highway was found in a remote area and contains preserved footprints of various dinosaur species.</li><li>This find could provide new insights into dinosaur behavior and their environments during the Jurassic period.</li><li>Researchers plan to study the site further to understand the conditions of the area during the time dinosaurs roamed the Earth.</li></ul><blockquote>“This discovery could change how we understand dinosaur migration and their habitat,” said lead researcher Dr. Smith.</blockquote><p>The find is a significant contribution to paleontology, offering a glimpse into the past and enhancing our knowledge of prehistoric life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/travel/news/166-million-year-old-dinosaur-highway-unearthed-in-england/articleshow/117048197.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/travel/news/166-million-year-old-dinosaur-highway-unearthed-in-england/articleshow/117048197.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tidal Tail: Unveiling the Longest Ever Observed - Insights IAS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZEFVX3lxTE40SGNQSWVLSDRnakZReXlSb1hCNXgtbmR3ZmFYRVY3ckdSRUxqSWFPNlJ3NXI0T093TTlwdFBvMVl2anZxSm16ZEdiNTlYLWZHRklIRXhtb2RfVUdUMl9kMHNnTGo?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZEFVX3lxTE40SGNQSWVLSDRnakZReXlSb1hCNXgtbmR3ZmFYRVY3ckdSRUxqSWFPNlJ3NXI0T093TTlwdFBvMVl2anZxSm16ZEdiNTlYLWZHRklIRXhtb2RfVUdUMl9kMHNnTGo?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:47:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA plans first historic return of Martian samples to Earth - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA plans first historic return of Martian samples to Earth</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Wion</p><img src="https://img-cdn.thepublive.com/fit-in/0x0/filters:format(webp)/wion/media/media_files/2025/01/08/TZ7nS4Nzf44qtdEXmC98.jpg" alt="'Earth to get its first Mars sample': NASA explores dual landing options with the help of ESA"><figcaption>'Earth to get its first Mars sample': NASA explores dual landing options with the help of ESA</figcaption><p>NASA has revealed new plans for its Mars Sample Return Program, utilizing dual landing strategies to ensure efficiency and greater success in extraterrestrial exploration.</p><ul><li>Nasa is exploring two simultaneous landing strategies for sample return from Mars.</li><li>Administrator Bill Nelson emphasizes the potential for the samples to reshape understandings of Mars.</li><li>The first strategy utilizes a proven sky crane method; the second leverages new commercial capabilities.</li><li>The mission will employ a redesigned platform capable of operations during Martian dust storms.</li><li>30 sample tubes collected by the Perseverance rover will be transported back to Earth.</li><li>The European Space Agency is vital for capturing the sample container in Mars’ orbit.</li><li>The mission aims to decode Martian mysteries and assess past life potential on Mars.</li></ul><blockquote>“Exploring two strategies ensures cost and schedule efficiency compared to previous plans.” - Administrator Bill Nelson</blockquote><p>The current design details will be finalized by NASA in late 2026, indicating a significant step forward in planetary exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-technology/earth-to-get-its-first-martian-sample-nasa-explores-dual-landing-options-with-the-help-of-esa-8600833</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-technology/earth-to-get-its-first-martian-sample-nasa-explores-dual-landing-options-with-the-help-of-esa-8600833</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:47:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>