<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:14:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:14:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Stunning Pictures Of Interacting Galaxies Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Stunning Pictures Of Interacting Galaxies Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116332764/116332764.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=1200404" alt="7 Stunning Pictures Of Interacting Galaxies Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope">
<figcaption>Credit: NASA-ESA-the-Hubble-Heritage-Team-STScI/AURA-ESA/Hubble-Collaboration</figcaption>
<p>NASA’s Hubble Space Telescope has captured breathtaking images of interacting galaxies, showcasing the beauty and complexity of these cosmic structures.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The article features seven remarkable images, each highlighting different interactions between galaxies.</li>
    <li>Images include Arp 148, Two Spiral Galaxies, and Portrait of Stephan’s Quintet, among others.</li>
    <li>Each image is accompanied by descriptions detailing the unique characteristics and phenomena observed in these galaxy interactions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Today, we understand that galaxy mergers significantly influence galaxy evolution, particularly the formation of elliptical galaxies."</blockquote>
<p>These stunning visuals not only enhance our understanding of the universe but also inspire awe at the vastness and beauty of space.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-stunning-pictures-of-interacting-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-hubblespacetelescope/photostory/116332737.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-stunning-pictures-of-interacting-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-hubblespacetelescope/photostory/116332737.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:11:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 colourful photos of universe captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-colourful-photos-of-universe-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7466565/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/7-colourful-photos-of-universe-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7466565/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:39:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Discover Alien-Like Predator 'Darkness' In Ocean - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Discover Alien-Like Predator 'Darkness' In Ocean</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024, 15:30 IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The new species is named Dulcibella camanchaca. (Representative Image)" />
<figcaption>The new species is named Dulcibella camanchaca. (Representative Image)</figcaption>
<p>Scientists have discovered a new amphipod named Dulcibella camanchaca in the Atacama Trench, a deep-sea area near South America, during a 2023 expedition.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Atacama Trench is about 7,902 metres (25,928 feet) deep.</li>
    <li>This species exhibits alien-like features and is associated with the term "camanchaca," meaning "darkness."</li>
    <li>Four specimens were identified and found to be genetically distinct from other amphipods.</li>
    <li>Dulcibella camanchaca measures approximately 4 cm (1.5 inches) and is characterized by its white translucent color.</li>
    <li>The species is a top predator in its extreme deep-sea ecosystem, scavenging smaller amphipods with specialized hunting appendages called gnathopods.</li>
    <li>This finding enhances understanding of biodiversity in the largely unexplored hadal zone.</li>
    <li>Studying this amphipod may provide insights into the potential for life on other planets, especially in water bodies on moons of Jupiter and Saturn.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This discovery is expected to offer insights into its evolutionary adaptations to the harsh conditions of its deep-sea habitat."</blockquote>
<p>This discovery of Dulcibella camanchaca highlights the ecological significance of the Atacama Trench and contributes to our understanding of deep-sea life and extraterrestrial possibilities. </p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/scientists-discover-alien-like-predator-darkness-in-ocean-aa-9156418.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/scientists-discover-alien-like-predator-darkness-in-ocean-aa-9156418.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:30:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Warns Of Two BIG Asteroids Making Close Approach To Earth Tomorrow: Should You Worry? - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Warns Of Two BIG Asteroids Making Close Approach To Earth Tomorrow: Should You Worry?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times Now News</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116331284,thumbsize-1191763,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116331284.jpg" alt="Asteroid (AI-Generated Image)" title="Asteroid (AI-Generated Image)">
<figcaption>Asteroid (AI-Generated Image)</figcaption>
<p>Two asteroids, 2024 XY5 and 2024 XB6, are set to pass close to Earth on December 16, 2024, prompting interest from astronomers. Although they do not pose any immediate threat, their approach emphasizes NASA's monitoring efforts of near-Earth objects.</p>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Asteroid 2024 XY5:</strong> 71 feet in diameter, will pass at a distance of 3,500,000 kilometers at 5:56 AM IST traveling at 17,389 km/h.</li>
    <li><strong>Asteroid 2024 XB6:</strong> 56 feet in diameter, will approach at 6,690,000 kilometers at 7:25 AM IST traveling at 23,787 km/h.</li>
    <li>Both asteroids do not pose a risk as they are smaller than the threshold for "potentially hazardous asteroids."</li>
    <li>Nasa actively tracks near-Earth objects to ensure safety against potential threats.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Despite their size and speed, NASA has confirmed that both asteroids will safely pass Earth without posing any risk.”</blockquote>
<p>Stay informed and vigilant about the risks posed by space debris, even if these asteroids are harmless. NASA's continued monitoring is essential for ensuring our planet's safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/nasa-warns-of-two-big-asteroids-making-close-approach-to-earth-tomorrow-should-you-worry-article-116331233</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/nasa-warns-of-two-big-asteroids-making-close-approach-to-earth-tomorrow-should-you-worry-article-116331233</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:12:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Discover Alien-Like Predator In Ocean's Depth, Call It 'Darkness' - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxPWUhocFpVaEdUWGFVbFFHai0wMGhaYlhTbjR6SHJKeXJDMDdnNGY4SlM1aTg3Z3RKd2ZHUXRTdmFVblJ3WVY0ZWNuaVppa1dDZklVZzlOSmN1bGF0OUNrYXI1VUZiZmd1Ty0xRmlQNnlqTUhhUlVhRFlaSFd1aDFHNjNpN2tEd2JqREpqVFctVXJiWDFDQ0ZQd2xFUVdIbjRaWG5XSnNxVkY4VXJYTXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxPWUhocFpVaEdUWGFVbFFHai0wMGhaYlhTbjR6SHJKeXJDMDdnNGY4SlM1aTg3Z3RKd2ZHUXRTdmFVblJ3WVY0ZWNuaVppa1dDZklVZzlOSmN1bGF0OUNrYXI1VUZiZmd1Ty0xRmlQNnlqTUhhUlVhRFlaSFd1aDFHNjNpN2tEd2JqREpqVFctVXJiWDFDQ0ZQd2xFUVdIbjRaWG5XSnNxVkY4VXJYTXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 03:24:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Perseverance Rover Reaches the Top Rim of the Jezero Crater - Universe Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Perseverance Rover Reaches the Top Rim of the Jezero Crater</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 12, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Universe Today</p>
<div>
    <figure>
        <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="843" src="https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pia26374-1024x843.jpg" alt="Route of the Perseverance Rover" srcset="https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pia26374-1024x843.jpg 1024w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pia26374-580x477.jpg 580w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pia26374-250x206.jpg 250w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pia26374-768x632.jpg 768w, https://www.universetoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pia26374.jpg 1129w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px">
        <figcaption><em>The route NASA’s Perseverance Mars rover took (in blue) as it climbed the western rim of Jezero Crater. Credit: NASA/JPL-Caltech/University of Arizona</em></figcaption>
    </figure>
</div>
<p>NASA’s Perseverance rover has successfully reached the top of Jezero Crater's rim, marking a significant milestone in its mission to explore the ancient Martian landscape.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The rover climbed 500 vertical meters over three and a half months to reach "Lookout Hill".</li>
    <li>Perseverance will now begin its "Northern Rim" campaign, aiming to explore geological samples over the next year.</li>
    <li>Four previous science campaigns have been completed since its landing in February 2021.</li>
    <li>The rover's current mission involves investigating new geological features and ancient environments.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p><em>“The Northern Rim campaign brings us completely new scientific riches as Perseverance roves into fundamentally new geology..." - Ken Farley, Project Scientist</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>As Perseverance begins to explore areas less affected by ancient impacts, it remains focused on finding biosignatures from Mars' wetter past, contributing to our understanding of the planet’s history and potential for life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.universetoday.com/170103/nasas-perseverance-rover-reaches-the-top-rim-of-the-jezero-crater/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.universetoday.com/170103/nasas-perseverance-rover-reaches-the-top-rim-of-the-jezero-crater/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:36:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five stunning images of Nebula captured by NASA Hubble Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Five stunning images of Nebula captured by NASA Hubble Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/prawn-nebula-HEADLINES.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=400&amp;h=800" alt="Prawn Nebula" />
<figcaption>Prawn Nebula captured by the Hubble Space Telescope.</figcaption>
<p>The article showcases five breathtaking images of different nebulae captured by NASA's Hubble Space Telescope, along with brief descriptions of each nebula's characteristics and significance.</p>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Abell 78:</strong> A unique planetary nebula formed from a star that exhausted its nuclear fuel, collapsing into a white dwarf.</li>
    <li><strong>Snowman Nebula:</strong> An emission nebula located 6,000 light-years away in the constellation Puppis.</li>
    <li><strong>Nebula With Superbubble:</strong> Known as N44, it contains glowing hydrogen gas and massive stars.</li>
    <li><strong>Prawn Nebula:</strong> A massive stellar nursery located in Scorpius, approximately 6,000 light-years from Earth.</li>
    <li><strong>Necklace Nebula:</strong> A planetary nebula formed from the remains of a Sun-like star, glowing brightly in its Hubble image.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The glowing remains of an ordinary, Sun-like star create the stunning appearance of the Necklace Nebula."</blockquote>
<p>This article illustrates the beauty and diversity of nebulae discovered by the Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting their importance in the study of the universe.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/five-stunning-images-of-nebula-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-7466057/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/five-stunning-images-of-nebula-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-7466057/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:33:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marius, the man who named Jupiter’s Galilean moons - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Marius, the man who named Jupiter’s Galilean moons</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 15, 2024<!-- Add the source if available --> </p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/sgvfmh/article68950335.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/15istb%20Simon_Marius%202.jpg" alt="This portrait of Marius appeared as a frontispiece (illustration facing the title page of a book) to the Mundus Iovialis." width="100%">
<figcaption>This portrait of Marius appeared as a frontispiece to the <i>Mundus Iovialis</i>. It also shows Jupiter’s moons in orbit around the planet – something that Galileo didn’t include in his book. | Photo Credit: WIKIMEDIA COMMONS</figcaption>
<p>Simon Marius, a 17th-century astronomer, is known for naming the four largest moons of Jupiter despite being overshadowed by Galileo, who claimed to have discovered them first. The debate over Marius' contributions continues today.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Marius was an astronomer, mathematician, physician, and calendar maker born in 1573 in Gunzenhausen, Germany.</li>
    <li>He independently observed Jupiter's moons on December 29, 1609, claiming to see “four tiny stars” aligned with the planet.</li>
    <li>In 1614, Marius published <i>Mundus Iovialis</i>, detailing his findings including Jupiter’s moons and the Andromeda Galaxy.</li>
    <li>His suggested names for the moons—Io, Europa, Ganymede, and Callisto—were influenced by the work of Johannes Kepler.</li>
    <li>Galileo accused Marius of plagiarism in 1623, resulting in ongoing debate about Marius' contributions to astronomy.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“While it is nigh impossible for us to determine if Marius does deserve credit for independently discovering the four major satellites of Jupiter, there’s no doubt that he was the one who gave them the names that are now in use.”</blockquote>
<p>The legacy of Simon Marius highlights the complexities of scientific discovery and the importance of acknowledgment in the history of astronomy. Despite controversies, his contributions to the naming of Jupiter’s moons remain significant.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/children/marius-the-man-who-named-jupiters-galilean-moons/article68950364.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/children/marius-the-man-who-named-jupiters-galilean-moons/article68950364.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 19:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Webb Telescope unveils a Milky Way-like galaxy from the early universe - Madhyamam]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPZk9kSHBfQXhpWGF0cExfSm1QUWJiUW5VUjA3a1N1b0lQaHFoZlR5Xzc2YWFSdk1aX2QxYS0xbkpIRFY1eWd1bUo4U01adUI4MkluN1BlQzMxdjVVOVBlNWVlYVphMGZBT3l3ZEhKZ3JrSjRoUFFiaVJ0S2hCaGZYWktuTDJsMEU0TTRfOXRTeldWUHNNTVJFay05ONIBoAFBVV95cUxQZ19pYThhT2IxWjlMLWxPd1F5R3ppbkFpSnVQN2llYTRsMEp2X3gtYlplWjdEUnpnd2hWRVo2alkwb0tpUmdyS3JpUlJCc0psMU1iTWlZdFZRTU9RMUw1M2pqbjFnVzJIeFJBeVlXSXl5Vnc0ZmpyTzRGaHduT0p5UWJGa2tBMkdoa1pFZWdJNDJZTjAtMGp1THBDeHNjUlox?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPZk9kSHBfQXhpWGF0cExfSm1QUWJiUW5VUjA3a1N1b0lQaHFoZlR5Xzc2YWFSdk1aX2QxYS0xbkpIRFY1eWd1bUo4U01adUI4MkluN1BlQzMxdjVVOVBlNWVlYVphMGZBT3l3ZEhKZ3JrSjRoUFFiaVJ0S2hCaGZYWktuTDJsMEU0TTRfOXRTeldWUHNNTVJFay05ONIBoAFBVV95cUxQZ19pYThhT2IxWjlMLWxPd1F5R3ppbkFpSnVQN2llYTRsMEp2X3gtYlplWjdEUnpnd2hWRVo2alkwb0tpUmdyS3JpUlJCc0psMU1iTWlZdFZRTU9RMUw1M2pqbjFnVzJIeFJBeVlXSXl5Vnc0ZmpyTzRGaHduT0p5UWJGa2tBMkdoa1pFZWdJNDJZTjAtMGp1THBDeHNjUlox?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 16:13:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Webb Telescope Reveals Firefly Sparkle, a Milky Way-Like Galaxy - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Webb Telescope Reveals Firefly Sparkle, a Milky Way-Like Galaxy</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 11, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/eSNLVyaw_VM/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video">
<figcaption>Video related to the discovery of the Firefly Sparkle galaxy.</figcaption>
<p>A galaxy nicknamed the Firefly Sparkle has been detected by NASA's James Webb Space Telescope, marking a significant discovery regarding the early universe and its galaxies.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Firefly Sparkle galaxy existed approximately 600 million years after the Big Bang.</li>
    <li>It has a mass similar to the Milky Way at a comparable stage of development.</li>
    <li>Distinctive for having ten active star clusters undergoing staggered star formation.</li>
    <li>Gravitational lensing greatly enhanced visibility, allowing detailed observation of its components.</li>
    <li>Two companion galaxies are expected to influence Firefly Sparkle's evolution over billions of years.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Each clump is undergoing a distinct phase of evolution." - Chris Willott</blockquote>
<p>This research, part of Webb's CAnadian NIRISS Unbiased Cluster Survey (CANUCS) programme, provides unparalleled insights into the universe's formative years.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/nasa-webb-detects-milky-way-s-early-twin-firefly-sparkle-from-600m-years-after-big-bang-7240359</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/nasa-webb-detects-milky-way-s-early-twin-firefly-sparkle-from-600m-years-after-big-bang-7240359</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:30:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Ingenuity helicopter to become Martian weather station after crash - Madhyamam]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxNQkU5aFdaR1NWSVEzQ1d0emxBR0tWWDFkQWRUUDZReHZkVmFuQjAtSktGclE0c3l2MWpEQUhJWGxRMVZsMnpjbWgxYkhyLV9OaU80SWxVaE5Yc0hVdGlHSGhtVWRtR1BidVcySlVHbmI5NDFpZHF3QldHV3psWnZGVjktUkoxbV83SUF2YTVQZTZfWHVvdHRNYjRXaUx3dndLeExtMDhOd0vSAa4BQVVfeXFMTVFXM2kwTmFzWmVqN1M2d2V0Y1h2YV84MHFpdjBRR2w0V0swQVJIMkxmX2VBQkJqa3ZXdjRnVV8xeThON2JMN0YxSG5qeGprYWNtdjBaUV9DczJmbG1NRnVZVUFnekVtbzVlSUN1UGs2YXZQalZxVnVCM05WczluSEl3WS1iVW15WEVoNVpRblB2dUxBVHRqeE5rVDdqcF9tOVhiaFlSQUFkX1Y2RW5B?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxNQkU5aFdaR1NWSVEzQ1d0emxBR0tWWDFkQWRUUDZReHZkVmFuQjAtSktGclE0c3l2MWpEQUhJWGxRMVZsMnpjbWgxYkhyLV9OaU80SWxVaE5Yc0hVdGlHSGhtVWRtR1BidVcySlVHbmI5NDFpZHF3QldHV3psWnZGVjktUkoxbV83SUF2YTVQZTZfWHVvdHRNYjRXaUx3dndLeExtMDhOd0vSAa4BQVVfeXFMTVFXM2kwTmFzWmVqN1M2d2V0Y1h2YV84MHFpdjBRR2w0V0swQVJIMkxmX2VBQkJqa3ZXdjRnVV8xeThON2JMN0YxSG5qeGprYWNtdjBaUV9DczJmbG1NRnVZVUFnekVtbzVlSUN1UGs2YXZQalZxVnVCM05WczluSEl3WS1iVW15WEVoNVpRblB2dUxBVHRqeE5rVDdqcF9tOVhiaFlSQUFkX1Y2RW5B?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:37:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[120 meteors per hour! Did you know about Geminid meteor shower? - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>120 meteors per hour! Did you know about Geminid meteor shower?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> etnownews.com</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/thumb/116318798.jpg?imgsize=22394&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="120 meteors per hour" />
<figcaption>During this peak, approximately 120 meteors can be seen per hour, traveling at speeds of 79,000 mph (127,000 kph).</figcaption>
<p>The Geminid meteor shower is set to showcase a dazzling display of meteors, with peak visibility expected on December 14, 2024. This celestial event is famed for producing up to 120 meteors per hour.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Geminid meteor shower occurs annually, known for its bright and fast meteors.</li>
    <li>Visible on December 14, this year’s event will allow viewers to see approximately 120 meteors per hour.</li>
    <li>The meteors travel at impressive speeds of 79,000 mph (127,000 kph) or 22 miles per second.</li>
    <li>The meteor shower runs from November 19 to December 24, peaking in mid-December.</li>
    <li>Finding a dark spot away from city lights will enhance viewing conditions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Under ideal conditions, up to 120 Geminid meteors can be seen every hour at its peak, with meteors notable for their brightness, speed, and golden color.”</blockquote>
<p>Be sure to find a comfortable viewing location and enjoy the spectacular Geminid meteor shower as it lights up the night sky!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/web-stories/120-meteors-per-hour-did-you-know-about-geminid-meteor-shower/photostory/116318783.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/web-stories/120-meteors-per-hour-did-you-know-about-geminid-meteor-shower/photostory/116318783.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:43:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jupiter’s Moon Io Shows No Magma Ocean as New Findings Explain Volcanic Eruptions - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Io's Volcano Mystery Solved: No Global Magma Ocean Found</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 12, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Nature</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/MQfE5DSNgfI/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Io's Volcano Mystery" />
<figcaption>Image depicting the volcanic activity on Io.</figcaption>
<p>Recent research has revealed that Jupiter's moon Io does not have a global magma ocean beneath its surface, challenging previous theories about its volcanic activity and implications for other celestial bodies.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The study analyzed data from NASA's Juno spacecraft and historical data from the Galileo mission.</li>
    <li>Findings indicate that Io's interior is solid, contrary to previous beliefs of a molten layer.</li>
    <li>Over 400 active volcanoes exist on Io, with lava sourced from localized pockets of melt in the mantle.</li>
    <li>The research has wider implications for understanding tidal heating on exoplanets orbiting M-dwarf stars.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The absence of a global magma ocean on Io challenges the assumption that such exoplanets would host extensive molten layers."</blockquote>
<p>This significant discovery not only reshapes our understanding of Io but also prompts a reevaluation of geological models for other celestial bodies influenced by tidal forces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/volcanic-eruptions-on-jupiter-s-moon-io-no-magma-ocean-discovered-7239615</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/volcanic-eruptions-on-jupiter-s-moon-io-no-magma-ocean-discovered-7239615</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8,000-Kilometer Deep Oceans on Uranus and Neptune? A Scientist’s Revelation - Indian Defence Review]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8,000-Kilometer Deep Oceans on Uranus and Neptune? A Scientist’s Revelation</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Defence Review</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://indiandefencereview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/scientist-proposes-existence-deep-oceans-uranus-neptune-potentially-5000-miles-deep.jpg" alt="Deep oceans on Uranus and Neptune" width="1200" height="800">
    <figcaption>8,000-Kilometer Deep Oceans on Uranus and Neptune? A Scientist’s Revelation - © Indian Defence Review</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A groundbreaking study suggests that Uranus and Neptune may conceal vast oceans beneath their atmospheres, potentially up to 5,000 miles deep, which could revolutionize our understanding of these ice giants.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Research led by Burkhard Militzer from UC Berkeley utilized advanced computer simulations.</li>
    <li>Layered structure proposed: thick hydrogen-helium atmosphere, deep ocean of water, and compressed hydrocarbons.</li>
    <li>The presence of these oceans may explain the unique magnetic fields of these planets as observed by NASA's Voyager 2.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Implications for the search for extraterrestrial life</h2>
<p>The discovery raises potential for habitable environments on icy moons, such as Miranda, which might harbor subsurface oceans.</p>
<figure>
    <table>
        <thead>
            <tr>
                <th>Planet</th>
                <th>Potential ocean depth</th>
                <th>Number of moons</th>
            </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <td>Uranus</td>
                <td>~5,000 miles</td>
                <td>27</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>Neptune</td>
                <td>~5,000 miles</td>
                <td>14</td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>
</figure>
<h2>Advancements in planetary modeling</h2>
<p>Militzer's team developed a model simulating 540 atoms under extreme conditions, aligning with Voyager 2's measurements, enhancing the credibility of the new theory.</p>
<blockquote>"One day, I looked at the model, and the water had separated from the carbon and nitrogen. What I couldn’t do 10 years ago was now happening." - Burkhard Militzer</blockquote>
<h2>Future exploration and confirmation</h2>
<p>NASA proposes a flagship mission to confirm the existence of these oceanic layers by 2034, taking advantage of a rare planetary alignment for faster travel.</p>
<p>These findings reshape our understanding of ice giants and expand the possibilities for extraterrestrial life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indiandefencereview.com/scientist-proposes-existence-deep-oceans-uranus-neptune-potentially-5000-miles-deep/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiandefencereview.com/scientist-proposes-existence-deep-oceans-uranus-neptune-potentially-5000-miles-deep/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists find alien-like predator in the deep ocean, name it Darkness - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:27:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Captures Active Volcano Eruption On Jupiter's Moon Io, Ending 44-Year-Old Mystery | WATCH - Jagran English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxNNlZ5T2FLUDMxUnV3azZJNlZsR2J4a3QzNkdjQ0pIcjJ2SDFoUmFtMzJ3SnhsN0xwamFyRWpoX1VJeGVCU0FVQ045azN1a3lVQUlwc1VlTGZ1eGswOU9lRDZuQXNydEhNM0dVTFhKQTVDeFV3MjFJNThrS193UHRSaThlVF82Nm5ZX2N2SGZSSEZKeEYtU0N4X2Zqc3NpZVEtTmtVYlNPLXZfeVItZnpZc1dHMy13VVdFRmRxUHU0YUNxZnhjak9lZjdn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxNNlZ5T2FLUDMxUnV3azZJNlZsR2J4a3QzNkdjQ0pIcjJ2SDFoUmFtMzJ3SnhsN0xwamFyRWpoX1VJeGVCU0FVQ045azN1a3lVQUlwc1VlTGZ1eGswOU9lRDZuQXNydEhNM0dVTFhKQTVDeFV3MjFJNThrS193UHRSaThlVF82Nm5ZX2N2SGZSSEZKeEYtU0N4X2Zqc3NpZVEtTmtVYlNPLXZfeVItZnpZc1dHMy13VVdFRmRxUHU0YUNxZnhjak9lZjdn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronauts’ stunning views of Earth from space - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Astronauts’ stunning views of Earth from space</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 4, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/04/900x1600/Earth_From_Space_1733300599052_1733300599210.jpg" alt="Earth views from space">
<figcaption>Photo Credit: NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article highlights breathtaking images captured by astronauts from space, showcasing the beauty and diversity of Earth.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Earth is the only known planet in our solar system with life.</li>
    <li>Astronauts witness Earth’s full beauty from space.</li>
    <li>The curvature and color contrasts of the planet are apparent from orbit.</li>
    <li>Natural phenomena like hurricanes are visible yet appear peaceful from space.</li>
    <li>The ISS orbits Earth every 90 minutes, allowing astronauts to see multiple views of the planet daily.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Astronauts’ views of Earth from space offer a stunning reminder of the planet's beauty.</blockquote>
<p>The stunning imagery captured by astronauts serves as a reminder of the fragile beauty of our planet and the need for its preservation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/trending/astronauts-stunning-views-of-earth-from-space-101733300312463.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/trending/astronauts-stunning-views-of-earth-from-space-101733300312463.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:03:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Ingenuity Helicopter May Become Weather Station for 20 Years on Mars - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Ingenuity Helicopter May Become Weather Station for 20 Years on Mars</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 18, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<img src="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/mars_helicopter_1734158083492.jpg" alt="NASA Ingenuity Helicopter" />
<figcaption>The Ingenuity Mars Helicopter has been repurposed as a weather station on Mars.</figcaption>
<p>The Ingenuity Mars Helicopter, originally deployed by NASA for flight testing, will now function as a weather station after sustaining damage during its 72nd flight. Despite losing its flying capabilities, the helicopter's systems remain operational for data collection.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The helicopter suffered rotor damage during its last flight on January 18, 2024.</li>
    <li>Ingenuity will record telemetry and take images every sol as a weather station.</li>
    <li>The navigation system struggles with uniform Martian terrain, complicating safe landings.</li>
    <li>Communication relies on the Perseverance rover, located 3 kilometers away.</li>
    <li>Ingenuity can potentially operate for up to 20 years, collecting valuable data.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"She's now going to continue on as a weather station of sorts, recording telemetry and taking images every sol." - Teddy Tzanetos, Ingenuity's project manager</blockquote>
<p>As Ingenuity's mission transitions, JPL is now considering the development of a new six-rotor Mars helicopter designed for extended scientific exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/nasas-ingenuity-mars-helicopter-becomes-weather-station-after-crash-7239365</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/nasas-ingenuity-mars-helicopter-becomes-weather-station-after-crash-7239365</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 10:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Very Beautiful Space Images Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Very Beautiful Space Images Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116294195/116294195.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=1518597" alt="6 Very Beautiful Space Images Captured By NASA Hubble Space Telescope">
<figcaption>Credit: NASA-ESA-M-Robberto-Space-Telescope-Science-Institute/ESA-and-the-Hubble-Space-Telescope-Orion-Treasury-Project-Team</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases six stunning images captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, celebrating the beauty and mystery of the cosmos while highlighting the telescope's remarkable capabilities.</p>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Orion Nebula:</strong> A captivating view showing the formation of over 3,000 stars.</li>
    <li><strong>Tarantula Nebula:</strong> Close-up of a stellar nursery with extreme phenomena in the Large Magellanic Cloud.</li>
    <li><strong>NGC 2174 (Monkey Head Nebula):</strong> A vibrant image celebrating Hubble's 24th year in orbit.</li>
    <li><strong>Inky Abyss (NGC 2022):</strong> A vast expanse of gas from a dying star.</li>
    <li><strong>Westerlund 2:</strong> A remarkable image of a star cluster released for Hubble's 25th anniversary.</li>
    <li><strong>Mystic Mountain:</strong> A dramatic portrayal of gas and dust, shaped by intense radiation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The pillar is gradually being eroded by intense radiation from nearby luminous stars, creating a scene even more striking than fiction."</blockquote>
<p>The images serve as a reminder of Hubble's significant contributions to our understanding of the universe, showcasing its lasting impact on astronomy and science.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-very-beautiful-space-images-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/116294175.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-very-beautiful-space-images-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/116294175.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 10:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ligand-engineered copper nanoclusters may aid in fight against CO2 emissions - Tech Explorist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ligand-engineered copper nanoclusters may aid in fight against CO2 emissions</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Tech Explorist</p>
<p>This article discusses a groundbreaking initiative by researchers to enhance the efficiency of electrochemical CO<sub>2</sub> reduction using ligand-engineered copper nanoclusters, demonstrating copper's potential in sustainable chemistry.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Research conducted by Tohoku University, Tokyo University of Science, and University of Adelaide.</li>
    <li>Engineering of copper nanocluster surfaces at the atomic level to improve selectivity and sustainability in carbon reduction.</li>
    <li>Focus on electrochemical CO<sub>2</sub> reduction reactions (CO<sub>2</sub>RR) which convert excess CO<sub>2</sub> into valuable products.</li>
    <li>Two Cu₁₄ nanoclusters were created with different thiolate ligands, showcasing the potential for varying product selectivity.</li>
    <li>The study highlights the importance of intercluster interactions in determining nanocluster stability and catalytic performance.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“To achieve this breakthrough, our team had to modify NCs at the atomic scale. However, it’s very challenging since the geometry of the NCs was heavily dependent on the precise parts that we needed to alter.” — Professor Yuichi Negishi</blockquote>
<blockquote>“These findings are pivotal for advancing the design of Cu NCs that combine stability with high selectivity, paving the way for more efficient and reliable electrochemical CO<sub>2</sub> reduction technologies.” — Professor Yuichi Negishi</blockquote>
<p>This research underscores the critical role of collaboration and innovative technology in addressing global carbon emission challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techexplorist.com/ligand-engineered-copper-nanoclusters-fight-against-co2-emissions/94619/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techexplorist.com/ligand-engineered-copper-nanoclusters-fight-against-co2-emissions/94619/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:57:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's critical warning: A 200-foot, airplane-sized asteroid is approaching Earth at high speed tomorrow - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-s-critical-warning-a-200-foot-airplane-sized-asteroid-is-approaching-earth-at-high-speed-tomorrow-article-12889891.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-s-critical-warning-a-200-foot-airplane-sized-asteroid-is-approaching-earth-at-high-speed-tomorrow-article-12889891.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:30:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Launches 22 Starlink Satellites Into Orbit on Falcon 9 Rocket From California - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPMW9XX1FSTTZRWDVsSU9vX2hmNkVZdXRnYVFBV0luSHpoUlhhS056Vl8xUHRwTVJKaVJaVGwzbkhhSWs5TEYwX2FLcFVTSjFseDVaQ1B0UkhpNUhWUmtFaGtWS0xpYWFmUV81Ni1ocEQxM0wycnprcnBmOVk3MW9fV1dURmN6UUZIbFpONmU5UlVHbDRsdFZ5cGVPbW5hTjNiU3E1RTFSa2U3OUNvYmthRjdSZE1pRkVmY2R4cUdIYk04UUFPdE82YnRzQXBhY25pN0pXOWswWWtCazhFUkItenMxSTA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPMW9XX1FSTTZRWDVsSU9vX2hmNkVZdXRnYVFBV0luSHpoUlhhS056Vl8xUHRwTVJKaVJaVGwzbkhhSWs5TEYwX2FLcFVTSjFseDVaQ1B0UkhpNUhWUmtFaGtWS0xpYWFmUV81Ni1ocEQxM0wycnprcnBmOVk3MW9fV1dURmN6UUZIbFpONmU5UlVHbDRsdFZ5cGVPbW5hTjNiU3E1RTFSa2U3OUNvYmthRjdSZE1pRkVmY2R4cUdIYk04UUFPdE82YnRzQXBhY25pN0pXOWswWWtCazhFUkItenMxSTA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:37:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists find alien-like predator in the deep ocean, name it Darkness - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists find alien-like predator in the deep ocean, name it Darkness</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/dvdc_1734164147227_1734164147564.jpg" alt="Researchers discovered a new predatory amphipod, Dulcibella camanchaca, in the Atacama Trench. (Pixabay)" title="Researchers discovered a new predatory amphipod, Dulcibella camanchaca, in the Atacama Trench. (Pixabay)">
<figcaption>Researchers discovered a new predatory amphipod, Dulcibella camanchaca, in the Atacama Trench. (Pixabay)</figcaption>
<p>A recent study reveals the discovery of Dulcibella camanchaca, a new predatory amphipod found at a depth of 7,902 meters in the Atacama Trench, highlighting the mysteries of deep-sea life.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The amphipod, named Dulcibella camanchaca, was found at an extraordinary depth, marking a significant milestone in deep-sea exploration.</li>
    <li>It is the first predatory amphipod documented in the hadal zone, where depths exceed 6,000 meters.</li>
    <li>The species showcases unique hunting behavior, differing from typical scavenger amphipods.</li>
    <li>The genus name Dulcibella is a nod to literary heritage, drawing from Don Quixote, while 'camanchaca' means 'darkness' in local languages.</li>
    <li>The study is believed to provide insights into extraterrestrial life by offering parallels to ocean moons like Europa and Enceladus.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The discovery of D. camanchaca enriches our understanding of deep-sea ecosystems and their potential connections to life beyond Earth.”</blockquote>
<p>This groundbreaking discovery emphasizes the need for further exploration of our oceans, which remain largely unexplored, and highlights the unique adaptations of life existing in extreme environments.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/scientists-find-alien-like-predator-in-the-deep-ocean-name-it-darkness-101734163376250.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/scientists-find-alien-like-predator-in-the-deep-ocean-name-it-darkness-101734163376250.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:18:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Artificial Solar Eclipse: Exploring the Sun's Corona - Insights IAS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid0FVX3lxTE5ueU9YZDliaDNsXzVqZ2xScTBGS09zMnJ1YU5wb0d0MTQ3YW03UmhaX2JXRWVrNlpsUXgzdDU4NkRZRU9tVElaMG1XWUpfczhsMjdLcWZIQy1fN0tkb3VEdjcxMkZsRzlWT0xQX2toNUltWVp3SjQ4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid0FVX3lxTE5ueU9YZDliaDNsXzVqZ2xScTBGS09zMnJ1YU5wb0d0MTQ3YW03UmhaX2JXRWVrNlpsUXgzdDU4NkRZRU9tVElaMG1XWUpfczhsMjdLcWZIQy1fN0tkb3VEdjcxMkZsRzlWT0xQX2toNUltWVp3SjQ4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 07:34:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Juno mission uncovers heart of Jovian moon's volcanic rage - CGTN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Juno mission uncovers heart of Jovian moon's volcanic rage</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Xinhua News Agency</p>
<img src="https://news.cgtn.com/news/2024-12-14/NASA-s-Juno-mission-uncovers-heart-of-Jovian-moon-s-volcanic-rage-1zjXenFAFfG/img/68f41429f50245388a1c8bf686defb93/68f41429f50245388a1c8bf686defb93.jpeg" alt="Jupiter's volcanic moon Io was captured by NASA's Juno during the spacecraft's close pass of the gas giant, February 3, 2024. /CFP">
<figcaption>Jupiter's volcanic moon Io was captured by NASA's Juno during the spacecraft's close pass of the gas giant, February 3, 2024. /CFP</figcaption>
<p>Scientists with NASA's Juno mission have revealed new insights into the volcanic activity of Jupiter's moon Io, showing that each volcano is likely powered by individual chambers of magma rather than a single ocean of magma.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The finding addresses a 44-year-old mystery regarding Io's volcanic activity.</li>
    <li>Io, similar in size to Earth's moon, is the most volcanically active body in the solar system, with approximately 400 volcanoes.</li>
    <li>The Juno spacecraft conducted close flybys of Io in December 2023 and February 2024, achieving proximity of about 1,500 kilometers to its surface.</li>
    <li>Juno collected high-precision data to analyze Io's gravity and the effects of tidal flexing on the moon.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Juno's discovery that tidal forces do not always create global magma oceans does more than prompt us to rethink what we know about Io's interior," - Ryan Park, Juno co-investigator.</blockquote>
<p>The insights gained from Juno's mission may also reshape our understanding of other celestial bodies and have broader implications for the study of planetary formation and evolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.cgtn.com/news/2024-12-14/NASA-s-Juno-mission-uncovers-heart-of-Jovian-moon-s-volcanic-rage-1zjXenFAFfG/p.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.cgtn.com/news/2024-12-14/NASA-s-Juno-mission-uncovers-heart-of-Jovian-moon-s-volcanic-rage-1zjXenFAFfG/p.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:44:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 latest images universe captured by NASA James Webb Space Telescope - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxOeTcybTNSYldwR0RTeVcwd0swNWpvQWJyS09rQmhtZ0xlemVqb2VKM2ZnNENmbnlweVl0X2hqU1c1cjVfMk9lNWdFUWpzSVA3Mk4zQ1FwQ3NnX3VzNnI2ekk1Q2UtVW55WThTa19iN3dPVzF0aVJ5dFRWVWVxY0s4a1VQVG90T3pqNFU3djUzNldlQi1MeUhVdWFZM2p4MTVuc1YwUE5oYXdvOWY1SWFXLUp6MDFLakdFXzU2cDVHUGJVQXJWRGNvbFQzLVfSAcwBQVVfeXFMTnk3Mm0zUmJXcEdEU3lXMHdLMDVqb0FicktPa0JobWdMZXplam9lSjNmZzRDZm55cHlZdF9oalNXNXI1XzJPZTVnRVFqc0lQNzJOM0NRcENzZ191czZyNnpJNUNlLVVueVk4U2tfYjd3T1cxdGlSeXRUVlVlcWNLOGtVUFRvdE96ajRVN3Y1MzZXZUItTHlIVXVhWTNqeDE1bnNWMFBOaGF3bzlmNUlhVy1KejAxS2pHRV81NnA1R1BiVUFyVkRjb2xUMy1X?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxOeTcybTNSYldwR0RTeVcwd0swNWpvQWJyS09rQmhtZ0xlemVqb2VKM2ZnNENmbnlweVl0X2hqU1c1cjVfMk9lNWdFUWpzSVA3Mk4zQ1FwQ3NnX3VzNnI2ekk1Q2UtVW55WThTa19iN3dPVzF0aVJ5dFRWVWVxY0s4a1VQVG90T3pqNFU3djUzNldlQi1MeUhVdWFZM2p4MTVuc1YwUE5oYXdvOWY1SWFXLUp6MDFLakdFXzU2cDVHUGJVQXJWRGNvbFQzLVfSAcwBQVVfeXFMTnk3Mm0zUmJXcEdEU3lXMHdLMDVqb0FicktPa0JobWdMZXplam9lSjNmZzRDZm55cHlZdF9oalNXNXI1XzJPZTVnRVFqc0lQNzJOM0NRcENzZ191czZyNnpJNUNlLVVueVk4U2tfYjd3T1cxdGlSeXRUVlVlcWNLOGtVUFRvdE96ajRVN3Y1MzZXZUItTHlIVXVhWTNqeDE1bnNWMFBOaGF3bzlmNUlhVy1KejAxS2pHRV81NnA1R1BiVUFyVkRjb2xUMy1X?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 01:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mind-Blowing Discovery, M87 Black Hole's Unprecedented Gamma-Ray Flare Reveals Secrets of Universe's Extreme Environments - Motorcycle Sports Australia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mind-Blowing Discovery, M87 Black Hole’s Unprecedented Gamma-Ray Flare Reveals Secrets of Universe’s Extreme Environments</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Motorcycle Sports</p>
<img width="750" height="375" src="https://motorcyclesports.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Design-sem-nome-17-750x375.jpg?ezimgfmt=rs:750x375/rscb1/ngcb1/notWebP" alt="Mind-Blowing Discovery, M87 Black Hole’s Unprecedented Gamma-Ray Flare Reveals Secrets of Universe’s Extreme Environments">
<figcaption>A gamma-ray flare from M87, a supermassive black hole, captured through advanced imaging.</figcaption>
<p>A colossal burst of gamma-rays from the supermassive black hole M87 has captivated astronomers, illuminating the cosmos with intense photons and revealing critical insights into the extreme environments around black holes.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The gamma-ray burst lasted three days and emitted photons billions of times more energetic than visible light.</li>
    <li>The study involved over 300 scientists collaborating on the research to explore the physics around supermassive black holes.</li>
    <li>The jets created by M87 are 140 times longer than the width of the Milky Way, showcasing immense cosmic forces.</li>
    <li>Researchers aim to understand the acceleration of particles near the black hole and within the jets.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We still don’t fully understand how particles are accelerated near the black hole or within the jet,” - Weidong Jin, UCLA.</blockquote>
<blockquote>“These efforts promise to shed light on the disk-jet connection and uncover the origins and mechanisms behind the gamma-ray photon emission.” - Giacomo Principe, University of Trieste.</blockquote>
<p>This groundbreaking observation not only enhances our understanding of black hole dynamics but also invites future explorations into the universe's most profound mysteries. The ongoing investigations hold the potential to significantly advance our grasp of classical physics and the extreme conditions surrounding black holes.]]></description>
            <link>https://motorcyclesports.net/mind-blowing-discovery-m87-black-holes-unprecedented-gamma-ray-flare-reveals-secrets-of-universes-extreme-environments/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://motorcyclesports.net/mind-blowing-discovery-m87-black-holes-unprecedented-gamma-ray-flare-reveals-secrets-of-universes-extreme-environments/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 21:07:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX rolls 7th Starship spacecraft out for testing ahead of next launch (photos) - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaceX rolls 7th Starship spacecraft out for testing ahead of next launch (photos)</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9UEHnemy27n7Qwm66ZkoGn-320-80.jpg" alt="a chrome spaceship stands on in front of a sleek black building." loading="lazy">
<figcaption>The Flight 7 Starship upper stage at SpaceX's Starbase facility. (Image credit: SpaceX)</figcaption>
<p>The world's most powerful rocket is preparing for its next test flight, with SpaceX's seventh Starship launch expected within the coming month as testing progresses at Starbase, Texas.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Starship upper stage is ready for its own testing following a successful static fire of the Super Heavy booster.</li>
    <li>SpaceX has not yet announced an official date for the integrated test flight, but NASA has indicated January 11 as a potential target.</li>
    <li>When fully assembled, the Starship and Super Heavy combination will reach nearly 400 feet tall, surpassing any rocket ever built.</li>
    <li>Starship aims to be the first fully reusable launch vehicle, with plans for mid-air catches of boosters by the launch tower.</li>
    <li>There were four Starship launches in 2025, and the number of launches is expected to increase as the program progresses.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Starship ready for testing ahead of Flight 7," - SpaceX</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming IFT-7 represents a significant step for SpaceX and its partnership with NASA, as Starship is pivotal for future lunar missions under the Artemis program.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/space-exploration/launches-spacecraft/spacex-rolls-7th-starship-spacecraft-out-for-testing-ahead-of-next-launch-photos</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/space-exploration/launches-spacecraft/spacex-rolls-7th-starship-spacecraft-out-for-testing-ahead-of-next-launch-photos</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 amazing images of galaxies captured by NASA Hubble Telescope - India.Com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Amazing Images of Galaxies Captured by NASA Hubble Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/GALAXY-ERIDANUS-HEADLINES.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=400&amp;h=800" alt="GALAXY ERIDANUS-HEADLINES" />
<figcaption>Incredible image of Galaxy Eridanus captured by the Hubble Telescope.</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases stunning images of various galaxies captured by the NASA Hubble Telescope, highlighting their unique features and beauty.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The lenticular galaxy NGC 5283, known for its active galactic nucleus.</li>
    <li>The jellyfish galaxy JW39, depicted in a serene pose.</li>
    <li>Galaxy JO204, recognized for its bright gas tendrils.</li>
    <li>Barred spiral galaxy NGC 685, set against a starry backdrop.</li>
    <li>The intriguing active galaxy Z 229-15, situated about 390 million light-years from Earth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This luminous image from the Hubble Space Telescope shows Z 229-15, a celestial object that lies about 390 million light-years from Earth in the constellation Lyra."</blockquote>
<p>The images displayed provide a glimpse into the vastness of space and the mesmerizing beauty of galaxies, showcasing the incredible capabilities of the Hubble Space Telescope in capturing these celestial wonders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/5-amazing-images-of-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-2-7464133/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/5-amazing-images-of-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-2-7464133/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 19:02:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 amazing images of galaxies captured by NASA Hubble Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Amazing Images of Galaxies Captured by NASA Hubble Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/GALAXY-ERIDANUS-HEADLINES.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=400&amp;h=800" alt="GALAXY ERIDANUS-HEADLINES" />
<figcaption>Incredible image of Galaxy Eridanus captured by the Hubble Telescope.</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases stunning images of various galaxies captured by the NASA Hubble Telescope, highlighting their unique features and beauty.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The lenticular galaxy NGC 5283, known for its active galactic nucleus.</li>
    <li>The jellyfish galaxy JW39, depicted in a serene pose.</li>
    <li>Galaxy JO204, recognized for its bright gas tendrils.</li>
    <li>Barred spiral galaxy NGC 685, set against a starry backdrop.</li>
    <li>The intriguing active galaxy Z 229-15, situated about 390 million light-years from Earth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This luminous image from the Hubble Space Telescope shows Z 229-15, a celestial object that lies about 390 million light-years from Earth in the constellation Lyra."</blockquote>
<p>The images displayed provide a glimpse into the vastness of space and the mesmerizing beauty of galaxies, showcasing the incredible capabilities of the Hubble Space Telescope in capturing these celestial wonders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/5-amazing-images-of-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-2-7464133/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/5-amazing-images-of-galaxies-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-2-7464133/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 19:02:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>