<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:28:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:28:25 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review of studies shows Indus Valley, other ancient societies in South Asia were able to develop resilience to climate change - Down To Earth Magazine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Review of studies shows Indus Valley, other ancient societies in South Asia were able to develop resilience to climate change</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 16 Dec 2024, 7:08 am</p><p>Ancient societies in South Asia, notably the Indus Valley Civilisation, were able to develop resilience to climate change, a new review of scientific studies has shown.</p><ul><li>The review examined historical and archaeological studies on climate resilience over the past 5,000 years.</li><li>It highlighted the need for holistic studies in climate resiliology.</li><li>The review cited three instances of resilience in the Indian subcontinent.</li><li>Stone toolkits found in India reveal human adaptability during the Toba super-eruption 74,000 years ago.</li><li>The Indus Valley Civilisation demonstrated advanced water management for agricultural resilience.</li></ul><blockquote>“These findings suggest that this catastrophic climate event had minimal effects on humans and did not cause a population bottleneck in the affected region.”</blockquote><p>The paper emphasizes the critical role of water management and urban planning in the survival and adaptation of ancient societies to climate changes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/climate-change/review-of-studies-shows-indus-valley-other-ancient-societies-in-south-asia-were-able-to-develop-resilience-to-climate-change</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.downtoearth.org.in/climate-change/review-of-studies-shows-indus-valley-other-ancient-societies-in-south-asia-were-able-to-develop-resilience-to-climate-change</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:08:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A particle that’s massless when moving in one direction but has a mass in the other direction - Tech Explorist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Discovery of Semi-Dirac Fermions in ZrSiS Crystal</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Tech Explorist</p>
<img src="https://www.techexplorist.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/quasiparticle-1024x682.jpg" alt="semi-Dirac fermion" width="1024" height="682">
<figcaption>The quasiparticle, called a semi-Dirac fermion, was first theorized 16 years ago, but was only recently spotted inside a crystal of semi-metal material called ZrSiS. The observation of the quasiparticle opens the door to future advances in a range of emerging technologies from batteries to sensors, according to researchers who made the discovery. Credit: Yinming Shao / Penn State.</figcaption>
<p>Scientists have observed semi-Dirac fermions, particles that can have mass in one direction and act massless in another, for the first time in a crystal called ZrSiS. This discovery was made accidentally while investigating the material's behavior under infrared light and magnetic fields.</p>
<ul>
<li>First observation of semi-Dirac fermions in ZrSiS crystals.</li>
<li>The particles behave differently depending on their movement direction.</li>
<li>The discovery was made using magneto-optical spectroscopy techniques.</li>
<li>The team cooled ZrSiS to extremely low temperatures for the study.</li>
<li>Finally, the energy level changes followed a unique power law indicative of these particles.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When a magnetic field is applied to any material, the energy levels of electrons become quantized. In this case, they didn’t.” – Yinming Shao</blockquote>
<p>This finding could have significant implications for future technologies by improving material properties related to electronics and sensors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techexplorist.com/particle-massless-moving-direction-mass-other-direction/94677/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techexplorist.com/particle-massless-moving-direction-mass-other-direction/94677/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:05:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How China could become the first country to bring back Mars samples by 2031 - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/how-china-could-become-the-first-country-to-bring-back-mars-samples-by-2031-article-12890667.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/how-china-could-become-the-first-country-to-bring-back-mars-samples-by-2031-article-12890667.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:03:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Do you know what is the the oldest object on Earth? Know details about this RARE blue crystal - Asianet Newsable ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxQVkpBblZXMDNUUDJNdE4xd2dPek1ELXM2ekEtNVRTQkZrSDVHeFV6VnkzQWVjMVhxWXJrSVB1am82WW9OMVZrLXdrSGNPYVhYVzFGSDRfQ3VYd2RwYjNaMFdta1g1S2R4c1F2RVRWYkR3d0lKMGMzdDB1TVZ4QjNWY0pFejVJam1jN2IwLVdOSUdZYkt2VERMWjJCdXd1Y1daUG1JbHNsSGYySVF1OTBJZkxtdnpnZFBCMHNLY0hkaWtZRXk1TkxpWER1RkQzM2t4c01adElsM1NJMXR5eGM3ZDA1anZRNXdwZ3fSAe8BQVVfeXFMTkdyTGRNd1BEWUw1bGl5eldWXzN6aUxxem5ObEVPTzYxMldFWWdMOWUyNnA1U2JOWmlLa0tjZnBIZGVBSzhBckhGTTBoRlNLOGdiQk5TRWN6aG5VVE9JaW1RemVGTmQzTXlES3J6bU9VYVpsc1NRSHdheTd5R3J2elc3S2JveFJkZTE5ZHc1QkNjMkpnRk4wZ0V2SDF2a0VHUGtfc0tkM19QSlU5RG5GRV9ZR1pMSzFUZXZJWlZpSlJHMHdFSnNsdjNHLTRpdDZlTjZKVm1OZlVkNzZLQjVhM0NiMERMZXQtOXVubnY1Ujg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxQVkpBblZXMDNUUDJNdE4xd2dPek1ELXM2ekEtNVRTQkZrSDVHeFV6VnkzQWVjMVhxWXJrSVB1am82WW9OMVZrLXdrSGNPYVhYVzFGSDRfQ3VYd2RwYjNaMFdta1g1S2R4c1F2RVRWYkR3d0lKMGMzdDB1TVZ4QjNWY0pFejVJam1jN2IwLVdOSUdZYkt2VERMWjJCdXd1Y1daUG1JbHNsSGYySVF1OTBJZkxtdnpnZFBCMHNLY0hkaWtZRXk1TkxpWER1RkQzM2t4c01adElsM1NJMXR5eGM3ZDA1anZRNXdwZ3fSAe8BQVVfeXFMTkdyTGRNd1BEWUw1bGl5eldWXzN6aUxxem5ObEVPTzYxMldFWWdMOWUyNnA1U2JOWmlLa0tjZnBIZGVBSzhBckhGTTBoRlNLOGdiQk5TRWN6aG5VVE9JaW1RemVGTmQzTXlES3J6bU9VYVpsc1NRSHdheTd5R3J2elc3S2JveFJkZTE5ZHc1QkNjMkpnRk4wZ0V2SDF2a0VHUGtfc0tkM19QSlU5RG5GRV9ZR1pMSzFUZXZJWlZpSlJHMHdFSnNsdjNHLTRpdDZlTjZKVm1OZlVkNzZLQjVhM0NiMERMZXQtOXVubnY1Ujg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:50:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Makes Humans Scarier Predators Than Tigers or Lions? - Science ABC]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What Makes Humans Scarier Predators Than Tigers or Lions?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Science ABC</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.scienceabc.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/silhouette-hunter-with-gun-reeds-against-sun-ambush-ducks-with-dogs.jpg-.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="667"><figcaption>Animal hunting by humans has been found to generate a fear response in animals that often exceeds the response they have to natural predators (Credits: antonmaster/Freepik)</figcaption><p>Humans are increasingly recognized as super-predators, exerting profound effects on wildlife and ecosystems. Research indicates that our presence alone can induce stress and behavioral changes in animals, often greater than those caused by natural predators.</p><ul><li>Research shows that humans kill more wildlife than apex predators like tigers and lions.</li><li>Human activities, including tourism and hunting, cause significant fear responses in wildlife.</li><li>Field experiments demonstrate that even subtle human disturbances can drastically alter animal behaviors.</li><li>The concept of humans as super-predators reflects extensive ecological impacts across various species and environments.</li></ul><blockquote>“Humans are super-predators. We not only kill more than the biggest predators in the animal kingdom, scientists have also found that our presence…can induce alarm and fear in the wildlife of that area.”</blockquote><p>Understanding the role of humans as dominant predators is critical for crafting effective wildlife management strategies and fostering long-term coexistence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scienceabc.com/humans/what-makes-humans-scarier-predators-than-tigers-or-lions.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.scienceabc.com/humans/what-makes-humans-scarier-predators-than-tigers-or-lions.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:31:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rengali Model School Student Lisa Meher Selected for ISRO Visit - Online Sambalpur]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sambalpur Student Lisa Meher Selected for ISRO Visit and Honored by Odisha CM</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 12, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Online Sambalpur</p><img src="https://onlinesambalpur.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/isro-lisa.jpg" alt="Lisa Meher" width="750" height="430"><figcaption>Lisa Meher, awarded by Odisha CM for her achievements.</figcaption><p>Lisa Meher, a Class 9 student from Rengali Model School, has been recognized by the Chief Minister of Odisha, securing an opportunity to visit ISRO after excelling in the Young Astronomer Talent Search Competition.</p><ul><li>Lisa was one of the top 30 finalists in the state-level competition.</li><li>The initiative was organized by Tata Steel and Pathani Samanta Planetarium.</li><li>Her selection included an invitation to attend a workshop at ISRO.</li><li>This recognition has inspired fellow students in Odisha.</li></ul><blockquote>“Lisa’s success serves as an inspiration for many young students in Odisha to pursue their dreams in science and technology.”</blockquote><p>The achievement of Lisa Meher showcases the potential of young talents in Odisha and highlights the importance of support for budding scientists.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://onlinesambalpur.com/rengali-model-school-student-lisa-meher-selected-for-isro-visit-honored-by-odisha-cm/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://onlinesambalpur.com/rengali-model-school-student-lisa-meher-selected-for-isro-visit-honored-by-odisha-cm/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:25:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hidden mechanism of swallowing revealed by Caenorhabditis elegans! - Asia Research News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.asiaresearchnews.com/content/hidden-mechanism-swallowing-revealed-caenorhabditis-elegans</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.asiaresearchnews.com/content/hidden-mechanism-swallowing-revealed-caenorhabditis-elegans</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:21:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ursid meteor shower 2024: Date, peak time, where, and how to watch the final meteor display of the year - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/ursid-meteor-shower-2024-date-peak-time-where-and-how-to-watch-the-final-meteor-display-of-the-year-article-12890640.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/ursid-meteor-shower-2024-date-peak-time-where-and-how-to-watch-the-final-meteor-display-of-the-year-article-12890640.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:17:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 stunning images of our solar system captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Stunning Images of Our Solar System Captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> HT TECH</p>
<img src="https://images.hindustantimes.com/tech/img/2024/12/16/900x1600/g0f7f6ecaceb9b22b21751494494bef709049f5933f0353ac2_1734322360961_1734322361183.jpg" alt="NASA Hubble Space Telescope" />
<figcaption>Image Credit: NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases five stunning images of the solar system captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting the beauty and complexity of our cosmic neighborhood.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The solar system is approximately 4.5 billion years old.</li>
    <li>Only two NASA spacecraft have exited our solar system.</li>
    <li>About 500,000 pieces of space junk are currently orbiting Earth.</li>
    <li>The Hubble Telescope captured a more powerful image of Mars in 2018 than previous spacecraft.</li>
    <li>Images also include alien aurorae on Uranus and northern auroras on Saturn.</li>
    <li>New insights into Jupiter's atmosphere have been gained through Hubble’s imagery.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Hubble’s near-infrared imaging showcased the rainbow view of Jupiter, providing astronomers with an understanding of the planet’s atmosphere.”</blockquote>
<p>The stunning images not only demonstrate the capabilities of modern telescopes but also inspire curiosity and wonder about the universe we inhabit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tech.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/5-stunning-images-of-our-solar-system-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-71734322315820.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tech.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/5-stunning-images-of-our-solar-system-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-71734322315820.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:23:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Superflares erupt from stars like our Sun once every 100 years - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Superflares Erupt from Stars Like Our Sun Once Every 100 Years</h1><p><strong>Published: 16 December 2024, Source: Science</strong></p><p>Our sun is a violent place, but scientists have observed even larger explosions from other stars, called superflares, which occur much more frequently than anticipated.</p><ul><li>Superflares are explosions with the power of a trillion hydrogen bombs.</li><li>Stars similar to our sun generate superflares approximately once every century.</li><li>A recent study re-evaluated superflare data using advanced methodologies and found the occurrence rate to be higher than previous estimates.</li><li>The research team analyzed data from NASA's retired Kepler space telescope to identify sun-like stars.</li><li>Only about 1 in 20 sun-like stars were found to produce superflares.</li></ul><blockquote>“A solar superflare is something that society needs to worry about,” said Hugh Hudson, an astronomer, emphasizing the potential risks involved.</blockquote><p>Understanding the frequency and implications of these events is crucial for preparing society for possible threats from solar activity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/science/space/superflares-erupt-from-stars-like-our-sun-once-every-100-years-3318940</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/science/space/superflares-erupt-from-stars-like-our-sun-once-every-100-years-3318940</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 03:41:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cosmic Chameleons: Mysterious “Dark Comets” May Hold Clues to Life’s Origins on Earth - SciTechDaily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/cosmic-chameleons-mysterious-dark-comets-may-hold-clues-to-lifes-origins-on-earth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scitechdaily.com/cosmic-chameleons-mysterious-dark-comets-may-hold-clues-to-lifes-origins-on-earth/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 03:24:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Time-Lapse Imagery Of China's Chang'e-6 After Landing On Far Side Of The Moon - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:50:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Mesmerising Images Of Stars Taken By NASA Hubble Space Telescope - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Mesmerising Images Of Stars Taken By NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116339911/116339911.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=1771596" alt="6 Mesmerising Images Of Stars Taken By NASA Hubble Space Telescope">
<figcaption>Credit: ESA/Hubble-NASA-M-Messa</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases six stunning images of stars captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, revealing the beauty and complexity of the universe.</p>
<ul>
  <li>ESO 245-5: A crowded star field showing a large part of a galaxy, located 15 million light-years away.</li>
  <li>Star AU Microscopii: Featuring a young planet and its dynamic relationship with a red dwarf star.</li>
  <li>Stellar Cradle: Showcases the protostellar object OH 339.88-1.26, filled with dusty lanes and bright stars.</li>
  <li>NGC 346: Depicts an active area of star formation within the Small Magellanic Cloud.</li>
  <li>Stargazing In NGC 6355: Illustrates the globular cluster located within our Milky Way galaxy.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Scientists were surprised to observe young stars spiraling towards the core of a large star cluster within the Small Magellanic Cloud.”</blockquote>
<p>This remarkable collection of images highlights the wonders of astronomy and encourages further exploration of the cosmos.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-mesmerising-images-of-stars-taken-by-nasa-hubble-spacetelescope/photostory/116339885.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/6-mesmerising-images-of-stars-taken-by-nasa-hubble-spacetelescope/photostory/116339885.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hubble took the closest-ever image of a quasar, and captured some 'weird things' - Earth.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hubble Captures Closest Image of Quasar 3C 273, Reveals Unique Structures</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Earth.com</p>
<img src="https://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/thumbnails/image/hubble_space_telescope.jpg" alt="Hubble Space Telescope" />
<figcaption>Image Credit: NASA, ESA, Bin Ren (Université Côte d’Azur/CNRS)</figcaption>
<p>Astronomers using NASA’s Hubble Space Telescope have explored the surrounding environment of quasar 3C 273 in unprecedented detail, revealing new features that may enhance our understanding of these powerful celestial objects.</p>
<ul>
<li>Quasars are extremely luminous astronomical entities, powered by supermassive black holes.</li>
<li>The latest observations highlighted “weird things” in the quasar’s vicinity, including blobs and a mysterious L-shaped filament.</li>
<li>Quasar 3C 273 is the closest known quasar, located 2.5 billion light-years from Earth, emitting more energy than the brightest elliptical galaxies.</li>
<li>Hubble’s advanced instruments allowed researchers to examine fine details of the quasar’s host galaxy, unveiling dusty disks and intricate interactions.</li>
<li>The recent study sets the stage for future observations with the James Webb Space Telescope.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Thanks to Hubble’s observing power, we’re opening a new gateway into understanding quasars.” - Bin Ren</blockquote>
<p>The insights gained from observing quasar 3C 273 enhance our understanding of the cosmic processes that shape galaxies and quasars throughout the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.earth.com/news/hubble-took-the-closest-ever-image-of-a-quasar-and-captured-some-weird-things/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.earth.com/news/hubble-took-the-closest-ever-image-of-a-quasar-and-captured-some-weird-things/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:20:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can we make black holes reveal themselves in echoes of light? - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can we make black holes reveal themselves in echoes of light?</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> December 16, 2024 05:30 am IST <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/sci-tech/science/ne90m/article68981566.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/11xxA_view_of_the_M87_supermassive_black_hole_in_polarised_light.tif.jpg" alt="A view of the M87 supermassive black hole in polarised light" title="A view of the M87 supermassive black hole in polarised light as captured by the Event Horizon Telescope and released in 2021."><figcaption>A view of the M87 supermassive black hole in polarised light as captured by the Event Horizon Telescope and released in 2021. | Photo Credit: EHT Collaboration (CC BY 4.0)</figcaption><p>This article examines recent research on light echoes around black holes, highlighting a new method for measuring their properties through effects on light, as reported by a Princeton University study.</p><ul><li>The study proposes using light echoes as a new way to measure black hole masses and spins.</li><li>Light passing around black holes bends and can create multiple light paths, leading to echoes.</li><li>The research employs a technique called long-baseline interferometry to detect these echoes.</li><li>The study focuses on black holes in the Milky Way and M87 galaxies.</li><li>Preliminary simulations support the technique and align with Einstein's theory of relativity.</li></ul><blockquote>Albert Einstein's general theory of relativity predicted that light echoes would occur, implying that they should be observable across different frequencies.</blockquote><p>The findings offer intriguing insights into black holes and could significantly enhance our understanding of their characteristics and behavior in the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/can-we-make-black-holes-reveal-themselves-in-echoes-of-light/article68981587.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/can-we-make-black-holes-reveal-themselves-in-echoes-of-light/article68981587.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new study warns about frequent solar superflares - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/a-new-study-warns-about-frequent-solar-superflares/articleshow/116347042.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/a-new-study-warns-about-frequent-solar-superflares/articleshow/116347042.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Europe Launches Mission to Create Simulated Solar Eclipse - VOA Learning English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Europe Launches Mission to Create Simulated Solar Eclipse</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 5, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> VOA Learning English</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://gdb.voanews.com/360070d9-0111-47a6-876d-6629289d52e7_w250_r0_s.jpg" alt="Artist's illustration of the Proba-3 satellites" />
  <figcaption>This artist illustration show the European Space Agency's Proba-3 satellites, which will operate from a high orbit above Earth. (Image Credit: ESA-P. Carril)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Two European satellites were launched on a mission to simulate total solar eclipses, aiming to enhance our understanding of solar activity and the sun's corona.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Launched by the European Space Agency (ESA) from southern India.</li>
  <li>The Proba-3 mission will test precision formation flying with satellites operating 150 meters apart.</li>
  <li>Planned artificial eclipses will allow for detailed observation of the sun without its overwhelming brightness.</li>
  <li>Each eclipse can last up to six hours, compared to the few minutes of natural eclipses.</li>
  <li>The project aims to gather 1,000 hours of totality over its two-year mission.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“For six hours at a time, it will be able to see the sun's faint atmosphere, the corona...,” ESA stated.</blockquote>
<p>This mission represents a significant step in solar research and is supported by over 40 European companies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://learningenglish.voanews.com/a/europe-launches-mission-to-create-simulated-solar-eclipse/7900218.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://learningenglish.voanews.com/a/europe-launches-mission-to-create-simulated-solar-eclipse/7900218.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Webb Telescope Delivers Amazing 4K Supernova Remnant Cassiopeia A - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 21:25:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch Amazing Views Of Earth And Moon From India’s Aditya-L1 Spacecraft - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 19:30:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rare gamma-ray flare unleashed from a supermassive black hole - Earth.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rare Gamma-Ray Flare Emanates from Supermassive Black Hole in M87</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Published in 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Astronomy and Astrophysics</p>
<img src="https://www.nasa.gov/image.jpg" alt="Gamma-ray flare from black hole M87">
<figcaption>Image Credit: NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses a rare gamma-ray flare detected from the supermassive black hole at the heart of the galaxy M87, offering new insights into the physical mechanisms of particle acceleration near black holes.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The flare was emitted from the black hole in 2018 and lasted approximately three days.</li>
  <li>It marked the first gamma-ray flaring event observed from this source in over a decade.</li>
  <li>The flare's photons reached energy levels of several teraelectronvolts (TeV).</li>
  <li>The emission region was estimated to be about ten times the size of the black hole.</li>
  <li>The findings were part of an international observational campaign involving over 25 telescopes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We were lucky to detect a gamma-ray flare from M87 during this Event Horizon Telescope’s multi-wavelength campaign.” - Giacomo Principe</blockquote>
<p>This discovery underscores the significance of collaborative research in astrophysics and opens avenues for further studies on supermassive black holes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.earth.com/news/rare-gamma-ray-flare-unleashed-from-a-supermassive-black-hole/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.earth.com/news/rare-gamma-ray-flare-unleashed-from-a-supermassive-black-hole/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 19:29:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mysterious 'Alien-Like' Creature Discovered By Scientists In Deep Ocean, Revealing Unexplored Marine World - Jagran English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mysterious 'Alien-Like' Creature Discovered By Scientists In Deep Ocean, Revealing Unexplored Marine Worlds</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 11, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> RealClearScience</p><img src="https://imgeng.jagran.com/images/2024/12/15/article/image/Marine-World-1734279668304.jpg" alt="Dulcibella camanchaca (Image credits: WHOI)" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Dulcibella camanchaca (Image credits: WHOI)</figcaption><p>The deep sea remains one of the most mysterious and least understood areas of our planet. Recently, scientists discovered a new species of amphipod named Dulcibella camanchaca in the Atacama Trench, likened to alien-like creatures due to its unique appearance.</p><ul><li>The discovery was made during a 2023 research expedition by the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution and Universidad de Concepción.</li><li>The Atacama Trench is known for harsh conditions, including high pressure and low light.</li><li>The name 'camanchaca' means 'darkness' in an Andean language, reflecting its deep-sea habitat.</li><li>The creature exhibits features that make it comparable to alien species, with a translucent body and elongated limbs.</li><li>This discovery emphasizes the unexplored diversity of life in ocean depths.</li></ul><blockquote>Dulcibella camanchaca: "A bizarre new predator has been discovered lurking 26,000 feet below the ocean's surface and has been named after its pitch-black home." — RealClearScience (@RCScience) December 11, 2024</blockquote><p>As scientists continue to study Dulcibella camanchaca, they aim to uncover further insights into life in the ocean’s depths.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://english.jagran.com/world/mysterious-alienlike-creature-discovered-by-scientists-in-deep-ocean-revealing-unexplored-marine-worlds-10207004</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://english.jagran.com/world/mysterious-alienlike-creature-discovered-by-scientists-in-deep-ocean-revealing-unexplored-marine-worlds-10207004</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 16:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mysterious 'mirror life' bacteria could take out everything on Earth, scientists warn - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:07:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[See the best Geminid meteor shower 2024 photos from around the world - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>See the best Geminid meteor shower 2024 photos from around the world</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/MKdHEnUPqZkP9CyGEZFM7J-1200-80.jpg" alt="Night sky showing the Milky Way and meteor streaks." loading="lazy">
<figcaption>(Image credit: Daisy Dobrijevic/Canva)</figcaption>
<p>The Geminid meteor shower dazzled skywatchers this week with stunning displays captured across the globe, even under the challenge of a full moon.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Geminids are known for their bright meteors and high hourly rates.</li>
<li>Photographer Osama Fathi captured impressive images of the shower from Egypt's Black Desert.</li>
<li>In Hawaii, the Subaru Telescope recorded over 150 meteors in one hour despite bright moonlight.</li>
<li>Amateur astronomers shared their best captures from various locations including Canada and Japan, showcasing the meteors along with notable celestial objects.</li>
<li>Various photographers documented unique phenomena during the shower, including multiple meteors appearing simultaneously.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Despite the meteor shower coinciding with a full moon this year, I managed to capture this image before its peak, successfully recording several meteors despite the presence of some light clouds that added an artistic touch to the light." - Osama Fathi</blockquote>
<p>The Geminid meteor shower continues to be a highlight for astronomers and astronomy enthusiasts alike, proving that even challenging conditions can yield breathtaking celestial displays.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/stargazing/meteors-showers/best-geminid-meteor-shower-2024-photos-from-around-the-world</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/stargazing/meteors-showers/best-geminid-meteor-shower-2024-photos-from-around-the-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:06:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Korean researchers make cost breakthrough in electrochemical CO2 Reduction via recyclable CuZn electrodes - Biofuels Digest]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.biofuelsdigest.com/bdigest/korean-researchers-make-cost-breakthrough-in-electrochemical-co2-reduction-via-recyclable-cuzn-electrodes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.biofuelsdigest.com/bdigest/korean-researchers-make-cost-breakthrough-in-electrochemical-co2-reduction-via-recyclable-cuzn-electrodes/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:52:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Majestic Pictures Of Space Captured By NASA - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Majestic Pictures Of Space Captured By NASA</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now Digital</p><img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116340896/116340896.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=1321706" alt="5 Majestic Pictures Of Space Captured By NASA"><figcaption>Credit: Times Now</figcaption><p>This article showcases five stunning images of space captured by NASA’s advanced telescopes, highlighting various celestial phenomena.</p><ul><li>NGC 3603: A brilliant cluster of young stars resembling a fireworks display.</li><li>Eta Carinae: A massive star on the verge of a supernova explosion.</li><li>Helix Nebula: A breathtaking view combining detailed and expansive perspectives.</li><li>Starburst Galaxy NGC 1569: An extraordinary starburst galaxy producing stars at an accelerated rate.</li><li>Carina Nebula: A view revealing hidden stellar nurseries and vibrant regions of star formation.</li></ul><blockquote>“Together, they create a seamless and breathtaking view of the Helix Nebula.”</blockquote><p>This collection reveals the beauty and complexity of the universe, demonstrating NASA's capabilities in astrophotography.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/5-majestic-pictures-of-space-captured-by-nasa/photostory/116340878.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/5-majestic-pictures-of-space-captured-by-nasa/photostory/116340878.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:30:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subabul seeds and insulin resistance management - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Subabul Seeds and Insulin Resistance Management</h1><p><strong>Updated - December 15, 2024</strong> at The Hindu Business Line</p><img src="https://bl-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/9lehle/article68988933.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/BL1612_Quantum_Lab01.jpg" alt="Subabul or Leucaena leucocephala" title="Subabul or Leucaena leucocephala" /><figcaption>Subabul or <i>Leucaena leucocephala</i> | Photo Credit: HemantPhotographer</figcaption><p>Researchers at the Institute of Advanced Study in Science and Technology have explored the potential of Subabul seeds in managing insulin resistance associated with type II diabetes, leading to the development of four active bio-compounds.</p><ul><li>Subabul, also known as <i>Leucaena leucocephala</i>, is a fast-growing tree found in tropical regions.</li><li>The leaves and seeds are nutritious and consumed in various forms.</li><li>Scientists developed a marker-assisted fraction to analyze the seeds' therapeutic properties.</li><li>The study underscores the importance of traditional plants in modern medicinal research.</li></ul><blockquote>“The therapeutic potential of Subabul highlights its importance in managing diabetes.”</blockquote><p>This research opens new avenues for utilizing traditional plants in managing metabolic disorders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/business-tech/subabul-seeds-and-insulin-resistance-management/article68988928.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/business-tech/subabul-seeds-and-insulin-resistance-management/article68988928.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:07:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why NISAR is a unique satellite, a remarkable mission - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why NISAR is a unique satellite, a remarkable mission</h1>
<p><strong>Updated on:</strong> December 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu Business Line</p>
<img src="https://bl-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/rer21u/article68988830.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/nisar.jpg" alt="Artist’s concept of NISAR satellite in orbit" title="Artist’s concept of NISAR satellite in orbit">
<figcaption>SINGULAR MISSION: Artist’s concept of NISAR satellite in orbit | Photo Credit: NASA/JPL-CALTECH</figcaption>
<p>Come March 2025, a significant space event will unfold with the launch of the 2.8-tonne NISAR satellite by ISRO. This satellite is the result of a notable India-US collaboration started in 2009, aiming to advance earth monitoring capabilities.</p>
<ul>
  <li>NISAR is a ‘synthetic aperture radar’ (SAR) satellite with capabilities that surpass its predecessors.</li>
  <li>It will measure surface motions, such as ice sheets and vegetation changes, down to fractions of an inch.</li>
  <li>The satellite will have a 12-day revisit cycle to monitor changes in designated locations.</li>
  <li>NISAR will produce 26 terabits of data per day, significantly aiding in disaster management and climate research.</li>
  <li>It employs innovative technologies like digital beam forming for enhanced imaging.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“NISAR mission is a new frontier” - Rakesh Bhan, former ISRO scientist.</blockquote>
<p>The NISAR satellite embodies a technological advancement in synthetic aperture radar, playing a crucial role in environmental monitoring and disaster response.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/business-tech/why-nisar-is-a-unique-satellite-a-remarkable-mission/article68988804.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/business-tech/why-nisar-is-a-unique-satellite-a-remarkable-mission/article68988804.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:43:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA warns, asteroids 2024 XY5 and 2024 XB6 race toward Earth — but are they really a threat? - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/world/nasa-warns-asteroids-2024-xy5-and-2024-xb6-race-toward-earth-but-are-they-really-a-threat-784185</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/world/nasa-warns-asteroids-2024-xy5-and-2024-xb6-race-toward-earth-but-are-they-really-a-threat-784185</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:38:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA warns: Asteroids 2024 XY5 and 2024 XB6 race toward Earth — But are they really a threat? - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/world/nasa-warns-asteroids-2024-xy5-and-2024-xb6-race-toward-earth-but-are-they-really-a-threat-784185</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/world/nasa-warns-asteroids-2024-xy5-and-2024-xb6-race-toward-earth-but-are-they-really-a-threat-784185</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:38:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astrophysics & Astronomy Institute to be Established in Honor of Pathani Samanta: Majhi – Employment & Education - E2India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxNaS13b2lvVjFHSmhLR3R2bHpkbjEzMzJHVFFKYTQzalBfNEwxaDY4Mk1GM1otTlB2c2g4WTBZWXZONElENklXd3ljWEE2MWctekVyWXQ1ZGVlUkctejJhaFh0TGQ1R3NZSmljTUdhdVFPUWN4MWZzWVJxb1VXVS1KaHVhQ1U1S0wwdkdPalJZUXJ0VDhfUG80REVwNnM5MVVTSklkMGlTaVJDUHN3UWxDbUR4T1luMk5tM1hV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxNaS13b2lvVjFHSmhLR3R2bHpkbjEzMzJHVFFKYTQzalBfNEwxaDY4Mk1GM1otTlB2c2g4WTBZWXZONElENklXd3ljWEE2MWctekVyWXQ1ZGVlUkctejJhaFh0TGQ1R3NZSmljTUdhdVFPUWN4MWZzWVJxb1VXVS1KaHVhQ1U1S0wwdkdPalJZUXJ0VDhfUG80REVwNnM5MVVTSklkMGlTaVJDUHN3UWxDbUR4T1luMk5tM1hV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:33:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>