<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:24:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:24:23 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA confirms Parker Solar Probe made close approach to the Sun - Euronews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Parker Solar Probe Makes Historic Close Approach to the Sun</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Latest Update</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>The Parker Solar Probe has successfully made the closest approach to the Sun, setting a record by coming within six million kilometers of the Sun's surface.</p><ul><li>The probe passed through the Sun's outer atmosphere, known as the corona.</li><li>It achieved speeds of 690,000 kph during its close approach.</li><li>The heat shield of the Parker can withstand temperatures reaching up to 1,370 degrees Celsius.</li><li>This mission aims to provide insights into the reasons behind the Sun's corona being significantly hotter than its surface.</li><li>Parker Solar Probe was launched in 2018 and is expected to continue orbiting the Sun until at least September.</li></ul><blockquote>“Parker Solar Probe was developed as part of NASA’s Living With a Star program to explore aspects of the Sun-Earth system that directly affect life and society,” said NASA in a statement.</blockquote><p>This successful mission is a significant step in understanding solar phenomena and their impact on Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.euronews.com/2024/12/28/nasa-confirms-solar-probe-has-made-record-breaking-close-approach-to-the-sun</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.euronews.com/2024/12/28/nasa-confirms-solar-probe-has-made-record-breaking-close-approach-to-the-sun</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 05:26:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China's new radio telescopes put into use for deep space exploration - CGTN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's New Radio Telescopes Enhance Deep Space Exploration</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Friday, Location: China</p><p>Two radio telescopes with 40-meter-diameter antennas have been launched to aid in deep space exploration and decoding cosmic mysteries, located in northeast and southwest China.</p><ul><li>The telescopes were built by the Shanghai Astronomical Observatory in Jilin Province and Xizang Autonomous Region.</li><li>China's Very-Long-Baseline Interferometry network now includes a control center in Shanghai and six stations, enhancing observational capabilities.</li><li>The telescopes allow for high-precision positioning and combining signals for a larger effective aperture in cosmic observation.</li><li>Observable sky area is expanded by 25%, with angular resolution improved by 18% in the X-band.</li><li>Previous missions supported include lunar exploration from Chang'e-1 to Chang'e-6 and the Mars mission Tianwen-1.</li><li>The telescopes will bolster future lunar and deep space missions.</li></ul><blockquote>“The two new telescopes will play an important role in future lunar exploration, as well as deep space missions...” – Ye Shuhua, Academician of CAS</blockquote><p>In conclusion, these advancements mark a significant step in China's capability for exploring the cosmos, supporting various scientific endeavors and enhancing international collaborations in astrophysical research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.cgtn.com/news/2024-12-28/China-s-new-radio-telescopes-put-into-use-for-deep-space-exploration-1zGWdKD1yiQ/p.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.cgtn.com/news/2024-12-28/China-s-new-radio-telescopes-put-into-use-for-deep-space-exploration-1zGWdKD1yiQ/p.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 01:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Just Proved Your Brain Operates at the Speed of a Snail—and It’s Shockingly Low - The Daily Galaxy --Great Discoveries Channel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Just Proved Your Brain Operates at the Speed of a Snail—and It’s Shockingly Low</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>Recent research from <strong>Caltech</strong> reveals that the human brain processes conscious thought at just <strong>10 bits per second</strong>, a speed dramatically slower than the billion bits per second our senses can collect, prompting important questions about cognitive capabilities.</p>
<img src='[Image URL]' alt='[Image Alt Text]' />
<figcaption>This graphic illustrates the disparity between sensory input and conscious thought processing speeds.</figcaption>
<p><strong>The 10-Bit Bottleneck:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Despite having <strong>85 billion neurons</strong>, only <strong>10 bits per second</strong> are processed consciously.</li>
<li>This processing speed is significantly slower than modern technologies like Wi-Fi.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Every moment, we are extracting just 10 bits from the trillion that our senses are taking in,” said Markus Meister, highlighting the stark difference between brain capacity and processing speed.</blockquote>
<p><strong>Evolutionary Implications:</strong> The research suggests that this limitation evolved as early nervous systems focused on basic survival tasks.</p>
<ul>
<li>Single-task focusing exemplifies the brain's slow yet precise processing.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our ancestors evolved in a world slow enough to make survival possible,” notes Zheng and Meister.</blockquote>
<p><strong>Impact on Future Technologies:</strong> The findings challenge expectations for brain-machine interfaces that aim to enhance communication speeds.</p>
<ul>
<li>Neural links would still be restricted by the brain's processing limit.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Future Research Directions:</strong> The study calls for more exploration into how the brain prioritizes sensory information.</p>
<ul>
<li>Understanding this selection is crucial to unlocking human cognition's architecture.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Redefining Intelligence:</strong> This study encourages defining intelligence not by speed but through an efficient and deliberate approach to processing information.</p>
<p>The findings reaffirm the complexity of human thought, revealing the balancing act between efficiency and precision in cognitive functions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://dailygalaxy.com/2024/12/scientists-just-proved-your-brain-operates-at-the-speed-of-a-snail-and-its-shockingly-low/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dailygalaxy.com/2024/12/scientists-just-proved-your-brain-operates-at-the-speed-of-a-snail-and-its-shockingly-low/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:18:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists develop an AI model that mimics human brain function - INDIAai]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxQTS1NRkEyczVNU0lPYk9RWW5JUE9NZEVoMnlxdl9BZUVlYjBqbkVJMHpDcUFpZHdQU2VveFBvU2FIbTEwZm9iaWdDT3RhRG1FUzJDRzhoTm5DeWRnUF96REUzaDIzaUlFWUxaV0lkOVV5UEhKOFpsRm1xb1o3VmQwWU5FSHhTQ0l0YjZ3VWlJaXN3TGJxUGpMc21R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxQTS1NRkEyczVNU0lPYk9RWW5JUE9NZEVoMnlxdl9BZUVlYjBqbkVJMHpDcUFpZHdQU2VveFBvU2FIbTEwZm9iaWdDT3RhRG1FUzJDRzhoTm5DeWRnUF96REUzaDIzaUlFWUxaV0lkOVV5UEhKOFpsRm1xb1o3VmQwWU5FSHhTQ0l0YjZ3VWlJaXN3TGJxUGpMc21R?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 21:27:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US News Live Today December 28, 2024: What is Kessler Syndrome? The growing threat of space junk and collisions - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Understanding Kessler Syndrome: The Growing Threat of Space Junk</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/photo-1446776709462-d6b525c57bd3_1735333518352_1735333523705.jpg" alt="US News Live: What is Kessler Syndrome? The growing threat of space junk and collisions" title="US News Live: What is Kessler Syndrome? The growing threat of space junk and collisions"><figcaption>US News Live: What is Kessler Syndrome? The growing threat of space junk and collisions</figcaption></img><p>The article discusses the increasing concern regarding Kessler Syndrome, a scenario where the density of objects in low Earth orbit makes collisions more likely, leading to a cascade of debris. The European Space Agency (ESA) warns that without intervention, this could jeopardize future space travel.</p><ul><li>ESA warns that unchecked debris accumulation could lead to Kessler Syndrome, rendering space travel impossible in the future.</li></ul><blockquote>“Unchecked debris accumulation could lead to Kessler Syndrome...”</blockquote><p>This information highlights the critical need for addressing space debris to ensure the sustainability of space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/latest-us-news-live-updates-december-28-2024-101735328044303.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/latest-us-news-live-updates-december-28-2024-101735328044303.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 21:08:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Webb Telescope: Dead Galaxies, Red Dots, and Discoveries in 3 Years - Observer Voice]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxNd1JucXYyV0NhZzZMN1lFWXFhUnRxMVd6amlDenhiczNGRGNnbzVOT3pBVmlIbVdWTlczSmxTMV9ndTNPWEZzcG1pb19fSWRFQnFYcXQ4bThBeDB1S2VLVGZoNm5ydTY3aXhWS3VTVm14LThMRUl5WlYxcDNXZUdSVjFFSXJlcjFtSDVnaXlVMDZWN0k1RzRnR3FFd1JsR21UdlpkdEJ3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxNd1JucXYyV0NhZzZMN1lFWXFhUnRxMVd6amlDenhiczNGRGNnbzVOT3pBVmlIbVdWTlczSmxTMV9ndTNPWEZzcG1pb19fSWRFQnFYcXQ4bThBeDB1S2VLVGZoNm5ydTY3aXhWS3VTVm14LThMRUl5WlYxcDNXZUdSVjFFSXJlcjFtSDVnaXlVMDZWN0k1RzRnR3FFd1JsR21UdlpkdEJ3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 19:22:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Parker Solar Probe Makes History With Closest Pass to Sun - Science@NASA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe Makes History With Closest Pass to Sun</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NASA Science</p>
<img src="https://science.nasa.gov/_nuxt/404-bg.B-eOJ4h_.jpg" alt="NASA Parker Solar Probe" />
<figcaption>Parker Solar Probe image</figcaption>
<p>The Parker Solar Probe has accomplished a historic milestone by making the closest-ever approach to the Sun.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Parker Solar Probe traveled within a remarkable distance of the Sun's surface.</li>
  <li>This mission aims to gather data on solar winds and the Sun's atmosphere.</li>
  <li>The probe's findings could enhance understanding of solar behavior and its impact on Earth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This mission represents a groundbreaking achievement in solar exploration,” said a NASA spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>This event marks a significant step in space exploration, providing insights that could shape future solar research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://science.nasa.gov/science-research/heliophysics/nasas-parker-solar-probe-makes-history-with-closest-pass-to-sun/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://science.nasa.gov/science-research/heliophysics/nasas-parker-solar-probe-makes-history-with-closest-pass-to-sun/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 18:22:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space is in the grip of Kessler Syndrome, thanks to growing debris - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxNeGhwaHFaM2dKNFlTZXRZbVQxSmd3a2I3Sk10Zi1udndyZ1VXMS1VSnJKcHlzNW5CVVVHRnptajlHSkM3QXp2LXFXNGhpUlV3dWdyTUtGOExaUVJTY3ByNVhjbUQ0SDZMcVlLcXFyZVU3NVk5WUZxSFVwZnlFd3FuX1F6dm5jaVQ2OEFiaGtzNWU1cUEtTTB1V3hkNzRBMmRkaFA4WUl4bFVTZXp3cU1LOTRMcWNBeU55SHZpdlpxeDRQTGVDWFBhenh6cWMwUWhw0gHWAUFVX3lxTE1DU0ZrN2dQZjJBd3QzS2x5ZE9Cbzd3c1k1X2tQTkpvaEdFU0k4TXBDR0lUODVkY0ticWVpYjVOYnpJaUwtellESHVDNk9rZUNmd0pBLWZENGkwSVJYekZGSlhWdVB1ME82dGNEMzQ1UUp5WmpqQzNRYldnakRyT0RKY0RnSDJqRHh4VllXckliSXQySzk4VG83ODgyTkdlSXk5TllDY3hWUEl6VnJ2OU1JdWRVLUxsS192THIwSEpldGxOUlhUNlpyY0J1b2x2a0Qzc2NGWlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxNeGhwaHFaM2dKNFlTZXRZbVQxSmd3a2I3Sk10Zi1udndyZ1VXMS1VSnJKcHlzNW5CVVVHRnptajlHSkM3QXp2LXFXNGhpUlV3dWdyTUtGOExaUVJTY3ByNVhjbUQ0SDZMcVlLcXFyZVU3NVk5WUZxSFVwZnlFd3FuX1F6dm5jaVQ2OEFiaGtzNWU1cUEtTTB1V3hkNzRBMmRkaFA4WUl4bFVTZXp3cU1LOTRMcWNBeU55SHZpdlpxeDRQTGVDWFBhenh6cWMwUWhw0gHWAUFVX3lxTE1DU0ZrN2dQZjJBd3QzS2x5ZE9Cbzd3c1k1X2tQTkpvaEdFU0k4TXBDR0lUODVkY0ticWVpYjVOYnpJaUwtellESHVDNk9rZUNmd0pBLWZENGkwSVJYekZGSlhWdVB1ME82dGNEMzQ1UUp5WmpqQzNRYldnakRyT0RKY0RnSDJqRHh4VllXckliSXQySzk4VG83ODgyTkdlSXk5TllDY3hWUEl6VnJ2OU1JdWRVLUxsS192THIwSEpldGxOUlhUNlpyY0J1b2x2a0Qzc2NGWlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:45:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Parker Solar Probe survives close brush with Sun’s scorching surface - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe Survives Close Brush with Sun’s Scorching Surface</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> Friday<br><strong>Source: </strong> The Tribune</p><p>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe has made a historic close approach to the sun, coming within a record-breaking 3.8 million miles (6 million kilometers) of its surface, successfully confirming its survival after the journey.</p><ul><li>The probe was launched in 2018 to study the sun up close.</li><li>During its recent approach, it reached speeds of 430,000 mph (690,000 kph).</li><li>The spacecraft is equipped with a heat shield capable of withstanding temperatures up to 2,500 degrees Fahrenheit (1,370 degrees Celsius).</li><li>Scientists aim to use the data collected to understand the sun’s outer atmosphere and solar wind better.</li></ul><blockquote>“The data from Parker will help them better understand why the sun’s outer atmosphere is hundreds of times hotter than its surface.”</blockquote><p>This remarkable achievement demonstrates the advances in space exploration technology, highlighting the Parker Solar Probe's contributions to solar science.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/science-technology/nasas-parker-solar-probe-survives-close-brush-with-suns-scorching-surface/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/science-technology/nasas-parker-solar-probe-survives-close-brush-with-suns-scorching-surface/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:28:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Parker Solar Probe ‘safe’ after record-breaking brush with scorching surface, ‘phones home’ after several days | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe ‘safe’ after record-breaking brush with scorching surface, ‘phones home’ after several days</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent Update | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>The Parker Solar Probe has successfully survived its closest approach to the Sun, reaching within 6 million kilometers of the star’s surface. NASA confirmed that the spacecraft is safe and continues to operate normally after its historic flyby.</p><ul><li>The Parker Solar Probe flew within 3.8 million miles (approximately 6 million kilometers) of the solar surface, marking the closest approach ever made by a human-made object.</li><li>The probe reported back to NASA on December 26, confirming its health and operational status after a brief period of silence during the flyby.</li><li>Launched in 2018, the Parker Solar Probe aims to study the Sun’s corona and the solar wind, contributing to our understanding of solar dynamics.</li><li>The spacecraft is equipped with a heat shield capable of withstanding temperatures up to 1370°C.</li><li>Scientists are hopeful that data collected during this mission will illuminate longstanding questions regarding the Sun's atmospheric temperatures and dynamics.</li></ul><blockquote>“Parker Solar Probe has phoned home! After passing just 3.8 million miles from the solar surface... we have received Parker Solar Probe’s beacon tone confirming the spacecraft is safe,” NASA stated.</blockquote><p>The successful operations and data collection from the Parker Solar Probe contribute valuable insights into solar physics, aiming to unravel mysteries about the Sun that affect space weather and, by extension, life on Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/news/nasas-parker-solar-probe-safe-after-record-breaking-brush-with-scorching-surface-phones-home-after-several-days-11735315988675.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/news/nasas-parker-solar-probe-safe-after-record-breaking-brush-with-scorching-surface-phones-home-after-several-days-11735315988675.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Mesmerising Images Of Star Clusters Taken By NASA Hubble Space Telescope - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Mesmerising Images Of Star Clusters Taken By NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/116721463/116721463.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=2235620" alt="7 Mesmerising Images Of Star Clusters Taken By NASA Hubble Space Telescope">
<figcaption>Credit: NASA-ESA-and-the-Hubble-Heritage-STScI/AURA-ESA/Hubble-Collaboration</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases stunning images of various star clusters captured by the NASA Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting their unique features and significance in the universe.</p>
<ul>
<li>NGC 3603: A vibrant star-forming region with a dense star cluster at its center.</li>
<li>R136: Home to some of the most massive stars discovered in the universe.</li>
<li>NGC 6397: One of the nearest globular clusters to Earth at approximately 7,800 light-years away.</li>
<li>30 Doradus: The largest and most active star-forming region in our galaxy.</li>
<li>Artist’s Concept of the Arches Cluster: Known for its dense collection of young stars located near the Milky Way’s center.</li>
<li>NGC 346: Part of the most energetic star-forming region in the Small Magellanic Cloud.</li>
<li>N11: An area in the Large Magellanic Cloud known for its active star formation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"These stunning images reveal the beauty and complexity of star formation in our universe." - Sparsh Sharma</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the photographs serve to remind us of the vastness and splendor of the cosmos, encouraging further exploration and understanding of our universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-mesmerising-images-of-star-clusters-taken-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/116721450.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/technology/7-mesmerising-images-of-star-clusters-taken-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope/photostory/116721450.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:00:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Will Miss Seeing Three Of The Four Eclipses In 2025, Says Ujjain Observatory - NDTV Profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Will Miss Seeing Three Of The Four Eclipses In 2025, Says Ujjain Observatory</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 27 Dec 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><img src="https://media.assettype.com/bloombergquint%2F2024-04%2F4ed5c6f2-9195-4f23-854e-ff5f9c50c87a%2FiStock_1412675099.jpg?w=1200" alt="A visual representation of eclipses" /><figcaption>(istock photo)</figcaption><p>The year 2025 will offer two solar and two lunar eclipses, but only one will be visible in India, according to Dr. Rajendra Prakash Gupt from the Jiwaji Observatory.</p><ul><li>One total lunar eclipse on March 14 will not be visible in India as it occurs during the day.</li><li>A partial solar eclipse on March 29 will also be missed in India, visible only from North America and Europe.</li><li>A full lunar eclipse between September 7 and 8 will be visible in India and several other regions.</li><li>The final eclipse in 2025 will be a partial solar eclipse from September 21 to 22, which India will miss.</li></ul><blockquote>“This partial solar eclipse will be visible in New Zealand, Eastern Melanesia, Southern Polynesia and West Antarctica,” said Gupt.</blockquote><p>India will have to wait for the one opportunity to witness a full lunar eclipse in 2025 amidst several missed opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtvprofit.com/nation/india-will-miss-seeing-three-of-the-four-eclipses-in-2025-says-ujjain-observatory</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtvprofit.com/nation/india-will-miss-seeing-three-of-the-four-eclipses-in-2025-says-ujjain-observatory</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:26:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why NASA scientists are surprised by the discovery of 'tipped-over' black hole - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Surprising Discovery of a Tipped-Over Black Hole</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> DNA India</p><img src="https://cdn.dnaindia.com/sites/default/files/2024/12/27/2669058-manmohan-singh-12.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(1200,900)" alt="Why NASA scientists are surprised by the discovery of 'tipped-over' black hole" width="640" height="480"><figcaption>Why NASA scientists are surprised by the discovery of 'tipped-over' black hole</figcaption><p>NASA scientists are puzzled by a new discovery regarding a supermassive black hole in the galaxy NGC 5084. This finding challenges existing assumptions about black holes.</p><ul><li>This black hole exhibits unexpected behavior, as revealed by new imaging techniques on old data.</li><li>Four long plumes of hot plasma were discovered, arranged in a unique 'X' shape.</li><li>The black hole and its dusty disk are tilted 90 degrees relative to the galaxy's plane.</li><li>Such orientation suggests a possible past collision with another galaxy.</li></ul><blockquote>“This tilted position is not what scientists expected and adds a new layer to our understanding of black holes.”</blockquote><p>This discovery not only reveals surprising traits of black holes but also prompts questions about their formation and evolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dnaindia.com/science/report-why-nasa-scientists-are-surprised-by-the-discovery-of-tipped-over-black-hole-3124561</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dnaindia.com/science/report-why-nasa-scientists-are-surprised-by-the-discovery-of-tipped-over-black-hole-3124561</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Study Reveals Chimpanzees Exhibit Varying Nut-Cracking Skills Within Same Group - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Some Chimpanzees Crack Nuts Better than Others, New Study Shows</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/UVMrH-cGuss/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Chimpanzees Nut Cracking Video" /><figcaption>Video showing chimpanzees cracking nuts.</figcaption><p>A recent study has highlighted significant variations in nut-cracking abilities among chimpanzees in the same group, suggesting differences in cognitive and motor skills.</p><ul><li>The research team analyzed 3,882 video instances of chimps attempting to crack nuts.</li><li>Five key factors measured included time taken, success rates, and the efficiency of different chimps.</li><li>Findings showed that proficiency in nut cracking generally improved with age.</li><li>No significant differences were found between male and female chimp nut-cracking skills.</li></ul><blockquote>“This research underscores the complexity of chimpanzee behaviour and provides a window into their problem-solving capabilities.”</blockquote><p>This study enhances our understanding of primate tool use and cognitive variation, shedding light on behaviors that could parallel early human technological developments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/chimpanzees-show-varying-nut-cracking-skills-study-finds-differences-in-tool-use-7342406</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/science/news/chimpanzees-show-varying-nut-cracking-skills-study-finds-differences-in-tool-use-7342406</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA spacecraft Parker Solar Probe ‘safe’ after closest-ever approach to the Sun - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Parker Solar Probe Safely Completes Historic Close Approach to the Sun</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/SPACE-EXPLORATION-SUN-0_1735306250088_1735306353427.JPG" alt="A 2018 artist's concept shows the Parker Solar Probe spacecraft flying into the Sun's outer atmosphere, called the corona, on a mission to help scientists learn more about the Sun. (via REUTERS)"><figcaption>A 2018 artist's concept shows the Parker Solar Probe spacecraft flying into the Sun's outer atmosphere, called the corona, on a mission to help scientists learn more about the Sun. (via REUTERS)</figcaption><p>NASA's Parker Solar Probe has successfully completed its closest approach to the Sun, coming within 3.8 million miles (6.1 million km) of the solar surface and entering the corona. The spacecraft is reported to be in good health and operational.</p><ul><li>The Parker Solar Probe transmitted a beacon signal confirming its status after the record-breaking approach.</li><li>The mission aims to enhance understanding of how solar material heats to millions of degrees and the origin of solar wind.</li><li>Traveling at speeds of up to 430,000 mph, the probe endured extreme temperatures of 1,800°F (982°C).</li><li>Mission Operations Manager Nick Pinkine noted the unprecedented nature of the probe's journey into uncharted territory.</li></ul><blockquote>“This close-up study of the Sun allows Parker Solar Probe to take measurements that help scientists better understand how material in this region gets heated to millions of degrees.” – NASA</blockquote><p>This successful mission marks a significant step in solar exploration and understanding the dynamics of our nearest star.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/science/nasa-spacecraft-parker-solar-probe-safe-after-closest-ever-approach-to-the-sun-101735306115792.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/science/nasa-spacecraft-parker-solar-probe-safe-after-closest-ever-approach-to-the-sun-101735306115792.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:09:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025 To Witness Four Eclipses Including Two Solar & Two Lunar, Only One Will Be Visible In India, Says Jiwaji - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2025 To Witness Four Eclipses Including Two Solar & Two Lunar, Only One Will Be Visible In India, Says Jiwaji</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Published on: December 27, 2024 - Source: Jiwaji Observatory</p><p>The year 2025 will have a total of four eclipses, comprising two solar and two lunar eclipses, but only one will be visible in India. The Jiwaji Observatory based in Ujjain provided details about the upcoming astronomical events.</p><ul><li>March 14: Full lunar eclipse (not visible in India)</li><li>March 29: Partial solar eclipse (not visible in India)</li><li>September 7 and 8: Full lunar eclipse (visible in India)</li><li>September 21 and 22: Partial solar eclipse (not visible in India)</li></ul><blockquote>“Indian astronomy lovers can be excited by the fact that the full lunar eclipse occurring between September 7 and 8 will be visible in the country.” - Dr Rajendra Prakash Gupt</blockquote><p>While 2024 had four celestial events, 2025 continues to generate interest among astronomy enthusiasts due to its limited visibility.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/indore/2025-to-witness-four-eclipses-including-two-solar-two-lunar-only-one-will-be-visible-in-india-says-jiwaji-observatory-ujjain</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/indore/2025-to-witness-four-eclipses-including-two-solar-two-lunar-only-one-will-be-visible-in-india-says-jiwaji-observatory-ujjain</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:40:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Growing Threat of Space Debris: Understanding the Kessler Syndrome - The Africa Logistics]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Growing Threat of Space Debris: Understanding the Kessler Syndrome</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> theafricalogistics.com</p><p>The Kessler Syndrome highlights the dangers of space debris and its catastrophic implications for modern satellites and technology. With increasing satellite launches, the threat of collisions in low Earth orbit looms larger.</p><h4>Key Points:</h4><ul><li><strong>Satellite Mega-Constellations:</strong> The increase in satellites for global internet services raises collision risks.</li><li><strong>Rocket Breakups:</strong> Recent disintegration of rockets adds to space debris concerns.</li><li><strong>Close Calls in Space:</strong> Near-collisions are on the rise, endangering existing satellite infrastructure.</li><li><strong>Rising Media Awareness:</strong> Global media emphasizes the urgency of addressing space debris.</li></ul><h4>Efforts to Mitigate the Threat:</h4><ul><li><strong>Active Debris Removal:</strong> Developing technologies for capturing and removing space debris.</li><li><strong>Smarter Satellite Design:</strong> Innovations like drag sails aim to reduce debris at the end of satellite lifecycles.</li><li><strong>International Guidelines:</strong> UNOOSA promotes responsible space practices to minimize debris.</li><li><strong>Collision Avoidance Systems:</strong> Advanced tracking systems are crucial for preventing impacts.</li></ul><h4>Conclusion:</h4><p>The risks of Kessler Syndrome urge for global action to manage space debris effectively and sustainably.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theafricalogistics.com/the-growing-threat-of-space-debris-understanding-the-kessler-syndrome/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theafricalogistics.com/the-growing-threat-of-space-debris-understanding-the-kessler-syndrome/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:29:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New molecular details on trans-Neptunian objects - Inceptive Mind]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.inceptivemind.com/blurb/new-molecular-details-trans-neptunian-objects/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.inceptivemind.com/blurb/new-molecular-details-trans-neptunian-objects/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Parker solar probe is 'safe' after historic closest approach to Sun - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Parker solar probe is 'safe' after historic closest approach to Sun</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p>
<p>The Parker Solar Probe has made history by becoming the first man-made object to complete a closest-ever approach to the Sun, and it's reported to be safe and operational.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The probe came within 3.8 million miles of the Sun's surface on December 24, 2023.</li>
  <li>It transmitted a beacon tone indicating good health after the record-breaking approach.</li>
  <li>The mission aims to uncover secrets about solar heat and solar wind.</li>
  <li>The spacecraft is traveling at a speed of 430,000 mph and withstood temperatures up to 1,800 degrees Fahrenheit.</li>
  <li>It has completed 21 passes of the Sun since its launch in 2018.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This close-up study of the Sun allows Parker Solar Probe to take measurements that help scientists better understand how material in this region gets heated to millions of degrees...” - NASA</blockquote>
<p>The detailed telemetry data on the probe's condition is expected on January 1, 2024.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/nasa-s-parker-solar-probe-is-safe-after-historic-closest-approach-to-sun-nc-124122700850_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/nasa-s-parker-solar-probe-is-safe-after-historic-closest-approach-to-sun-nc-124122700850_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:23:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists concerned over major volcanic eruption - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/techandscience/scientists-concerned-over-major-volcanic-eruption/vi-AA1wzfcM</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/en-in/news/techandscience/scientists-concerned-over-major-volcanic-eruption/vi-AA1wzfcM</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:45:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four eclipses in 2025 but only one will be visible in India Ujjain observatory - The Week]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Four Eclipses in 2025: Only One Visible from India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><p>The year 2025 will feature two solar and two lunar eclipses, but only one will be visible from India, according to the Ujjain-based Jiwaji Observatory.</p><ul><li>A total lunar eclipse on March 14 will not be visible in India as it occurs during the daytime here.</li><li>A partial solar eclipse on March 29 will also be missed by Indian observers.</li><li>The full lunar eclipse on September 7-8 will be visible in India and other regions.</li><li>The last eclipse of the year is a partial solar eclipse on September 21-22, which won't be visible in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“Indian astronomy lovers can be excited by the fact that the full lunar eclipse occurring between September 7 and 8 will be visible in the country.” - Dr. Rajendra Prakash Gupt</blockquote><p>In summary, despite multiple eclipses in 2025, only one will allow viewers in India to witness the celestial phenomenon.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theweek.in/wire-updates/national/2024/12/27/bes5-mp-eclipses-newyear.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theweek.in/wire-updates/national/2024/12/27/bes5-mp-eclipses-newyear.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:35:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Great magnetic drift: North Pole’s journey to Siberia - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Great Magnetic Drift: North Pole’s Journey to Siberia</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> 27 December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Telangana Today</p><figure><img width='1200' height='720' src='https://media.telanganatoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/earth-Magnetic-North-Pole-shifts-scaled-1.jpg' alt='Great magnetic drift: North Pole’s journey to Siberia'><figcaption>The magnetic North Pole’s rapid shift toward Siberia disrupts navigation systems and raises concerns about a potential pole reversal.</figcaption></figure><p>The magnetic North Pole is moving towards Russia at an unpredictable pace, causing concern among scientists due to its implications on global navigation systems.</p><ul><li>The magnetic North Pole shifts due to convection currents in Earth’s outer core.</li><li>Recent movements have slowed from 55 km per year to 25 km per year.</li><li>This shift disrupts the World Magnetic Model (WMM) used in GPS and military navigation.</li><li>The movement may signal potential future magnetic pole reversals.</li><li>Robust monitoring is necessary to prepare for possible disruptions.</li></ul><blockquote>“This ongoing polar odyssey underscores the importance of vigilance in an ever-changing world.”</blockquote><p>The shift of the magnetic North Pole toward Siberia raises alarm among scientists and highlights the importance of continued research and monitoring of Earth’s magnetic field.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://telanganatoday.com/great-magnetic-drift-north-poles-journey-to-siberia</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://telanganatoday.com/great-magnetic-drift-north-poles-journey-to-siberia</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:28:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New giant eye for deep space exploration: my country officially launches two 40-meter radio telescopes - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxPb3RSX2NfaVZ2QVl2azF5bVlkSEd1MGktTzA2SVNmVGhGYnFHQks5eGNZbG53LTFQUnpnczJvOGR1Mk9qSkYyRkNVY1NZSlBJVE5ra3dXbFBBRUlHVEllWGpvLVZUVFROVkRPMDV4NDV5SEFXM0NIdTR1NE5KWkNxSUZFV0UyTFVuS2w2bGIya01jdWhqV09xMzFUeW5kZVpETHVlajRRTmNTeUJsSFdaclU2bVM3ZDlyQjZLaTBMRnpBVklzWFZtU2Fn0gHKAUFVX3lxTE9vdFJfY19pVnZBWXZrMXltWWRIR3UwaS1PMDZJU2ZUaEZicUdCSzl4Y1lsbnctMVBSemdzMm84ZHUyT2pKRjJGQ1VjU1lKUElUTmtrd1dsUEFFSUdUSWVYam8tVlRUVE5WRE8wNXg0NXlIQVczQ0h1NHU0TkpaQ3FJRkVXRTJMVW5LbDZsYjJrTWN1aGpXT3EzMVR5bmRlWkRMdWVqNFFOY1N5QmxIV1pyVTZtUzdkOXJCNktpMExGekFWSXNYVm1TYWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygFBVV95cUxPb3RSX2NfaVZ2QVl2azF5bVlkSEd1MGktTzA2SVNmVGhGYnFHQks5eGNZbG53LTFQUnpnczJvOGR1Mk9qSkYyRkNVY1NZSlBJVE5ra3dXbFBBRUlHVEllWGpvLVZUVFROVkRPMDV4NDV5SEFXM0NIdTR1NE5KWkNxSUZFV0UyTFVuS2w2bGIya01jdWhqV09xMzFUeW5kZVpETHVlajRRTmNTeUJsSFdaclU2bVM3ZDlyQjZLaTBMRnpBVklzWFZtU2Fn0gHKAUFVX3lxTE9vdFJfY19pVnZBWXZrMXltWWRIR3UwaS1PMDZJU2ZUaEZicUdCSzl4Y1lsbnctMVBSemdzMm84ZHUyT2pKRjJGQ1VjU1lKUElUTmtrd1dsUEFFSUdUSWVYam8tVlRUVE5WRE8wNXg0NXlIQVczQ0h1NHU0TkpaQ3FJRkVXRTJMVW5LbDZsYjJrTWN1aGpXT3EzMVR5bmRlWkRMdWVqNFFOY1N5QmxIV1pyVTZtUzdkOXJCNktpMExGekFWSXNYVm1TYWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:23:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Parker solar probe makes a historic Sun encounter as fastest man-made object ever: Explained in 10 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Parker Solar Probe Makes Historic Approach to the Sun</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>December 24, 2023<br/><strong>Source: </strong>Economic Times</p><figure><img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116708946,width-650,height-488,imgsize-100518,resizemode-75/parker-solar-probe-nasa-closest-approach-to-sun.jpg" alt="Parker Solar Probe NASA closest approach to Sun" height="488" width="650"><figcaption>The Parker Solar Probe made a fiery dive close to the solar surface on Christmas Eve morning.</figcaption></figure><p>The Parker Solar Probe has successfully made its closest-ever approach to the Sun, coming within 3.86 million miles, setting a record for human-made objects.</p><ul><li>The spacecraft is about the size of a small car and was launched in 2018.</li><li>This closest approach took place on December 24, 2023, within the solar corona.</li><li>The probe is designed to gather data about the Sun's outer atmosphere and solar wind.</li><li>Parker Solar Probe will endure extreme temperatures and speeds, moving at 430,000 mph.</li><li>It aims to solve mysteries regarding solar wind and the temperature of the corona.</li></ul><blockquote>“No human-made object has ever passed this close to a star, so Parker will truly be returning data from uncharted territory.” - Nick Pinkine, Mission Operations Manager</blockquote><p>This monumental achievement marks a significant milestone in solar research, potentially leading to new insights into solar phenomena.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/global-trends/nasas-parker-solar-probe-makes-a-historic-sun-encounter-closest-approach-sun-as-fastest-man-made-object-ever/articleshow/116708722.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/global-trends/nasas-parker-solar-probe-makes-a-historic-sun-encounter-closest-approach-sun-as-fastest-man-made-object-ever/articleshow/116708722.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:46:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA warns! Two airplane-sized asteroids to pass close to Earth tomorrow – here’s what you need to know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA warns! Two airplane-sized asteroids to pass close to Earth tomorrow – here’s what you need to know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116705304,imgsize-39122,width-400,resizemode-4/116705304.jpg" alt="NASA warns! Two airplane-sized asteroids to pass close to Earth tomorrow – here’s what you need to know" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Asteroids 2024 YC1 and 2024 YQ2 are set to make a close approach to Earth.</figcaption><p>In late December 2024, NASA has confirmed that two asteroids, 2024 YC1 and 2024 YQ2, will pass safely close to Earth, occurring at a distance well beyond the danger zone. Despite being a cause for attention, both pose no risk of collision.</p><ul><li>Asteroid 2024 YC1 is approximately 170 feet long and will pass Earth at 639,000 miles away, moving at 20,666 miles per hour.</li><li>Asteroid 2024 YQ2 is smaller, at around 80 feet, and will pass Earth at a slightly higher speed of 23,313 miles per hour.</li><li>Nasa's monitoring of asteroids is critical for planetary defense and understanding solar system formation.</li><li>Ongoing observation and study of NEOs (Near-Earth Objects) help prepare for potential future threats.</li><li>The impacts of past asteroids have had devastating effects on Earth, emphasizing the need for continuous monitoring.</li></ul><blockquote>“One such impact is said to have caused the extinction of dinosaurs about 66 million years ago.”</blockquote><p>The close approaches of 2024 YC1 and 2024 YQ2 reiterate the importance of asteroid monitoring as part of NASA's planetary defense strategy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-warns-two-airplane-sized-asteroids-to-pass-close-to-earth-tomorrow-heres-what-you-need-to-know/articleshow/116704764.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-warns-two-airplane-sized-asteroids-to-pass-close-to-earth-tomorrow-heres-what-you-need-to-know/articleshow/116704764.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Missions List 2025: From Starship Flight 7 Launch to Crew-10 Mission, Here’s Brief on Major - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAJBVV95cUxPVklPLWpBeGVXVEtuQ0YxYU44SExlcnZDN0tmVGpsdzFZT0pNRHdua3k5UVVGQjZwejRySHdFS0RCZVNlR29fbHJlZ3pUTkRjZ0E2RnBrYUNSN0twT3I1TFZfZTJmaUo4QTRSenIwdWJ0YUtiaEo3aHBvUGpZa2Z4Zml3MVNGRXJkd1VmSGtwUWFyUmhYOEpaU3BkUU4zNkt3ZG90eWlpeWNfeGlZMWZSR3ZDWUI3WDlPZUxBMTAwV0pObnY3bFhEdzNUdzIweUpjdGVVVkkxc0lkMUo2WWFqTmhDcG1idXRQMmk3ODY0WkJyclhYY2s3U2VtSDN1VnVGY2V4RUxGRkhIUkNJNnM4RW9TN2NwSGJ4aGwtS0xZdzhXSnVX0gGqAkFVX3lxTFBNZ3JySHNQLUtzcjFXSXg3dk1HeG9VTFBGbnhzMXpJMS1KQjRBWWxVdm9XUWlGLVFoMWo3WlhxbkdKZ096N29FVk54cHhRdmFjd3JjZVJIem56VjRzMW9JTVRTS05RSlQ1MFNyRVg1bU45ZXMtRVFITGc4b2hseWota2JqOUFrR002MS1OQmo1MThNWGlnS1dmY24yaEZ0UGQ3WXQwUWpmMTQ2cG9OYlNIdHBhMy1mSVQ0MjBVblRtMVBvbk5NYXBmSHNsS1Vnc0dSYzlqLU9aa1puR2NwcHNuZGVJM1hDRmhEODVtaFdSc0hHLWFTSHBmRko3V2VjVUNYUW1fc0ZsNk9PYzhKM2twMXVtX0tIbk1nZjhJV3pTZTJMQVdocDloNVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAJBVV95cUxPVklPLWpBeGVXVEtuQ0YxYU44SExlcnZDN0tmVGpsdzFZT0pNRHdua3k5UVVGQjZwejRySHdFS0RCZVNlR29fbHJlZ3pUTkRjZ0E2RnBrYUNSN0twT3I1TFZfZTJmaUo4QTRSenIwdWJ0YUtiaEo3aHBvUGpZa2Z4Zml3MVNGRXJkd1VmSGtwUWFyUmhYOEpaU3BkUU4zNkt3ZG90eWlpeWNfeGlZMWZSR3ZDWUI3WDlPZUxBMTAwV0pObnY3bFhEdzNUdzIweUpjdGVVVkkxc0lkMUo2WWFqTmhDcG1idXRQMmk3ODY0WkJyclhYY2s3U2VtSDN1VnVGY2V4RUxGRkhIUkNJNnM4RW9TN2NwSGJ4aGwtS0xZdzhXSnVX0gGqAkFVX3lxTFBNZ3JySHNQLUtzcjFXSXg3dk1HeG9VTFBGbnhzMXpJMS1KQjRBWWxVdm9XUWlGLVFoMWo3WlhxbkdKZ096N29FVk54cHhRdmFjd3JjZVJIem56VjRzMW9JTVRTS05RSlQ1MFNyRVg1bU45ZXMtRVFITGc4b2hseWota2JqOUFrR002MS1OQmo1MThNWGlnS1dmY24yaEZ0UGQ3WXQwUWpmMTQ2cG9OYlNIdHBhMy1mSVQ0MjBVblRtMVBvbk5NYXBmSHNsS1Vnc0dSYzlqLU9aa1puR2NwcHNuZGVJM1hDRmhEODVtaFdSc0hHLWFTSHBmRko3V2VjVUNYUW1fc0ZsNk9PYzhKM2twMXVtX0tIbk1nZjhJV3pTZTJMQVdocDloNVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:08:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Years After JWST's Launch, Here's What It Has Taught Us About The Universe - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/3-years-after-jwsts-launch-heres-what-it-has-taught-us-about-the-universe</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/3-years-after-jwsts-launch-heres-what-it-has-taught-us-about-the-universe</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:08:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brunhes–Matuyama Reversal: When Earth's Magnetic Field Flips - IFLScience]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Brunhes–Matuyama Reversal: When Earth's Magnetic Field Flips</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> <time datetime="2024-12-26T21:19:18.000Z">15 hours ago</time> <strong>Source:</strong> IFL Science</p><div><img src="https://assets.iflscience.com/assets/articleNo/77396/aImg/81119/magnetic-fields-m.png" alt="Diagram showing the magnetic fields around Earth." loading="lazy"><figcaption>The magnetic fields of Earth, like the Sun, can flip.<br>Image credit: Alones/Shutterstock.com</figcaption></div><p>The Earth's magnetic field can flip over long timescales, such as during the Brunhes–Matuyama reversal, which happened about 780,000 years ago. The poles can move anywhere from 10,000 years to over 50 million years apart, with the last true reversal being a subject of scientific research.</p><ul><li>The Earth's magnetic field is not static and has been recorded to weaken over time.</li><li>Temporary reversal events have been documented, such as the Laschamp event 41,000 years ago.</li><li>Reversal events have significant geological implications, influencing magnetic pole positions and climate.</li><li>Neanderthal extinction and megafauna extinction events have been hypothesized to relate to magnetic shifts, but evidence remains inconclusive.</li></ul><blockquote>“The field geometry of reversed polarity lasted for only about 440 years, and it was associated with a field strength that was only one quarter of today's field.” - Norbert Nowaczyk, GFZ German Research Centre for Geosciences.</blockquote><p>Understanding these magnetic changes is important as they may continue to influence life on Earth, and current predictions about the mobility of the magnetic poles indicate ongoing shifts that could lead to future reversals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.iflscience.com/brunhes-matuyama-reversal-when-earths-magnetic-field-flips-77396</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.iflscience.com/brunhes-matuyama-reversal-when-earths-magnetic-field-flips-77396</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:07:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA’s Parker Solar Probe Reports Successful Closest Approach to Sun - NASA Blogs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA’s Parker Solar Probe Reports Successful Closest Approach to Sun</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 26, 2024 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Johns Hopkins Applied Physics Laboratory</p><p>The Parker Solar Probe successfully made its closest approach to the Sun, transmitting a beacon signal back to Earth indicating its operational status.</p><ul><li>The probe passed approximately 3.8 million miles from the solar surface at speeds nearing 430,000 miles per hour on December 24.</li><li>A signal was received by the mission operations team shortly before midnight EST on December 26.</li><li>Upcoming telemetry data is expected to provide further insights on January 1.</li><li>The mission aims to better understand the heating of solar materials and the origins of solar wind.</li><li>Part of NASA’s Living With a Star program, the probe's mission continues to contribute to solar science.</li></ul><blockquote>“This close-up study of the Sun allows Parker Solar Probe to take measurements that help scientists better understand how material in this region gets heated to millions of degrees.”</blockquote><p>This successful approach reinforces the importance of the Parker Solar Probe in understanding solar phenomena critical to life on Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://blogs.nasa.gov/parkersolarprobe/2024/12/27/nasas-parker-solar-probe-reports-successful-closest-approach-to-sun/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blogs.nasa.gov/parkersolarprobe/2024/12/27/nasas-parker-solar-probe-reports-successful-closest-approach-to-sun/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:00:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[6 Black hole images at the center of galaxy captured by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>6 Black hole images at the center of galaxy captured by NASA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/black-hole-8.jpg" alt="6 Black hole images at the center of galaxy captured by NASA" width="1280" height="768">
<figcaption>6 Black hole images at the center of galaxy captured by NASA</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the impressive images of black holes captured by NASA, highlighting the technological collaboration involved in this monumental achievement.</p>
<ul>
  <li>A black hole is defined as a dense object with an extreme gravitational pull.</li>
  <li>Images were obtained using a global network of eight radio telescopes, functioning as an Earth-sized telescope.</li>
  <li>The first image of a supermassive black hole was obtained in 2019 from the M87 galaxy.</li>
  <li>In 2022, the first image of Sagittarius A*, the black hole at the Milky Way's center, was released.</li>
  <li>The M87 black hole is approximately 6.5 billion times the mass of the Sun, while Sagittarius A* is about 4 million times the mass of the Sun.</li>
  <li>The captured images illustrate the black hole located about 55 million light-years away from Earth.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Thanks For Reading! Next: 7 stunning images of deep space shared by NASA.”</blockquote>
<p>This accomplishment marks a significant milestone in astrophysics, deepening our understanding of black holes and space.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/6-black-hole-images-at-the-center-of-galaxy-captured-by-nasa-7496154/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/6-black-hole-images-at-the-center-of-galaxy-captured-by-nasa-7496154/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:13:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>