<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:27:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:27:28 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nasa’s Mars mission will plug into nuke power - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nasa’s Mars Mission Will Utilize Nuclear Power</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 14, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116398214,imgsize-24806,width-400,resizemode-4/116398214.jpg" alt="Nasa’s Mars mission will plug into nuke power" title="Reuters photo" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Reuters photo</figcaption><p>Nasa has announced plans to use nuclear power for upcoming crewed missions to Mars, with a potential launch around 2035. This decision supports the vision of establishing a sustainable human presence on the Red Planet.</p><ul><li>Nasa has chosen fission (nuclear) power as the primary energy source for Mars missions.</li><li>This decision is part of the “2024 Architecture Concept Review Cycle” aimed at long-term exploration in deep space.</li><li>Nuclear power is preferred over solar due to its consistent power generation, especially during dust storms on Mars.</li><li>A mission with two crew members would require at least 10 kilowatts of energy, while larger crews would need hundreds of kilowatts.</li></ul><blockquote>“Fission can provide consistent power generation for a wide range of potential landing sites round-the-clock and during dust storms.”</blockquote><p>This initiative marks a critical step towards ensuring energy reliability for future Mars explorations, showcasing Nasa's commitment to advancing deep space technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasas-mars-mission-will-plug-into-nuke-power/articleshow/116397936.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasas-mars-mission-will-plug-into-nuke-power/articleshow/116397936.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's urgent asteroid alert: 84-foot airplane-sized asteroid set to pass very close to Earth tomorrow - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasas-urgent-asteroid-alert-84-foot-airplane-sized-asteroid-set-to-pass-very-close-to-earth-tomorrow-article-12891966.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasas-urgent-asteroid-alert-84-foot-airplane-sized-asteroid-set-to-pass-very-close-to-earth-tomorrow-article-12891966.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:03:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA James Webb Space Telescope reveals rocky planet formation in harsh environments - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's James Webb Space Telescope Reveals Rocky Planet Formation in Harsh Environments</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 16, 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> The Astrophysical Journal</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116395242,imgsize-23490,width-400,resizemode-4/116395242.jpg" alt="NASA James Webb Space Telescope" />
<figcaption>Image source: NASA</figcaption>
<p>The recent findings from NASA’s James Webb Space Telescope reveal that planets can form and survive in environments that are much harsher than previously believed. This challenges long-held theories about planet formation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>James Webb Telescope findings suggest long-lasting planet-forming disks exist around stars with low heavy elements.</li>
  <li>Planet-forming disks can survive for tens of millions of years, providing ample time for planets to form.</li>
  <li>Research challenges traditional models that argue planets cannot form in metal-poor environments.</li>
  <li>Implications extend to understanding planet formation in the early universe, potentially dating back to shortly after the Big Bang.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This implies that planets could have begun forming at a much earlier stage in the universe’s history than previously thought.” - Guido De Marchi</blockquote>
<p>The discovery revolutionizes our understanding of planet formation and opens new avenues for research in astronomy, particularly regarding the early universe and the origins of our solar system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-reveals-rocky-planet-formation-in-harsh-environments/articleshow/116394921.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-reveals-rocky-planet-formation-in-harsh-environments/articleshow/116394921.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three asteroids are on their way to Earth - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Three Asteroids Approaching Earth Soon</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 2024 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p>
<img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2024/11/cropped-Asteroid-10ITG-1732178249694.jpg" alt="Asteroids approaching Earth" />
<figcaption>Three asteroids are making close passes by Earth in December 2024.</figcaption>
<p>On December 17, 2024, three asteroids will approach Earth, presenting unique scientific research opportunities. The asteroids include 2022 YO1, 2024 XR6, and 2024 XC17, all deemed non-threatening to the planet.</p>
<ul>
<li>Asteroids 2022 YO1, 2024 XR6, and 2024 XC17 are set for close encounters with Earth.</li>
<li>2022 YO1 will approach within 7,56,604 kilometers and measures 2.6–5.9 meters.</li>
<li>2024 XR6, measuring 12–26 meters, will pass at about 15 million kilometers away.</li>
<li>2024 XC17, measuring 9.1–20 meters, will come within 7.8 million kilometers.</li>
<li>All asteroids pose no threat to Earth and will provide research opportunities for astronomers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Astronomers are tracking the asteroids with advanced systems to study their trajectories, sizes, and compositions, enhancing understanding of near-Earth dynamics.</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming flybys of these asteroids present an excellent opportunity for scientific observation without endangering Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/science/three-asteroids-are-on-their-way-to-earth-195107-17-12-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/science/three-asteroids-are-on-their-way-to-earth-195107-17-12-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:20:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India makes breakthrough discovery in solar system with three suns - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/india-makes-breakthrough-discovery-in-solar-system-with-three-suns/articleshow/116140629.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/india-makes-breakthrough-discovery-in-solar-system-with-three-suns/articleshow/116140629.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World’s first COF sensors: Detecting dehydration in plants - Tech Explorist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techexplorist.com/world-first-cof-sensors-detecting-dehydration-plants/94761/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techexplorist.com/world-first-cof-sensors-detecting-dehydration-plants/94761/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 06:50:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA funded commercial space station Starlab meets crucial developmental milestones - News9 LIVE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Starlab Space Station Achieves Key Development Milestones</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Science News</p><img width="802" height="464" src="https://images.news9live.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Starlab.jpg?w=802&amp;enlarge=true" alt="Illustration of Starlab. (Image Credit: Starlab)." title="Starlab"><figcaption>Illustration of Starlab. (Image Credit: Starlab).</figcaption><p>Starlab is a NASA-funded commercial space station initiative aimed at ensuring the continuity of scientific operations as the International Space Station approaches retirement. The project has successfully met multiple developmental milestones.</p><ul><li>Starlab has passed reviews for its habitat structural test article, systems design, integrated operations, and structural test plan.</li><li>The structural test article verifies the design of the space station's habitation module.</li><li>Proper safety reviews and preliminary design reviews are expected to complete by the end of the year.</li></ul><h2>Low Earth Orbit Destination</h2><p>NASA is also partnering with private companies like Axiom Space and Boeing for developing additional commercial low Earth orbit destinations, reinforcing its foothold in microgravity research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news9live.com/science/nasa-funded-commercial-space-station-starlab-meets-crucial-developmental-milestones-2775366</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news9live.com/science/nasa-funded-commercial-space-station-starlab-meets-crucial-developmental-milestones-2775366</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 06:45:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Christmas in space: Sunita Williams and crew in holiday mood as Dragon departs - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Christmas in Space: Sunita Williams and Crew Celebrate the Holidays Aboard the ISS</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 17, 2024<br /><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/sunita-williams-christmas-in-space-172455691-16x9_0.jpeg?VersionId=pV6w.glRqbRdlxCprfudo2W2koHrrKvN&amp;size=690:388" alt="Sunita Williams Christmas in space" title="The festive atmosphere aboard the ISS is enhanced by the stunning views of Earth from space. (Photo: Nasa)"><figcaption>The festive atmosphere aboard the ISS is enhanced by the stunning views of Earth from space. (Photo: Nasa)</figcaption><p>Sunita Williams and her crew aboard the International Space Station (ISS) are celebrating Christmas in space with festive traditions and outreach efforts.</p><ul><li>The crew is sharing holiday traditions and festive cheer despite being far from Earth.</li><li>They plan to enjoy special meals and connect with family via video calls.</li><li>They are participating in educational outreach, engaging with students on Earth.</li><li>The SpaceX Dragon capsule recently undocked, carrying supplies and gifts for the crew.</li></ul><blockquote>NASA said that after re-entering Earth's atmosphere, the spacecraft will make a parachute-assisted splashdown off the coast of Florida.</blockquote><p>Williams reflects on the significance of celebrating the holidays in space, highlighting the stunning views of Earth and the unique experiences they share.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/christmas-in-space-sunita-williams-and-crew-in-holiday-mood-as-dragon-departs-2650912-2024-12-17</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/science/story/christmas-in-space-sunita-williams-and-crew-in-holiday-mood-as-dragon-departs-2650912-2024-12-17</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 06:34:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twins were the norm for our ancient primate ancestors — one baby at a time had evolutionary advantages - Down To Earth Magazine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Twins Were Common for Ancient Primate Ancestors, Study Finds</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Publication Date: Not specified, Source: Not specified</p><p>Twins have been rare in human history and for that reason can seem special. Many cultures associate twins with health and vitality, while others see them as a philosophical reminder of the duality of life and death, good and evil.</p><p>Our recent research suggests that twins were actually the norm much further back in primate evolution, rather than an unusual occurrence worthy of note. Despite the fact that almost all primates today, including people, usually give birth to just one baby, our most recent common ancestor, which roamed North America about 60 million years ago, likely gave birth to twins as the standard.</p><ol><li>Twins were the norm for ancient primate ancestors about 60 million years ago.</li><li>The switch to singletons occurred early on, at least 50 million years ago, and was advantageous for primates to develop only one fetus per pregnancy.</li><li>Having a single offspring allowed for larger bodies and brains, crucial for complex learning.</li><li>Rates of twins have almost doubled in the US over the past 50 years due to advances in assistive reproductive technologies.</li><li>Having twins today can be dangerous for both the mother and babies, with more than half of all twins in the US being born prematurely.</li></ol><blockquote>Our findings don’t mean that having twins today is a disadvantage — although, as a mother of multiples, Tesla can certainly say it’s not easy. But having twins today is quite a different experience from our tiny primate ancestors birthing in the trees 60 million years ago.</blockquote><p>Despite these risks, our research shows that twins are a critical part of our genetic history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/science-technology/twins-were-the-norm-for-our-ancient-primate-ancestors-one-baby-at-a-time-had-evolutionary-advantages</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.downtoearth.org.in/science-technology/twins-were-the-norm-for-our-ancient-primate-ancestors-one-baby-at-a-time-had-evolutionary-advantages</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 06:02:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 mesmerising star formation images captured by NASA James Webb Space Telescope - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Mesmerising Star Formation Images Captured by NASA James Webb Space Telescope</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> HT TECH</p><img src="https://images.hindustantimes.com/tech/img/2024/12/17/900x1600/g1a9b3e4233ad38fe6367dd84b59fd93a6984f5e9d1efc930a_1734412505644_1734412505862.jpg" alt="Star Formation Image" /><figcaption>Image Credit: Pixabay</figcaption><p>This article presents five stunning images of star formation, beautifully captured by the NASA James Webb Space Telescope, shedding light on the fascinating processes involved in star formation.</p><ul><li>Star formation can occur through various means such as the collision of different molecular clouds and galaxies.</li><li>It takes between 10,000 to 100,000 years for a star to reach its fully formed shape.</li><li>The Hubble and Webb telescopes have unveiled mesmerizing images showcasing young star clusters and star formation regions.</li><li>Notable regions explored include NGC 602 and NGC 604, which are hotbeds of stellar activity.</li><li>The Rho Ophiuchi cloud complex is highlighted as the closest star-forming region to Earth.</li></ul><blockquote>“These images demonstrate the ongoing processes of star formation and the beauty of the universe.”</blockquote><p>This collection of images reminds us of the vastness and complexity of our universe and the exciting discoveries facilitated by advanced space telescopes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tech.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/5-mesmerising-star-formation-images-captured-by-nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-71734412280057.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tech.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/5-mesmerising-star-formation-images-captured-by-nasa-james-webb-space-telescope-71734412280057.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 05:22:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 breathtaking NASA Hubble images unveiling wonders of the universe | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/news/5-breathtaking-nasa-hubble-images-unveiling-wonders-of-the-universe-11734410175044.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/news/5-breathtaking-nasa-hubble-images-unveiling-wonders-of-the-universe-11734410175044.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 05:08:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA captures stunning image of dust-covered InSight Lander on Mars: See how dust shapes the red planet - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-captures-stunning-image-of-dust-covered-insight-lander-on-mars-see-how-dust-shapes-the-red-planet-article-12891490.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/science/nasa-captures-stunning-image-of-dust-covered-insight-lander-on-mars-see-how-dust-shapes-the-red-planet-article-12891490.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:15:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Webb telescope finds planet-forming disks lived longer in early universe - CGTN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.cgtn.com/news/2024-12-17/Webb-finds-planet-forming-disks-lived-longer-in-early-universe-1zoVU67FBfy/p.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.cgtn.com/news/2024-12-17/Webb-finds-planet-forming-disks-lived-longer-in-early-universe-1zoVU67FBfy/p.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:13:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX’s second-generation starship launch enters countdown, S33 completes static ignition - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxNR2lUR1JVVjRYN2Q4MUpBMHBhQzhMcnFWcmxVbUh0cnhRQnVIaEd0WmZmYmxSM1hrNGN5WEtHbWdzS25rTEZkcWpnNWtmWWJkc3V4VndKMXVkdExFUEl4cmVLNW10SFNMbVJSTW0xTTVYNDU0cTdacXRmaFFBTWRPV0dGZlVSMk1FNWxEYjl2SUhqdExTTW9PeGRsdDVrOHUwYUUtTXhhT3RsUGhHdnZZVW1YemlLMVRGcDN6Tk1ETzVXaGx2cFI2Z1JoQUgxUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxNR2lUR1JVVjRYN2Q4MUpBMHBhQzhMcnFWcmxVbUh0cnhRQnVIaEd0WmZmYmxSM1hrNGN5WEtHbWdzS25rTEZkcWpnNWtmWWJkc3V4VndKMXVkdExFUEl4cmVLNW10SFNMbVJSTW0xTTVYNDU0cTdacXRmaFFBTWRPV0dGZlVSMk1FNWxEYjl2SUhqdExTTW9PeGRsdDVrOHUwYUUtTXhhT3RsUGhHdnZZVW1YemlLMVRGcDN6Tk1ETzVXaGx2cFI2Z1JoQUgxUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 04:07:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jupiter's Hellish Moon Isn't Powered by a Hidden Ocean of Magma, Study Finds - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jupiter's Moon Io Powered by Localized Magma Chambers, Not a Global Ocean</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Science Alert</p><figure><img decoding="async" src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/12/IoCutout.jpg" alt="Io interior" width="642" height="642" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Artist's illustration showing the internal structure of Io: a mostly solid mantle (green hues), with substantial melt (yellows and oranges), overlying a liquid core (red/black). (NASA/Caltech-JPL/SwRI)</figcaption></figure><p>New research indicates that the volcanic activity on Jupiter's moon Io is not driven by a hidden ocean of magma, as previously suggested. Instead, scientists have found that the volcanoes are fed by a network of small magma chambers within a primarily solid mantle.</p><ul><li>The study used NASA's Juno spacecraft images and gravitational data.</li><li>It counters previous theories suggesting a global magma ocean under Io’s surface.</li><li>The findings have implications for understanding planetary formation and evolution.</li><li>Io's surface is covered with volcanic remnants from its numerous eruptions.</li><li>This research provides insights into tidal heating processes in celestial bodies.</li></ul><blockquote>“This constant flexing creates immense energy, which literally melts portions of Io's interior,” says Scott Bolton, a space physicist involved in the study.</blockquote><p>The research highlights the complexity of tidal heating effects and broadens the understanding of volcanic processes on other celestial bodies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/jupiters-hellish-moon-isnt-powered-by-a-hidden-ocean-of-magma-study-finds</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/jupiters-hellish-moon-isnt-powered-by-a-hidden-ocean-of-magma-study-finds</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 02:45:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Earth at risk? James Webb Space Telescope discovered many tiny asteroids in the asteroid belt between - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>James Webb Space Telescope Detects Numerous Tiny Asteroids Between Mars and Jupiter</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116373906,imgsize-10526,width-400,resizemode-4/116373906.jpg" alt="Is Earth at risk? James Webb Space Telescope discovered many tiny asteroids in the asteroid belt between Jupiter and Mars" title="Image source: Space.com" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Image source: Space.com</figcaption><p>Astronomers using the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) have discovered a large number of tiny asteroids in the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter, raising concerns about their potential risk to Earth.</p><ul><li>Discovery of an unexpectedly high number of tiny asteroids in the asteroid belt.</li><li>The asteroids are significantly smaller than those that caused the extinction of the dinosaurs but pose a greater risk due to their higher collision frequency with Earth.</li><li>A new computational method developed by astronomers allows for improved detection of these small asteroids using GPU technology.</li><li>Among the discoveries, six asteroids have orbits that could potentially intersect with Earth's orbit.</li><li>The JWST's infrared capabilities enhance the detection of faint and fast-moving asteroids.</li><li>Future observations using JWST and other advanced telescopes, like the Vera C. Rubin Observatory, will enhance tracking and identification of small asteroids.</li></ul><blockquote>“This newfound ability to detect small asteroids ... is a critical step toward improving planetary defense.”</blockquote><p>The advancements made by the JWST in detecting small asteroids highlight the growing importance of planetary defense strategies and monitoring potential threats to Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/is-earth-at-risk-james-webb-space-telescope-discovered-many-tiny-asteroids-in-the-asteroid-belt-between-jupiter-and-mars/articleshow/116373808.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/is-earth-at-risk-james-webb-space-telescope-discovered-many-tiny-asteroids-in-the-asteroid-belt-between-jupiter-and-mars/articleshow/116373808.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Laser beam casts a shadow in a ruby crystal - physicsworld.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTE10TElvTF9fZzNzZEMtUHVlV3VuUzRlMEJjM2x2T2FwWjM3WkE4Q2pXeTBYWlRET0V3WDNWTWNVSENsbzc2QW5uMlZSdEpWa0ZTSHFlaUViV24xcldSeDlFelNxU2tUaHVrVE4tdjY2N0NSSnplc3ZaQ2ZzMA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTE10TElvTF9fZzNzZEMtUHVlV3VuUzRlMEJjM2x2T2FwWjM3WkE4Q2pXeTBYWlRET0V3WDNWTWNVSENsbzc2QW5uMlZSdEpWa0ZTSHFlaUViV24xcldSeDlFelNxU2tUaHVrVE4tdjY2N0NSSnplc3ZaQ2ZzMA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 01:05:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA's Perseverance Rover Completes Its Epic Climb to Crater Rim - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA's Perseverance Rover Completes Its Epic Climb to Crater Rim</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 12, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Universe Today</p><figure><img decoding="async" src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/12/perserverence_journey_map.jpg" alt="perseverance journey on Mars" width="642" height="486" loading="lazy"><figcaption>The route NASA's Perseverance Mars rover took (in blue) as it climbed the western rim of Jezero Crater. (NASA/JPL-Caltech/University of Arizona)</figcaption></figure><p>NASA's Perseverance rover has successfully reached the top of Jezero Crater's rim, a significant milestone achieved after three and a half months of climbing. This journey enhances the rover's ability to explore a new geological area on Mars.</p><ul><li>The Perseverance rover climbed 500 vertical meters (1,640 vertical feet) to reach Lookout Hill.</li><li>The upcoming Northern Rim campaign will see the rover drive 6.4 kilometers (4 miles) to investigate up to four locations for geological samples.</li><li>Perseverance has completed four prior science campaigns since landing in February 2021, focusing on different aspects of Jezero Crater's geology.</li><li>Significant geological features and potential ancient life evidence are present in the new targeted area.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Northern Rim campaign brings us completely new scientific riches as Perseverance roves into fundamentally new geology." - Ken Farley, Caltech</blockquote><p>This achievement is crucial for furthering our understanding of Mars's geology and potential for past life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/nasas-perseverance-rover-completes-its-epic-climb-to-crater-rim</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/nasas-perseverance-rover-completes-its-epic-climb-to-crater-rim</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:24:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA releases long-term strategy for robotic Mars exploration - SpaceNews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA releases long-term strategy for robotic Mars exploration</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 11, 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p>
<p>The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) has unveiled a new strategy to enhance robotic exploration of Mars, proposing a series of smaller, science-driven missions to prepare for future human exploration.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nasa's 20-year plan encourages low-cost missions at each launch opportunity.</li>
<li>The strategy introduces three key science themes: searching for life, supporting human exploration, and understanding Mars as a dynamic planetary system.</li>
<li>Smaller missions are expected to cost between $100 million and $300 million each and will focus on specific scientific questions.</li>
<li>The plan emphasizes collaboration with commercial and international partners.</li>
<li>Nasa's 2025 budget proposal includes $40 million for Mars robotic exploration technologies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We want to do that with lower-cost missions that are science driven and has the capability of providing flexible, rapid response to discoveries.” - Becky McCauley Rench</blockquote>
<p>This strategy is aimed at expanding our understanding of Mars and lays the groundwork for future human missions to the planet, emphasizing scientific inquiry and innovative partnerships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://spacenews.com/nasa-releases-long-term-strategy-for-robotic-mars-exploration/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://spacenews.com/nasa-releases-long-term-strategy-for-robotic-mars-exploration/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:54:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Worms at Chernobyl Appear Mysteriously Unscathed by Radiation - ScienceAlert]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Worms at Chernobyl Appear Mysteriously Unscathed by Radiation</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> March 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Science Alert</p>
<img src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2024/12/1709591439460-642x482.jpg" alt="A person wearing PPE, standing in a field" width="642" height="482">
<figcaption>Tintori in the Chornobyl Exclusion Zone, wearing personal protective equipment to safeguard against radioactive dust and debris. (<a href="https://www.nyu.edu/about/news-publications/news/2024/march/worms-chornobyl-pnas.html">Matthew Rockman</a>)</figcaption>
<p>Microscopic worms, specifically nematodes, living in the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone are found to have no signs of radiation damage to their genomes, suggesting their resilience to extreme conditions. This research could provide insights into DNA repair mechanisms relevant for human medicine.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nematodes collected from the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone show no genomic damage.</li>
  <li>The CEZ is heavily contaminated, yet these worms adapt without apparent harm.</li>
  <li>Research led by Sophia Tintori focuses on understanding the underlying mechanisms of their resilience.</li>
  <li>The findings may help explain individual susceptibility to cancer and inform medical research.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Now that we know which strains of <em>O. tipulae</em> are more sensitive or more tolerant to DNA damage, we can use these strains to study why different individuals are more likely than others to suffer the effects of carcinogens," said Tintori.</blockquote>
<p>This study sheds light on the complex interactions between living organisms and extreme environmental conditions, with potential implications for long-term health and disease understanding.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencealert.com/worms-at-chernobyl-appear-mysteriously-unscathed-by-radiation</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencealert.com/worms-at-chernobyl-appear-mysteriously-unscathed-by-radiation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 22:12:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Finalizes Strategy for Sustaining Human Presence in Low Earth Orbit - IT News Online]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQdll3LWdYWXJOanN2MGlVS21nZ1BKaHY0RnhPZTFOenU5LWdRdXNTRjdwNVZKZk92SVlqb3JvSktfY0V1el90N3U3WDFDUmhZWDRmXzhNRFhiTi1BQmRRN2FtNXg4dWV4Z3ZKVmNuLVVWMmVnMGc1OVlVcmkxTXk0MnlxRHBJVFlqWUdCWXFWWm03aDl1cGVrbkR3VU5TYUhrYVpWcHVoLWpVdmRoSWU0M2VEYmp1SlpXeG14Tg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQdll3LWdYWXJOanN2MGlVS21nZ1BKaHY0RnhPZTFOenU5LWdRdXNTRjdwNVZKZk92SVlqb3JvSktfY0V1el90N3U3WDFDUmhZWDRmXzhNRFhiTi1BQmRRN2FtNXg4dWV4Z3ZKVmNuLVVWMmVnMGc1OVlVcmkxTXk0MnlxRHBJVFlqWUdCWXFWWm03aDl1cGVrbkR3VU5TYUhrYVpWcHVoLWpVdmRoSWU0M2VEYmp1SlpXeG14Tg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:57:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new method to detect dehydration in plants - MIT News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A New Method to Detect Dehydration in Plants</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 1, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Nature Communications</p>
<p>Researchers at the Singapore-MIT Alliance for Research and Technology (SMART) have developed a breakthrough sensor technology that can detect drought stress in plants in real-time, allowing for timely interventions to prevent crop loss.</p>
<ul>
<li>Development of the world's first covalent organic framework (COF) sensors integrated within silk fibroin microneedles for in-planta detection of physiological pH changes.</li>
<li>The sensors can detect early signs of drought stress, providing warnings up to 48 hours in advance compared to traditional methods.</li>
<li>This technology aims to enhance agricultural practices amidst challenges such as climate change and reduced resources.</li>
<li>The integration of COF-based sensors and biomaterials facilitates seamless monitoring of plant health.</li>
<li>The findings are published in an open-access paper titled “Chromatic Covalent Organic Frameworks Enabling In-Vivo Chemical Tomography.”</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This type of sensor can be easily attached to the plant and queried with simple instrumentation. It can therefore bring powerful analyses into the hands of farmers and researchers alike.” - Professor Michael Strano</blockquote>
<p>This new sensor technology represents a significant advancement in precision agriculture, potentially optimizing crop production and resilience to drought.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.mit.edu/2024/new-method-detect-dehydration-plants-1216</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.mit.edu/2024/new-method-detect-dehydration-plants-1216</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Finalizes Strategy for Sustaining Human Presence in Low Earth Orbit - StreetInsider.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.streetinsider.com/PRNewswire/NASA+Finalizes+Strategy+for+Sustaining+Human+Presence+in+Low+Earth+Orbit/24110769.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.streetinsider.com/PRNewswire/NASA+Finalizes+Strategy+for+Sustaining+Human+Presence+in+Low+Earth+Orbit/24110769.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:41:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Finalizes Strategy for Sustaining Human Presence in Low Earth Orbit - NASA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Finalizes Strategy for Sustaining Human Presence in Low Earth Orbit</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><p>NASA has released its final goals and objectives to sustain a human presence in low Earth orbit, paving the way for advancements in microgravity science and international collaboration.</p><ul><li>The strategy outlines 13 goals and 44 objectives for low Earth orbit.</li><li>It aims to ensure the U.S. leadership in space as the ISS approaches retirement in 2030.</li><li>Stakeholder engagement included over 1,800 comments and workshops to refine the strategy.</li><li>The goals span commercial infrastructure, scientific research, and international cooperation.</li><li>The initiative supports deep space exploration efforts toward missions to the Moon and Mars.</li></ul><blockquote>“As we near the retirement of the International Space Station in 2030, these objectives are a pivotal next step in solidifying U.S. leadership in space.” - Pam Melroy, NASA Deputy Administrator</blockquote><p>The finalized objectives will help NASA navigate the transition to commercial space stations and maintain continuous human presence, essential for future deep space missions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-finalizes-strategy-for-sustaining-human-presence-in-low-earth-orbit/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-finalizes-strategy-for-sustaining-human-presence-in-low-earth-orbit/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:04:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Webb Space Telescope witnesses Firefly Sparkle galaxy 'being assembled brick by brick' (image, video) - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>James Webb Space Telescope witnesses Firefly Sparkle galaxy 'being assembled brick by brick'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec. 11 <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><figure><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/HWnnQHinuSXUG3MRWUygEG-320-80.jpg" alt="The Firefly Sparkle Galaxy" /><figcaption>The Firefly Sparkle Galaxy belongs to a cluster of three galaxies known as MACS J1423. This dazzling galaxy is teaming with star clusters that resemble a swarm of lightning bugs on a warm summer night. (Image credit: NASA, ESA, CSA, STScI, Chris Willott (National Research Council Canada), Lamiya Mowla (Wellesley College), Kartheik Iyer (Columbia University))</figcaption></figure><p>A newly discovered relic galaxy from the early universe, dubbed the Firefly Sparkle Galaxy, has provided insights into the formation of our Milky Way.</p><ul><li>The Firefly Sparkle Galaxy appears as a warped arc rich with star clusters.</li><li>Its mass is similar to that of the young Milky Way at an equivalent developmental stage.</li><li>NASA's James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) utilized gravitational lensing to uncover this galaxy and two of its companions.</li><li>Researchers identified 10 distinct star clusters within this galaxy, indicating various stages of star formation.</li><li>The interactions with its companion galaxies are vital for its growth and evolution.</li></ul><blockquote>"I didn’t think it would be possible to resolve a galaxy that existed so early in the universe into so many distinct components..." - Lamiya Mowla</blockquote><p>This discovery marks a significant step in understanding galaxy formation, showcasing how gravitational interactions influence the growth of young galaxies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/the-universe/galaxies/james-webb-space-telescope-spots-dazzling-firefly-sparkle-galaxy-bears-striking-resemblance-to-young-milky-way-image-video</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/the-universe/galaxies/james-webb-space-telescope-spots-dazzling-firefly-sparkle-galaxy-bears-striking-resemblance-to-young-milky-way-image-video</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ISRO’s latest Space Feat—PSLV-C59 /Proba-3 Mission - Brighter Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxORHFSajQ5ejBldzk4VUhiUHRyb1dDeEVLTHU4MjBXVVRmSWZELU0tRnZ2cm1PeWp4Y0xYTlBiS2tyUVdaX09SdVNRSHpzRE4wMTVXSlJzM1o5azh3X2lHUUxwTm9FT2h0dnp1SnNCQkpia1Exa3p5NGxmZE52RzkwZg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxORHFSajQ5ejBldzk4VUhiUHRyb1dDeEVLTHU4MjBXVVRmSWZELU0tRnZ2cm1PeWp4Y0xYTlBiS2tyUVdaX09SdVNRSHpzRE4wMTVXSlJzM1o5azh3X2lHUUxwTm9FT2h0dnp1SnNCQkpia1Exa3p5NGxmZE52RzkwZg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:58:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[9 spectacular images of space captured by NASA Hubble Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>9 Spectacular Images of Space Captured by NASA Hubble Telescope</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://www.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/QT-Antennae-Galaxies-reloaded.jpg" alt="QT Antennae Galaxies reloaded">
<figcaption>Antennae Galaxies reloaded: The NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope has snapped the best ever image of the Antennae Galaxies.</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases stunning images taken by the Hubble Space Telescope, highlighting significant celestial phenomena and features.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Antennae Galaxies reloaded - best image captured by Hubble.</li>
  <li>Extreme star cluster reveals a huge cavity shaped by hot blue stars.</li>
  <li>Galaxy NGC 2525 - located 70 million light-years from Earth.</li>
  <li>Hubble’s 31st anniversary celebrated with a view of AG Carinae.</li>
  <li>Lagoon Nebula - Hubble's colorful image for its 28th anniversary.</li>
  <li>Magnetic monster NGC 1275 captured in stunning detail.</li>
  <li>New stars blowing a cavity in a fascinating star-forming region.</li>
  <li>Rings of Relativity depicting GAL-CLUS-022058.</li>
  <li>The Eagle nebula resembling a winged creature.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Thanks For Reading! Next: 5 Birds with razor sharp memory.”</blockquote>
<p>The images from Hubble not only demonstrate the advancements in space observation but also inspire awe and curiosity about the universe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/9-spectacular-images-of-space-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-7470444/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/9-spectacular-images-of-space-captured-by-nasa-hubble-telescope-7470444/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:33:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Distinguishing Albino Zebras from Elephants | by Avi Loeb | Dec, 2024 - Medium]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://medium.com/@avi-loeb/distinguishing-albino-zebras-from-elephants-0116cee91e7a</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/@avi-loeb/distinguishing-albino-zebras-from-elephants-0116cee91e7a</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 20:06:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First-Ever Black Hole Image Sharpened Using Machine Learning - MSN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.msn.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.msn.com/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 19:51:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Performs First Air Crash Investigation on a World Located 100 Million Miles Away - autoevolution]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.autoevolution.com/news/nasa-performs-first-air-crash-investigation-on-a-world-located-100-million-miles-away-244245.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.autoevolution.com/news/nasa-performs-first-air-crash-investigation-on-a-world-located-100-million-miles-away-244245.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 19:18:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>