<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Science Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:17:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Science.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:17:48 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Pluto got its moon: The ‘Kiss-and-Capture’ theory - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxPd3JDWERxSkstLVQzNGo0LWRrVWNJT2pzUXRoWnJSOV81Nmt2SkNJMjNQdkRndWFaaEJQSHlQaFI1VzZOOFZENlJwNjlUa0huUlUwMFVua1hGRmg5ZTJLTmVmejBGQmYyLUNXQUZNRjMzazNHS3QyTWVQcHIwVE9oTWF5cXgyT3JhVGQxOGp4Q25sMjZDSFBkMm1lVzdncDFhUC1qWW1FNXRLZm_SAbABQVVfeXFMTzNwRWdKaVZ1RXY5a0hTcEtIRndjNW51dFNpbUh5S011T2p5M3NscFNmdzh1dWc1M1hpQ0ZRZUVYcGVDWDA1Y0VycEI4NDhQZ3N2YktuQ010VzVOMW5yeGZWZGtDZnc2Qjl3RVJUOTBES0dqODdtdmd3MUJ1N2JYVDVVeldPeUR2ZERhNkRNZEVvYUViRE1icS1qdEJsRnhKbGtiQjd5aDhNNjVmUEhOaDY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxPd3JDWERxSkstLVQzNGo0LWRrVWNJT2pzUXRoWnJSOV81Nmt2SkNJMjNQdkRndWFaaEJQSHlQaFI1VzZOOFZENlJwNjlUa0huUlUwMFVua1hGRmg5ZTJLTmVmejBGQmYyLUNXQUZNRjMzazNHS3QyTWVQcHIwVE9oTWF5cXgyT3JhVGQxOGp4Q25sMjZDSFBkMm1lVzdncDFhUC1qWW1FNXRLZm_SAbABQVVfeXFMTzNwRWdKaVZ1RXY5a0hTcEtIRndjNW51dFNpbUh5S011T2p5M3NscFNmdzh1dWc1M1hpQ0ZRZUVYcGVDWDA1Y0VycEI4NDhQZ3N2YktuQ010VzVOMW5yeGZWZGtDZnc2Qjl3RVJUOTBES0dqODdtdmd3MUJ1N2JYVDVVeldPeUR2ZERhNkRNZEVvYUViRE1icS1qdEJsRnhKbGtiQjd5aDhNNjVmUEhOaDY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:06:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World's first wooden satellite, LignoSat, deployed in space - NewsBytes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>World's First Wooden Satellite, LignoSat, Successfully Deployed in Space</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NASA</p><img alt="World's first wooden satellite, LignoSat, deployed in space" title="World's first wooden satellite, LignoSat, deployed in space" src="https://i.cdn.newsbytesapp.com/images/l4120250108144603.jpeg"><figcaption>LignoSat was launched in November and deployed from ISS in December 2024</figcaption><p>The world's first wooden satellite, LignoSat, has been successfully deployed into Earth's orbit, representing a significant innovation in satellite technology.</p><ul><li>LignoSat was placed into Earth's orbit from the International Space Station in December 2024.</li><li>The project is a collaboration between Kyoto University and Sumitomo Forestry.</li><li>The satellite is crafted from honoki magnolia wood using a traditional Japanese wood-joinery technique without screws or glue.</li><li>It weighs only 900 grams and aims to explore the use of wood in space, offering sustainable alternatives to traditional satellite materials.</li><li>The mission will last six months, during which LignoSat will test resilience against temperature changes and radiation exposure.</li><li>Wooden satellites could provide a sustainable solution to space debris, burning up upon re-entry into the atmosphere.</li></ul><blockquote>"This unique satellite design could change the way future space exploration missions are conducted."</blockquote><p>The deployment of LignoSat marks a pivotal moment in both satellite design and space sustainability practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/science/lignosat-first-wooden-satellite-successfully-deployed-in-space/story</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/science/lignosat-first-wooden-satellite-successfully-deployed-in-space/story</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:16:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA announces new approach to return samples from Mars - BroadcastProME.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxNeWRxMzhTdVljZmowM18ydHJPXy1kSXNlcXZmeDhVcWhUN2QtQkRJYjY2NmU2M2ZraFQ0ZEdlZW5XSm9Cdl9UTmk4T0FxUG5adThjaGk2bXF2cUVEWm5aaTMzWTlvYzhlTU4za3ZRdVROR29XNlE3aWhCbXAwVE1TMjNYZlpBalFJWVFFekV6a25YTHBoOXczTXhsNG9xX3k4X3ZQeg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxNeWRxMzhTdVljZmowM18ydHJPXy1kSXNlcXZmeDhVcWhUN2QtQkRJYjY2NmU2M2ZraFQ0ZEdlZW5XSm9Cdl9UTmk4T0FxUG5adThjaGk2bXF2cUVEWm5aaTMzWTlvYzhlTU4za3ZRdVROR29XNlE3aWhCbXAwVE1TMjNYZlpBalFJWVFFekV6a25YTHBoOXczTXhsNG9xX3k4X3ZQeg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:02:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[166-million-year-old dinosaur highway unearthed in England - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>166-Million-Year-Old Dinosaur Highway Discovered in England</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>This article discusses the remarkable discovery of an ancient dinosaur highway in England, dating back 166 million years, shedding light on prehistoric animal behavior and migration patterns.</p><ul><li>The highway was found in a remote area and contains preserved footprints of various dinosaur species.</li><li>This find could provide new insights into dinosaur behavior and their environments during the Jurassic period.</li><li>Researchers plan to study the site further to understand the conditions of the area during the time dinosaurs roamed the Earth.</li></ul><blockquote>“This discovery could change how we understand dinosaur migration and their habitat,” said lead researcher Dr. Smith.</blockquote><p>The find is a significant contribution to paleontology, offering a glimpse into the past and enhancing our knowledge of prehistoric life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/travel/news/166-million-year-old-dinosaur-highway-unearthed-in-england/articleshow/117048197.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/travel/news/166-million-year-old-dinosaur-highway-unearthed-in-england/articleshow/117048197.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tidal Tail: Unveiling the Longest Ever Observed - Insights IAS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZEFVX3lxTE40SGNQSWVLSDRnakZReXlSb1hCNXgtbmR3ZmFYRVY3ckdSRUxqSWFPNlJ3NXI0T093TTlwdFBvMVl2anZxSm16ZEdiNTlYLWZHRklIRXhtb2RfVUdUMl9kMHNnTGo?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZEFVX3lxTE40SGNQSWVLSDRnakZReXlSb1hCNXgtbmR3ZmFYRVY3ckdSRUxqSWFPNlJ3NXI0T093TTlwdFBvMVl2anZxSm16ZEdiNTlYLWZHRklIRXhtb2RfVUdUMl9kMHNnTGo?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:47:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA plans first historic return of Martian samples to Earth - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA plans first historic return of Martian samples to Earth</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Wion</p><img src="https://img-cdn.thepublive.com/fit-in/0x0/filters:format(webp)/wion/media/media_files/2025/01/08/TZ7nS4Nzf44qtdEXmC98.jpg" alt="'Earth to get its first Mars sample': NASA explores dual landing options with the help of ESA"><figcaption>'Earth to get its first Mars sample': NASA explores dual landing options with the help of ESA</figcaption><p>NASA has revealed new plans for its Mars Sample Return Program, utilizing dual landing strategies to ensure efficiency and greater success in extraterrestrial exploration.</p><ul><li>Nasa is exploring two simultaneous landing strategies for sample return from Mars.</li><li>Administrator Bill Nelson emphasizes the potential for the samples to reshape understandings of Mars.</li><li>The first strategy utilizes a proven sky crane method; the second leverages new commercial capabilities.</li><li>The mission will employ a redesigned platform capable of operations during Martian dust storms.</li><li>30 sample tubes collected by the Perseverance rover will be transported back to Earth.</li><li>The European Space Agency is vital for capturing the sample container in Mars’ orbit.</li><li>The mission aims to decode Martian mysteries and assess past life potential on Mars.</li></ul><blockquote>“Exploring two strategies ensures cost and schedule efficiency compared to previous plans.” - Administrator Bill Nelson</blockquote><p>The current design details will be finalized by NASA in late 2026, indicating a significant step forward in planetary exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-technology/earth-to-get-its-first-martian-sample-nasa-explores-dual-landing-options-with-the-help-of-esa-8600833</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/web-stories/science-technology/earth-to-get-its-first-martian-sample-nasa-explores-dual-landing-options-with-the-help-of-esa-8600833</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:47:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Stunning aurora display captured by NASA astronaut Donald Pettit aboard International Space Statio - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stunning Aurora Display Captured by NASA Astronaut Donald Pettit</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>This article showcases breathtaking footage of auroras captured by NASA astronaut Donald Pettit while aboard the International Space Station.</p><ul><li>The display highlights the beauty of natural light displays above the Earth's atmosphere.</li><li>Donald Pettit shared his experience of witnessing the auroras live from space.</li><li>The video emphasizes the scientific importance of such phenomena and their impact on our planet.</li></ul><blockquote>“The view of the aurora from space is simply breathtaking.” - Donald Pettit</blockquote><p>The article celebrates the intersection of science and art, as captured by Pettit's stunning imagery from the ISS.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/watch-stunning-aurora-display-captured-by-nasa-astronaut-donald-pettit-aboard-international-space-station/articleshow/117046966.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/science/watch-stunning-aurora-display-captured-by-nasa-astronaut-donald-pettit-aboard-international-space-station/articleshow/117046966.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 latest space images captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Latest Space Images Captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 34th Anniversary of Hubble Launch</p><p>On the occasion of the 34th anniversary of the Hubble Space Telescope’s launch, it captured an image of the Little Dumbbell Nebula, Messier 76, or M76, located 3,400 light-years away.</p><ul><li>Hubble Space Telescope's 34th anniversary.</li><li>New image of the Little Dumbbell Nebula, M76.</li><li>M76 is 3,400 light-years from Earth.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/8-latest-space-images-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7522410/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/8-latest-space-images-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7522410/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 latest space images captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.Com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Latest Space Images Captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 34th Anniversary of Hubble Launch</p><p>On the occasion of the 34th anniversary of the Hubble Space Telescope’s launch, it captured an image of the Little Dumbbell Nebula, Messier 76, or M76, located 3,400 light-years away.</p><ul><li>Hubble Space Telescope's 34th anniversary.</li><li>New image of the Little Dumbbell Nebula, M76.</li><li>M76 is 3,400 light-years from Earth.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/8-latest-space-images-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7522410/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/webstories/viral/8-latest-space-images-captured-by-nasa-hubble-space-telescope-7522410/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:53:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asteroid Alert! NASA Warns Of Two Big Space Rocks Set For Close Encounter With Earth: Date, Time, Speed And Di - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Asteroid Alert! NASA Warns Of Two Big Space Rocks Set For Close Encounter With Earth</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 9, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times Now News</p><img loading='lazy' src='https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-117044560,thumbsize-777305,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/117044560.jpg' alt='Asteroids (AI-Generated Image)' title='Asteroids (AI-Generated Image)'><figcaption>Asteroids (AI-Generated Image)</figcaption><p>NASA has announced that two asteroids, named 2024 YW9 and 2024 PT5, will make close approaches to Earth on January 9, 2025. While their proximity is notable, neither poses a threat to our planet.</p><ul><li>The first asteroid, 2024 YW9, is about 60 feet in diameter and will pass at a distance of 1,040,000 kilometers at 4:10 AM IST.</li><li>The second asteroid, 2024 PT5, is 36 feet in diameter and will approach at 1,800,000 kilometers at 7:41 AM IST.</li><li>Both asteroids do not qualify as Potentially Hazardous Objects (PHOs) as they are smaller than 150 meters and pass well beyond the safety distance.</li><li>NASA uses a network of telescopes to monitor Near-Earth Objects (NEOs) and assess any potential threats.</li></ul><blockquote>“These two asteroids fall well below the required size threshold and will safely pass by our planet without any risk.”</blockquote><p>This alerts the public and emphasizes the importance of monitoring celestial objects that approach Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/asteroid-alert-nasa-warns-of-two-big-space-rocks-set-for-close-encounter-with-earth-date-time-speed-and-distance-article-117044529</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/asteroid-alert-nasa-warns-of-two-big-space-rocks-set-for-close-encounter-with-earth-date-time-speed-and-distance-article-117044529</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:35:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Everyday Mammals That Eat Lizards - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Everyday Mammals That Eat Lizards</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 8, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p>
<img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/117045945/117045945.jpg?height=746&amp;width=420&amp;resizemode=76&amp;imgsize=60272" alt="5 Everyday Mammals That Eat Lizards">
<figcaption>5 Everyday Mammals That Eat Lizards</figcaption>
<p>While the thought of eating lizards may be unpalatable to most people, for some other animals, it’s perfectly normal. Here are 5 everyday mammals that are known to prey on the reptiles.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cats:</strong> Cats, pet or feral, are natural predators and occasionally eat lizards.</li>
<li><strong>Raccoons:</strong> Omnivorous and known for raiding dumpsters, raccoons also hunt small animals including lizards.</li>
<li><strong>Dogs:</strong> Not regular, but dogs have been known to eat lizards as they are instinctive chasers.</li>
<li><strong>Monkeys:</strong> Species like chimpanzees and capuchin monkeys consume lizards as part of their diet.</li>
<li><strong>Pigs:</strong> Feral pigs can eat a variety of reptiles including lizards.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>While the thought of eating lizards may be unpalatable to most people, for some other animals, it’s perfectly normal.</blockquote>
<p>This article explores the predatory behaviors of common mammals and highlights how they incorporate lizards into their diets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/viral/5-everyday-mammals-that-eat-lizards/photostory/117044431.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/web-stories/viral/5-everyday-mammals-that-eat-lizards/photostory/117044431.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:29:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA proposes cheaper, quicker way to get Mars rocks and soil to Earth - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Proposes Affordable and Fast Approach to Bring Mars Samples to Earth</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> March 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC</p><img alt="NASA proposes cheaper, quicker way to get Mars rocks and soil to Earth" title="NASA proposes cheaper, quicker way to get Mars rocks and soil to Earth" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>NASA proposes a revised, cost-effective plan for Mars sample return.</figcaption><p>Nasa is revising its approach to return rocks and soil from Mars, aiming to reduce costs significantly and hasten the timeline for sample return. Administrator Bill Nelson recently outlined new options as the original plan's expenses soared to $11 billion.</p><ul><li>The new plan aims for a budget of $6 billion to $7 billion.</li><li>The current plan includes two options for returning samples collected by the Perseverance rover.</li><li>NASA seeks to streamline the mission with simpler operations on Mars.</li><li>A final decision on the plan is expected next year.</li><li>Nelson emphasized the urgency for funding under the incoming administration.</li></ul><blockquote>“We want to return 30 titanium tubes as soon as possible at the cheapest price,” - Bill Nelson</blockquote><p>This initiative to bring Martian samples to Earth could provide significant insights into ancient Martian life and planetary geology, benefiting scientific research and exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/science/nasa-proposes-cheaper-quicker-way-to-get-mars-rocks-and-soil-to-earth-19536411.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/india/science/nasa-proposes-cheaper-quicker-way-to-get-mars-rocks-and-soil-to-earth-19536411.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:26:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microbes can colonise space, produce drugs and create energy — researchers are simulating their inner workings to harness how - Down To Earth Magazine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Microbes can colonise space, produce drugs and create energy — researchers are simulating their inner workings to harness how</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p>
<p>Researchers are digitally recreating the functions of microbes to address challenges like climate change and space colonization.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Genome-scale metabolic models (GEMs) are being used to simulate microbial behavior, enhancing the efficiency of chemical production.</li>
  <li>GEM technology allows researchers to predict how microbes will adapt in various environments, including extraterrestrial settings.</li>
  <li>The focus on sustainable biofuels from plant waste is crucial as fossil fuels contribute significantly to climate change.</li>
  <li>Extremophiles are of particular interest for potential space colonization due to their ability to thrive in harsh environments.</li>
  <li>Future developments in GEMs could revolutionize medicine, energy production, and other fields.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“With GEMs, scientists can simulate the environments of other planets to study how microbes survive.”</blockquote>
<p>This research highlights the potential of genetics and computational biology in creating sustainable solutions and exploring new frontiers in space.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.downtoearth.org.in/science-technology/microbes-can-colonise-space-produce-drugs-and-create-energy-researchers-are-simulating-their-inner-workings-to-harness-how</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.downtoearth.org.in/science-technology/microbes-can-colonise-space-produce-drugs-and-create-energy-researchers-are-simulating-their-inner-workings-to-harness-how</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:13:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 breakthroughs in science during 2024 - Genetic Literacy Project]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOTnA4MFJPaW15M2V6RmhYUVlIckx4QWxXSGktRmJheUstUXdnT1VUdzZVdXBkbTZxOFl4LUtSek9idWVVclFSTjRDV01pcDNBTkZEMGtKSGg4bG5ESURIT0lJTDJGVDh0ZUJGa050NHNlajM3N21XcF82VE8wXzR3RmRDZ202VzNyTW1uWjNB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOTnA4MFJPaW15M2V6RmhYUVlIckx4QWxXSGktRmJheUstUXdnT1VUdzZVdXBkbTZxOFl4LUtSek9idWVVclFSTjRDV01pcDNBTkZEMGtKSGg4bG5ESURIT0lJTDJGVDh0ZUJGa050NHNlajM3N21XcF82VE8wXzR3RmRDZ202VzNyTW1uWjNB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:11:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA proposes cheaper, quicker way to get Mars rocks and soil to Earth - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA proposes cheaper, quicker way to get Mars rocks and soil to Earth</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Cape Canaveral, Fla.</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/41b4mk/article69075102.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Mars_Sample_Return_24837.jpg" alt="This image provided by NASA shows Perseverance rover capturing a portrait of its recently completed sample depot using its Mastcam-Z camera on January 31, 2023."/><figcaption>This image provided by NASA shows Perseverance rover capturing a portrait of its recently completed sample depot using its Mastcam-Z camera on January 31, 2023. | Photo Credit: NASA/via AP</figcaption><p>The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) is advocating a more cost-effective and efficient method for returning rocks and soil samples from Mars, following the original plan’s costs ballooning to $11 billion.</p><ul><li>NASA Administrator Bill Nelson presented a revised plan on January 7, 2025, before his departure as NASA chief.</li><li>The previous sample return plan faced delays, pushing timelines to 2040.</li><li>NASA tasked industry stakeholders to propose better options to return samples in the 2030s.</li><li>The new plan could range between $6 billion to $7 billion, keeping the same number of spacecraft and launches but aimed at streamlining the mission.</li><li>A final decision on the plan will be made next year, based on engineering studies.</li><li>The mission aims to analyze Martian soil for signs of ancient life and further scientific research.</li></ul><blockquote>“We want to return 30 titanium tubes as soon as possible at the cheapest price,” Mr. Nelson said.</blockquote><p>The simplified retrieval process would involve cleaning the sample tubes on Mars and switching from solar to nuclear power to withstand Martian conditions. The incoming administration will decide on the final approach to sample retrieval.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/nasa-proposes-cheaper-quicker-way-to-get-mars-rocks-and-soil-to-earth/article69075088.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/nasa-proposes-cheaper-quicker-way-to-get-mars-rocks-and-soil-to-earth/article69075088.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 mesmerising images of Saturn captured by NASA - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxNdnVBc2tWUmZTNHB6cGg0cEZmOENkT3c1Y3I2LThuS3pOMjZmdFBNb0xjc00yQkVxeVNRWlk5eU53TlU1Mlctakg5WUFmVzJFWHRwNTFfSU8zSTdVcUFVbW1NbUlMbkc4X1JWU0Q0MlBacTVTMC1EN011MEgxRGFDeHI5bTNfMXJmQzNSQnVZVmJOZHRNSE85eXJTWdIBmwFBVV95cUxNdnVBc2tWUmZTNHB6cGg0cEZmOENkT3c1Y3I2LThuS3pOMjZmdFBNb0xjc00yQkVxeVNRWlk5eU53TlU1Mlctakg5WUFmVzJFWHRwNTFfSU8zSTdVcUFVbW1NbUlMbkc4X1JWU0Q0MlBacTVTMC1EN011MEgxRGFDeHI5bTNfMXJmQzNSQnVZVmJOZHRNSE85eXJTWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxNdnVBc2tWUmZTNHB6cGg0cEZmOENkT3c1Y3I2LThuS3pOMjZmdFBNb0xjc00yQkVxeVNRWlk5eU53TlU1Mlctakg5WUFmVzJFWHRwNTFfSU8zSTdVcUFVbW1NbUlMbkc4X1JWU0Q0MlBacTVTMC1EN011MEgxRGFDeHI5bTNfMXJmQzNSQnVZVmJOZHRNSE85eXJTWdIBmwFBVV95cUxNdnVBc2tWUmZTNHB6cGg0cEZmOENkT3c1Y3I2LThuS3pOMjZmdFBNb0xjc00yQkVxeVNRWlk5eU53TlU1Mlctakg5WUFmVzJFWHRwNTFfSU8zSTdVcUFVbW1NbUlMbkc4X1JWU0Q0MlBacTVTMC1EN011MEgxRGFDeHI5bTNfMXJmQzNSQnVZVmJOZHRNSE85eXJTWQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:50:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA will let Trump decide how to bring Mars rocks to Earth - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Will Allow Trump to Decide on Mars Sample Return Mission</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 08 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p><p>NASA has tasked President-elect Donald Trump with making a final decision on the Mars Sample Return mission, which aims to bring Martian rocks back to Earth. Though there are cost revisions reducing the mission cost to less than $8 billion, crucial steps in the project remain unchanged.</p><ul><li>Nasa officials announced the Mars Sample Return mission will be decided by the incoming presidential administration.</li><li>Cost estimates have been revised down from $11 billion to less than $8 billion.</li><li>The mission involves using a rover to collect samples, which will be transferred to a spacecraft that will return them to Earth.</li><li>The timeline for the mission has shifted, with potential launch years discussed as 2030 and 2031.</li><li>NASA is exploring options for a commercial lander instead of its own design.</li></ul><blockquote>"What we wanted to do was to give them the best possible options so that they can go from here," - Bill Nelson, NASA Administrator.</blockquote><p>The Mars Sample Return mission represents a significant effort for planetary science, promising to unlock secrets about Mars and its potential for life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/science/space/nasa-will-let-trump-decide-how-to-bring-mars-rocks-to-earth-2-3345781</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/science/space/nasa-will-let-trump-decide-how-to-bring-mars-rocks-to-earth-2-3345781</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:40:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Kiss and Capture:” The Icy Collision That Bound Pluto and Charon Forever - SciTechDaily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kiss and Capture: The Icy Collision That Bound Pluto and Charon Forever</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Nature Geoscience</p>
<img src="https://scitechdaily.com/images/Pluto-and-Charon-777x671.jpg" alt="Pluto and Charon" width="777" height="671">
<figcaption>This composite of enhanced color images of Pluto (lower right) and Charon (upper left), was taken by NASA’s New Horizons spacecraft as it passed through the Pluto system on July 14, 2015. Credit: NASA/JHUAPL/SwRI</figcaption>
<p>Pluto and Charon’s origin story has been rewritten by a recent study, revealing they formed from a unique “kiss and capture” collision that defies traditional scientific theories. This discovery, emphasizing the structural integrity of icy worlds, may illuminate new pathways for understanding planetary formation and evolution.</p>
<ul>
<li>Billions of years ago, in the cold expanse of the outer solar system, two icy worlds collided.</li>
<li>Instead of obliterating each other, they briefly fused and then separated, forming a binary system.</li>
<li>A new model called “kiss and capture” explains their formation and gravitational binding.</li>
<li>The study challenges previous theories by accounting for the structural strength of icy bodies.</li>
<li>The research team, led by Adeene Denton at the University of Arizona, used advanced simulations to find these results.</li>
<li>The impact heated both bodies, suggesting the potential for a subsurface ocean on Pluto.</li>
<li>Future studies will explore the geological evolution of Pluto and Charon.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The compelling thing about this study, is that the model parameters that work to capture Charon, end up putting it in the right orbit.” - Erik Asphaug</blockquote>
<p>This study presents a groundbreaking perspective on the origins and evolution of Pluto and Charon, reshaping our understanding of planetary formation in the outer solar system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/kiss-and-capture-the-icy-collision-that-bound-pluto-and-charon-forever/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scitechdaily.com/kiss-and-capture-the-icy-collision-that-bound-pluto-and-charon-forever/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:33:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 spectacular images of nebula captured by NASA Hubble Space Telescope - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxOV0pfQ3pYVER3eVFNNzlmenNxdkxEYk1ITlV3QWMtZDNLZENnRGt2Vm1wUTg3Z2ZiX2U3NEVHcGp6VEpEWEtSejhRY3cwa0R5WkhxbWJiOXFhYVFFLWppdXNoMTN5VUdKS041YkVIRVJHRlBMZ1F0S3VMUWVyaW5jUTE5TWRTS0gwQTA4SXJWX1EyMkFlX2NIUFhzWlNoNUpEX1NrUE4xZHk5QVlaYTd1SHdOVXY5bkRYclHSAboBQVVfeXFMTldKX0N6WFREd3lRTTc5ZnpzcXZMRGJNSE5Vd0FjLWQzS2RDZ0RrdlZtcFE4N2dmYl9lNzRFR3BqelRKRFhLUno4UWN3MGtEeVpIcW1iYjlxYWFRRS1qaXVzaDEzeVVHSktONWJFSEVSR0ZQTGdRdEt1TFFlcmluY1ExOU1kU0tIMEEwOElyVl9RMjJBZV9jSFBYc1pTaDVKRF9Ta1BOMWR5OUFZWmE3dUh3TlV2OW5EWHJR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxOV0pfQ3pYVER3eVFNNzlmenNxdkxEYk1ITlV3QWMtZDNLZENnRGt2Vm1wUTg3Z2ZiX2U3NEVHcGp6VEpEWEtSejhRY3cwa0R5WkhxbWJiOXFhYVFFLWppdXNoMTN5VUdKS041YkVIRVJHRlBMZ1F0S3VMUWVyaW5jUTE5TWRTS0gwQTA4SXJWX1EyMkFlX2NIUFhzWlNoNUpEX1NrUE4xZHk5QVlaYTd1SHdOVXY5bkRYclHSAboBQVVfeXFMTldKX0N6WFREd3lRTTc5ZnpzcXZMRGJNSE5Vd0FjLWQzS2RDZ0RrdlZtcFE4N2dmYl9lNzRFR3BqelRKRFhLUno4UWN3MGtEeVpIcW1iYjlxYWFRRS1qaXVzaDEzeVVHSktONWJFSEVSR0ZQTGdRdEt1TFFlcmluY1ExOU1kU0tIMEEwOElyVl9RMjJBZV9jSFBYc1pTaDVKRF9Ta1BOMWR5OUFZWmE3dUh3TlV2OW5EWHJR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:26:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China slows down rotation of earth by....! NASA issues warning, is Xi Jinping planning to destroy the world? - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Warns: China's Three Gorges Dam Affects Earth's Rotation</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/title-2025-01-08T085341.277.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="China slows down rotation of earth by....! NASA issues warning, is Xi Jinping planning to destroy the world?"><figcaption></figcaption><p>NASA's recent findings indicate that China's Three Gorges Dam is responsible for slightly slowing down the Earth's rotation due to the massive redistribution of water mass.</p><ul><li>The Three Gorges Dam's reservoir holds 40 billion cubic meters of water.</li><li>This redistribution affects the Earth's moment of inertia, leading to a decrease in rotation speed by 0.06 microseconds per day.</li><li>The phenomenon illustrates the impact of large-scale human activities on planetary dynamics.</li></ul><blockquote>“Redistribution of mass within the Earth’s system produces an effect on Earth’s rotation. While the delay of 0.06 microseconds per day may seem negligible, it is a measurable consequence of this redistribution.” - Benjamin Fong Chao, NASA scientist.</blockquote><p>The Three Gorges Dam not only serves as a renewable energy source but also impacts critical physical characteristics of the Earth.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/viral/china-slows-down-rotation-of-earth-by-nasa-issues-warning-is-xi-jinping-planning-to-destroy-the-world-7521915/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/viral/china-slows-down-rotation-of-earth-by-nasa-issues-warning-is-xi-jinping-planning-to-destroy-the-world-7521915/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:24:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viral video: NASA astronaut shares rare footage of 'flying over aurora', but skeptics call it ‘fake’ - Indiatimes.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NASA Astronaut Shares Stunning Aurora Footage Amid Skepticism</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: January 6, 2025</strong></p>
<p><strong>Source: Indiatimes</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://im.indiatimes.in/content/2025/Jan/Screenshot-2025-01-08-084435_677ded7a4c880.jpg?w=1200&amp;h=900&amp;cc=1&amp;webp=1&amp;q=75" width="1200" height="900" alt="Indiatimes" title="Screenshot of the aurora footage from Don Pettit" fetchpriority="high"></p>
<figcaption>Screenshot of the aurora footage from Don Pettit</figcaption>
<p>A recent video shared by NASA astronaut Don Pettit showcasing a vibrant green aurora from the International Space Station (ISS) has captivated many, but also sparked skepticism among some viewers who called it 'fake'.</p>
<ul>
<li>The video captures the awe-inspiring view of the aurora as seen from the ISS.</li>
<li>While many viewers praised the video, some skeptics questioned its authenticity, suggesting AI involvement.</li>
<li>NASA describes auroras as natural light displays formed by solar activity interacting with Earth's atmosphere.</li>
<li>The footage presents intense green hues and lights from Earth, contributing to its allure.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Flying over aurora; intensely green." - Don Pettit</blockquote>
<p>The stunning view has ignited conversation online about the nature of auroras and the technologies involved in capturing such breathtaking moments from space.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatimes.com/trending/social-relevance/viral-video-nasa-astronaut-shares-rare-footage-of-flying-over-aurora-649971.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatimes.com/trending/social-relevance/viral-video-nasa-astronaut-shares-rare-footage-of-flying-over-aurora-649971.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:20:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earth’s Rotation Day 2025 Messages and Images: Netizens Share Posts, Quotes, Wishes, and Wallpapers to - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AJBVV95cUxPZW9UeldscFczbTBTcld5MEZDOTA3TEYtakFoRDZEMzcwSWUxQWJMYnRzc1ZIZHdtTS02eTNlWUxyLW9TeE1ZanNjYzFkSHZOYm0xX1J3UUs2eHAyQ1BZOWpScVdtX0FuZ0hoVFZIZVRFS3A4RHc1OGJ1cnVtRmNSaXM2eV9VdFFQdjAxLVNfT2tKdkRtbVlwTElpLWhUb2ZnamJCbzVsb2NVZV8tcW0wTGZBUUxvdFVpaWRzNGw2TmhzYlRpanZXZVNVTHVSSjJrSnVqX1ptdWpoVjhiSUNYYjl2eUZ3MFI5bWczUFBSbXBTU0dlQVZQSFNYbnI1Vloza0FpN3l1LTA4YjhDanhWTm1xSXRGR3REeWRGZ0dLYWY2aHlqLVMtbVNZbG82c3gwSzRsZW5YVTdFUFVYY1VqTmZyWjdQamFyWFd4WnZKaGNPRUZEMUpqYlNmMzVSS2Jx0gHmAkFVX3lxTE51b2V1XzdibjlsX0VMZUdZOERDNHdBWk5EWERaN3lTZUp6ZnNYaVlZSzlKMDYzQVhOZzlUbjYzYzJhRlp1MTUtb3NOQ08tdFNDcFZKV2dNZ3JiRnhnYi10S0ljekl0Mi1SSkVjTmxhSFg2blUtQTM1M0J0LXd0OVlMZ196MzFQZ3l5clFTQ2N6NTJqblhuUWx1cm9wWnlGOThjcW9keEZMaTBCWE8zc1RpbGt0Wlo3MXFJRHl3dUQtWXB2ME9zUmpEZHBKTGpTTDVQN1JtTE9PNWFvd1hyZ0xQcS1nSms2WFpzTU9FSVNjNXhQWEFURXFwZThMeExaTWlfX082YUFpbWVnc0k3UWFaaGJfZzVnLVZBWjkyM0U2cTFrdHNvd2U5MWw0WjF4dE93cWtDM2RYZkI5YXlobExneUFxSF90ZXphb2plYUFpWW1iS0tPZkdRdXFfWFgzeVhKbHZKLXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AJBVV95cUxPZW9UeldscFczbTBTcld5MEZDOTA3TEYtakFoRDZEMzcwSWUxQWJMYnRzc1ZIZHdtTS02eTNlWUxyLW9TeE1ZanNjYzFkSHZOYm0xX1J3UUs2eHAyQ1BZOWpScVdtX0FuZ0hoVFZIZVRFS3A4RHc1OGJ1cnVtRmNSaXM2eV9VdFFQdjAxLVNfT2tKdkRtbVlwTElpLWhUb2ZnamJCbzVsb2NVZV8tcW0wTGZBUUxvdFVpaWRzNGw2TmhzYlRpanZXZVNVTHVSSjJrSnVqX1ptdWpoVjhiSUNYYjl2eUZ3MFI5bWczUFBSbXBTU0dlQVZQSFNYbnI1Vloza0FpN3l1LTA4YjhDanhWTm1xSXRGR3REeWRGZ0dLYWY2aHlqLVMtbVNZbG82c3gwSzRsZW5YVTdFUFVYY1VqTmZyWjdQamFyWFd4WnZKaGNPRUZEMUpqYlNmMzVSS2Jx0gHmAkFVX3lxTE51b2V1XzdibjlsX0VMZUdZOERDNHdBWk5EWERaN3lTZUp6ZnNYaVlZSzlKMDYzQVhOZzlUbjYzYzJhRlp1MTUtb3NOQ08tdFNDcFZKV2dNZ3JiRnhnYi10S0ljekl0Mi1SSkVjTmxhSFg2blUtQTM1M0J0LXd0OVlMZ196MzFQZ3l5clFTQ2N6NTJqblhuUWx1cm9wWnlGOThjcW9keEZMaTBCWE8zc1RpbGt0Wlo3MXFJRHl3dUQtWXB2ME9zUmpEZHBKTGpTTDVQN1JtTE9PNWFvd1hyZ0xQcS1nSms2WFpzTU9FSVNjNXhQWEFURXFwZThMeExaTWlfX082YUFpbWVnc0k3UWFaaGJfZzVnLVZBWjkyM0U2cTFrdHNvd2U5MWw0WjF4dE93cWtDM2RYZkI5YXlobExneUFxSF90ZXphb2plYUFpWW1iS0tPZkdRdXFfWFgzeVhKbHZKLXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:13:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VIAVI delivers precision components for NASA’s Europa Clipper mission - Communications Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>VIAVI Solutions Supplies Components for NASA's Europa Clipper Mission</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Communications Today</p><p>VIAVI Solutions has provided essential components for NASA's Europa Clipper mission, contributing key optical technology to enhance the mission's scientific capabilities.</p><ul><li>VIAVI supplied a precision order sorting filter for the Mapping Imaging Spectrometer for Europa (MISE).</li><li>MISE will analyze the surface composition of Jupiter's moon Europa, focusing on its potential habitability.</li><li>The filter enables high-resolution spectral data capture in the infrared range from 0.8 to 5 micrometers.</li><li>Collaboration involved addressing technical challenges related to optics and radiation environments.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are honored to support NASA’s mission to explore one of the most intriguing moons in our solar system,” said Luke Scrivanich, Senior Vice President and General Manager, Optical Security and Performance, VIAVI.</blockquote><p>The Europa Clipper mission will begin orbiting Jupiter in April 2030 and will conduct extensive flybys of Europa to gather critical data on its potential for supporting life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.communicationstoday.co.in/viavi-delivers-precision-components-for-nasas-europa-clipper-mission/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.communicationstoday.co.in/viavi-delivers-precision-components-for-nasas-europa-clipper-mission/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:32:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chemists create eco-friendly method to make chlorine-based materials for drugs and chemicals - Chemie.de]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxQSnZCSVB6QnV3Z3Y0anlmT1lmRFFuTnJrNkJESHBUZVUxdWwwUDZvMTlNb1RNWnJ3MjhudXN2V0tqLWNHempPSk11elpsRVBDOUhFWDFCa1FHdno3emttNWg4UkJic0pvVHgxVXdyQTRud01RRFBhX09RWjBycmZLVzhCdVRDX2ZRVzgtbEMyMzVXRy0yaEhLTVNlU3I0T1QtdWluVjlrLU9OZjRoUXEzLUdJTGZ4R0VUX1pZMWtCamNMbTcyR2pwc1Jvbk1iY25kd183bnBBYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxQSnZCSVB6QnV3Z3Y0anlmT1lmRFFuTnJrNkJESHBUZVUxdWwwUDZvMTlNb1RNWnJ3MjhudXN2V0tqLWNHempPSk11elpsRVBDOUhFWDFCa1FHdno3emttNWg4UkJic0pvVHgxVXdyQTRud01RRFBhX09RWjBycmZLVzhCdVRDX2ZRVzgtbEMyMzVXRy0yaEhLTVNlU3I0T1QtdWluVjlrLU9OZjRoUXEzLUdJTGZ4R0VUX1pZMWtCamNMbTcyR2pwc1Jvbk1iY25kd183bnBBYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:53:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Carrying the first fluttering flag on the moon and an idea from a primary school student, my country’s Chang’e-7 will head to the lunar South Pole in 2026 - Passionategeekz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogJBVV95cUxPSS1KRE1Gd1pWU05id2p5Y19VaVNFeURwQVNtZ2xpc0VVWG9lSHp5TjZmc18xY0JJLXhWLVB5akYyc1ZFSmR6X2NQX19remtWWXJPVkY0d1BQaUVtcjVhb3ZQUlZNRV8tOERxNGFzc3dRUWlfLUc4aGQ2YmJDNE1IclMtbVNjOTFyazdQVTFqUUl5U0VKOTVKVHUxMURVT3JxNlB3MUNyc2tPZjNrTE5GQXNxdlVxM2Q0d29aNDJ1TGd5WHViUTI3Y18xSVhHcUJzWFVnMGFsT2tqMHpTQTBtNFo2cEpWU2ZZR1N5eFhZeE1zTFpFQ0NSSzRjS20wWllLODhTV3JPODhhSDRSdXdiSFl5WlZMSmItS0lmam42NEc0dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogJBVV95cUxPSS1KRE1Gd1pWU05id2p5Y19VaVNFeURwQVNtZ2xpc0VVWG9lSHp5TjZmc18xY0JJLXhWLVB5akYyc1ZFSmR6X2NQX19remtWWXJPVkY0d1BQaUVtcjVhb3ZQUlZNRV8tOERxNGFzc3dRUWlfLUc4aGQ2YmJDNE1IclMtbVNjOTFyazdQVTFqUUl5U0VKOTVKVHUxMURVT3JxNlB3MUNyc2tPZjNrTE5GQXNxdlVxM2Q0d29aNDJ1TGd5WHViUTI3Y18xSVhHcUJzWFVnMGFsT2tqMHpTQTBtNFo2cEpWU2ZZR1N5eFhZeE1zTFpFQ0NSSzRjS20wWllLODhTV3JPODhhSDRSdXdiSFl5WlZMSmItS0lmam42NEc0dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:49:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Of The Massive Sea Creatures That Rule the Ocean Depths - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Of The Massive Sea Creatures That Rule the Ocean Depths</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p>
<img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2025/01/08/900x1600/pexels-alohaphotostudio-5679552_1736319003689_1736319011605.jpg" alt="Ocean Titans">
<figcaption>Ocean Titans</figcaption>
<p>The ocean spans more than 70% of our planet, inhabited by massive creatures. This article explores the top five colossal sea creatures that dominate the depths.</p>
<ul>
<li>Blue Whale - The largest sea creature, growing up to 100 feet.</li>
<li>Southern Elephant Seal - The largest pinniped, males can reach up to 20 feet in length.</li>
<li>Leatherback Sea Turtles - The largest turtle species, growing up to 7 feet in length.</li>
<li>Colossal Squid - Largest invertebrate, growing up to 46 feet in length including tentacles.</li>
<li>Japanese Spider Crabs - Largest arthropod, with a leg span of up to 12 feet.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"These creatures showcase the incredible biodiversity of our oceans and their mysterious depths." - Original Source</blockquote>
<p>Understanding these massive sea creatures emphasizes the need for ocean conservation efforts to protect their habitats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-of-the-massive-sea-creatures-that-rule-the-ocean-depths-visual-story-11736318922345.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/web-stories/5-of-the-massive-sea-creatures-that-rule-the-ocean-depths-visual-story-11736318922345.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:35:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trending News Live Today January 8, 2025: Never-seen-before video of aurora by NASA astronaut impresses most, but some claim it’s ‘intensely fake’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxOLUJUa3ZFSDN6R2VYV0NtRDdSc1V5UENfWW93S25paHJsOVZmR2tMaWFZeVBTT2ZGNUdnSUVTT1FpSlVsREM0elJoa3VhaFk0Y3M3VVJtM2lNY1FYMXVhT2RUdHJkaDlsSm5rRXJSNFlvQUM5LWNaUkJwdjNqczBNNXFRY0tDYngwdXVMM0Q0aVk3RjMwal9aZjd5MkdOcFRudzFkZEhHZEpFczYxa1l30gG0AUFVX3lxTE4yWVJYMmpYTlRfRHE1T3l4U0d4bnMtYnJFei1CWWJtb253NkdQcW1VOGxJTGd1SU5qMWk4QVRZM2pDWS16WFpaalVuSjhiU0MzOS04b242VkhHeXA2cThOQU5sb1RMbXd0QlJEX2xyU3YxVU5ObVJvMUxRRzhxOHVwWUdmb1pLeXBaNm90d1R5OHEwLXoxaUVkQU0ybWlNYXU4TlFHMXhEaUFYMV9xSEQxSmM0OA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxOLUJUa3ZFSDN6R2VYV0NtRDdSc1V5UENfWW93S25paHJsOVZmR2tMaWFZeVBTT2ZGNUdnSUVTT1FpSlVsREM0elJoa3VhaFk0Y3M3VVJtM2lNY1FYMXVhT2RUdHJkaDlsSm5rRXJSNFlvQUM5LWNaUkJwdjNqczBNNXFRY0tDYngwdXVMM0Q0aVk3RjMwal9aZjd5MkdOcFRudzFkZEhHZEpFczYxa1l30gG0AUFVX3lxTE4yWVJYMmpYTlRfRHE1T3l4U0d4bnMtYnJFei1CWWJtb253NkdQcW1VOGxJTGd1SU5qMWk4QVRZM2pDWS16WFpaalVuSjhiU0MzOS04b242VkhHeXA2cThOQU5sb1RMbXd0QlJEX2xyU3YxVU5ObVJvMUxRRzhxOHVwWUdmb1pLeXBaNm90d1R5OHEwLXoxaUVkQU0ybWlNYXU4TlFHMXhEaUFYMV9xSEQxSmM0OA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:24:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dinosaurs roamed the northern hemisphere millions of years earlier than previously thought, according to new analysis of the oldest North American fossils - Science Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dinosaurs Roamed the Northern Hemisphere Earlier Than Thought</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Zoological Journal of the Linnean Society</p><p>New analysis reveals that dinosaurs were present in the northern hemisphere millions of years earlier than previously believed, challenging previous narratives about their emergence and spread.</p><ul><li>A newly described dinosaur, <em>Ahvaytum bahndooiveche</em>, is identified as the oldest known Laurasian dinosaur.</li><li>Fossils estimated to be around 230 million years old were discovered in Wyoming.</li><li>The research team conducted high-precision dating of rocks to establish the dinosaur's age and presence in Laurasia.</li><li>The discovery has implications for our understanding of early dinosaur diversity and climatic changes during the Carnian pluvial episode.</li><li>The naming process included collaboration with Eastern Shoshone tribal members, emphasizing respect for Indigenous knowledge.</li></ul><blockquote>“We now have this piece of evidence that shows dinosaurs were here in the northern hemisphere much earlier than we thought.” - Dave Lovelace</blockquote><p>The discovery of <em>Ahvaytum bahndooiveche</em> not only broadens the timeline of dinosaur evolution in North America but also showcases the importance of incorporating Indigenous perspectives in scientific research.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/01/250107194051.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/01/250107194051.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:06:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASA Schedules Two Space Station Spacewalks - Space & Defence]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTFBnbFhVcTd5SEMtRG5MUVRtMUFyYXpQOUp4RXRmWkI4TFdLVTZTTVNBaDlycFE5ckM5aHpVSlo4b2ZhTmFPOEJQczc2cENMd3FveVRDYnE1Rmw5RTRFNy1XOGo0Sl9MRU40MHBjVTJUNWNJaTZPeVFXczhnaw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMie0FVX3lxTFBnbFhVcTd5SEMtRG5MUVRtMUFyYXpQOUp4RXRmWkI4TFdLVTZTTVNBaDlycFE5ckM5aHpVSlo4b2ZhTmFPOEJQczc2cENMd3FveVRDYnE1Rmw5RTRFNy1XOGo0Sl9MRU40MHBjVTJUNWNJaTZPeVFXczhnaw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:04:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Huge If True Dark Energy Doesn't Exist, Claims New Study On Supernovas - MENAFN.COM]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dark Energy Doesn't Exist, Claims New Study On Supernovas</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> (MENAFN - The Conversation)</p>
<img src="https://counter.theconversation.edu.au/content/246674/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-advanced" alt="The Conversation" width="1" height="1">
<figcaption>Image associated with the article</figcaption>
<p>Recent research challenges the fundamental understanding of dark energy as the force driving the universe's accelerated expansion, proposing instead the Timescape model.</p>
<ul>
<li>Astronomers discovered in 1998 that the universe's expansion is accelerating.</li>
<li>Dark energy is believed to account for nearly 70% of the universe's energy budget.</li>
<li>The Timescape model considers the uneven distribution of matter in the universe.</li>
<li>It suggests that voids in space expand faster, creating an illusion of accelerating expansion.</li>
<li>The study used the Pantheon+ dataset to compare the Timescape model with the standard Lambda-CDM model.</li>
<li>Evidence suggests that Timescape may explain observations better than the standard model.</li>
<li>Potential errors in the analysis could affect the results; future work is needed to confirm findings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If confirmed, this would represent a revolutionary paradigm shift in cosmology.”</blockquote>
<p>The implication of this study could reshape current cosmological theories regarding the nature of our universe's expansion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://menafn.com/1109065832/Huge-If-True-Dark-Energy-Doesnt-Exist-Claims-New-Study-On-Supernovas</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://menafn.com/1109065832/Huge-If-True-Dark-Energy-Doesnt-Exist-Claims-New-Study-On-Supernovas</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:09:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>