<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:19:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 14:19:39 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia Highlights, 4th Test Day 5: AUS beat IND by 184 runs at Melbourne and take 2-1 lead in series - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia Highlights, 4th Test Day 5</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 26, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/IND-vs-AUS-Boxing-Day-Test-Day-5.jpg?w=750" alt="India vs Australia Live Score, 4th Test: Day 5 action unfolds at MCG today." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>India vs Australia Live Score, 4th Test: Day 5 action unfolds at MCG today.</figcaption><p>Australia beat India by 184 runs in the fourth Test at Melbourne, taking a 2-1 lead in the series.</p><ul><li>India was chasing 340 runs but collapsed for 155.</li><li>Yashasvi Jaiswal scored 84 runs, but his dismissal changed the game.</li><li>Pat Cummins and Scott Boland each took three wickets for Australia.</li></ul><blockquote>“India won the opening Test in Perth and Australia bounced back at Adelaide. With this win, Australia takes a 2-1 lead.”</blockquote><p>The final Test will start in Sydney on Friday, marking a crucial game in the series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-day-5-live-score-india-vs-australia-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-melbourne-cricket-ground-victoria-9750446/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-day-5-live-score-india-vs-australia-live-cricket-scorecard-updates-melbourne-cricket-ground-victoria-9750446/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nahi Lag Raha Zor ": 'Exhausted' Jasprit Bumrah's Desperate Plea To Rohit Sharma Goes Viral - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1><i>Nahi Lag Raha Zor</i>: 'Exhausted' Jasprit Bumrah's Desperate Plea To Rohit Sharma Goes Viral</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/qvjn6a18_ca_625x300_30_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="&quot;<i>Nahi Lag Raha Zor</i>&quot;: 'Exhausted' Jasprit Bumrah's Desperate Plea To Rohit Sharma Goes Viral"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah expresses his exhaustion during the match.</figcaption></p><p>Indian fast bowler Jasprit Bumrah pleaded with captain Rohit Sharma, expressing his fatigue after a grueling bowling effort in the fourth Test against Australia. Despite his discomfort, Bumrah's performance was crucial in the match.</p><ul><li>Bumrah claimed a five-wicket haul against Australia in Melbourne.</li><li>He bowled 24 overs in the second innings and a total of 53.2 overs in the match.</li><li>Bumrah was heard on a stump mic saying, '<em>Bas ab, nahi laga raha zor</em>' (Enough now. I cannot find strength anymore).</li><li>Former cricketer Simon Katich praised debutant Sam Konstas for his portrayal of Test cricket's challenges.</li></ul><blockquote>Video is here. Feel for him <a href="https://t.co/B34mC7ffTN">https://t.co/B34mC7ffTN</a> — kohlinoor (@cricketxper) December 29, 2024</blockquote><p>Bumrah's performance continues to highlight the demands placed on fast bowlers in Test cricket, and his plea reflects the physical toll of the game.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/nahi-lag-raha-zor-exhausted-jasprit-bumrahs-desperate-plea-to-rohit-sharma-goes-viral-7361422</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/nahi-lag-raha-zor-exhausted-jasprit-bumrahs-desperate-plea-to-rohit-sharma-goes-viral-7361422</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 13:14:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunil Gavaskar Lashes Out At Seniors Virat Kohli, Rohit Sharma After 4th Test Humiliation: "All They.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunil Gavaskar Lashes Out At Seniors Virat Kohli, Rohit Sharma After 4th Test Humiliation: "All They Had To Do..."</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>December 30, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8bnni5p_virat-kohli-rohit-sharma-x_625x300_30_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Sunil Gavaskar Lashes Out At Seniors Virat Kohli, Rohit Sharma After 4th Test Humiliation: 'All They Had To Do...'"/><figcaption>Sunil Gavaskar discusses the performance of Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma after the Boxing Day Test.</figcaption><p>The legendary Sunil Gavaskar criticized senior players Rohit Sharma and Virat Kohli following India's defeat in the Boxing Day Test against Australia, blaming the top-order for their failure to chase a target of 340 runs.</p><ul><li>India lost the match by 184 runs, trailing 1-2 in the five-match series.</li><li>Yashasvi Jaiswal was the exception, scoring 84 runs.</li><li>Gavaskar highlighted the importance of contributions from the top-order players.</li><li>He suggested that the future of Kohli and Sharma will depend on the selectors' decisions.</li></ul><blockquote>“The seniors have not really made the contribution that they should have, all that they had to do was bat out today and live to fight another day in Sydney,” - Sunil Gavaskar.</blockquote><p>Gavaskar also praised Jaiswal's performance while criticizing Rishabh Pant's shot selection, which he believes led to the collapse of the batting order.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/sunil-gavaskar-lashes-out-at-seniors-virat-kohli-rohit-sharma-after-4th-test-humiliation-all-they-had-to-do-7364205</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/sunil-gavaskar-lashes-out-at-seniors-virat-kohli-rohit-sharma-after-4th-test-humiliation-all-they-had-to-do-7364205</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 12:51:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RAN vs DC Live Score, Match 2 | Rangpur Riders vs Dhaka Capitals Score & Updates of Match 2 - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rangpur Riders vs Dhaka Capitals, Match 2 - Live Cricket Score</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 30 Dec 2024, Mon, 6:00 PM IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Bangladesh Premier League</p><img src="https://www.crictracker.com/_next/image/?url=%2F_next%2Fstatic%2Fmedia%2Farticle-placeholder.7ee1b1ea.jpg&amp;w=40&amp;q=75" alt="Match Logo"><figcaption>Match Logo for Rangpur Riders vs Dhaka Capitals</figcaption><p>Dhaka Capitals elected to bowl first in the second match of the Bangladesh Premier League 2025, held at the Shere Bangla National Stadium, Mirpur, Dhaka.</p><ul><li>Current Run Rate: 10.91</li><li>Key Stats: Partnership of 18 runs in 9 balls.</li><li>Last 5 Overs: 18 runs, 0 wickets lost.</li><li>Toss: Dhaka Capitals chose to field.</li></ul><blockquote>“What a delivery! Steven Taylor goes forward, exhibits impeccable timing as batter hammers and sends it flying to the deep mid wicket region for a remarkable Maximum!”</blockquote><p>The match is currently ongoing with Rangpur Riders starting strong with their innings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/live-scores/ran-vs-dc-match-2-t20-bangladesh-premier-league-30-dec-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/live-scores/ran-vs-dc-match-2-t20-bangladesh-premier-league-30-dec-2024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:53:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Unfit for FIDE job': Magnus Carlsen hits out at Viswanathan Anand - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQeEFULWdXS1Fwa21EbWt4bm4yNTZTNXlxYWM3VHc4MC1TeFUtQTk3YkwxTm5lZm5XNl80WGluRENpMmlJenlDQlFhVkN5dnlUUlFRSXR4czhZS0pqS081ejM5cnpCd2xVMHdmUHZDc1BSS1p5aENzd2Z0bnNOM1I3RzhjQ0lMRVl5VkJCd1d5TjNCYmlNd2N5VWpVU0JzZVVLQ1FNQUNTbERtcm9ZcTFzZXZHemZsUzNWYUJBRXpINk8yYldHR19OLVBhel90OXFpU1JfQg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQeEFULWdXS1Fwa21EbWt4bm4yNTZTNXlxYWM3VHc4MC1TeFUtQTk3YkwxTm5lZm5XNl80WGluRENpMmlJenlDQlFhVkN5dnlUUlFRSXR4czhZS0pqS081ejM5cnpCd2xVMHdmUHZDc1BSS1p5aENzd2Z0bnNOM1I3RzhjQ0lMRVl5VkJCd1d5TjNCYmlNd2N5VWpVU0JzZVVLQ1FNQUNTbERtcm9ZcTFzZXZHemZsUzNWYUJBRXpINk8yYldHR19OLVBhel90OXFpU1JfQg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Juthe Log ": Rohit Sharma And Co. Blasted By Ex-India Star On Yashasvi Jaiswal DRS Row - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1><i>Juthe Log</i>: Rohit Sharma And Co. Blasted By Ex-India Star On Yashasvi Jaiswal DRS Row</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/7n0f6io_team-india-afp_625x300_30_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Juthe Log: Rohit Sharma And Co. Blasted By Ex-India Star On Yashasvi Jaiswal DRS Row"><figcaption>Image: India's cricket team at the fourth Test against Australia.</figcaption><p>Former Indian cricketer Surinder Khanna criticized the Indian team's performance in the fourth Test against Australia, particularly focusing on Yashasvi Jaiswal's controversial DRS dismissal, which stirred debate about fairness in the game.</p><ul><li>India lost the match by 184 runs, trailing 2-1 in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy series.</li><li>Jaiswal's dismissal was reviewed via DRS with inconclusive evidence.</li><li>Khanna emphasized the need for fair play and called the team's performance underwhelming.</li><li>India's point percentage in the World Test Championship has dropped to 52.78.</li><li>Australia is close to securing a spot in the WTC final, needing just one win from their upcoming matches.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no point in making controversy... you have to play fair wicket first then only you'll start winning.” - Surinder Khanna</blockquote><p>India's cricket team faces challenges ahead but can still qualify for the WTC final if they win their last Test against Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharma-and-co-called-liars-by-ex-india-star-on-yashasvi-jaiswal-drs-controversy-7362985</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharma-and-co-called-liars-by-ex-india-star-on-yashasvi-jaiswal-drs-controversy-7362985</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:40:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If Rishabh's at fault so are Virat and Rohit - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit, Kohli and Pant central to India's MCG fall</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024-25<br><strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p><img height="654" width="980" alt="Kohli walks back to the pavilion after being dismissed for 5" title="Kohli walks back to the pavilion after being dismissed for 5" src="/a/img/v1/980x654/i1/c594347/kohli-walks-back-to-the-pavili.jpg" itemprop="contentUrl"><figcaption>Kohli walks back to the pavilion after being dismissed for 5 ©Getty</figcaption><p>This article discusses India's performance in a crucial Test match at the MCG, focusing on the disappointing dismissals of key players Rohit Sharma, Virat Kohli, and Rishabh Pant, which contributed to their collapse and subsequent loss.</p><ul><li>Rishabh Pant's aggressive shot after Tea marked a turning point.</li><li>Virat Kohli fell to a wide delivery, disappointing in his final innings at MCG.</li><li>Rohit Sharma struggled to find form, leading to another low score.</li><li>The team suffered a dramatic collapse of 7 wickets for 34 runs.</li><li>The match showcased the unpredictable nature of Test cricket.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was a celebration of Test cricket. It was a celebration of its vagaries. It was a celebration of its intricacies.”</blockquote><p>Overall, despite a commendable effort earlier in the match, India failed to convert their position into a victory, highlighting the critical moments that led to their downfall.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132956/if-rishabhs-at-fault-so-are-virat-and-rohit</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132956/if-rishabhs-at-fault-so-are-virat-and-rohit</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:34:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma, Virat Kohli, Rishabh Pant and the three shots that sunk India at MCG - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma, Virat Kohli, Rishabh Pant and the three shots that sunk India at MCG</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<p>In a disappointing test match at the MCG, India was defeated by Australia by 184 runs, with critical errors from key players leading to their demise. Despite having the chance to potentially win the series, India must now regroup for the next test.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rishabh Pant's poor shot selection cost India dearly in the final session.</li>
  <li>Virat Kohli's dismissal showcased a lack of discipline, raising questions about his form and future.</li>
  <li>India's captain Rohit Sharma also contributed to the team's downfall with a mental error.</li>
  <li>Australia celebrated their victory, marking it as one of their best tests with a record crowd of 373,691.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It’s a sad moment, but not a surprise.” - Jim Maxwell on Kohli's dismissal.</blockquote>
<p>This match highlighted the urgent need for India to reassess their strategies and mental toughness as they move forward in the series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-virat-kohli-rishabh-pant-3-shots-mcg-india-9751679/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-virat-kohli-rishabh-pant-3-shots-mcg-india-9751679/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 11:07:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jacob Duffy lands knockout blows to claim 2-0 series lead - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jacob Duffy lands knockout blows to claim 2-0 series lead</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p>
<p><i>New Zealand</i> 186 for 5 (Chapman 42, Hay 41, Robinson 41) beat <i>Sri Lanka</i> 141 (Perera 48, Duffy 4-15) by 45 runs.</p>
<p>In a convincing second T20I victory, New Zealand's comprehensive team effort saw them emerge victorious over Sri Lanka, securing a 2-0 series lead.</p>
<ul>
  <li>New Zealand set a target of 187 runs for Sri Lanka, who struggled to achieve it, managing only 141 runs.</li>
  <li>Jacob Duffy's exceptional bowling performance, taking 4 wickets for just 15 runs, played a crucial role in New Zealand's win.</li>
  <li>Mitchell Hay was named player of the match for his explosive 41 runs off just 19 balls.</li>
  <li>Sri Lanka's batting woes continued, with their inability to finish innings strongly raising concerns.</li>
  <li>Key contributors for Sri Lanka included Kusal Perera and Pathum Nissanka, but their efforts were not enough.</li>
  <li>New Zealand displayed controlled aggression and effective running between the wickets, significantly outpacing Sri Lanka.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Duffy's 4 for 15 was far and away the best bowling effort, as he provided crucial breakthroughs across Sri Lanka's innings.”</blockquote>
<p>This victory highlights New Zealand's dominance in the series thus far, leaving Sri Lanka searching for answers as they continue to struggle in away conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2024-25-1443537/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2nd-t20i-1443544/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2024-25-1443537/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2nd-t20i-1443544/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:52:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Kohli deserves a longer rope, can't compare him with Rohit': Sanjay Manjrekar - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sanjay Manjrekar Supports Virat Kohli Amid Criticism After Test Loss</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>New Delhi</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116797878,imgsize-38252,width-400,resizemode-4/116797878.jpg" alt="Sanjay Manjrekar on Kohli and Rohit" title="(AP Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Sanjay Manjrekar comments on the performances of Kohli and Rohit Sharma.</figcaption><p>After India's heavy 184-run loss to Australia, former cricketer Sanjay Manjrekar expressed support for Virat Kohli, stating he deserves more time in Test cricket.</p><ul><li>Criticism surrounds both Kohli and Rohit's performances after the Boxing Day Test.</li><li>Manjrekar argues that Kohli is a superior Test batter compared to Rohit.</li><li>He emphasizes the need for the batting coach's role in addressing Kohli's issues.</li><li>Rohit is viewed as capable but struggling, according to Manjrekar.</li><li>India faces a challenging 340-run chase with poor performance in critical moments.</li></ul><blockquote>“So Virat Kohli obviously deserves a longer rope. It's not so much about Virat Kohli. I want to know what the batting coach of India is doing.” - Sanjay Manjrekar</blockquote><p>This commentary from Manjrekar reflects ongoing debates about player performance and team strategies as India looks towards future matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/kohli-deserves-a-longer-rope-cant-compare-him-with-rohit-sanjay-manjrekar/articleshow/116797875.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/kohli-deserves-a-longer-rope-cant-compare-him-with-rohit-sanjay-manjrekar/articleshow/116797875.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah nominated for ICC Test Cricketer of the Year Award | Check full list - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxPQzA0QXNCQTN4S3pFVTMyODJTRkx5MkpENDZMSXVwVC1FMmtTREYxdzJKb2tRdjZCWUtDcW9nMGtnM3YxWVc3ZVZJZ1VTYTNKU3RNYUtOSWlxYXY0SVZiZHgtQVc1TVlOYjFCZzhVdGJPVU9TbnZRRzlTVHJmV1c3cFV4TVpnRDFVUGVsY2lYZjVBcjBVd0FOTXV3RVkwLW1DNzF4MTBlbGZxS0FzT25Ec0xyTXcySl9fNlFEU3lkTkJTbnNCZ05zVHZ5amN3YlpvdDM1VWQwYjB3bW9xYk5v0gHkAUFVX3lxTE9ycmpPUFR1MHozYjREV0wtRlJ6ZlFja0J0eS05QzFJQ0dSM2Q1elRJeW1rTlNNekxfZzNoVGdyR0VjV0xla2ZaMHNTSGhWbDVRazdyUS0zYkZPWW1hbjJ2V3MxS0FaTTh6clpqcnF5TV94ZHhqY0t2UnVCZ1I2d1lIMXhOVHRYTzNJRnQ3aEVRVF93QUxfSTZBVk8tNnl4cjhuRXg5ejFxbGlUSy1ia3lUUkpMOEtCa1J4S1Bzbm1hdDFNWnAweGYzMUVGbGNHRHVGQUgta0pvMmJzbHRFLUNTYXY1MA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxPQzA0QXNCQTN4S3pFVTMyODJTRkx5MkpENDZMSXVwVC1FMmtTREYxdzJKb2tRdjZCWUtDcW9nMGtnM3YxWVc3ZVZJZ1VTYTNKU3RNYUtOSWlxYXY0SVZiZHgtQVc1TVlOYjFCZzhVdGJPVU9TbnZRRzlTVHJmV1c3cFV4TVpnRDFVUGVsY2lYZjVBcjBVd0FOTXV3RVkwLW1DNzF4MTBlbGZxS0FzT25Ec0xyTXcySl9fNlFEU3lkTkJTbnNCZ05zVHZ5amN3YlpvdDM1VWQwYjB3bW9xYk5v0gHkAUFVX3lxTE9ycmpPUFR1MHozYjREV0wtRlJ6ZlFja0J0eS05QzFJQ0dSM2Q1elRJeW1rTlNNekxfZzNoVGdyR0VjV0xla2ZaMHNTSGhWbDVRazdyUS0zYkZPWW1hbjJ2V3MxS0FaTTh6clpqcnF5TV94ZHhqY0t2UnVCZ1I2d1lIMXhOVHRYTzNJRnQ3aEVRVF93QUxfSTZBVk8tNnl4cjhuRXg5ejFxbGlUSy1ia3lUUkpMOEtCa1J4S1Bzbm1hdDFNWnAweGYzMUVGbGNHRHVGQUgta0pvMmJzbHRFLUNTYXY1MA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:27:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BGT 2024: Major controversies in India vs Australia Test series so far; Virat Kohli-Sam Konstas, Siraj-Head, and more - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/bgt-2024-major-controversies-in-india-vs-australia-test-series-so-far-virat-kohli-sam-konstas-siraj-head-and-more-11735552979717.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/bgt-2024-major-controversies-in-india-vs-australia-test-series-so-far-virat-kohli-sam-konstas-siraj-head-and-more-11735552979717.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:23:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma says poor form ‘mentally disturbing’ after India loses Melbourne Test - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Calls Poor Form 'Mentally Disturbing' After Australia's Victory in Fourth Test</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/g7w5rh/article69042921.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2191796525.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma looks dejected after dismissal" />
<figcaption>Rohit Sharma of India looks dejected after being dismissed by Pat Cummins of Australia on day five of the fourth Test in the series between Australia and India at Melbourne Cricket Ground on December 30, 2024 | Photo Credit: Getty Images</figcaption>
<p>After India's defeat against Australia in the fourth Test, captain Rohit Sharma expressed his disappointment over the team's performance and acknowledged the mental toll it has taken on him.</p>
<ul>
  <li>India lost the fourth Test against Australia at the Melbourne Cricket Ground.</li>
  <li>Rohit mentioned that the team had opportunities to draw the game but failed to capitalize.</li>
  <li>He described his struggles as a batter, stating that many things are not falling into place and that it is 'mentally disturbing.'</li>
  <li>Looking forward, Rohit emphasized the importance of playing well in the upcoming match in Sydney to aim for a series draw.</li>
  <li>He addressed questions about Rishabh Pant's dismissals and the management of Jasprit Bumrah's bowling workload.</li>
  <li>Rohit praised the performance of Nitish Kumar and recognized the hard work of Mohammed Siraj and Akash Deep.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Obviously, few results have not gone our way and as a captain, it is disappointing. As a batter, a lot of the things I am trying to do are not falling in place. Mentally, look, it is disturbing.”</blockquote>
<p>Rohit's insights reflect the challenges faced by the Indian team and highlight the mental aspects of performance in competitive sports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sport/cricket/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-a-lot-of-things-im-trying-to-do-are-not-falling-in-place-says-rohit-sharma-on-poor-batting-form/article69042918.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sport/cricket/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-a-lot-of-things-im-trying-to-do-are-not-falling-in-place-says-rohit-sharma-on-poor-batting-form/article69042918.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shortlist for Sir Garfield Sobers Trophy for Men’s Cricketer of the Year announced - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shortlist for Sir Garfield Sobers Trophy for Men’s Cricketer of the Year announced</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<img src="https://images.icc-cricket.com/image/upload/t_ratio21_9-size60/prd/ICC_Awards_2024_-_Sir_Garfield_Sobers_Trophy_-_Nominees_21x9" alt="ICC Awards 2024 - Sir Garfield Sobers Trophy - Nominees 21x9" />
<figcaption>ICC Awards 2024 - Sir Garfield Sobers Trophy - Nominees</figcaption>
<p>The shortlist for the Sir Garfield Sobers Trophy, honoring the Men’s Cricketer of the Year, has been revealed. The nominees include Harry Brook, Jasprit Bumrah, Joe Root, and Travis Head, each with outstanding performances throughout the year.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Harry Brook (England):</strong> 1100 runs from 12 Tests, average 55.00, Highest Score 317</li>
  <li><strong>Jasprit Bumrah (India):</strong> 71 wickets from 13 Tests, average 14.92; 15 wickets from 8 T20Is, average 8.26</li>
  <li><strong>Joe Root (England):</strong> 1556 runs from 17 Tests, average 55.57, Highest Score 262</li>
  <li><strong>Travis Head (Australia):</strong> 608 runs from 9 Tests, average 40.53; 539 runs from 15 T20Is, strike rate 178.47</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Harry Brook emerged as one of England’s most reliable performers...”</blockquote>
<p>The nominees represent a mix of aggressive batting and pivotal roles in their respective teams, showcasing their skills in a variety of cricket formats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/shortlist-for-sir-garfield-sobers-trophy-for-men-s-cricketer-of-the-year-announced</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/shortlist-for-sir-garfield-sobers-trophy-for-men-s-cricketer-of-the-year-announced</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 10:01:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Third Umpire Did Make...": On Yashasvi Jaiswal Controversy, Simon Taufel's Blunt Verdict - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yashasvi Jaiswal's Controversial Dismissal: Simon Taufel's Verdict</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source: December 30, 2024 | <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/">NDTV Sports</a></strong></p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/r0kh88a_jaiswal_625x300_30_December_24.jpeg" alt="" width="639" height="479"><figcaption>Yashasvi Jaiswal was dismissed in a controversial manner at MCG.</figcaption>
<p>India opener Yashasvi Jaiswal's contentious dismissal sparked a controversy on the final day of the fourth Test against Australia at the Melbourne Cricket Ground. Jaiswal was given out caught behind despite no clear edge being shown on the Snicko. The decision was made by third umpire Saikat Sharfuddoula, overturning the on-field umpire's not out call. Jaiswal, batting on 84, argued with the umpires before walking back.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jaiswal was dismissed on 84 after a solid innings of 208 deliveries.</li>
  <li>The dismissal led to chants of "cheater" around the MCG.</li>
  <li>The incident follows a similar controversy in the opening Test in Perth involving opener KL Rahul.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Yeh optical illusion hai." - Sunil Gavaskar questions the third umpire's decision to overrule the Snicko technology.</blockquote>
<p>Former ICC Elite Panel umpire Simon Taufel told Channel 7 that the third umpire made the correct decision to overrule the on-field umpire's not out call based on clear deflection off the bat.</p>
<p>This incident has reignited the debate around the use of technology in making decisions in cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/third-umpire-did-make-on-yashasvi-jaiswal-controversy-simon-taufels-blunt-verdict-7361702</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/third-umpire-did-make-on-yashasvi-jaiswal-controversy-simon-taufels-blunt-verdict-7361702</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:56:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravi Shastri On Retirement Rumors: 'Virat Kohli Will Play 3-4 More Years, For Rohit Sharma It's…' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxNMFh2blpxN3BOeUd5UE1aM3J4UF93ZVVfbWJEMkRhc0VnUTVhMFUtUUQ3cTh0T1c2NFl4WTByWXZma2ZuU04tdG12LUEtS2diU2RrN3cwVHJUN09WTzRzcUhhTlYxeUlZNURlMVdLMERnWjJDMHd0VUhfdHdjenc0dEhUZkVwc2xEd19Jckl0R3I3dnRzMGRacnhnbTYxMXdqRmNaOEt6bEJvTThEM3NlTEgyWU1FekswM2hFd1c1T0UwQ3piR085ZTdXeFBBdnRM0gHWAUFVX3lxTE41NHpfdk1ZYkthazZFWUhwdjE0bXR2R3h0QVdOY2VpbWhzcTRFUENNZmFTZmZQcHJDSmExRjdlMF9QNzFycW5US3lhNE5DcUZzLTNmU28yZ19qa2ROZUt1TkNqeGxReXBubTFFWkVBSjMwcTZuQzdSLXc4VE5rUjVyaTFpV1l1S2tlVk9tX1A0UnVLRDd2ejI1U255b2tEWGpKNXNwR3dkcjRLb2NZNV9CUDZXbkRSczZxMmh3YXNYLWhmVWpHNEdVb014V0l6dlQ3LTVwcFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxNMFh2blpxN3BOeUd5UE1aM3J4UF93ZVVfbWJEMkRhc0VnUTVhMFUtUUQ3cTh0T1c2NFl4WTByWXZma2ZuU04tdG12LUEtS2diU2RrN3cwVHJUN09WTzRzcUhhTlYxeUlZNURlMVdLMERnWjJDMHd0VUhfdHdjenc0dEhUZkVwc2xEd19Jckl0R3I3dnRzMGRacnhnbTYxMXdqRmNaOEt6bEJvTThEM3NlTEgyWU1FekswM2hFd1c1T0UwQ3piR085ZTdXeFBBdnRM0gHWAUFVX3lxTE41NHpfdk1ZYkthazZFWUhwdjE0bXR2R3h0QVdOY2VpbWhzcTRFUENNZmFTZmZQcHJDSmExRjdlMF9QNzFycW5US3lhNE5DcUZzLTNmU28yZ19qa2ROZUt1TkNqeGxReXBubTFFWkVBSjMwcTZuQzdSLXc4VE5rUjVyaTFpV1l1S2tlVk9tX1A0UnVLRDd2ejI1U255b2tEWGpKNXNwR3dkcjRLb2NZNV9CUDZXbkRSczZxMmh3YXNYLWhmVWpHNEdVb014V0l6dlQ3LTVwcFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:35:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Golden-arm Head was helping with Australia's over rate - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/golden-arm-travis-head-was-helping-with-australia-over-rate-1467229</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/golden-arm-travis-head-was-helping-with-australia-over-rate-1467229</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:27:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FIDE CEO responds to Magnus Carlsen’s ‘f*** you’ rant: ‘I know no less colourful words than him’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FIDE CEO responds to Magnus Carlsen’s ‘f*** you’ rant: ‘I know no less colourful words than him’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/New-Project-2024-12-30T144559.000.jpg?w=640" alt="FIDE's Sutovsky gave his own version after the firefighting was over and Magnus Carlsen had been successfully coaxed to play in the World Blitz Championship. (FIDE)" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>FIDE's Sutovsky gave his own version after the firefighting was over and Magnus Carlsen had been successfully coaxed to play in the World Blitz Championship. (FIDE)</figcaption><p>Magnus Carlsen and FIDE have resolved their dispute, allowing Carlsen to participate in the FIDE World Rapid and Blitz Championship in New York following a controversial fine for attire.</p><ul><li>Carlsen expressed frustration over a fine for wearing jeans during the rapid section of the tournament.</li><li>In a prior statement, Carlsen used expletives to convey his displeasure with FIDE's rules.</li><li>FIDE CEO Emil Sutovsky acknowledged the situation, emphasizing that personal attacks are not constructive.</li><li>Sutovsky defended his role, citing improvements in tournament organization under his leadership.</li><li>Carlsen criticized FIDE's former player representative, Viswanathan Anand, suggesting he wasn't fit for the role.</li></ul><blockquote>“If the question is how I respond to Magnus’ words, I know no less colourful words than him, trust me.” - Emil Sutovsky</blockquote><p>The incident underscores ongoing tensions within the chess community regarding FIDE's regulations and leadership dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/chess/magnus-carlsen-f-you-response-fide-ceo-sutovsky-9751459/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/chess/magnus-carlsen-f-you-response-fide-ceo-sutovsky-9751459/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['The King is dead': Simon Katich's scathing comment on Virat Kohli's MCG failure - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/the-king-is-dead-simon-katichs-scathing-comment-on-virat-kohlis-mcg-failure/articleshow/116795266.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/the-king-is-dead-simon-katichs-scathing-comment-on-virat-kohlis-mcg-failure/articleshow/116795266.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's WTC Final chances not over yet: How can they qualify after Boxing day Test defeat? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAJBVV95cUxNYzBFQVJocmJlQ1d5dTJ2NnE5RVAzUWxYY0xjMEpnd2hlNWV5dFBjWEU4dldwbU5iTWl6ZHhwMFpJWVNFUHIzWGllSjZvdE1jdnNmWHZvenRCR0xFdWlhT3BSbVFfa0RDNVBUcVN4RDRqTjh6YU9jMG9LSkRQeFoyekotV19hcnctX3I5RzFiQTBCZmJ2ejFCZnl5SHBHWEtvR0xOdUs1ZnAyQnlqR3oxeWw5aUJJM1ozTzZKTGdXeE9RZWRDOTk5RDhjVWs5UTZUOHBSa1FBWmRhUXBFa0RFMlVYRWI0OWt5TnBTczNtajRvRTcwTE16amxKM21GZUg4dFI4Q3lrS0oyRHFZLVE2bA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAJBVV95cUxNYzBFQVJocmJlQ1d5dTJ2NnE5RVAzUWxYY0xjMEpnd2hlNWV5dFBjWEU4dldwbU5iTWl6ZHhwMFpJWVNFUHIzWGllSjZvdE1jdnNmWHZvenRCR0xFdWlhT3BSbVFfa0RDNVBUcVN4RDRqTjh6YU9jMG9LSkRQeFoyekotV19hcnctX3I5RzFiQTBCZmJ2ejFCZnl5SHBHWEtvR0xOdUs1ZnAyQnlqR3oxeWw5aUJJM1ozTzZKTGdXeE9RZWRDOTk5RDhjVWs5UTZUOHBSa1FBWmRhUXBFa0RFMlVYRWI0OWt5TnBTczNtajRvRTcwTE16amxKM21GZUg4dFI4Q3lrS0oyRHFZLVE2bA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 09:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Captain Cry Baby': After Virat Kohli Row, Australian Media Hits New Low With Rohit Sharma Jibe - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Captain Cry Baby: After Virat Kohli Row, Australian Media Hits New Low With Rohit Sharma Jibe</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8mh28isg_asc_625x300_30_December_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Captain Cry Baby: After Virat Kohli Row, Australian Media Hits New Low With Rohit Sharma Jibe"><figcaption>An edited picture of Rohit Sharma published by Australian media © X (Twitter)</figcaption><p>The Australian media has targeted Indian captain Rohit Sharma over his frustrated reaction to young teammate Yashasvi Jaiswal dropping three catches during the Boxing Day Test. This follows prior criticism directed at Virat Kohli over a separate incident.</p><ul><li>The West Australian tabloid labeled Rohit as 'Captain Cry Baby' after he expressed visible frustration with Jaiswal's poor fielding.</li><li>Rohit's body language was scrutinized by former players, emphasizing the need for support towards younger teammates.</li><li>Despite Jaiswal usually being a reliable fielder, he faced backlash for the dropped catches, leading to tensions within the team.</li></ul><blockquote>“I've got to be honest, I don't like that reaction from the Indian skipper... You don't need to see that as a young player.” — Mike Hussey</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the intense pressure on players in high-stakes cricket and the media's role in shaping public perception of athlete behavior.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/captain-cry-baby-after-virat-kohli-row-australian-media-hits-new-low-with-rohit-sharma-jibe-7361079</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/captain-cry-baby-after-virat-kohli-row-australian-media-hits-new-low-with-rohit-sharma-jibe-7361079</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:45:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma to retire from Tests after Border-Gavaskar Trophy in Sydney? Report suggests India captain is trying to… - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/rohit-sharma-to-retire-from-tests-after-border-gavaskar-trophy-in-sydney-heres-what-report-says-11735547236469.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/rohit-sharma-to-retire-from-tests-after-border-gavaskar-trophy-in-sydney-heres-what-report-says-11735547236469.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:35:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma on Yashasvi Jaiswal’s controversial DRS dismissal: ’Don’t know how umpires want to use technology’ - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Comments on Controversial DRS Dismissal of Yashasvi Jaiswal</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>India captain Rohit Sharma raised concerns about the use of technology in cricket after Yashasvi Jaiswal's controversial dismissal in the fourth Test against Australia, which resulted in India's defeat.</p>
<img src='URL_TO_IMAGE' alt='Rohit Sharma post-match press conference' />
<figcaption>Rohit Sharma addresses the media post-match.</figcaption>
<p>During the match, Jaiswal was given out despite no clear evidence of a contact with the ball, leading to confusion and frustration.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jaiswal was batting on 84 when he was controversially given out.</li>
  <li>The Indian batting lineup faltered, getting all out for 155 runs.</li>
  <li>Rohit Sharma expressed his doubts regarding the accuracy of DRS technology.</li>
  <li>India's loss resulted in a significant setback for their World Test Championship hopes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I don't know what to make of (that decision) because the technology didn't show anything but with naked eye it seem that he did touch something,” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the incident has sparked a debate on the reliability of DRS in cricket, particularly in high-stakes matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/rohit-sharma-on-yashasvi-jaiswal-controversial-drs-dismissal-dont-know-how-umpires-want-to-use-technology-ind-vs-aus-11735545280830.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/rohit-sharma-on-yashasvi-jaiswal-controversial-drs-dismissal-dont-know-how-umpires-want-to-use-technology-ind-vs-aus-11735545280830.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:15:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anushka Sharma, Athiya Shetty shocked at Virat Kohli, KL Rahul's early dismissal in India vs Australia Boxing Day Test - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Reactions of Anushka Sharma and Athiya Shetty to Early Dismissals of Virat Kohli and KL Rahul in India vs Australia Test Match</h1><p><strong>Publish Date: Dec 30, 2024<br>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/Au_1735545661576_1735545671708.jpg" alt="Anushka Sharma, Athiya Shetty shattered after Virat Kohli, KL Rahul's early dismissal in Ind vs Aus test match." title="Anushka Sharma, Athiya Shetty shattered after Virat Kohli, KL Rahul's early dismissal in Ind vs Aus test match."><figcaption>Anushka Sharma, Athiya Shetty shattered after Virat Kohli, KL Rahul's early dismissal in Ind vs Aus test match.</figcaption><p>Anushka Sharma and Athiya Shetty, wives of Indian cricket team players Virat Kohli and KL Rahul, were recently seen at the Melbourne Cricket Ground for the fourth test match between India and Australia. Their reactions to their husbands' early dismissals during the game have gone viral on social media.</p><ol><li>The actors were seen expressing disappointment and worry as their husbands, Virat Kohli and KL Rahul, were dismissed early in the match.</li><li>Virat Kohli scored 5 runs in 29 balls, and KL Rahul was dismissed without scoring any runs.</li><li>The early dismissals of the cricketers left India at 33/3 and shocked not only the fans but also their wives, Anushka Sharma and Athiya Shetty.</li></ol><p>Fans reacted to their expressions, with some comparing their reactions to the overall mood of Indian cricket fans, while others criticized their husbands' performances.</p><p>Anushka Sharma and Athiya Shetty have been away from the film industry for some time now, focusing on their families. Both have recently welcomed new additions to their families.</p><p>Catch every big hit and news from the cricket world here.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/anushka-sharma-athiya-shetty-shocked-at-virat-kohli-kl-rahuls-early-dismissal-in-india-vs-australia-boxing-day-test-101735545116946.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/anushka-sharma-athiya-shetty-shocked-at-virat-kohli-kl-rahuls-early-dismissal-in-india-vs-australia-boxing-day-test-101735545116946.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:12:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Risk of over-bowling Jasprit Bumrah, but he's lacked support': Rohit Sharma after MCG defeat - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Risk of over-bowling Jasprit Bumrah, but he's lacked support: Rohit Sharma after MCG defeat</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date]<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116792940,imgsize-100072,width-400,resizemode-4/116792940.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah holds up the ball as he leaves the field after taking five wickets at the MCG. (AP/PTI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah holds up the ball as he leaves the field after taking five wickets at the MCG. (AP/PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>In a recent press conference, India captain Rohit Sharma expressed his concerns regarding Jasprit Bumrah's heavy bowling workload and the lack of adequate support during the team’s defeat by 184 runs in the fourth Test against Australia.</p><ul><li>Bumrah took 9 wickets for 156 runs in the match, becoming the fastest Indian bowler to reach 200 Test wickets.</li><li>Despite Bumrah's outstanding performance, India was unable to secure a victory due to a batting collapse, losing seven wickets for just 34 runs.</li><li>Rohit acknowledged the risk of over-bowling Bumrah and noted his exhaustion by the end of the match.</li><li>He praised Bumrah's commitment and selflessness but highlighted the ongoing issue of insufficient support for the star bowler.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is a risk of over-bowling Bumrah, but when someone is in form, you tend to bowl him more.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>The team must find ways to better support Bumrah as they prepare for the final Test of the series, scheduled to commence at the Sydney Cricket Ground on January 3.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/risk-of-over-bowling-jasprit-bumrah-but-hes-lacked-support-rohit-sharma-after-mcg-defeat/articleshow/116792965.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/risk-of-over-bowling-jasprit-bumrah-but-hes-lacked-support-rohit-sharma-after-mcg-defeat/articleshow/116792965.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nominees for ICC Men’s Test Cricketer of the Year unveiled - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nominees for ICC Men’s Test Cricketer of the Year unveiled</h1><p><strong>Date: October 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: ICC Cricket</strong></p><img src="https://images.icc-cricket.com/image/upload/t_ratio21_9-size60/prd/ICC_Awards_2024_-_Men_s_Test_Cricketer_of_the_Year_-_Nominees_21x9" alt="ICC Awards 2024 - Men_s Test Cricketer of the Year - Nominees 21x9" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Nominees for the prestigious award</figcaption><p>The ICC has unveiled the nominees for the Men’s Test Cricketer of the Year, showcasing stellar performances from four elite players throughout 2024.</p><ul><li><strong>Joe Root (England)</strong>: 1556 runs from 17 Tests, average 55.57, with six centuries and a standout score of 262 against Pakistan.</li><li><strong>Jasprit Bumrah (India)</strong>: 71 wickets from 13 Tests, average 14.92, notable for a five-wicket haul and capturing three wickets in a crucial match against Australia.</li><li><strong>Kamindu Mendis (Sri Lanka)</strong>: 1049 runs from nine Tests, average 74.92, remembered for being the joint-third quickest to reach 1000 Test runs.</li><li><strong>Harry Brook (England)</strong>: 1100 runs from 12 Tests, average 55.00, highlighted by a remarkable triple century against Pakistan.</li></ul><blockquote>“2024 was a remarkable year for all these nominees, showcasing their exceptional talent in international cricket.” - ICC spokesperson</blockquote><p>The recognition of these players signifies their contributions to the sport and sets the stage for an exciting awards ceremony.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/nominees-for-icc-men-s-test-cricketer-of-the-year-unveiled</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/nominees-for-icc-men-s-test-cricketer-of-the-year-unveiled</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:05:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma Likely To Retire After Sydney Test: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Likely To Retire After Sydney Test: Report</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Rohit Sharma has been struggling for runs in Australia."><figcaption>Rohit Sharma has been struggling for runs in Australia.</figcaption><p>Rohit Sharma is reportedly considering retirement from Test cricket after the upcoming Sydney Test, dependent on India's performance in the World Test Championship.</p><ul><li>Sharma has struggled for runs this series, scoring only 31 runs in five innings.</li><li>India needs to win the Sydney Test and hope for favorable results in subsequent matches to qualify for the WTC Final.</li><li>His captaincy has seen India lose five out of the last six Tests played.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was the flattest track yet, and India still managed to keep Australia down to chaseable targets.”</blockquote><p>Rohit’s potential retirement comes amid challenging performances, and he could leave the game after the Border-Gavaskar Trophy in Sydney if the team does not qualify for the finals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-likely-to-retire-after-sydney-test-report-9172396.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-likely-to-retire-after-sydney-test-report-9172396.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:59:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All-time attendance record for a Test in Australia broken at the MCG - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>All-time attendance record for a Test in Australia broken at the MCG</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Cricket Australia</p><p>A new attendance record for a Test match in Australia has been established at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG), with over 373,691 spectators attending the fourth Test between Australia and India.</p><img src='https://example.com/mcg-image.jpg' alt='MCG Test Match Attendance Record'><figcaption>Record crowd at the MCG during the Test match.</figcaption><p>The attendance surpassed the old record of 350,534 set in 1937, with significant crowds throughout the match.</p><ul><li>Over 373,691 total attendees, breaking a nearly 90-year-old record.</li><li>First session of the fifth day had 51,371 attendees, culminating in a total of 74,362.</li><li>Daily attendance figures were 87,242, 85,147, 83,073, 43,867, and 74,362.</li><li>Parking areas were opened to accommodate the large crowd, causing some delays.</li></ul><blockquote>“The crowds have been absolutely extraordinary for this Test match.”</blockquote><p>This historic match highlights cricket's popularity in Australia and sets a new benchmark for future events at the MCG.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/bgt-boxing-day-test-all-time-attendance-record-for-a-test-in-australia-broken-at-the-mcg-1467148</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/bgt-boxing-day-test-all-time-attendance-record-for-a-test-in-australia-broken-at-the-mcg-1467148</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:54:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma on Yashasvi Jaiswal's dismissal: 'In all fairness, it looked like he touched it' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma on Yashasvi Jaiswal's dismissal: 'In all fairness, it looked like he touched it'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert publication date here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert source here]</p><p>Indian cricket captain Rohit Sharma discussed the dismissal of young player Yashasvi Jaiswal during a recent match, mentioning that it appeared Jaiswal may have touched the ball.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma expressed his thoughts on Jaiswal's controversial dismissal.</li><li>He noted that the event raised discussions among players and commentators.</li><li>This incident has brought attention to the need for clear communication regarding such dismissals.</li></ul><blockquote>'In all fairness, it looked like he touched it,' Rohit Sharma stated regarding the dismissal.</blockquote><p>The discussion highlights the complexities of cricket rules and the importance of player perspectives in match situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rohit-sharma-on-yashasvi-jaiswals-dismissal-in-all-fairness-it-looked-like-he-touched-it/articleshow/116791542.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rohit-sharma-on-yashasvi-jaiswals-dismissal-in-all-fairness-it-looked-like-he-touched-it/articleshow/116791542.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BPL 2024-2025: Match 1, FBA vs DBR Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BPL match between FBA vs DBR? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxOSS1maUo5dnlOb0VjVkM4d2k4UDVKYl82YV84QUwzLTBodFhkMHphb0xsQzNyQ29WT0xncVhLUllqQXZYY3pHQjhLLTZfeF9hd3U5NGExY2c1M0h4NG1TUnJJYWdIZUVZQ0JkS1c0TGJBUEZmdGJ5SGpTR0NwT1ZHN2ZvbEJvd2JBLUJGYXNWZmZSU25TWVRvcXRwUkowMTU4WnJQZFF4U1o5WEdUUWEwRlZOeFgzZTRpY2dzV3laUXI2QkN4RE12bDBpTkxrbk5NNHdsYVFEeXlXMVRPZWg4VmdyRlhlV2F60gHwAUFVX3lxTFBvYkFXTS1iUXRNVThnZ0N5UkNYSktHVWpQVWtFeWVqMWpBbEN4TmpURXlSajhXcTQtX2JHeFFOR0FUWlRhU2RkYUJtbFp0c056ZjFUWlM0WmRjbVdCbWFLZ1Q2WFRCNmVnZzI5SVdPTVd5WEZqUkQ4U3RWRGw1OExsQnZCcjFwNnRleGtMQ25DN1ZSc3BRMTc3VkN1SG01Y1dfczZ0c2Vfb2FHb2ZaSWdEOXB0YUhrQUtaQXVwYXY3QW9iQmFqN3N6TVRES0F3d3JrZVVBVmF6ZVgzMFhyVFlJLTZfLVlvUkI1blpMbEpUeA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxOSS1maUo5dnlOb0VjVkM4d2k4UDVKYl82YV84QUwzLTBodFhkMHphb0xsQzNyQ29WT0xncVhLUllqQXZYY3pHQjhLLTZfeF9hd3U5NGExY2c1M0h4NG1TUnJJYWdIZUVZQ0JkS1c0TGJBUEZmdGJ5SGpTR0NwT1ZHN2ZvbEJvd2JBLUJGYXNWZmZSU25TWVRvcXRwUkowMTU4WnJQZFF4U1o5WEdUUWEwRlZOeFgzZTRpY2dzV3laUXI2QkN4RE12bDBpTkxrbk5NNHdsYVFEeXlXMVRPZWg4VmdyRlhlV2F60gHwAUFVX3lxTFBvYkFXTS1iUXRNVThnZ0N5UkNYSktHVWpQVWtFeWVqMWpBbEN4TmpURXlSajhXcTQtX2JHeFFOR0FUWlRhU2RkYUJtbFp0c056ZjFUWlM0WmRjbVdCbWFLZ1Q2WFRCNmVnZzI5SVdPTVd5WEZqUkQ4U3RWRGw1OExsQnZCcjFwNnRleGtMQ25DN1ZSc3BRMTc3VkN1SG01Y1dfczZ0c2Vfb2FHb2ZaSWdEOXB0YUhrQUtaQXVwYXY3QW9iQmFqN3N6TVRES0F3d3JrZVVBVmF6ZVgzMFhyVFlJLTZfLVlvUkI1blpMbEpUeA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 07:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>