<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 08:24:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 08:24:47 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker Khel Ratna row: Why exception was made for Mohammed Shami last year - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manu Bhaker Khel Ratna row: Why exception was made for Mohammed Shami last year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Available <strong>Source:</strong> Not Available</p><p>In this article, the controversy surrounding the Khel Ratna award exemptions for athletes like Mohammed Shami is discussed, highlighting the discrepancies in eligibility and recognition.</p><ul><li>Focus on the Khel Ratna award and its significance.</li><li>Discussion of exceptions made in awarding athletes.</li><li>Comparison with other athletes and their eligibility.</li><li>Impact of this decision on sports recognition in India.</li></ul><blockquote>Quote or statistic related to the impact of these decisions on athletes.</blockquote><p>This situation raises important questions about fairness and transparency in sports awards.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/more-sports/others/manu-bhaker-khel-ratna-row-why-exception-was-made-for-mohammed-shami-last-year/articleshow/116621625.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/more-sports/others/manu-bhaker-khel-ratna-row-why-exception-was-made-for-mohammed-shami-last-year/articleshow/116621625.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma breaks silence on Virat Kohli's outside off-stump woes: ‘You only said he’s a modern-day great' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Discusses Virat Kohli's Struggles With Outside Off-Stump Deliveries</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/Australia-India-Cricket-32_1735020677273_1735020766952.jpg" alt="India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and teammate Virat Kohli leave the field(AP)" title="India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and teammate Virat Kohli leave the field(AP)" />
<figcaption>India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and teammate Virat Kohli leave the field(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Rohit Sharma has addressed the media regarding Virat Kohli's recent difficulties with deliveries outside the off-stump during the Border-Gavaskar Trophy, expressing confidence that Kohli will find a way to score runs in the upcoming Tests.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rohit laughed when asked about Kohli's form, emphasizing Kohli's status as a modern-day great.</li>
  <li>Kohli has had a challenging series, with only one century to his name so far.</li>
  <li>Multiple bowlers, including Boland and Hazlewood, have troubled Kohli with their bowling style.</li>
  <li>Rohit himself is also struggling, particularly with in-swing deliveries.</li>
  <li>The upcoming Boxing Day Test is crucial for India's batting lineup as the series is tied 1-1.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“You only said he is a modern-day great. Modern-day greats will figure out their way or the path (to overcome issues),” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote>
<p>Sharma remains confident that both he and Kohli will rectify their issues as they prepare for the important matches ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-breaks-silence-on-virat-kohlis-off-stump-woes-in-australia-you-only-said-he-s-a-modern-day-great-101735020561996.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-breaks-silence-on-virat-kohlis-off-stump-woes-in-australia-you-only-said-he-s-a-modern-day-great-101735020561996.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:15:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tanush Kotian to join India's Test squad as Ashwin's replacement - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tanush Kotian to Join India's Test Squad as Ashwin's Replacement</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert date here] | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p><img src='https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg' alt='Tanush Kotian' /><figcaption>Tanush Kotian</figcaption></p><p>Tanush Kotian, a crucial player for Mumbai, has been selected to replace R Ashwin in the Indian squad for the upcoming Border-Gavaskar Trophy Tests due to Ashwin's retirement.</p><ul><li>Kotian is traveling to Melbourne following Ashwin's retirement after the third Test.</li><li>He is seen as a backup for spinners Washington Sundar and Ravindra Jadeja, with Axar Patel unavailable.</li><li>Rohit Sharma commented on Kotian's call-up, highlighting his domestic achievements.</li><li>Kotian's impressive Ranji Trophy performance last season contributed to Mumbai's victory, leading to him being named Player-of-the-Tournament.</li><li>He has played 33 first-class matches, recorded 101 wickets, and scored 1525 runs.</li></ul><blockquote>"Tanush was the right option for us at this point. He's certainly shown in the domestic level what he's capable of. He's probably one of the reasons why Mumbai has gone on to win the Ranji Trophy last year." <cite>Rohit Sharma</cite></blockquote><p>With many players unavailable, Kotian's inclusion marks a significant opportunity for the young allrounder in international cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-tanush-kotian-join-india-squad-ashwin-replacement-1466332</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-tanush-kotian-join-india-squad-ashwin-replacement-1466332</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:03:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Women vs West Indies Women Match Prediction - Who will win today’s 2nd ODI match between IND-W vs WI-W? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxNdF8xNXVoR19acG9aT0RUSnVmcFV5a0RKV0xQXzdTbVk0cTMtOHFNdk1QejBHZUVwYTAxZXpSdnhjT3hsY0lOdThlelJTT0loZTA5Tnp5a0JGblR4c2wyYUM0bGJtWHBKOF9YTENfUVgtSlQzeU1mb3VMOFpmUlNJM2doc1hLNHc1b2ZCdGVsYkVyeXl2N0Q3RFRHM2lIN2YwcGo4M2tEcDRtUTlFa0FZNzltNl93VmEzMXhaSEN4elowU3loM3VRUUVvR1Z3VXVHN0UyQTQ3elg4TVFaTTdDWDZwRzI3eldGQnAwN3dIclE5QdIB-gFBVV95cUxNS1pmZHRJb29tYWprWHpzZ2FuQWlCWlI4cTFBc01SYWIzVEhRcTNxcUVNTWVHVTdxR1RFV05XUjZhWXUtTU5oZXUzVHhjZWw3R3ZndG12U1lwMjl0RUFlWjJ3VWhKR2hjTTBrWVBMYm1RVzRRUzN3b2Eta1pfSTRrVDF1eHZxVmk2VHk3WXBqVVNqTEc4dEtSakZZUGZ5MGh5MktaRHJVZU95MkJDcmZEMjRWOFVaV1ZFUjRmVnVaTnNsYUdHalJ3SzZnOG94MDJMYW1fUV9IdmdyWWpVOGZXakNzZmxKaHQ1SFh0VUlMdzg0bVJVR0FNLTZn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxNdF8xNXVoR19acG9aT0RUSnVmcFV5a0RKV0xQXzdTbVk0cTMtOHFNdk1QejBHZUVwYTAxZXpSdnhjT3hsY0lOdThlelJTT0loZTA5Tnp5a0JGblR4c2wyYUM0bGJtWHBKOF9YTENfUVgtSlQzeU1mb3VMOFpmUlNJM2doc1hLNHc1b2ZCdGVsYkVyeXl2N0Q3RFRHM2lIN2YwcGo4M2tEcDRtUTlFa0FZNzltNl93VmEzMXhaSEN4elowU3loM3VRUUVvR1Z3VXVHN0UyQTQ3elg4TVFaTTdDWDZwRzI3eldGQnAwN3dIclE5QdIB-gFBVV95cUxNS1pmZHRJb29tYWprWHpzZ2FuQWlCWlI4cTFBc01SYWIzVEhRcTNxcUVNTWVHVTdxR1RFV05XUjZhWXUtTU5oZXUzVHhjZWw3R3ZndG12U1lwMjl0RUFlWjJ3VWhKR2hjTTBrWVBMYm1RVzRRUzN3b2Eta1pfSTRrVDF1eHZxVmk2VHk3WXBqVVNqTEc4dEtSakZZUGZ5MGh5MktaRHJVZU95MkJDcmZEMjRWOFVaV1ZFUjRmVnVaTnNsYUdHalJ3SzZnOG94MDJMYW1fUV9IdmdyWWpVOGZXakNzZmxKaHQ1SFh0VUlMdzg0bVJVR0FNLTZn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 05:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: Ball Hits The Roof Of Stadium In Big Bash League 2024, Injures Bowler's Hand - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxOY0V6SjVKNFhNaDkyV3puQmNXMkpCdHVYQkdtNjBOeTdkNXAxREdWakV4VmJKLTJuQ3pON2p1Zk9vMk4wdUtqdk5CX3lCLXZzVE1qNF9jVHdHUWxYTF9HUnpkbnBIQWZ6Ym1ISnlUNkJRUWExdWVPaW8ta2ZyNVJoT0pXSXI0cU5ROEZ1WW1QQ0ZtbHI1M1Y1a1I1QWw5czUzSnk1YTVNX3BISExGcUJVVUdXUXpsUnQtMlBFV9IBxAFBVV95cUxQZGtBZnM2Tjd5Y0NaSGl1aF9vT1l5ZTdWdnlCOWxaaEtRSklCOUdmd3ZINFpGSVc1RVQzaGhMVlNhczhVUDVtZ3pPLUM4Z1lKeGtWVlMxS000b05MNXVpMHVPb3o5ampaVGR6S3JROE5UbGZUb0hFbVllSXZUNTZjMFZ5VDVBRWpmSEtEb2NCdG81SWJNcmI5cHd0TDV4eGZsVnIwU0ZTRU4waWF5ZTJrRWNFa3pMMWt1SllhNzBxaG1uVE9w?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxOY0V6SjVKNFhNaDkyV3puQmNXMkpCdHVYQkdtNjBOeTdkNXAxREdWakV4VmJKLTJuQ3pON2p1Zk9vMk4wdUtqdk5CX3lCLXZzVE1qNF9jVHdHUWxYTF9HUnpkbnBIQWZ6Ym1ISnlUNkJRUWExdWVPaW8ta2ZyNVJoT0pXSXI0cU5ROEZ1WW1QQ0ZtbHI1M1Y1a1I1QWw5czUzSnk1YTVNX3BISExGcUJVVUdXUXpsUnQtMlBFV9IBxAFBVV95cUxQZGtBZnM2Tjd5Y0NaSGl1aF9vT1l5ZTdWdnlCOWxaaEtRSklCOUdmd3ZINFpGSVc1RVQzaGhMVlNhczhVUDVtZ3pPLUM4Z1lKeGtWVlMxS000b05MNXVpMHVPb3o5ampaVGR6S3JROE5UbGZUb0hFbVllSXZUNTZjMFZ5VDVBRWpmSEtEb2NCdG81SWJNcmI5cHd0TDV4eGZsVnIwU0ZTRU4waWF5ZTJrRWNFa3pMMWt1SllhNzBxaG1uVE9w?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 05:19:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On Doubts Over Travis Head's Participation In Boxing Day Test, Australia Coach Paints Clear Picture - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>On Doubts Over Travis Head's Participation In Boxing Day Test, Australia Coach Paints Clear Picture</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/kn65a0jg_travis-head_625x300_15_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Travis Head" /><figcaption>Travis Head during practice ahead of the Boxing Day Test.</figcaption><p>Ahead of the fourth Test against India, Australia coach Andrew McDonald reassures that Travis Head is fit to play after a minor quad strain.</p><ul><li>Travis Head suffered a minor quad strain during the Brisbane Test but had a short running and fielding session on Tuesday.</li><li>He is the leading run-scorer in the series with 409 runs at an average of 81.80.</li><li>Coach McDonald reported no major fitness concerns regarding Head's participation.</li><li>McDonald expressed confidence, stating Head has completed running drills and appears ready for the match.</li><li>In his career against India, Head averages 51.09 in Tests and has scored 897 runs at an average of 74.75 since the WTC final.</li><li>Australia and India are level at 1-1 in the series with two matches remaining.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no concern at the moment. Has he been officially ticked off? I am not sure... But no concerns from my end.” - Andrew McDonald</blockquote><p>The reassurance from the coach bodes well for Australia's chances as they prepare for a crucial encounter at the MCG.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/on-doubts-over-travis-heads-participation-in-boxing-day-test-australia-coach-paints-clear-picture-7319338</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/on-doubts-over-travis-heads-participation-in-boxing-day-test-australia-coach-paints-clear-picture-7319338</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:58:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I don't blow kisses to my better half sitting in dressing room or hospitality box': Ravichandran Ashwin debunks myths - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxQeXJXb3d3MnBCb0NkSlpFb1NOREkySVNDUzRsaUdvY2JsYW1EM1VaTmRla3VuV0xQMTRYMzFCYTBpX2JpLTBtcThkak5DcE1RRUM3blFvQUpsZDYyV3dkRWZGWUY1SVU3cXQ1OGJjVDdFX0J5ZjllRVBVZWFiak43elhITUtrZzJsbkVmQk9WZC1udlloclliZXRORk1QTk1EU1MtU1hmempVSFQtUXBxbjdzRl9KY0tGcC1ENnA1N0pOVms1ak84QTQtN1dXcURndlVDUWQ3LUZrS08xdktpMkNxSlozS1VLTnlMQzd4SjBpWmtfUi1TazF2OUE0LTBveW9pU9IBigJBVV95cUxQYjZPZUt2YWRqbF84MjBZYURSNWczR0Rua2FWUEFEdlhsQTloZVlDREkzTTNMaEJEa1F3dGp0c2w3WVA2ZHVnMlQwZTlzYTZoSFNKdl9EWkg3NURKdXZ0X2NJM1RfVE96NldONVJCMldrQ2ZtVjJTRHl3b0c4TjdNMUI1Y0lpQUVJcUhpQUwxcG9xSXhJNVlEQ2pNa0xNdkpvY3lZYnBvOWY2UDhMNDR6Qk54cE0taXJRcm9PcVNIcE9vcm1IVTMtVU5LSzh1VXh6ZDA4Z25JZHp5RGpWYWp0QnhWemdPQmYwal9MV1RFVVBHVGhWc3M1Q1BaVGhqRzZwXzY2bXBMMzZQZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxQeXJXb3d3MnBCb0NkSlpFb1NOREkySVNDUzRsaUdvY2JsYW1EM1VaTmRla3VuV0xQMTRYMzFCYTBpX2JpLTBtcThkak5DcE1RRUM3blFvQUpsZDYyV3dkRWZGWUY1SVU3cXQ1OGJjVDdFX0J5ZjllRVBVZWFiak43elhITUtrZzJsbkVmQk9WZC1udlloclliZXRORk1QTk1EU1MtU1hmempVSFQtUXBxbjdzRl9KY0tGcC1ENnA1N0pOVms1ak84QTQtN1dXcURndlVDUWQ3LUZrS08xdktpMkNxSlozS1VLTnlMQzd4SjBpWmtfUi1TazF2OUE0LTBveW9pU9IBigJBVV95cUxQYjZPZUt2YWRqbF84MjBZYURSNWczR0Rua2FWUEFEdlhsQTloZVlDREkzTTNMaEJEa1F3dGp0c2w3WVA2ZHVnMlQwZTlzYTZoSFNKdl9EWkg3NURKdXZ0X2NJM1RfVE96NldONVJCMldrQ2ZtVjJTRHl3b0c4TjdNMUI1Y0lpQUVJcUhpQUwxcG9xSXhJNVlEQ2pNa0xNdkpvY3lZYnBvOWY2UDhMNDR6Qk54cE0taXJRcm9PcVNIcE9vcm1IVTMtVU5LSzh1VXh6ZDA4Z25JZHp5RGpWYWp0QnhWemdPQmYwal9MV1RFVVBHVGhWc3M1Q1BaVGhqRzZwXzY2bXBMMzZQZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:44:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Did India Choose Tanush Kotian Over Kuldeep Yadav & Axar Patel? Skipper Rohit Sharma Explains - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Explains Selection of Tanush Kotian for the Test Squad</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Tanush Kotian (Image: PTI)"><figcaption>Tanush Kotian (Image: PTI)</figcaption><p>Indian skipper Rohit Sharma shared insights into the squad selection for the 2024-25 Border-Gavaskar Trophy, highlighting the inclusion of Tanush Kotian over Kuldeep Yadav and Axar Patel.</p><ul><li>Kuldeep Yadav's recovery from hernia surgery and Axar Patel's recent fatherhood opened opportunities for Kotian.</li><li>Kotian was a standout player in the 2024-25 Ranji Trophy, with impressive stats of 502 runs and 29 wickets in 10 matches.</li><li>Sharma mentioned the need for a backup spinner due to injuries and recoveries in the team.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tanush was here a month back... Not that Tanush is not good enough. He has shown in the last two years what he has done in domestic cricket and we really wanted just a backup.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>Rohit emphasized the importance of Kotian's recent form and readiness, stating that he is a valuable option for the team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/why-did-india-choose-tanush-kotian-over-kuldeep-yadav-axar-patel-skipper-rohit-sharma-explains-9166394.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/why-did-india-choose-tanush-kotian-over-kuldeep-yadav-axar-patel-skipper-rohit-sharma-explains-9166394.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:37:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Modern-day great Virat Kohli will figure it out' - Rohit Sharma - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Modern-day great Virat Kohli will figure it out' - Rohit Sharma</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116617365,imgsize-113936,width-400,resizemode-4/116617365.jpg" alt="Virat Kohli (BCCI Photo)" title="Virat Kohli (BCCI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Virat Kohli (BCCI Photo)</figcaption><p>As India and Australia prepare for the fourth Test of the Border Gavaskar Trophy, Kohli's inconsistent performance is under scrutiny. Captain Rohit Sharma expresses confidence in Kohli, stating he believes Kohli will regain his form.</p><ul><li>Kohli has scored 126 runs in five Test innings during the series, with an average of 31.50.</li><li>Rohit Sharma, despite his own struggles, remains optimistic about Kohli’s ability to turn things around.</li><li>Rohit commented on modern-day greats like Kohli saying they will find their own path to success.</li><li>The team dynamics have shifted, with Rohit batting in the middle order, affecting his performance.</li><li>Rohit has insisted on keeping the team's batting order strategy private.</li></ul><blockquote>"Modern-day greats will figure out their own way of (carving out their) path." - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>In summary, while Kohli's form has been a concern, Rohit Sharma's confidence in his ability to bounce back is a reassuring message for fans as India looks to make a mark in the ongoing series against Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/modern-day-great-virat-kohli-will-figure-it-out-rohit-sharma/articleshow/116617360.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/modern-day-great-virat-kohli-will-figure-it-out-rohit-sharma/articleshow/116617360.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Kuldeep Yadav doesn't have visa and Axar...': Rohit Sharma reveals why Tanush Kotian was picked as Ashwin's replacement - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma explains why Tanush Kotian was picked as Ashwin's replacement ahead of Kuldeep Yadav and Axar Patel</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 10:23 AM IST <strong>Source:</strong> HT Sports</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/rohit_tanush_1735010867716_1735010881281.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma reveals why Tanush Kotian was picked" title="Rohit Sharma reveals why Tanush Kotian was picked"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma reveals why Tanush Kotian was picked</figcaption><p>India’s cricket team captain Rohit Sharma explained the decision to select Tanush Kotian as a replacement for the retired Ravichandran Ashwin in the upcoming Border-Gavaskar Trophy Tests.</p><ul><li>Tanush Kotian was chosen as Ashwin's replacement after Ashwin's retirement from international cricket.</li><li>Rohit humorously noted that Kuldeep Yadav was not selected due to visa issues.</li><li>Kotian recently performed well in the ‘A’ tour in Australia.</li><li>Kuldeep Yadav is recovering from hernia surgery, and Axar Patel recently became a father, making him unavailable.</li><li>Kotian has a strong track record in first-class cricket, with 101 wickets and 1525 runs.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tanush was here a month back and Kuldeep doesn't have a visa... we wanted a back-up in case we play two spinners in Sydney or Melbourne.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>The selection highlights the team's strategy to ensure readiness with injuries and personal matters affecting player availability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/kuldeep-yadav-doesnt-have-visa-axar-patel-rohit-sharma-why-tanush-kotian-was-picked-as-ashwin-replacement-101735010015441.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/kuldeep-yadav-doesnt-have-visa-axar-patel-rohit-sharma-why-tanush-kotian-was-picked-as-ashwin-replacement-101735010015441.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker Said "Shouldn't Have Gone To Olympics, Won Medals": Heartbroken Father - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxQZ1lvTmM2b0dOWmVyTzlLMWN3SjNfc1Q3SWgyTUNTaFh4aUtNLVJaalRVSllLbzVlckJsU3ZFbjdnY2V6MTB0UTdjMW1OWTB3ckZuTnBWUkpQOXZKVjZ3b1B1eTFIbUhGUHdhaDRlMFhkTTI0MHd1YXBpSmFDcTZHSXpHYTFLUHltcmVZR21ESW03eXFqVnYzdHU5QlIwbmFTa3VLbFZ2UVhMU0lqTGducGdQakJXZ2VySkowZmphMmdWRGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxQZ1lvTmM2b0dOWmVyTzlLMWN3SjNfc1Q3SWgyTUNTaFh4aUtNLVJaalRVSllLbzVlckJsU3ZFbjdnY2V6MTB0UTdjMW1OWTB3ckZuTnBWUkpQOXZKVjZ3b1B1eTFIbUhGUHdhaDRlMFhkTTI0MHd1YXBpSmFDcTZHSXpHYTFLUHltcmVZR21ESW03eXFqVnYzdHU5QlIwbmFTa3VLbFZ2UVhMU0lqTGducGdQakJXZ2VySkowZmphMmdWRGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:43:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS, Boxing Day Test: Sam Konstas to debut, Travis Head an injury doubt - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS, Boxing Day Test: Sam Konstas to debut, Travis Head an injury doubt</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116615562,imgsize-95020,width-400,resizemode-4/116615562.jpg" alt="IND vs AUS, Boxing Day Test: Sam Konstas to debut, Travis Head an injury doubt" title="Sam Konstas is set to make his Test debut against India in the Boxing Day Test at the MCG." decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Sam Konstas is set to make his Test debut against India in the Boxing Day Test at the MCG. (Image: X)</figcaption><p>Sam Konstas is set to make his Test debut against India in the Boxing Day Test, becoming the youngest Australian Test debutant since Pat Cummins in 2011.</p><ul><li>Konstas confirmed by Australia coach Andrew McDonald to debut.</li><li>He scored 107 runs in a practice match against India three weeks ago.</li><li>Travis Head's participation is uncertain due to a quad strain.</li><li>Head has begun light training but faces fitness tests.</li><li>Scott Boland is likely to replace Josh Hazlewood in the playing XI.</li></ul><blockquote>“He’s been very similar to what I’ve seen on the outside … he’s composed, relaxed.” - Andrew McDonald on Sam Konstas</blockquote><p>The anticipation for Sam Konstas's debut is high, while Travis Head's injury poses a potential setback for the Australian team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-sam-konstas-to-debut-travis-head-an-injury-doubt/articleshow/116615092.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-sam-konstas-to-debut-travis-head-an-injury-doubt/articleshow/116615092.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli's Friend Shares Health Update, Makes Big Medical Bills Revelation - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli's Friend Shares Health Update, Makes Big Medical Bills Revelation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hlqqq0m8_vinod-kambli-pti_625x300_24_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Vinod Kambli's Friend Shares Health Update, Makes Big Medical Bills Revelation"><figcaption>Vinod Kambli during his hospital stay</figcaption><p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli has shown improvement after being hospitalized due to a urinary infection. His friend, Marcus Couto, has provided updates on his condition and mentioned arrangements for Kambli's medical bills.</p><ul><li>Kambli was admitted to a hospital in Thane due to health deterioration.</li><li>He is suffering from a urinary infection but is now doing 'fine'.</li><li>Couto suggests keeping Kambli in the hospital for about a month for further treatment.</li><li>A hospital owner facilitated Kambli's admission.</li><li>Kambli expressed gratitude to the medical team for their care.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is because of the doctor here that I am alive... All I would say is that I will do whatever sir (referring to the doctor) asks me to.” - Vinod Kambli</blockquote><p>Kambli's recent public appearance was at the inauguration of coach Ramakant Achrekar's memorial.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/vinod-kamblis-friend-shares-health-update-makes-big-medical-bills-revelation-7319066</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/vinod-kamblis-friend-shares-health-update-makes-big-medical-bills-revelation-7319066</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:59:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Konstas' MCG debut confirmed, Head faces a fitness test - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Konstas to Make MCG Test Debut as Head Faces Fitness Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><img src='https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg' alt='Story Image'><figcaption>Konstas looks 19, behaves 30, and is unfazed about a Test debut at the MCG</figcaption><p>Sam Konstas will debut for Australia on Boxing Day, becoming the fourth-youngest Test debutant. Meanwhile, coach Andrew McDonald expresses confidence in Travis Head's fitness after a minor injury.</p><ul><li>Sam Konstas will make his Test debut against India at 19 years and 85 days old.</li><li>Coach Andrew McDonald confirms Konstas was notified of his selection.</li><li>Travis Head is undergoing a fitness test after suffering a minor quad strain.</li><li>Australia will make at least two changes, with Konstas and Scott Boland replacing Nathan McSweeney and Josh Hazlewood, respectively.</li></ul><blockquote>“We said from the get go, when leading into the summer, that we wouldn't shy away, and age was no barrier,” said McDonald.</blockquote><p>The announcement of the final team lineup is expected on Christmas Day.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/konstas-debut-confirmed-head-faces-a-fitness-test-1466357</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/konstas-debut-confirmed-head-faces-a-fitness-test-1466357</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:53:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ashwin answers 'very simple question': What sets Dhoni apart as captain? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashwin answers 'very simple question': What sets Dhoni apart as captain?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>In a recent discussion, Indian cricketer Ravichandran Ashwin highlighted the unique qualities that set MS Dhoni apart as a captain, emphasizing his decision-making skills and leadership style.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Ashwin notes that Dhoni's calmness in pressure situations is unmatched.</li>
  <li>The ability to adapt strategies based on the game's demands was a recurring theme.</li>
  <li>Dhoni's trust in his players encourages them to perform their best.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Dhoni’s decision-making always stands out when the stakes are high.” - Ravichandran Ashwin</blockquote>
<p>This discussion sheds light on the reasons behind Dhoni's success as a captain and his influence on Indian cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/ravichandran-ashwin-answers-very-simple-question-what-sets-ms-dhoni-apart-as-captain/articleshow/116614660.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/ravichandran-ashwin-answers-very-simple-question-what-sets-ms-dhoni-apart-as-captain/articleshow/116614660.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PV Sindhu & Venkata Datta Sais Net Worth 2024: How Rich Is Indias Star Shuttler And Her Husband? In Pics - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu & Venkata Datta Sais Net Worth 2024: How Rich Is India’s Star Shuttler And Her Husband?</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 24, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Zee News</p><img src="https://english.cdn.zeenews.com/sites/default/files/2024/12/24/1615828-snapinsta.app47031541813873107888971011016197735334546893n1080.jpg?im=Resize=(400)" alt="PV Sindhu and Venkata Datta Sai"/><figcaption>PV Sindhu and Venkata Datta Sai</figcaption><p>Indian badminton star PV Sindhu recently married tech executive Venkata Datta Sai, prompting discussions about their financial empires. Both excel in their fields, showcasing their achievements and combined wealth.</p><ul><li>Sindhu's net worth is estimated at ₹59 crore ($7.1 million).</li><li>Venkata Datta Sai has a net worth of ₹150 crore.</li><li>Sindhu owns a luxurious hilltop home in Hyderabad.</li><li>She has a growing car collection featuring brands like BMW and Mahindra.</li><li>Sindhu has lucrative endorsement deals, including a ₹50 crore contract with Li Ning.</li><li>Venkat's corporate work includes serving as Executive Director at Posidex Technologies.</li><li>The couple's wedding in December 2024 highlighted their shared commitment to success.</li></ul><blockquote>"Their union is not only a celebration of love but also of mutual accomplishments and ambitions."</blockquote><p>The couple is poised for further success in their respective endeavors, marking them as a dynamic force in sports and business.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/photos/sports/pv-sindhu-venkata-datta-sais-net-worth-2024-how-rich-is-indias-star-shuttler-and-her-husband-in-pics-2835167</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/photos/sports/pv-sindhu-venkata-datta-sais-net-worth-2024-how-rich-is-indias-star-shuttler-and-her-husband-in-pics-2835167</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ponting analyses Gill's overseas struggles - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ponting Analyzes Gill's Struggles Overseas</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Ricky Ponting has analyzed Shubman Gill's recent performances overseas, suggesting that the young opener is over-complicating his batting approach.</p><ul><li>After an injury setback, Gill has struggled with scores of 31, 28, and 1 in his recent matches.</li><li>Ponting believes Gill has changed his technique too much and needs to trust his instincts more.</li><li>He emphasized the need for Gill to adopt a confident mindset while batting.</li></ul><blockquote>“If he goes in with that mindset and that attitude, then things could change here in Melbourne for him.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Ponting encourages Gill to focus on his attacking style to improve his performance in future matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/world-test-championship/news/ponting-analyses-gill-s-overseas-struggles</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/world-test-championship/news/ponting-analyses-gill-s-overseas-struggles</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:07:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bumrah targeted with big allegation, Aussie media blamed for not saying it out loud: 'Is it not politically correct?' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bumrah targeted with big allegation, Aussie media blamed for not saying it out loud: 'Is it not politically correct?'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/AP12-15-2024-000007B-0_1735004026968_1735004037684.jpg" alt="India's Jasprit Bumrah looks on during play on day two of the third cricket test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane(AP)" title="India's Jasprit Bumrah looks on during play on day two of the third cricket test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane(AP)"><figcaption>India's Jasprit Bumrah looks on during play on day two of the third cricket test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane(AP)</figcaption>
<p>In the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy series, Indian fast bowler Jasprit Bumrah has been accused of having a suspect bowling action. Veteran sports commentator Ian Maurice suggests that political correctness is preventing a thorough examination of Bumrah's technique.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bumrah has taken 21 wickets in six innings with an average of 10.90 in the series.</li>
  <li>Ian Maurice claims Australian media is hesitant to scrutinize Bumrah's action due to fear of being labeled racist.</li>
  <li>Greg Chappell has defended Bumrah, calling his bowling action legal and unique.</li>
  <li>Concerns about Bumrah's action arose after comparisons to former cricketer Mohammad Hasnain, who was banned for suspect action.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“By the way, please stop this nonsense of questioning Bumrah's action. It is unique, but it is unequivocally clean.” - Greg Chappell</blockquote>
<p>This debate highlights the ongoing challenges in addressing issues of fairness and transparency in sports while respecting cultural sensitivities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-targeted-with-big-allegation-aussie-media-blamed-for-not-saying-it-out-loud-is-it-not-politically-correct-101735003837788.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-targeted-with-big-allegation-aussie-media-blamed-for-not-saying-it-out-loud-is-it-not-politically-correct-101735003837788.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:05:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R Ashwin Hits Bullseye, Explains Difference Between MS Dhoni And Other Captains - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>R Ashwin Hits Bullseye, Explains Difference Between MS Dhoni And Other Captains</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width='639' height='479' src='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/qrmafk8g_ms-dhoni-and-r-ashwin-bcci_625x300_24_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605' alt='R Ashwin and MS Dhoni' /><figcaption>File photo of MS Dhoni and R Ashwin © BCCI/Sportzpics</figcaption><p>Ravichandran Ashwin highlights the attributes that make MS Dhoni a standout captain compared to others, emphasizing his focus on the basics and decision-making during critical moments.</p><ul><li>Ashwin praises Dhoni's ability to stick to fundamental principles of cricket.</li><li>Dhoni's calm leadership led India to several significant victories, including T20 and ODI World Cups.</li><li>Examples of Dhoni allowing bowlers to express themselves while enforcing standards.</li><li>Dhoni's captaincy in IPL helped Tushar Deshpande become a top wicket-taker.</li><li>Statistical overview of Dhoni's success as a captain in all formats.</li></ul><blockquote>"In my head, I think he does most of the basic things right... over the years, I realised people have forgotten the basics." - R Ashwin</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Ashwin's observations shed light on Dhoni's unique style of captaincy, which balances simplicity with effectiveness, making him one of cricket's most revered leaders.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/r-ashwin-hits-bullseye-explains-difference-between-ms-dhoni-and-other-captains-7317802</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/r-ashwin-hits-bullseye-explains-difference-between-ms-dhoni-and-other-captains-7317802</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:57:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jio and Star to operate as unified entity from India-England series - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jio and Star to Operate as Unified Entity for Upcoming India-England Series</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Tue, Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p><img height="396" width="595" alt="Star and Jio formally came together in November 2024 when Reliance Industries Ltd announced the merger" title="Star and Jio formally came together in November 2024 when Reliance Industries Ltd announced the merger" src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c383312/star-and-jio-formally-came-tog.jpg"><figcaption>Star and Jio formally came together in November 2024 when Reliance Industries Ltd announced the merger © Getty</figcaption><p>The merger between Jio and Star has been officially completed, allowing the two major sports broadcasters to operate as one. This integration will prominently feature during England's upcoming tour of India.</p><ul><li>The integration begins with the England tour, scheduled for January 22 to February 12, featuring an eight-match white-ball series.</li><li>Star will primarily broadcast the matches on Star Sports and Disney+ Hotstar, while JioCinema and Sports18 will also be involved.</li><li>The merger announcement included a ₹11,500 crore investment from Reliance for the joint venture aimed at growth.</li><li>The joint venture is valued at approximately ₹70.352 crore (USD 8.5 billion) and is controlled by Reliance Industries.</li></ul><blockquote>“The merger of the media and JioCinema businesses has become effective following the necessary regulatory approvals.”</blockquote><p>This merger represents a significant shifting landscape in sports broadcasting in India, with traditional powerhouses facing new competition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132883/jio-and-star-to-operate-as-unified-entity-from-india-england-series</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132883/jio-and-star-to-operate-as-unified-entity-from-india-england-series</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:52:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli-Babar Azam Comparisons Laughed Off By Ex-Pakistan Star: "Even Joe Root, Steve Smith..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli-Babar Azam Comparisons Laughed Off By Ex-Pakistan Star: "Even Joe Root, Steve Smith..."</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> August 25, 2022 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-08/1mr5tvog_virat-kohli-babar-azam-afp_625x300_25_August_22.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Virat Kohli-Babar Azam Comparisons Laughed Off By Ex-Pakistan Star: &quot;Even Joe Root, Steve Smith...&quot;"/><figcaption>Mohammad Amir feels Virat Kohli can't be compared to anyone. © AFP</figcaption><p>Former Pakistan cricketer Mohammad Amir, shortly after his retirement, has declared India’s Virat Kohli as the greatest player of this generation, dismissing comparisons with other cricketers.</p><ul><li>Amir believes comparing Kohli with players like Babar Azam, Steve Smith, or Joe Root is laughable.</li><li>He states Kohli's unmatched performance across all formats makes him incomparable.</li><li>Amir praised Kohli's work ethic and resilience, noting his comeback after a tough phase in 2014.</li><li>Amir reminisced that his career highlight was dismissing Sachin Tendulkar in 2009.</li></ul><blockquote>“Virat Kohli is the greatest player of this generation... We cannot compare Virat Kohli to anyone because he has won so many matches for India.” - Mohammad Amir</blockquote><p>In a solid endorsement of Kohli's achievements, Amir emphasizes the Indian cricketer's legacy and impact on the game.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/virat-kohli-babar-azam-comparisons-laughed-off-by-ex-pakistan-star-even-joe-root-steve-smith-7308968</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/virat-kohli-babar-azam-comparisons-laughed-off-by-ex-pakistan-star-even-joe-root-steve-smith-7308968</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:47:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma Troubled By Part-Timer Devdutt Padikkal In Nets, Video Viral - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-troubled-by-part-timer-devdutt-padikkal-in-nets-video-viral-7312682</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-troubled-by-part-timer-devdutt-padikkal-in-nets-video-viral-7312682</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:43:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ben Stokes ruled out of all cricket for three months - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ben Stokes Ruled Out of Cricket for Three Months Due to Injury</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Tue, Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c590565/ben-stokes-will-be-out-of-acti.jpg" alt="Ben Stokes will be out of action for at least three months" title="Ben Stokes will be out of action for at least three months">
<figcaption>Ben Stokes will be out of action for at least three months © Getty</figcaption>
<p>Ben Stokes has been ruled out of all cricket for at least three months with a torn left hamstring, sustained during the third Test against New Zealand, which England won.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Stokes missed the England squad for the Champions Trophy due to his injury.</li>
  <li>He had previous injury issues, including knee surgery in October 2023.</li>
  <li>In August, he suffered a similar hamstring injury that limited his playing time.</li>
  <li>Stokes had been managing his workload and opted out of IPL 2024.</li>
  <li>He expressed confidence in his physical fitness before the injury occurred.</li>
  <li>He will also miss next year's Hundred competition starting on January 9.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I have to work so much harder on the physical side of the job to allow me to go out and do my job...” - Ben Stokes</blockquote>
<p>This latest injury adds to Stokes' challenges on the field, potentially impacting England's future performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132884/ben-stokes-ruled-out-of-all-cricket-for-three-months</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132884/ben-stokes-ruled-out-of-all-cricket-for-three-months</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:43:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I Deserve It. Let India Decide...": What Manu Bhaker Told Father On Khel Ratna Snub - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Some Orders Being Followed: Manu Bhaker's Father Hints At Khel Ratna Snub 'Conspiracy'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> July 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/d9uaet08_manu-bhaker-x_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Some Orders Being Followed: Manu Bhaker's Father Hints At Khel Ratna Snub 'Conspiracy'"><figcaption>File image of Manu Bhaker. © X (Twitter)</figcaption><p>Manu Bhaker, despite her remarkable achievements including two bronze medals at the Paris Olympic Games, has been snubbed for the Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna award by the Sports Ministry. Her father, Ram Kishan, implies a questionable decision-making process within the committee, voicing their belief that she is deserving of the award and criticizing the lack of respect for Olympic medalists.</p><ul><li>Manu Bhaker won two bronze medals at the Paris Olympics, making history for female shooters in India.</li><li>Her father claims there may be a conspiracy behind the lack of recommendation for the prestigious Khel Ratna award.</li><li>There is a contrast between the Sports Ministry's claim that Manu did not apply for the award and her father's assertions of multiple applications.</li><li>Her absence from the nominees list has disappointed many supporters, further fueled by previous controversies surrounding her social media posts.</li></ul><blockquote>"Despite such a fantastic performance if Manu is not recommended for Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna, then I am forced to believe that all is not well in the committee, or some orders were being followed." - Ram Kishan</blockquote><p>This controversy raises questions about the integrity of the awards process and highlights the challenges faced by athletes in India. Manu Bhaker's story reminds us of the need for recognition and support for those who achieve excellence in sports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/shooting/i-deserve-it-let-india-decide-what-manu-bhaker-told-father-on-khel-ratna-snub-7316545</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/shooting/i-deserve-it-let-india-decide-what-manu-bhaker-told-father-on-khel-ratna-snub-7316545</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:40:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prayers from Pakistan for Vinod Kambli's recovery: 'Duaon mei usko yaad rakhein' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prayers from Pakistan for Vinod Kambli's recovery: 'Duaon mei usko yaad rakhein'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Unavailable] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Unavailable]</p>
<p>Fans and well-wishers from Pakistan have come together to express their prayers and support for Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli, advocating for his recovery during his time of need.</p>
<ul>
<li>Pakistani fans are sending heartfelt messages and prayers to Kambli.</li>
<li>The cricketer's situation has sparked widespread concern among his supporters across borders.</li>
<li>Quotes from Pakistani celebrities highlight the solidarity shown for Kambli.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Duaon mei usko yaad rakhein" - [Notable Person's Name]</blockquote>
<p>This collective support demonstrates the power of sports in uniting fans and spreading positive vibes, regardless of national borders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/prayers-from-pakistan-for-vinod-kamblis-recovery-duaon-mei-usko-yaad-rakhein/articleshow/116613748.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/prayers-from-pakistan-for-vinod-kamblis-recovery-duaon-mei-usko-yaad-rakhein/articleshow/116613748.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shreyas Iyer strengthens chances for CT squad; Kishan, Gaikwad present case with centuries in Vijay Hazare Trophy - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Iyer, Kishan, and Gaikwad Shine in Vijay Hazare Trophy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/Shreyas_Iyer_Gaikwad_Kishan_1734962714354_1734962720113.jpg" alt="Ishan Kishan, Ruturaj Gaikwad present cases for CT squad with centuries in Vijay Hazare Trophy; Shreyas Iyer also shines(PTI and X Images)"><figcaption>Ishan Kishan, Ruturaj Gaikwad present cases for CT squad with centuries in Vijay Hazare Trophy; Shreyas Iyer also shines(PTI and X Images)</figcaption><p>Ishan Kishan, Ruturaj Gaikwad, and Shreyas Iyer all made strong cases for selection to the Indian Champions Trophy squad during the ongoing Vijay Hazare Trophy, showcasing exceptional batting performances.</p><ul><li>Ishan Kishan scored 134 runs off 78 balls, leading Jharkhand to a 9-wicket win against Manipur.</li><li>Ruturaj Gaikwad hit 148 runs off just 74 balls, helping Maharashtra to a comfortable 9-wicket victory over Services.</li><li>Shreyas Iyer contributed 44 runs off 20 balls in Mumbai's 3-wicket win against Hyderabad, maintaining his impressive form.</li><li>Krunal Pandya scored 80 runs off 54 balls, aiding Baroda in securing a 62-run win over Kerala.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kishan scored 134 runs, hitting 16 fours and 6 sixes.”</blockquote><blockquote>“Gaikwad’s 148 included 16 fours and 11 sixes.”</blockquote><p>The performances of Kishan, Gaikwad, and Iyer not only highlight their abilities but also their potential contributions to the Indian team in upcoming tournaments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/shreyas-iyer-strengthens-chances-for-ct-squad-kishan-gaikwad-present-case-with-centuries-in-vijay-hazare-trophy-101734961665971.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/shreyas-iyer-strengthens-chances-for-ct-squad-kishan-gaikwad-present-case-with-centuries-in-vijay-hazare-trophy-101734961665971.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:56:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘…MS Dhoni would be livid, he would take me off the bowling’: Ashwin dissects basics that set legendary captain apart - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashwin Discusses What Sets MS Dhoni Apart as a Captain</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/Ashwin_CSK_BCCI_1639749410486_1734972696240.jpeg" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin reveals what makes MS Dhoni truly great as a leader. (BCCI)"><figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin reveals what makes MS Dhoni truly great as a leader. (BCCI)</figcaption><p>Ravichandran Ashwin highlights MS Dhoni's excellence as a captain, emphasizing that he excels in the basics of cricket, which many captains overlook.</p><ul><li>Dhoni recognized Ashwin's potential during the 2010 IPL season.</li><li>Ashwin recalls specific moments where Dhoni's expectations pushed players to perform better.</li><li>Ashwin emphasizes the importance of basic cricketing skills, which are often forgotten.</li><li>The conversation reveals insights into Dhoni's strategy and leadership approach.</li></ul><blockquote>“He does most basic things right, and most other captains miss the basic elementary things.” - Ravichandran Ashwin</blockquote><p>This conversation sheds light on the essential qualities that make MS Dhoni a legendary captain and highlights Ashwin's admiration for his leadership style.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ms-dhoni-would-be-livid-he-would-take-me-off-the-bowling-ashwin-dissects-basics-that-set-legendary-captain-apart-101734972698340.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ms-dhoni-would-be-livid-he-would-take-me-off-the-bowling-ashwin-dissects-basics-that-set-legendary-captain-apart-101734972698340.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:49:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Australian cricketers Pat Cummins, Steve Smith, Travis Head and others described BCCI and ICC: Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australian Cricketers Comment on ICC and BCCI Ahead of Test Match</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/smith_head_icc_bcci_1734933452438_1734933463540.jpg" alt="Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket" title="Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket"><figcaption>Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket</figcaption><p>Amid rising tensions between India and Australia, Australian cricketers, including Pat Cummins and Travis Head, made their comments on the ICC and BCCI during a game organized by ABC Sport.</p><ul><li>Pat Cummins described ICC, BCCI, and Indian cricket as 'Big'.</li><li>Travis Head referred to the BCCI as 'rulers' and the ICC as 'second'.</li><li>Glenn Maxwell, Alex Carey, and Steve Smith called the BCCI 'powerful' while describing the ICC as 'boss' and 'not as powerful'.</li><li>Steve Smith later backtracked on his remark, claiming it was a joke and restated the ICC as 'leaders'.</li><li>Usman Khawaja chose to 'pass' on describing the ICC, referencing past controversies with the organization.</li></ul><blockquote>“No, no I can't say that. It was a joke.” - Steve Smith</blockquote><p>The light-hearted game shed light on the players' perceptions of cricket's governing bodies as they prepare for the crucial Border-Gavaskar Trophy match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/steve-smith-calls-icc-not-as-powerful-as-bcci-then-immediately-backtracks-travis-head-says-indian-board-rulers-101734930106913.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/steve-smith-calls-icc-not-as-powerful-as-bcci-then-immediately-backtracks-travis-head-says-indian-board-rulers-101734930106913.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I am alive because…': Vinod Kambli clutches doctor's hand, gives first statement from hospital bed - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli's Emotional Hospital Statement: Grateful to Doctors</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Dec 24, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/20241223-MTH-PGD-MN-Vinod-kambali-001004-0_1734999473491_1734999481025.JPG" alt="Vinod Kambli continues to undergo treatment in Thane's Akruti Hospital(PTI)" title="Vinod Kambli continues to undergo treatment in Thane's Akruti Hospital(PTI)">
<figcaption>Vinod Kambli continues to undergo treatment in Thane's Akruti Hospital(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli, recovering from clots in his brain, expressed profound gratitude to his doctors for saving his life during an emotional hospital statement while receiving treatment in Thane.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kambli was hospitalized due to clots in his brain, reportedly in critical condition.</li>
    <li>He recounted a touching moment of holding his doctor’s hand and thanked them for their care.</li>
    <li>His condition deteriorated recently after suffering from a urinary infection.</li>
    <li>Despite past financial struggles, Kambli expressed commitment to rehabilitation if offered help by the cricket community.</li>
    <li>Acknowledged support from fans and the medical team during his recovery.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I am alive because of the doctors here. All I would say is that I will do whatever sir (referring to the doctor) asks me to. People will see the inspiration that I'll give them," said Kambli.</blockquote>
<p>Kambli's ongoing recovery brings hope, as he remains grateful for the support from both healthcare professionals and fans, highlighting a poignant chapter in his life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/i-am-alive-because-vinod-kambli-clutches-doctors-hand-gives-first-statement-from-hospital-bed-101734999376454.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/i-am-alive-because-vinod-kambli-clutches-doctors-hand-gives-first-statement-from-hospital-bed-101734999376454.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:34:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli is fine, says his friend Marcus Couto after ex-cricketer is hospitalized - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli is fine, says his friend Marcus Couto after ex-cricketer is hospitalized</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified. <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified.</p><p>Vinod Kambli, the former Indian cricketer, has been hospitalized recently, but his friend Marcus Couto has confirmed that he is doing fine.</p><ul><li>Kambli was hospitalized, prompting concern among fans and supporters.</li><li>His friend Marcus Couto provided reassurance about Kambli's health status.</li><li>The situation reflects the ongoing interest in Kambli’s well-being among the public.</li></ul><blockquote>“Vinod is fine, don’t worry,” said Marcus Couto.</blockquote><p>This reassurance from a close friend helps alleviate concerns surrounding Vinod Kambli's health following his hospitalization.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-is-fine-says-his-friend-couto-after-ex-cricketer-is-hospitalized/articleshow/116613381.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-is-fine-says-his-friend-couto-after-ex-cricketer-is-hospitalized/articleshow/116613381.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>