<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 03:21:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 03:21:16 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FIDE World Rapid and Blitz Chess Championships 2024: Carlsen announces shock withdrawal; Arjun, Harika, Humpy among leaders after Day 2 - ESPN India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FIDE World Rapid and Blitz Chess Championships 2024: Carlsen announces shock withdrawal; Arjun, Harika, Humpy among leaders after Day 2</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN</p><img src="https://a.espncdn.com/combiner/i?img=/i/columnists/espn_generic_m.jpg&amp;h=80&amp;w=80&amp;scale=crop" alt="" width="40" height="40"><figcaption>Image Credit: ESPN</figcaption><p>Magnus Carlsen's unexpected withdrawal from the World Rapid & Blitz Championships was triggered by a dress code violation, leading to a $200 fine and not being paired for a round.</p><ul><li>Carlsen withdrew after refusing to comply with the tournament's dress code regulations.</li><li>Volodar Murzin, Arjun Erigaisi, Jan-Krzysztof Duda, and Alexander Grischuk are leading the Open championship.</li><li>Harika Dronavalli, Koneru Humpy, and Ju Wenjun are leading the Women's division.</li></ul><blockquote>Ian Nepomniachtchi was also fined for a dress code violation but complied with the regulations.</blockquote><p>Carlsen expressed his frustration with FIDE, stating he was tired of their regulations. FIDE defended its dress code, emphasizing professionalism and fairness for all participants.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espn.in/chess/story/_/id/43187695/fide-world-rapid-blitz-chess-championships-2024-magnus-carlsen-announces-shock-withdrawal-arjun-erigaisi-harika-dronavalli-koneru-humpy-leaders-day-2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espn.in/chess/story/_/id/43187695/fide-world-rapid-blitz-chess-championships-2024-magnus-carlsen-announces-shock-withdrawal-arjun-erigaisi-harika-dronavalli-koneru-humpy-leaders-day-2</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 02:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 3 Live Updates: Nitish Reddy Nears 50, 250 Up For India But Follow-On Scare Remains - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 3 Live Updates</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/00ps8ku_nitish-reddy-afp_625x300_28_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 3 Live Updates" />
<figcaption>Nitish Reddy in action on Day 3 of the 4th Test.</figcaption>
<p>Nitish Reddy and Washington Sundar's partnership is pivotal for India as they stand on 250 runs but face the looming threat of follow-on against a determined Australian bowling line-up. The outcome of this match could heavily influence the series and World Test Championship finals.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Nitish Reddy approaches his half-century after a confident display of batting.</li>
    <li>India has scored 250 runs, but six wickets are down.</li>
    <li>Australia is pressing hard to avoid India building a substantial lead.</li>
    <li>The match is crucial for India's chances in the World Test Championship.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The way India plays today might well decide the course of the series and World Test Championship final.”</blockquote>
<p>This match remains critical for both teams as India seeks to avoid defeat while Australia aims to secure an upper hand in the series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-3-live-score-updates-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-7344658</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-3-live-score-updates-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-7344658</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 02:29:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boxing Day Test LIVE updates: Piastri has playful dig at Kohli’s bump as Australia chase three wickets after lunch - The Age]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Boxing Day Test LIVE updates: Piastri pokes fun at Kohli as Australia targets wickets after lunch</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2024-12-28T14:13:15+11:00">December 28, 2024</time><strong> Source:</strong> Live Cricket Update</p><p>Australian cricketer Oscar Piastri made a playful remark about Virat Kohli during the ongoing Boxing Day Test. The match continues with Australia aiming to secure three critical wickets following the lunch break.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>Piastri humorously commented on Kohli's appearance.</li><li>Australia is strategizing to capture three wickets shortly after lunch.</li><li>The live updates emphasize the fluctuating conditions of the game.</li></ul><blockquote>“At least I didn’t cop a hip and shoulder”: Piastri on his experience during the match.</blockquote><p>This light-hearted interaction between players highlights the competitive yet friendly nature of international cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theage.com.au/sport/cricket/boxing-day-test-live-updates-series-on-the-line-as-aussies-chase-wickets-as-day-three-against-india-20241227-p5l0vo.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theage.com.au/sport/cricket/boxing-day-test-live-updates-series-on-the-line-as-aussies-chase-wickets-as-day-three-against-india-20241227-p5l0vo.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 02:14:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Rohit Sharma is finished': India captain told to 'retire', hand over leadership to Bumrah as fans lose patience - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Faces Calls to Retire as Frustration Grows Among Fans</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-103_1735348907571_1735348920657.jpg" alt="India's Rohit Sharma prepares to bat on the second day of the fourth cricket Test match between Australia and India at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG)(AFP)"><figcaption>India's Rohit Sharma prepares to bat on the second day of the fourth cricket Test match between Australia and India at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG)(AFP)</figcaption><p>Rohit Sharma’s disappointing performance as an opener has sparked criticism and calls for him to retire. Following a poor showing in the fourth Test against Australia, fans are urging him to step down and hand over the captaincy to Jasprit Bumrah.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma was dismissed for just 3 runs after facing five balls in the Melbourne Test.</li><li>His performance has been under scrutiny, with just 152 runs in his last 14 innings.</li><li>Netizens have expressed frustration on social media, calling for his retirement.</li><li>Ricky Ponting criticized Rohit's batting performance as lazy and unfocused.</li><li>Sunil Gavaskar suggested that Rohit might consider retirement if his form does not improve in upcoming matches.</li></ul><blockquote>“Out of form is one thing, but Rohit Sharma is giving Negative Energy now.” - Fan comment on social media</blockquote><p>The ongoing debate around Rohit’s future in the team highlights the intense pressure on athletes to perform at the highest level.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-is-finished-india-captain-told-to-retire-hand-over-leadership-to-jasprit-bumrah-as-fans-lose-patience-101735293900108.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-is-finished-india-captain-told-to-retire-hand-over-leadership-to-jasprit-bumrah-as-fans-lose-patience-101735293900108.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 01:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli grabs headlines again with his gesture for Steve Smith after Australia batter equals Gavaskar, Lara in MCG - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli Congratulates Steve Smith on 34th Test Century at MCG</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> HT Sports</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/kohlismtih_1735347060907_1735347084407.jpeg" alt="Virat Kohli gestures at Steve Smith(x)" title="Virat Kohli gestures at Steve Smith(x)">
<figcaption>Virat Kohli gestures at Steve Smith(x)</figcaption>
<p>Virat Kohli showed sportsmanship as he congratulated Steve Smith for his 34th Test century during the Boxing Day Test at the MCG, despite facing criticism for a prior incident in the match.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kohli applauded Smith as he scored his century, showcasing camaraderie.</li>
    <li>The gesture follows Kohli's earlier criticism for a physical confrontation with a young player.</li>
    <li>Smith equaled greats like Sunil Gavaskar and Brian Lara with his 34th Test century.</li>
    <li>Kohli and Smith have a long history, starting from their U19 cricket days.</li>
    <li>Australia scored 474 runs in their first innings, with Smith contributing significantly before being dismissed for 140.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Kohli's gesture for Smith in the 2019 ODI World Cup, asking the crowd not to boo the Australian batter, earned the ICC Fair Play award that year.”</blockquote>
<p>This incident marks a moment of respect and sportsmanship in cricket, highlighting the relationships between players beyond rivalry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-grabs-headlines-again-with-his-gesture-for-steve-smith-after-australia-batter-equals-gavaskar-lara-in-mcg-101735273951957.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-grabs-headlines-again-with-his-gesture-for-steve-smith-after-australia-batter-equals-gavaskar-lara-in-mcg-101735273951957.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 01:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Nathan Lyon Mocks KL Rahul With Rohit Sharma Remark Over Batting Order Fiasco - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nathan Lyon Mocks KL Rahul Over Batting Order Change in MCG Test</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/siq25dj8_rahul-lyon-x_625x300_27_December_24.jpeg" alt="Nathan Lyon Mocks KL Rahul" /><figcaption>Nathan Lyon mocks KL Rahul during the MCG Test.</figcaption><p>Nathan Lyon taunted KL Rahul during the second day of the 4th Test against Australia, highlighting a batting order shift that saw Rahul demoted to No. 3.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma returned to open the batting, pushing KL Rahul down the order.</li><li>Rohit managed just three runs, raising questions about his decision.</li><li>Nathan Lyon questioned Rahul on why he was demoted while batting.</li><li>Criticism of Rohit's performance came from notable former Australian cricketers.</li></ul><blockquote>Nathan Lyon to KL Rahul: what did you do wrong to bat one down.</blockquote><p>The event highlights the pressures faced by players during crucial matches, with public and expert scrutiny following their every move.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/nathan-lyon-mocks-kl-rahul-with-rohit-sharma-remark-over-batting-order-fiasco-watch-7341957</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/nathan-lyon-mocks-kl-rahul-with-rohit-sharma-remark-over-batting-order-fiasco-watch-7341957</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 01:13:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Stupid, stupid, stupid’: Rishabh Pant’s bizarre dismissal at MCG leaves Sunil Gavaskar fuming - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rishabh Pant's Dismissal at MCG Draws Criticism from Sunil Gavaskar</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Rishabh-Pant.jpg?w=640" alt="Rishabh Pant" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Rishabh Pant in action on Day 3 of the fourth Test between India and Australia. (Screengrab)</figcaption><p>In a disappointing turn during the Boxing Day Test match against Australia, Rishabh Pant's bizarre dismissal sparked outrage, particularly from former captain Sunil Gavaskar.</p><ul><li>Pant began confidently, playing aggressive yet calculated shots until the 56th over.</li><li>Gavaskar criticized Pant's choice to attempt a risky 'falling sweep' shot while two fielders were positioned for it.</li><li>The dismissal was characterized by Gavaskar as “stupid” and regrettable, undermining the team's efforts.</li><li>Comments from other commentators echoed the sentiment that Pant's decision-making lacked prudence given the match context.</li></ul><blockquote>“Stupid, stupid, stupid!” - Sunil Gavaskar on Rishabh Pant's dismissal.</blockquote><p>This incident showcases the fine line between aggression and recklessness in cricket, leaving fans and analysts questioning Pant's judgment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/stupid-stupid-stupid-rishabh-pants-bizarre-dismissal-at-mcg-leaves-sunil-gavaskar-fuming-9748188/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/stupid-stupid-stupid-rishabh-pants-bizarre-dismissal-at-mcg-leaves-sunil-gavaskar-fuming-9748188/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 01:11:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magnus Carlsen kicked out of World Rapid and Blitz Championship for wearing jeans; ‘Stupid principle,' says champion - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Magnus Carlsen Disqualified from World Rapid and Blitz Championship Over Jeans Controversy</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/CHESS-IND-17_1735348010577_1735348029878.jpg" alt="Norway's chess grandmaster Magnus Carlsen(AFP)" title="Norway's chess grandmaster Magnus Carlsen(AFP)">
<figcaption>Norway's chess grandmaster Magnus Carlsen(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Magnus Carlsen, a multiple-time world champion, was disqualified from the World Rapid and Blitz Championship 2024 in New York due to a breach of the tournament's dress code by wearing jeans. Despite being fined and asked to change, Carlsen refused, leading to his disqualification.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Carlsen was disqualified for wearing jeans, explicitly prohibited by the tournament's dress code.</li>
  <li>Initially fined $200, Carlsen declined to change into formal attire immediately.</li>
  <li>FIDE emphasized that the rules applied equally to all players, including notable players like Carlsen.</li>
  <li>Other players, such as Ian Nepomniachtchi, complied with dress code regulations after being fined.</li>
  <li>Carlsen expressed frustration with FIDE, calling the dress code “stupid” and declaring he no longer wanted to engage with them.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I am pretty tired of FIDE, so I want no more of this... maybe it’s a stupid principle, but I don’t think it’s any fun,” said Carlsen.</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights the tension between individual player preferences and established tournament rules, raising questions about the rigidity of such regulations in professional chess.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/magnus-carlsen-kicked-out-of-world-rapid-and-blitz-championship-for-wearing-jeans-stupid-principle-says-champion-101735347865014.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/magnus-carlsen-kicked-out-of-world-rapid-and-blitz-championship-for-wearing-jeans-stupid-principle-says-champion-101735347865014.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 01:10:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Ego kha gya': Rishabh Pant slammed for 'gift-wrapping' his wicket to Australia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Ego kha gya': Rishabh Pant slammed for 'gift-wrapping' his wicket to Australia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> NEW DELHI</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116728342,imgsize-68046,width-400,resizemode-4/116728342.jpg' alt='Rishabh Pant (Image credit: X)' title='Rishabh Pant (Image credit: X)' decoding='async' fetchpriority='high'><figcaption>Rishabh Pant (Image credit: X)</figcaption><p>Rishabh Pant faced criticism after a poor decision led to his dismissal during a crucial moment in the fourth Test against Australia. Initially looking strong, Pant's reckless shot selection proved costly for India.</p><ul><li>Pant attempted a risky lap shot over fine leg after facing discomfort from the ball hitting him on the stomach.</li><li>On the subsequent delivery, he again played a premeditated shot, resulting in a catch by Nathan Lyon.</li><li>The dismissal was heavily critiqued, with comments highlighting his reckless approach and reference to ego.</li><li>The series is currently tied at 1-1, with both teams showing strong performances thus far.</li></ul><blockquote>“What a crap shot by Rishabh Pant. Ego pe baat aa gayi thi and ego kha gya. Terrible way to get out, and Pant is flop in this series so far,”</blockquote><blockquote>“Rishabh Pant playing that pre-meditated ramp shot to a ball pitched outside offstump to get out. Looks Indian batsmen have given this up,”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Rishabh Pant's performance in this series has come under scrutiny, and his recent dismissal is seen as a pivotal moment affecting India's chances in the ongoing match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rishabh-pant-slammed-for-gift-wrapping-his-wicket-to-australia-mcg-test-ind-vs-aus/articleshow/116728335.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rishabh-pant-slammed-for-gift-wrapping-his-wicket-to-australia-mcg-test-ind-vs-aus/articleshow/116728335.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 3 Live Updates: Rishabh Pant Departs After Flashy Shot, India Stare At Follow On - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 3 Live Updates</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mnhb7908_ravindra-jadeja-afp_625x300_28_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="India vs Australia 4th Test, Day 3 Live Updates: India's Condition Worsens, Follow-On Scare On As Ravindra Jadeja Departs">
<figcaption>Ravindra Jadeja's wicket raises concerns for India.</figcaption>
<p>India is in a precarious position on Day 3 of the 4th Test against Australia after losing their seventh wicket, Ravindra Jadeja. With their follow-on score in jeopardy, the team is desperate to build a solid partnership to avoid defeat.</p>
<ul>
<li>Australia posted a total of 474 runs in their first innings.</li>
<li>India is currently 221 runs for 7 wickets with Nitish Reddy and Washington Sundar at the crease.</li>
<li>Jadeja's departure marks a significant setback as he was expected to score critical runs.</li>
<li>If India fails to perform today, their chances of reaching the World Test Championship (WTC) final diminish significantly.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The way India play today might well decide the course of the series and World Test Championship final equation.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, India's batting performance today is crucial to their WTC hopes, and every run counts as they face mounting pressure from the Australian bowlers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-3-live-score-updates-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-7344658</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-4th-test-day-3-live-score-updates-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-7344658</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:38:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gukesh challenges Carlsen once again, adds drama with brutal response to Norwegian's criticism: ‘When the best player…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gukesh Challenges Carlsen with a Bold Response to Criticism</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/1000000457_1734108982133_1735321411937.jpg" alt="D Gukesh publicly challenged Magnus Carlsen once again." title="D Gukesh publicly challenged Magnus Carlsen once again."><figcaption>D Gukesh publicly challenged Magnus Carlsen once again.</figcaption></figure><p>D Gukesh publicly challenged Magnus Carlsen once again after his recent World Chess Championship victory against Ding Liren. Gukesh responded to Carlsen's criticism of his match, stating that it's not the fault of other players if the top player chooses not to compete.</p><ul><li>Gukesh is the youngest-ever world chess champion, winning against defending champion Ding Liren.</li><li>He criticized Carlsen for downplaying his victory and the quality of the match.</li><li>Gukesh emphasized that he welcomed Carlsen's return to competition.</li><li>He described criticism as a source of motivation throughout his career.</li><li>Gukesh will face Viswanathan Anand, Carlsen, and Arjun Erigaisi in upcoming matches.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was clear that while the match was between two of the best players in the world, it was not a decider on who is the best. When the best player doesn’t want to play, it’s not the fault of other players.” - D Gukesh</blockquote><p>Gukesh's bold response and public challenge suggest a competitive spirit as he looks to establish himself further in the chess world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/gukesh-challenges-carlsen-once-again-adds-drama-with-brutal-response-to-norwegians-criticism-when-the-best-player-101735321239723.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/gukesh-challenges-carlsen-once-again-adds-drama-with-brutal-response-to-norwegians-criticism-when-the-best-player-101735321239723.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:06:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World Rapid and Blitz Championship 2024 LIVE Updates, Day 2: Arjun to face Volodar Murzin; Vantika vs Humpy in Round 7 - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>World Rapid and Blitz Championship 2024 LIVE Updates, Day 2: Highlights and Results</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 28, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Sportstar</strong></p>
<img src="https://ss-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/tfh8gi/article69034898.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/CHESS%203.png" alt="World Rapid and Blitz Championship" />
<figcaption>Follow all live updates of the World Rapid and Blitz Championship 2024 happening in Wall Street, New York.</figcaption>
<p>Catch all the live updates of Day 2 of the World Rapid and Blitz Championship 2024 in Wall Street, New York, where 17 Indians are in action.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Arjun and Pranav are both on a score of 5.5.</li>
  <li>Koneru Humpy and Harika Dronavalli are currently in the top 10 of the Women's section.</li>
  <li>The event is critical for Arjun as he vies for a spot in the Candidates 2026.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Pranav moves to 5.5 after seven rounds with a win over Grigoryan.”</blockquote>
<p>The day is filled with intense matches as the chess players showcase their skills in rapid and blitz formats, making significant strides towards potential championships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/chess/world-rapid-and-blitz-championship-2024-live-updates-day-2-score-streaming-info-highlights-news/article69034781.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/chess/world-rapid-and-blitz-championship-2024-live-updates-day-2-score-streaming-info-highlights-news/article69034781.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:48:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Aap Hi Boliye': Sanjay Manjrekar & Irfan Pathan Clash Over Yashasvi Jaiswal-Virat Kohli Run-Out | Watch - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aap Hi Boliye: Sanjay Manjrekar & Irfan Pathan Clash Over Yashasvi Jaiswal-Virat Kohli Run-Out | Watch</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Sanjay Manjrekar (L) and Irfan Pathan." title="Sanjay Manjrekar (L) and Irfan Pathan."><figcaption>Sanjay Manjrekar (L) and Irfan Pathan.</figcaption><p>During a heated exchange, former cricketers Sanjay Manjrekar and Irfan Pathan debated the controversial run-out of Yashasvi Jaiswal during the Boxing Day Test in Melbourne. The argument centered on whether Virat Kohli or Jaiswal was at fault for the run-out.</p><ul><li>Manjrekar blamed Kohli for making a 'schoolboy error' by looking at the ball instead of watching Jaiswal.</li><li>Pathan argued that Jaiswal should not have called for the run if he believed Kohli was reluctant to run.</li><li>The disagreement escalated into a sarcastic exchange on the cricketing rules governing running between wickets.</li></ul><blockquote>“Just because it’s Virat Kohli, we are thinking too much from his point of view.” - Sanjay Manjrekar</blockquote><p>The debate reflects the high tensions and passionate opinions surrounding cricketing decisions during live matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/aap-he-boliye-sanjay-manjrekar-irfan-pathan-clash-over-yashasvi-jaiswal-virat-kohli-run-out-watch-9169689.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/aap-he-boliye-sanjay-manjrekar-irfan-pathan-clash-over-yashasvi-jaiswal-virat-kohli-run-out-watch-9169689.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:21:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Virat Kohli's Viral Reaction After Steve Smith Breaks All-Time Test Century Record Against India - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/watch-virat-kohlis-viral-reaction-after-steve-smith-breaks-all-time-test-century-record-against-india-9169690.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/watch-virat-kohlis-viral-reaction-after-steve-smith-breaks-all-time-test-century-record-against-india-9169690.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:20:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stats - Corbin Bosch's boss-mode outing in the Boxing Day Test - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa-vs-pak-2024-25-corbin-boschs-boss-mode-outing-in-the-boxing-day-test-1466845</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa-vs-pak-2024-25-corbin-boschs-boss-mode-outing-in-the-boxing-day-test-1466845</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 19:34:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naseem Shah smiles at Test cricket on a rollercoaster day - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxNSzdUYXRzZldSRU5WZDhMbzVndmFUUnp5OEFUd180OUJKUHl6d1VEb3piajVYMUtseGVINF9zOFFUVkJQU29uOVo1bW5iajNUV0prVThkUWx1eDhtWXZlVV9QNzJUTXJUYVl3T1h5ak1KU1hJQzVfMnh5QXd0NEN4Z1ptOGhkYkhIU2c0UzBCcElSRFFkeFhSbXFQNGFXRVRuNWfSAbMBQVVfeXFMTl9vU1ZWWjRCUE9SZlJ2TEt1a3BVS3lzS05UWF9LQ0xUcTZZOGRwa0owTjNPUG1YejVVSXE5Qjh1Mzc5dDloVVk1ZER5UmJTakdlcEJ4N2t3dVVETUdLdVZmRkJ3OE9KcUluTWZLRWs0bWQ2M3h3SnBqb0d4U1lBLWcyNXNiWnlEdlp3YjZhTldiS0lqWkhWcVVzdVZrV1FEYUtmNW5qSklXSng4ZDB0dGNLREE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxNSzdUYXRzZldSRU5WZDhMbzVndmFUUnp5OEFUd180OUJKUHl6d1VEb3piajVYMUtseGVINF9zOFFUVkJQU29uOVo1bW5iajNUV0prVThkUWx1eDhtWXZlVV9QNzJUTXJUYVl3T1h5ak1KU1hJQzVfMnh5QXd0NEN4Z1ptOGhkYkhIU2c0UzBCcElSRFFkeFhSbXFQNGFXRVRuNWfSAbMBQVVfeXFMTl9vU1ZWWjRCUE9SZlJ2TEt1a3BVS3lzS05UWF9LQ0xUcTZZOGRwa0owTjNPUG1YejVVSXE5Qjh1Mzc5dDloVVk1ZER5UmJTakdlcEJ4N2t3dVVETUdLdVZmRkJ3OE9KcUluTWZLRWs0bWQ2M3h3SnBqb0d4U1lBLWcyNXNiWnlEdlp3YjZhTldiS0lqWkhWcVVzdVZrV1FEYUtmNW5qSklXSng4ZDB0dGNLREE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 18:33:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pro Kabaddi League set for Australia debut - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pro Kabaddi League Set for Australia Debut</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/PKL-Melbourne-Raid-is-league-s-maiden-foray-Down-U_1735320559154.jpeg" alt="PKL Melbourne Raid is league’s maiden foray Down Under. (PKL)">
<figcaption>PKL Melbourne Raid is league’s maiden foray Down Under. (PKL)</figcaption>
<p>The Pro Kabaddi League is hosting its first event in Australia, a two-game exhibition known as PKL Melbourne Raid, featuring teams composed of the league's best talent alongside an Australian team.</p>
<ul>
<li>The event will take place in Melbourne, coinciding with the culmination of the current PKL season.</li>
<li>Four teams will compete: PKL All Star Mavericks, PKL All Star Masters, Pro Kabaddi All Stars, and Aussie Raiders.</li>
<li>The event aims to promote kabaddi in uncharted markets like Australia.</li>
<li>Ajay Thakur predicts potential growth for Australian kabaddi players despite their current lack of technical expertise.</li>
<li>Josh Kennedy, a former AFL star, will lead the Aussie Raiders team.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I feel this initiative is very good for the game as it is high time the sport reaches out to unexplored territories.” - Ajay Thakur</blockquote>
<p>This inaugural event in Australia is expected to contribute to the growth of kabaddi as an international sport.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/pro-kabaddi-league-set-for-australia-debut-101735320562269.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/pro-kabaddi-league-set-for-australia-debut-101735320562269.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:29:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hardik Pandya to play in Vijay Hazare Trophy from Saturday - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPNTRCZFowZkNlNF80Y3hRTFJ2OFZwMG5IQW1Ndlpfa0FfcXdxNmc3S01BdDVtSUVwVUdRdWc3UGF5d2pLQzVGREhXd2VONVQzMW1DQjRyRzI3MFpRd0JZTm9qdEtEeGpzdTZhV1ZhdjN0YTR0UkxjcjBaLVAzekV3RmJBcWVsV051WHlCVEVGM0dSLWxfWFJkNzhLY0pVQjV0ZnRTLTln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxPNTRCZFowZkNlNF80Y3hRTFJ2OFZwMG5IQW1Ndlpfa0FfcXdxNmc3S01BdDVtSUVwVUdRdWc3UGF5d2pLQzVGREhXd2VONVQzMW1DQjRyRzI3MFpRd0JZTm9qdEtEeGpzdTZhV1ZhdjN0YTR0UkxjcjBaLVAzekV3RmJBcWVsV051WHlCVEVGM0dSLWxfWFJkNzhLY0pVQjV0ZnRTLTln?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:26:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[King Cup International Badminton Open: Lakshya Sen enters semis after clinching thriller - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lakshya Sen Advances to Semifinals at King Cup International Badminton Open</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/20241201-LKO-DGP-MN-Syed-Modi-Badminton-006-0_1735317782323_1735317793210.JPG" alt="Lakshya Sen in action." title="Lakshya Sen in action."><figcaption>Lakshya Sen in action.</figcaption><p>India's Lakshya Sen showcased an impressive performance to defeat Angus Ng Ka Long of Hong Kong China and secure his place in the semifinals of the inaugural King Cup International Badminton Open.</p><ul><li>Sen triumphed over Long with a score of 10-21, 21-13, 21-13.</li><li>This victory marks the first time Sen has beaten Long in four tries.</li><li>Sensational performances from top-ranked players, including Paris Olympics silver medallist Kunlavut Vitidsarn and world number 2 Anders Antonsen, highlight the competition.</li><li>The tournament was founded by two-time Olympic champion Lin Dan of China and does not contribute to BWF ranking points.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was a slow start for Lakshya, but once he got going, he won the next two games with ease.”</blockquote><p>With his recent victory at the Syed Modi Super 300 tournament, Sen is in contention among the top shuttlers for the prestigious title.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/king-cup-international-badminton-open-lakshya-sen-enters-semis-after-clinching-thriller-101735317645723.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/king-cup-international-badminton-open-lakshya-sen-enters-semis-after-clinching-thriller-101735317645723.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:45:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Test records for Zimbabwe and Williams as Afghanistan toil - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Test Records for Zimbabwe and Williams as Afghanistan Toil</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/09/30/550x309/Cricket_5_1727677577296_1727677629651.jpg" alt="Test records for Zimbabwe and Williams as Afghanistan toil" title="Test records for Zimbabwe and Williams as Afghanistan toil"><figcaption>Test records for Zimbabwe and Williams as Afghanistan toil</figcaption></figure><p>Zimbabwe achieved significant milestones in their Test match against Afghanistan, with historic performances from Sean Williams and the team overall.</p><ul><li>Zimbabwe posted their highest Test innings total of 586 runs.</li><li>Sean Williams scored 154 runs, setting a new personal best against Afghanistan.</li><li>Craig Ervine contributed with a score of 104 runs.</li><li>Zimbabwe managed to create records during their ongoing Test match in Bulawayo, while Afghanistan was struggling at 95 for 2.</li></ul><blockquote>"If I can lead by example and not by talking I believe my young teammates will learn quickly," said Sean Williams.</blockquote><p>This match underscores Zimbabwe's improving performance in international cricket, aiming for their first Test win since their last encounter with Afghanistan three years ago.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/test-records-for-zimbabwe-and-williams-as-afghanistan-toil-101735317508492.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/test-records-for-zimbabwe-and-williams-as-afghanistan-toil-101735317508492.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:38:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ervine, Bennett tons headline Zimbabwe's day - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxQTkNFVXBwQzFjVllrTWFUX0xfWlJucmlCdzFGdmVjMXJ5ZTdDSXNxWXNWVWNlRGRkYmF3X2hjd1hyUzRBeXFNaW1HdGV4clpHVHAzV3hnYTBJN0kzNzlCdXAyU0x3WmIybGVMTXU4aWRaVm9qOEZaZ0VWTzVkaGJPcVNkMFNOazQzNEtsU3VENy1FNTRsSFVkQXRPcmI3RENOZk9KTkZjVGQ5UHBhMUE1R0dveGZIN3pHNEtibnNJc1JnUnNWMEV0OA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxQTkNFVXBwQzFjVllrTWFUX0xfWlJucmlCdzFGdmVjMXJ5ZTdDSXNxWXNWVWNlRGRkYmF3X2hjd1hyUzRBeXFNaW1HdGV4clpHVHAzV3hnYTBJN0kzNzlCdXAyU0x3WmIybGVMTXU4aWRaVm9qOEZaZ0VWTzVkaGJPcVNkMFNOazQzNEtsU3VENy1FNTRsSFVkQXRPcmI3RENOZk9KTkZjVGQ5UHBhMUE1R0dveGZIN3pHNEtibnNJc1JnUnNWMEV0OA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:10:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lazavik Beats Carlsen; Murzin, Sargsyan, Dominguez, Naroditsky Lead Open - Chess.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lazavik Beats Carlsen; Murzin, Sargsyan, Dominguez, Naroditsky Lead Open</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Chess.com</p><figure><img src="https://images.chesscomfiles.com/uploads/v1/images_users/tiny_mce/AnthonyLevin/php5hoKzO.jpg" alt="Open playing hall." width="1575" height="2048"><figcaption>The Open playing hall. Photo: Lennart Ootes/FIDE.</figcaption></figure><p>In a gripping round of the 2024 FIDE World Rapid Chess Championship, GM Denis Lazavik scored a dramatic victory against Magnus Carlsen, who now sits with a disappointing score of 2.5 out of 5. Meanwhile, GMs Volodar Murzin, Shant Sargsyan, Leinier Dominguez, and Daniel Naroditsky are leading the Open section with 4.5 points each.</p><ul><li>Lazavik achieved a key upset over Carlsen.</li><li>Alice Lee leads the Women's Championship with a perfect score of 4/4.</li><li>Strong competitors like Gukesh Dommaraju are absent from the tournament.</li></ul><blockquote><p><strong>If he makes this comeback back into the event, we'll all be shocked.</strong><br>—Aman Hambleton on Magnus Carlsen</p></blockquote><p>With rounds continuing, the competition remains fierce, with many top players vying for the titles in both Open and Women’s sections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championship-day-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championship-day-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan lose their way after Bosch bash hands South Africa advantage - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan Struggles Against South Africa After Corbin Bosch's Stellar Performance</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p><p>In a gripping Test match, Pakistan found themselves trailing South Africa by two runs after a challenging performance, largely influenced by Corbin Bosch's outstanding debut half-century.</p><img src="link_to_image" alt="Corbin Bosch batting"/><figcaption>Corbin Bosch's remarkable performance on debut.</figcaption><p>The match saw South Africa post a total of 301, bolstered by Bosch's 81 runs, while Pakistan responded with 211 in their first innings and struggled in their second. Here are the key points:</p><ul><li>Corbin Bosch made history with the highest score by a No. 9 batter on debut in Tests.</li><li>Pakistan lost three quick wickets, trailing by only two runs at 88 for 3 in their second innings.</li><li>South Africa's middle order faced criticism for poor shot selection.</li><li>Pakistan has concerns over variable bounce as they look to build a defendable target.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bosch's delight as he ended unbeaten on 81 and was given the new ball in the second innings in a match where he has had a Midas touch.”</blockquote><p>The match continues to unfold, with both teams looking to capitalize on their respective strengths in the days ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/south-africa-vs-pakistan-2024-25-1432205/south-africa-vs-pakistan-1st-test-1432217/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/south-africa-vs-pakistan-2024-25-1432205/south-africa-vs-pakistan-1st-test-1432217/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:33:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Time In 147 Years: South Africa Debutant Corbin Bosch Scripts History, Achieves Unique Feat - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPdUthZThLMnlFaHk4ck1aaG5CVVBBNzZNQWtEN21FbUh2blhNQ3MyaWdXYUlvdHhBRUVvV2FocFNkTWtWWWthLWVld0E4WEZsSDZ3OWlzVjVJMkJwVVNDdWVYczNWRTZ1emp4T2U3bVBKR3NVN21reFAzdnRVc0JHMGpQX3ZrWjc1eTZJWFFLeFpPRjVNNWFMb3doXzJrSzVadWt0WjBTZ1RvVDhUMjJLc1FXZWd1ZzV1aWZKaXJrUnROd3RRRUREV2VRYm51VHJ60gHYAUFVX3lxTFBrOUVJdzREUkplODcxcGlwT1hCUWMzR2FCNmdiS1RVUXd6MGxfcEdhOTdyZEduUzZ3Uy1pbkRjdGpnNEphRURXMWZDUXlUaEU4QnRlOWtQY2U2WVJXRjJtRE14UzZIMEY4UEhWRkZGVU5Qbzl2VnVNWlNaSHZrdUlHSndxVVdOSDI3QUJoMGd6ODlQV085WWwxbUpCVkhLT3F2bzlveTRScUlMUkZ6Z3lPbkM1aHE4anZrQU4wWUJRczZpTlZ6bDJxWkZLekJUNVcya0xpOTVQYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPdUthZThLMnlFaHk4ck1aaG5CVVBBNzZNQWtEN21FbUh2blhNQ3MyaWdXYUlvdHhBRUVvV2FocFNkTWtWWWthLWVld0E4WEZsSDZ3OWlzVjVJMkJwVVNDdWVYczNWRTZ1emp4T2U3bVBKR3NVN21reFAzdnRVc0JHMGpQX3ZrWjc1eTZJWFFLeFpPRjVNNWFMb3doXzJrSzVadWt0WjBTZ1RvVDhUMjJLc1FXZWd1ZzV1aWZKaXJrUnROd3RRRUREV2VRYm51VHJ60gHYAUFVX3lxTFBrOUVJdzREUkplODcxcGlwT1hCUWMzR2FCNmdiS1RVUXd6MGxfcEdhOTdyZEduUzZ3Uy1pbkRjdGpnNEphRURXMWZDUXlUaEU4QnRlOWtQY2U2WVJXRjJtRE14UzZIMEY4UEhWRkZGVU5Qbzl2VnVNWlNaSHZrdUlHSndxVVdOSDI3QUJoMGd6ODlQV085WWwxbUpCVkhLT3F2bzlveTRScUlMUkZ6Z3lPbkM1aHE4anZrQU4wWUJRczZpTlZ6bDJxWkZLekJUNVcya0xpOTVQYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:33:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Virat Kohli would have...': Sunil Gavaskar reacts to Yashasvi Jaiswal run out, claims 'but the thing was...' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunil Gavaskar Analyzes Yashasvi Jaiswal's Run Out with Virat Kohli</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-167_1735312077071_1735312090651.jpg" alt="Yashasvi Jaiswal and Virat Kohli were involved in a horrendous mix-up on Day 2 of the Melbourne Test." title="Yashasvi Jaiswal and Virat Kohli were involved in a horrendous mix-up on Day 2 of the Melbourne Test."><figcaption>Yashasvi Jaiswal and Virat Kohli were involved in a horrendous mix-up on Day 2 of the Melbourne Test. (Photo by William WEST / AFP)</figcaption><p>The article discusses a mix-up between Virat Kohli and Yashasvi Jaiswal that led to Jaiswal's run out during the Boxing Day Test against Australia. Sunil Gavaskar provides insights into the situation and the implications of their partnership.</p><ul><li>Jaiswal and Kohli had a 102-run partnership before the run out occurred.</li><li>Gavaskar remarks that despite the risk, Kohli would have made his ground if he had run on Jaiswal's call.</li><li>Justin Langer commented on Pat Cummins' athletic ability in preventing the run.</li><li>At the end of Day 2, India was at 164/5, trailing by 310 runs.</li></ul><blockquote>“It would have been a quick run, and somebody like Virat Kohli would definitely have made it. But the thing was, he looked at the fielder...” - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote><p>The mix-up highlights the critical importance of communication and awareness in cricket, especially during high-pressure situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-would-have-sunil-gavaskar-reacts-to-yashasvi-jaiswal-run-out-claims-but-the-thing-was-101735311880005.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-would-have-sunil-gavaskar-reacts-to-yashasvi-jaiswal-run-out-claims-but-the-thing-was-101735311880005.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:32:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PV Sindhu And Venkata Datta Sai's Wedding Decor - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu's Unique Floral Decorations For Her Wedding To Venkata Datta Sai In Udaipur</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/gws/ms/pv-sindhu-and-venkata-datta-sais-wedding-decor/assets/2.jpeg?1735312595" alt="Background Image">
<figcaption>Image Credits: NDTV</figcaption>
<p>The wedding celebration of PV Sindhu and Venkata Datta Sai featured exquisite floral decorations set against a royal backdrop, showcasing a blend of North and South Indian cultures.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The wedding started with a royal sangeet inspired by the sets of the classic Mughal-E-Azam.</li>
  <li>The venue was transformed into a historical escape with jaali detailing and brass lamps.</li>
  <li>For the Haldi ceremony, the couple chose an unconventional color scheme, moving away from typical yellow.</li>
  <li>Red and terracotta tones were used for the centre stage with traditional Rajasthani motifs.</li>
  <li>The Pellikuthuru ceremony showcased a classic white and gold decor with light blooms and brass accents.</li>
  <li>The varmala ceremony featured a unique blend of purple and red floral arrangements.</li>
  <li>The reception boasted a lush green palette enhanced by glowing candles and a stunning chandelier.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The wedding was a complete fusion of the couple's North and South Indian heritage, featuring lush floral and ivory-carved pillars."</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the wedding was a beautifully orchestrated fusion of traditional and modern elements, reflecting the couple's unique styles and backgrounds.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/auto/webstories/pv-sindhus-unique-floral-decorations-for-her-wedding-to-venkata-datta-sai-in-udaipur-29910</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/auto/webstories/pv-sindhus-unique-floral-decorations-for-her-wedding-to-venkata-datta-sai-in-udaipur-29910</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:23:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Babar Azam sets history, becomes only third player in world to achieve..., the other two are... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Babar Azam Achieves Historic Milestone</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/babar-azam-sets-history-becomes-only-third-player-in-world-to-achieve-the-other-two-are-202412-1735312082.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Babar Azam sets history becomes only third player in world to achieve the other two are "><figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption><p>Babar Azam has made history by becoming the third player in the world to achieve a significant milestone in cricket.</p><ul><li>Babar Azam created history in Centurion, South Africa.</li><li>He became the third player to score over 4,000 runs in all three formats of the game.</li><li>Notable predecessors include India's Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma.</li><li>The historic achievement was marked during the first Test match against South Africa.</li></ul><blockquote>"While he solidified his place in cricketing history, he couldn't make a notable impact on Pakistan's innings."</blockquote><p>The achievement highlights Babar's significant contribution to cricket and places him alongside two of the game's greats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/babar-azam-sets-history-becomes-only-third-player-in-world-to-achieve-the-other-two-are-416680/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/babar-azam-sets-history-becomes-only-third-player-in-world-to-achieve-the-other-two-are-416680/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:10:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coach of the year: Craig Fulton, the 'friend' whose 'clear vision' guided Team India to Olympic bronze - ESPN India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Coach of the year: Craig Fulton, the 'friend' whose 'clear vision' guided Team India to Olympic bronze</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN</p>
<p>The Indian men's hockey team defied expectations at the Paris Olympics, securing a bronze medal under the guidance of coach Craig Fulton. Despite early setbacks, Fulton’s unique coaching approach and strong rapport with players led to success.</p>
<ul>
<li>Craig Fulton was appointed following a disappointing World Cup and worked to build relationships with the players.</li>
<li>Captain Harmanpreet Singh highlighted Fulton's calm demeanor and focus on player development over immediate results.</li>
<li>Fulton adapted his coaching strategies to enhance players' strengths and adjust tactics during matches.</li>
<li>Despite winning bronze, Fulton remains driven for greater achievements, emphasizing a clear vision for the team.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Even after the bronze medal, he was a bit upset because he knew we deserved more." - Captain Harmanpreet Singh</blockquote>
<p>Craig Fulton’s effective leadership and innovative coaching style have not only led to an Olympic medal but have also redefined teamwork and strategy in Indian hockey.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espn.in/espn/story/_/id/43180865/coach-year-craig-fulton-harmanpreet-singh-friend-clear-vision-guided-team-india-olympic-bronze</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espn.in/espn/story/_/id/43180865/coach-year-craig-fulton-harmanpreet-singh-friend-clear-vision-guided-team-india-olympic-bronze</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SA vs PAK, 1st Test: Pakistan’s Babar Azam tries luck with bail flip trend by imitating Mohammed Siraj | Watch - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Babar Azam Embraces Bail Flip Trend in First Test Against South Africa</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><div><p>In a bid to change their fortunes on the field, Pakistan's star batter Babar Azam participated in the bail-switching trend during the first Test against South Africa at Centurion.</p><img src="https://t.co/TpM3X01jc6" alt="Babar Azam changing the bails."><figcaption>Babar Azam changing the bails.</figcaption><p>Following the trend popularized by former England pacer Stuart Broad, Babar attempted this quirky method to break partnerships or shift the game's momentum. Although the superstition may not evidence immediate results, it adds a playful element to competitive Test cricket.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Babar Azam flipped the bails on Day 2 of the Test match.</li><li>The bail-switching trend has gained popularity among cricketers, beginning with Stuart Broad.</li><li>Despite its superstition roots, this act introduces humor into the game.</li><li>Pakistan scored 70 runs for 2 wickets in their second innings, trailing by 20 runs.</li></ul><blockquote>Babar Azam changing the bails. — 𝙎𝙝𝙚𝙧𝙞 (@CallMeSheri1) December 27, 2024</blockquote><p>The bail-switching act showcases the lighter side of competitive cricket while Babar Azam looks to illuminate a challenging match.</p></div>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/sa-vs-pak-1st-test-pakistan-babar-azam-tries-luck-with-bail-flip-trend-imitating-mohammed-siraj-watch-11735310539595.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/sa-vs-pak-1st-test-pakistan-babar-azam-tries-luck-with-bail-flip-trend-imitating-mohammed-siraj-watch-11735310539595.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:49:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS 4th Test Match, Melbourne Weather Updates: Will rain impact India vs Australia Boxing Day Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS 4th Test Match, Melbourne Weather Updates: Will rain impact India vs Australia Boxing Day Test on Day 3?</h1><p><strong>Date: December 28, 2023</strong> | <strong>Source: Times of India</strong></p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116718718,imgsize-184236,width-400,resizemode-4/116718718.jpg" alt="Melbourne Cricket Ground" title="Melbourne Cricket Ground (AP Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Melbourne Cricket Ground (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>Day 3 of the 4th Test between India and Australia at the iconic Melbourne Cricket Ground could face disruptions due to rain, impacting the match's outcome.</p><ul><li>The visitors, India, are trailing by 310 runs, battling to avoid the follow-on.</li><li>There is a 79% chance of rain during the afternoon on December 28.</li><li>Showers are expected during the critical middle session; temperatures forecasted at 23°C and wind gusts up to 48 km/h.</li><li>Humidity at 58% could benefit swing bowlers, complicating batting conditions.</li><li>Steve Smith scored 140 for Australia, and Jasprit Bumrah took 4 wickets for India.</li><li>India ended Day 2 at 164/5, with Jaiswal scoring 82.</li></ul><blockquote>“The looming possibility of rain could halt their momentum and may even tempt Australia to enforce the follow-on if the situation demands.”</blockquote><p>As the match progresses, the unpredictable weather makes it crucial for India to capitalize while minimizing disruptions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-match-melbourne-weather-updates-will-rain-impact-india-vs-australia-boxing-day-test-on-day-3/articleshow/116718244.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-match-melbourne-weather-updates-will-rain-impact-india-vs-australia-boxing-day-test-on-day-3/articleshow/116718244.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>