<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:19:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:19:03 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker, D Gukesh Among Four Champion Athletes Selected For Khel Ratna Award - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manu Bhaker, D Gukesh Among Four Champion Athletes Selected For Khel Ratna Award</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 02, 2025, 21:01 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Khel Ratna for Manu Bhaker and D Gukesh (PTI)" title="Khel Ratna for Manu Bhaker and D Gukesh (PTI)"><figcaption>Khel Ratna for Manu Bhaker and D Gukesh (PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>The Ministry of Youth Affairs & Sports has announced the National Sports Awards 2024, honoring Manu Bhaker, D Gukesh, Harmanpreet Singh, and Praveen Kumar with the Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna Award.</p><ul><li>Ministry announced the awards on January 02, 2025.</li><li>Manu Bhaker is the first athlete from independent India to win two medals in a single Olympics.</li><li>D Gukesh became the youngest World champion and helped the Indian team win gold at the Chess Olympiad.</li><li>Harmanpreet Singh led the Indian hockey team to a bronze medal and Praveen Kumar was crowned T64 champion in para athletics.</li><li>The awards ceremony will be held on January 17, 2025, at Rashtrapati Bhavan.</li></ul><blockquote>"The awardees will receive their awards from the President of India."</blockquote><p>The recognition of these athletes highlights their contributions and achievements in Indian sports, inspiring future generations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/sports/manu-bhakar-d-gukesh-harmanpreet-singh-and-praveen-kumar-to-be-conferred-major-dhyan-chand-khel-ratna-award-9175230.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/sports/manu-bhakar-d-gukesh-harmanpreet-singh-and-praveen-kumar-to-be-conferred-major-dhyan-chand-khel-ratna-award-9175230.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 16:34:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir turns down request to 'allow Rohit Sharma to play in Sydney and retire' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Rejects Rohit Sharma's Playing Request Ahead of Sydney Test</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-35_1735831316045_1735831333536.jpg" alt="Indian coach Gautam Gambhir (L) and captain Rohit Sharma (R) chat in the nets at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG) in Melbourne --(AFP)"><figcaption>Indian coach Gautam Gambhir (L) and captain Rohit Sharma (R) chat in the nets at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG) in Melbourne --(AFP)</figcaption><p>In a recent turn of events, Gautam Gambhir has opted not to include Rohit Sharma in the playing XI for the final Test against Australia, prioritizing team performance over individual requests.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma, amidst poor performance, decided to 'opt out' of the playing XI.</li><li>His performance in the series has been subpar, averaging just 6.20.</li><li>Shubman Gill is set to replace Rohit in Sydney, while KL Rahul will open the innings.</li><li>Gambhir's decision is influenced by the need for a win to bolster India's chances in the World Test Championship.</li><li>An influential cricket administrator requested Gambhir allow Rohit to play and retire on-field, which he declined.</li></ul><blockquote>“Everything is fine with Rohit. The head coach is there. That should be fine.” – Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>The decision emphasizes Gambhir's commitment to team success as India eyes the Border-Gavaskar Trophy and a spot in the World Test Championship final.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/gautam-gambhir-turns-down-request-to-allow-rohit-sharma-to-play-in-sydney-test-and-retire-india-vs-australia-101735831210508.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/gautam-gambhir-turns-down-request-to-allow-rohit-sharma-to-play-in-sydney-test-and-retire-india-vs-australia-101735831210508.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:49:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Secrets of Newlands pitch keep Pakistan guessing on team combination - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa-vs-pak-2nd-test-secrets-of-newlands-pitch-keep-pakistan-guessing-on-team-combination-1467500</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa-vs-pak-2nd-test-secrets-of-newlands-pitch-keep-pakistan-guessing-on-team-combination-1467500</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:33:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir Rejected Request To Keep Rohit Sharma In Playing XI For 5th Australia Test: Report - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Rejects Request to Keep Rohit Sharma in the Playing XI for the 5th Australia Test</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 25, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/anie0gdg_csa_625x300_02_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Gautam Gambhir Rejected Request To Keep Rohit Sharma In Playing XI For 5th Australia Test: Report"><figcaption>Gautam Gambhir rejected the request to keep Rohit Sharma in the playing XI.</figcaption><p>Indian cricket team skipper Rohit Sharma is set to be rested for the fifth Test against Australia due to poor form, with reports indicating he managed only 31 runs in his last three matches of the series, while Shubman Gill is likely to replace him.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma has faced challenges during the test series, scoring poorly.</li><li>An influential cricket administrator's request to retain him was turned down by Gambhir.</li><li>Gambhir's priority remains India's chances in the World Test Championship (WTC) final.</li><li>If not played, Rohit would become the first Indian captain dropped for poor performance in a Test.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah might take over leadership if Rohit is sidelined.</li></ul><blockquote>“Performance is the only thing that would keep a player in the dressing room helmed by him.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>This decision highlights the emphasis on performance as India aims to compete for the WTC final. Whether Rohit plays or not may significantly impact his future in Test cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-rejected-request-to-keep-rohit-sharma-in-playing-xi-for-5th-australia-test-report-7385280</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-rejected-request-to-keep-rohit-sharma-in-playing-xi-for-5th-australia-test-report-7385280</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:56:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli Meets Sam Konstas' Brothers After Shoulder-Barging Row. This Happens Next - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli Meets Sam Konstas' Brothers After Shoulder-Barging Row</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024</p> <p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p> <img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fblrt2qg_virat-kohli-sam-konstas-x_625x300_26_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Virat Kohli and Sam Konstas' Brothers" /> <figcaption>Virat Kohli Meets Sam Konstas' Brothers After Shoulder-Barging Row. This Happens Next</figcaption> <p>Virat Kohli has moved on from his recent on-field altercation with Sam Konstas, being seen posing with the Australian cricketer's brothers at an event hosted by PM Anthony Albanese.</p> <ul> <li>Kohli was fined 20% of his match fee and received a demerit point for his confrontation with Konstas.</li> <li>The gathering was part of a New Year's reception for the upcoming Border-Gavaskar Trophy Test series.</li> <li>PM Albanese humorously suggested legislation to limit Jasprit Bumrah's bowling during the meeting.</li> <li>The series currently stands at 2-1 in favor of Australia.</li> <li>The final Test match will start on January 3 at SCG, coinciding with 'Jane McGrath Day' for cancer awareness.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“We could pass a law here that says he has to bowl left-handed or off one step,” said PM Albanese about Jasprit Bumrah.</blockquote> <p>This event signals a positive and amiable gesture from Kohli, reinforcing mutual respect in sportsmanship.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/virat-kohli-meets-sam-konstas-brothers-after-shoulder-barging-row-this-happens-next-7378741</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/virat-kohli-meets-sam-konstas-brothers-after-shoulder-barging-row-this-happens-next-7378741</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 14:05:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Shadow Of Old Self": Inside Rohit Sharma's Last Batting Session With Team India Ahead Of 5th Test - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxPZEx5TEZmU253OXFhYmZfQU9OT1dzMzVFWGY5dkI3aG5GaGxvN2haaWp4b2tkTFNsVjFHaUZJNnQ4NDNBaXQyTzZNT2o0SXV6blVnOWJPcGVaLUFhcjdzem1xUE9aOW9RUUYtMzB6YlFXTGZJRldIWFQtSnNocE9aUEVwaFlGV3RDMk9USUloVWl4bVdfX25MYVhlSVBuVHRKcDY3NWsxclJWa2RFUUhZb2Nnd3Jxd0R3eGprX1M1RGVONzdHSkFrem5LWUxjdTlaNEtv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxPZEx5TEZmU253OXFhYmZfQU9OT1dzMzVFWGY5dkI3aG5GaGxvN2haaWp4b2tkTFNsVjFHaUZJNnQ4NDNBaXQyTzZNT2o0SXV6blVnOWJPcGVaLUFhcjdzem1xUE9aOW9RUUYtMzB6YlFXTGZJRldIWFQtSnNocE9aUEVwaFlGV3RDMk9USUloVWl4bVdfX25MYVhlSVBuVHRKcDY3NWsxclJWa2RFUUhZb2Nnd3Jxd0R3eGprX1M1RGVONzdHSkFrem5LWUxjdTlaNEtv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:15:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir, Rohit Sharma Ignore Each Other During Practice - Report Makes 'Split' Claim - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir, Rohit Sharma Ignore Each Other During Practice - Report Makes 'Split' Claim</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/2crlcn9o_cs_625x300_02_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Gautam Gambhir, Rohit Sharma Ignore Each Other During Practice - Report Makes 'Split' Claim">
<figcaption>Gautam Gambhir (L) and Rohit Sharma</figcaption>
<p>In a bizarre turn of events at the Sydney Cricket Ground, communication seemingly broke down between coach Gautam Gambhir and captain Rohit Sharma as they prepared for the final Test. Reports indicate a split in their relationship, exacerbated by Sharma's poor performance this season.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gambhir and Sharma showed little communication during practice sessions.</li>
  <li>Gambhir did not confirm Sharma's place in the playing eleven.</li>
  <li>There are rumors of Sharma being “rested,” indicating a possible drop from the team.</li>
  <li>Sharma appeared uncomfortable and isolated during practice and discussions.</li>
  <li>Gambhir emphasized “honesty” and “performance” as key criteria for team selection.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We will look at the pitch and decide,” - Gautam Gambhir on Rohit's inclusion.</blockquote>
<p>The dynamic between coach and captain raises concerns about team morale and performance heading towards a critical match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-rohit-sharma-ignore-each-other-during-practice-report-makes-split-claim-7384866</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-rohit-sharma-ignore-each-other-during-practice-report-makes-split-claim-7384866</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:50:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With Rohit Sharma dropped for SCG Test, India's predicted XI vs Australia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Predicted XI vs Australia After Rohit Sharma's Omission for SCG Test</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116887570,imgsize-136200,width-400,resizemode-4/116887570.jpg" alt="With Rohit Sharma dropped for SCG Test, India's predicted XI vs Australia" title="Team India (AP Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Team India (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>This article discusses the Indian cricket team's predicted playing XI for the upcoming Test match against Australia at the SCG, following the dropping of captain Rohit Sharma due to poor form.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma has been dropped after a series of disappointing performances in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li><li>His batting average for the year is significantly low at 24.76, including only two centuries.</li><li>KL Rahul is expected to open the batting alongside Yashasvi Jaiswal.</li><li>Shubman Gill is likely to return to the team after being dropped previously.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah will captain the team in Rohit's absence.</li></ul><blockquote>“In India’s last five Test defeats, Rohit's performance has nosedived, with his average plummeting to a mere 11.20 across 10 innings.”</blockquote><p>India is looking to bounce back after recent defeats, with a lineup that aims to balance experience and youthful talent against Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/with-rohit-sharma-dropped-for-scg-test-indias-predicted-xi-vs-australia/articleshow/116887238.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/with-rohit-sharma-dropped-for-scg-test-indias-predicted-xi-vs-australia/articleshow/116887238.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unscripted endings! MS Dhoni, Rohit Sharma, and the 'quiet' goodbyes - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unscripted endings! MS Dhoni, Rohit Sharma, and the 'quiet' goodbyes</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116887052,imgsize-29874,width-400,resizemode-4/116887052.jpg" alt="Unscripted endings! MS Dhoni, Rohit Sharma, and the 'quiet' goodbyes" title="Rohit Sharma (Getty Images)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma (Getty Images)</figcaption><p>Cricketers in India, though revered, often depart with little fanfare. Rohit Sharma, while transitioning from T20 to potential retirement from Test cricket, faces an unscripted exit like many legends before him.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma's last appearance in red-ball cricket was in the Boxing Day Test in Melbourne.</li><li>His recent Test performances have been underwhelming, raising questions about his position in the team.</li><li>Fellow cricketers like MS Dhoni, Rahul Dravid, and VVS Laxman experienced similarly quiet retirements.</li><li>Dhoni's retirement announcement came unexpectedly from the BCCI, without prior indication from the player.</li><li>Rohit is expected to miss the upcoming SCG Test amid speculations on his future.</li></ul><blockquote>“MS Dhoni, one of India’s greatest Test captains under whose leadership India became the No. 1 Test team, has decided to retire from Test cricket,” the BCCI stated.</blockquote><p>The pattern of quiet retirements continues in Indian cricket, highlighting the emotional farewells of celebrated players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/unscripted-endings-ms-dhoni-rohit-sharma-and-the-quiet-goodbyes/articleshow/116886985.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/unscripted-endings-ms-dhoni-rohit-sharma-and-the-quiet-goodbyes/articleshow/116886985.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Selfish, Spiteful, Disruptive": R Ashwin Blasted By South Africa Great For Mid-Series Retirement - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxNN2psZ0NkZ3V0R0liYmdwSVFXa3A0UEdSdkEtekFBNjhCbXNvLTNGcEtseEFmZi15NjdiRUh6YVdmeUY5bVQ1Wm80TjE1Z0tFMVZ3Qnl2T19BS0hkcU0wWEI5SFR2ZzhZbGVtc0ZPWnhZV1ctbXZPcFhaaXMwMUV1Rk1aSHNqdXd5MGgwdEFZZWVuMWpiZ2loU1FpVVBDdVA2a1haYklpbjQ3M2x3ZVlUbzN4SWRjUXp6cmdkY2NZd051TzFiNGRtLTJXT0o0Nml0Z3RXWG5vSFNmWl81YlhYMXV6ZDVmUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxNN2psZ0NkZ3V0R0liYmdwSVFXa3A0UEdSdkEtekFBNjhCbXNvLTNGcEtseEFmZi15NjdiRUh6YVdmeUY5bVQ1Wm80TjE1Z0tFMVZ3Qnl2T19BS0hkcU0wWEI5SFR2ZzhZbGVtc0ZPWnhZV1ctbXZPcFhaaXMwMUV1Rk1aSHNqdXd5MGgwdEFZZWVuMWpiZ2loU1FpVVBDdVA2a1haYklpbjQ3M2x3ZVlUbzN4SWRjUXp6cmdkY2NZd051TzFiNGRtLTJXT0o0Nml0Z3RXWG5vSFNmWl81YlhYMXV6ZDVmUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:06:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India’s surprising selection call in Melbourne needs valid reason, says Shastri - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shastri Questions India's Selection Call Regarding Gill</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified <strong>Source: </strong>Not specified</p><p>Ravi Shastri has raised concerns about India’s decision to exclude Shubman Gill from the playing XI despite his impressive performance in 2024.</p><ul><li>In 12 Tests in 2024, Gill scored 866 runs at an average of 43.3, including three centuries.</li><li>His overall overseas performance has been inconsistent, with an average of 23.8 since 2021.</li><li>Shastri argues that a player averaging over 40 should not be sitting out.</li></ul><blockquote>“How can he be out of the XI is my question,” Shastri stated.</blockquote><p>This statement highlights the ongoing discussions around team selection in Indian cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/world-test-championship/news/india-s-surprising-selection-call-in-melbourne-needs-valid-reason-says-shastri</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/world-test-championship/news/india-s-surprising-selection-call-in-melbourne-needs-valid-reason-says-shastri</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:02:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Replaced, Big Decision On Pant; Pacer Returns After 365 Days! India's Playing XI For SCG Test: Report - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Playing XI for SCG Test: Rohit Replaced, Pacer Returns After 365 Days</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <em>Not specified</em>, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116886298,thumbsize-78262,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116886298.jpg" alt="Pant Gambhir Rohit" title="Pant Gambhir Rohit">
<figcaption>Photo: AP</figcaption>
<p>India is set to make two changes to their playing XI for the fifth Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy (BGT) against Australia at Sydney Cricket Ground (SCG).</p>
<ul>
<li>Rohit Sharma opts out of the match; Jasprit Bumrah will captain the team again.</li>
<li>KL Rahul returns to open the innings, while Shubman Gill is also included in the team.</li>
<li>Rishabh Pant retains his spot despite recent criticism regarding his performance.</li>
<li>Prasidh Krishna replaces Akash Deep, who is sidelined due to injury.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Pant has a terrific record at the venue, making 292 runs in three innings at an average of 146.”</blockquote>
<p>This Test marks Prasidh's return after missing a significant time due to injury, having last played in January 2023.</p>
<p><strong>India Playing XI for Sydney Test:</strong> KL Rahul, Yashasvi Jaiswal, Shubman Gill, Virat Kohli, Nitish Kumar Reddy, Ravindra Jadeja, Washington Sundar, Jasprit Bumrah (C), Mohammed Siraj, Prasidh Krishna.</p>
<p>The upcoming match is crucial for India to retain the Border-Gavaskar Trophy and qualify for the final of the 2025 World Test Championship.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-replaced-jasprit-bumrah-captain-big-decision-on-rishabh-pant-prasidh-krishna-returns-after-365-days-indias-playing-xi-for-scg-5th-test-vs-australia-report-article-116884985</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-replaced-jasprit-bumrah-captain-big-decision-on-rishabh-pant-prasidh-krishna-returns-after-365-days-indias-playing-xi-for-scg-5th-test-vs-australia-report-article-116884985</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:47:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Rohit Sharma's dismal show in 2024 triggered his downfall - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How Rohit Sharma's dismal show in 2024 triggered his downfall</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <time datetime="2024-12-31">December 31, 2024</time> <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116886005,imgsize-40986,width-400,resizemode-4/116886005.jpg" alt="How Rohit Sharma's dismal show in 2024 triggered his downfall" title="Rohit Sharma. (Pic Credit - X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Rohit Sharma. (Pic Credit - X)</figcaption>
<p>India's skipper Rohit Sharma faced a significant career downturn in 2024, showcasing a series of performances that led to his dropping from the final Test against Australia.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rohit struggled throughout 2024, averaging just 24.76 in 14 Tests.</li>
  <li>In key series, he failed to convert starts, highlighting technical vulnerabilities.</li>
  <li>His performances included only 2 centuries and 2 half-centuries.</li>
  <li>Critics cited declining footwork and captaincy challenges during crucial matches.</li>
  <li>Rohit scored a mere 31 runs across five innings in the ongoing series against Australia.</li>
  <li>Speculation rises over his future as captain following decisions affecting his leadership roles.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Rohit stated: "...as a captain, yes, that is disappointing... mentally, it’s disturbing without a doubt..."</blockquote>
<p>The struggles Rohit faced this year have led selectors to consider younger options, with his future in Test cricket now uncertain.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/how-rohit-sharmas-dismal-show-in-2024-triggered-his-downfall/articleshow/116886037.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/how-rohit-sharmas-dismal-show-in-2024-triggered-his-downfall/articleshow/116886037.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["He Should Tell Virat Kohli...": India Great Blasts Gautam Gambhir's 'Batting' Coaching - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"He Should Tell Virat Kohli...": India Great Blasts Gautam Gambhir's 'Batting' Coaching</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/knn8msqg_virat-kohli-out_625x300_30_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="He Should Tell Virat Kohli..." /><figcaption>India's star batter Virat Kohli struggles during the Test series against Australia.</figcaption><p>Indian cricketer Virat Kohli faces difficulties in the ongoing Test series against Australia, raising questions about the effectiveness of head coach Gautam Gambhir's support.</p><ul><li>Kohli has scored only 167 runs in four matches with an average of 27.83.</li><li>He has been struggling with deliveries outside the off-stump, leading to many dismissals.</li><li>A former player criticized Gambhir for not providing adequate guidance to Kohli.</li><li>Concerns grow regarding team morale and communication under Gambhir's coaching.</li><li>The Indian team faces challenges in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy against a strong Australian side.</li></ul><blockquote>“If he knows what is wrong, he should tell him,” an unnamed former player stated about Gambhir's lack of communication with Kohli.</blockquote><p>The article highlights the growing frustrations regarding the coaching staff's handling of star players amid a challenging Test series and raises questions about future performance and team dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/he-should-tell-virat-kohli-india-great-blasts-gautam-gambhirs-batting-coaching-7377439</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/he-should-tell-virat-kohli-india-great-blasts-gautam-gambhirs-batting-coaching-7377439</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:13:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS 5th Test Predicted Playing 11: With Rohit Sharma’s place in the XI hanging by a thread, here is a look at the Predicted XI for the SCG Test - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS 5th Test Predicted Playing 11</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/IND-AUS-captaincy.jpg?w=640' alt='India vs Australia Playing 11: India Australia Test captaincy Rohit Sharma BGT' width='640' height='360'><figcaption>India vs Australia Playing 11 should Rohit Sharma not be included in team (AP Photo/Asanka Brendon Ratnayake)</figcaption><p>The fifth Test of the Border Gavaskar Trophy is starting soon, and important decisions loom for the Indian team regarding their lineup.</p><ul><li>Captain Rohit Sharma's inclusion is uncertain amid speculations of his potential exclusion.</li><li>Coach Gautam Gambhir addressed concerns about Rohit’s absence from the press conference.</li><li>Akash Deep is ruled out due to injury, with Prasidh Krishna or Harshit Rana favored as replacements.</li><li>Holding the series is crucial for India's aspirations in the World Test Championship.</li><li>Australia has confirmed Beau Webster replacing Mitchell Marsh.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will have a look at the pitch, and then decide the playing 11.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>Both teams face key decisions as the match approaches, with dire stakes involved for India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/predicted-xi-with-rohit-sharmas-place-in-the-xi-hanging-by-a-thread-9756345/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/predicted-xi-with-rohit-sharmas-place-in-the-xi-hanging-by-a-thread-9756345/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:05:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ruben Amorim's dream Manchester United XI if he lands FOUR transfers in January - The Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ruben Amorim's dream Manchester United XI if he lands 4 January transfers</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> January 2025<br><strong>Source: </strong> Mirror</p>
<img src="https://i2-prod.mirror.co.uk/incoming/article34395714.ece/ALTERNATES/n615/0_GettyImages-2191216331.jpg" alt="Ruben Amorim" width="160" height="90">
<figcaption>Ruben Amorim has a lot of work to do</figcaption>
<p>As Manchester United struggles in early 2025, manager Ruben Amorim is eyeing key transfers in the January window to revive the team's fortunes.</p>
<ul>
  <li>United's four consecutive defeats have raised relegation concerns.</li>
  <li>Amorim has had a rocky start, winning only four of the first eleven games.</li>
  <li>Players let go could include Marcus Rashford.</li>
  <li>Key transfer targets include Alphonso Davies, Bruno Guimaraes, and Dani Olmo, alongside goalkeeper Viktor Gyokeres.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The days when teams don’t sell big players are gone,” said Eddie Howe.</blockquote>
<p>Amorim needs to secure immediate reinforcements to avoid any further decline in the team's performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mirror.co.uk/sport/football/news/man-utd-transfers-amorim-gyokeres-34402013</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mirror.co.uk/sport/football/news/man-utd-transfers-amorim-gyokeres-34402013</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:02:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma's Act During Meet With Australia PM Fuels 'All Is Not Well' Speculations: Report - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma's Act During Meet With Australia PM Fuels 'All Is Not Well' Speculations: Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/u7jm6nl_rohit-sharma_625x300_02_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Rohit Sharma" /><figcaption>Indian cricket team captain Rohit Sharma</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team captain Rohit Sharma is facing criticism for his performance in the ongoing Test series against Australia, having missed the first Test due to personal reasons and struggling with a low score since joining the team.</p><ul><li>Rohit missed the first Test for the birth of his second child.</li><li>He has scored only 31 runs in three matches since joining the series.</li><li>Rohit withdrew from making an address at an official function with the Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese.</li><li>Head coach Gautam Gambhir's comments have fueled speculation about Rohit's spot in the playing XI for the upcoming Test.</li></ul><blockquote>"Everything is fine with Rohit and I don't think it's anything traditional (fronting up for the pre-match presser)." - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>The speculation surrounding Rohit Sharma's place in the team continues to grow as he faces criticism, leaving fans and experts wondering about the implications for the Indian cricket team's future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharmas-act-during-meet-with-australia-pm-fuels-all-is-not-well-speculations-report-7383900</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharmas-act-during-meet-with-australia-pm-fuels-all-is-not-well-speculations-report-7383900</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:56:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravi Shastri: Won’t be surprised if Rohit Sharma retires from Test cricket - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravi Shastri: Won’t be surprised if Rohit Sharma retires from Test cricket</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/90jyu9/article69053471.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/AP12_30_2024_000005B.jpg" alt="India’s captain Rohit Sharma. File" title="India’s captain Rohit Sharma. File"><figcaption>India’s captain Rohit Sharma. File | Photo Credit: AP</figcaption><p>Former India head coach Ravi Shastri suggests that Rohit Sharma may soon retire from Test cricket, citing the emergence of younger talents like Shubman Gill as pressure on Rohit’s position.</p><ul><li>Rohit has only scored a highest of 10 runs in the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li><li>Head coach Gautam Gambhir did not confirm Rohit's place in the upcoming match, heightening speculation.</li><li>Shastri believes Rohit should leave the game on a high note if he chooses to retire.</li></ul><blockquote>"I won't be shocked at all (if Sharma retires) because he's not getting younger." - Ravi Shastri</blockquote><p>Shastri emphasizes that Rohit needs to play with freedom and be more aggressive in his batting approach.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sport/cricket/wont-be-surprised-if-rohit-retires-from-test-cricket-shastri/article69053441.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sport/cricket/wont-be-surprised-if-rohit-retires-from-test-cricket-shastri/article69053441.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Novak Djokovic sets-up Brisbane quarter-final against Reilly Opelka by beating Gael Monfils - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Novak Djokovic sets-up Brisbane quarter-final against Reilly Opelka by beating Gael Monfils</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Sports News</p><p>Novak Djokovic kept his hopes of winning a 100th career ATP title alive with a straightforward 6-3 6-3 win against Gael Monfils in the Brisbane International last 16. He will face Reilly Opelka in the quarter-finals.</p><ol><li>Djokovic won with a score of 6-3 6-3.</li><li>He converted his only break point in the first set.</li><li>Djokovic achieved his 20th career win against Monfils.</li><li>Opelka hit 25 aces in his match against Matteo Arnaldi.</li></ol><blockquote>“Opelka has been injured and he struggled a lot for a couple of years,” said Djokovic. “My gosh, I'm going to have to probably step back a few steps for that first serve.”</blockquote><p>Djokovic's upcoming match marks the first time he will play against Opelka.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/sport/tennis/articles/crk058ej23do</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/sport/tennis/articles/crk058ej23do</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:32:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS: Jasprit Bumrah to lead India in Sydney Test as Rohit Sharma opts out - Report - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS: Jasprit Bumrah to lead India in Sydney Test as Rohit Sharma opts out - Report</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 02, 2025</strong> / <strong>Source: Moneycontrol</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250102102306_captas.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="IND vs AUS: Fast-bowler Jasprit Bumrah will lead Team India in Sydney Test. (Photo: PTI)" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>IND vs AUS: Fast-bowler Jasprit Bumrah will lead Team India in Sydney Test. (Photo: PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Fast-bowler Jasprit Bumrah will lead Team India in the fifth and final Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy in Sydney, as Rohit Sharma opts out.</p>
<ul>
<li>Rohit Sharma has informed the coach and chairman of selectors about his decision.</li>
<li>Shubman Gill returns to the lineup, set to bat at number three.</li>
<li>KL Rahul will open alongside Yashasvi Jaiswal.</li>
<li>Prasidh Krishna replaces the injured Akash Deep.</li>
<li>Coach Gautam Gambhir engaged in intense discussions with Bumrah during practice.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>'Honesty is important': says coach Gautam Gambhir</blockquote>
<p>This significant shift raises questions about Rohit Sharma's future in the team as the new World Championship Cycle begins.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/sports/cricket/ind-vs-aus-jasprit-bumrah-to-lead-india-in-sydney-test-as-rohit-sharma-opts-out-report-article-12902199.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/sports/cricket/ind-vs-aus-jasprit-bumrah-to-lead-india-in-sydney-test-as-rohit-sharma-opts-out-report-article-12902199.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:23:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma dropped for SCG Test vs Australia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Dropped from the SCG Test Against Australia</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Sydney, January 2024</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116883492,imgsize-18634,width-400,resizemode-4/116883492.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma dropped for SCG Test vs Australia" title="Rohit Sharma (X Photo)" decoding="async"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma (Image Credit: Times of India)</figcaption><p>Rohit Sharma has been dropped from India's playing XI for the upcoming Test against Australia due to a string of poor performances. His exclusion follows a disappointing run in the series and a shift in batting positions that disrupted team balance.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma missed the first Test for the birth of his second child.</li><li>He struggled in recent matches, scoring only 31 runs in five innings at an average of 6.20 in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li><li>Since March 2024, Rohit has made just 154 runs in 15 innings, averaging 10.26.</li><li>Gautam Gambhir is set to take over as captain for the final Test, hoping to restore energy and unity in the dressing room.</li><li>The new opening partnership will likely involve KL Rahul and Yashasvi Jaiswal.</li></ul><blockquote>“The writing was very much on the wall for the 37-year-old who was certain to bid goodbye to Test cricket after the Sydney fixture.”</blockquote><p>With Rohit's future uncertain, the team looks to rebound in the final match of the series, aiming to retain the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rohit-sharma-dropped-for-scg-test-vs-australia/articleshow/116883518.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rohit-sharma-dropped-for-scg-test-vs-australia/articleshow/116883518.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Shubman Gill to lead India in Sydney Test?': Ex-Indian cricketer draws attention to visuals - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shubman Gill to potentially lead India in Sydney Test?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/India-batter-Shubman-Gill-made-way-for-a-third-spe_1735811506639_1735811660266.jpg" alt="India batter Shubman Gill made way for a third specialist all-rounder in Washington Sundar in the fourth Test in Melbourne(HT_PRINT)"><figcaption>India batter Shubman Gill made way for a third specialist all-rounder in Washington Sundar in the fourth Test in Melbourne(HT_PRINT)</figcaption><p>The recent practice session of the Indian cricket team has sparked rumors that Shubman Gill may lead the team in the fifth Test against Australia in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy series, as uncertainty surrounds the participation of captain Rohit Sharma.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma's availability for the match is unclear, prompting discussions about Gill's potential leadership role.</li><li>Sreevats Goswami, a former U-19 World Cup player, highlighted a viral visual from the practice session that fueled speculation about Gill's captaincy.</li><li>Goswami suggested this could signal a new era in Indian cricket as they look ahead to the next World Test Championship cycle.</li><li>Gill was benched for the prior match in Melbourne, which led to discussions on team composition and player roles.</li></ul><blockquote>“Going by a particular visual, Gill to lead India in Sydney test? So India already looking ahead to the next WTC cycle. This will be interesting.” - Sreevats Goswami</blockquote><p>The possibility of Gill returning to the XI hinges on whether Rohit Sharma is dropped, marking a significant shift in Indian cricket dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/shubman-gill-to-lead-india-in-sydney-test-vs-australia-ex-indian-cricketer-draws-attention-scg-visuals-101735811406137.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/shubman-gill-to-lead-india-in-sydney-test-vs-australia-ex-indian-cricketer-draws-attention-scg-visuals-101735811406137.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:16:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magnus Carlsen breaks silence on match-fixing claim, says ‘was joking’ in viral video: ‘Lacking decisive tiebreak rules’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/magnus-carlsen-breaks-silence-on-match-fixing-claim-says-was-joking-in-viral-video-lacking-decisive-tiebreak-rules-101735812591663.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/magnus-carlsen-breaks-silence-on-match-fixing-claim-says-was-joking-in-viral-video-lacking-decisive-tiebreak-rules-101735812591663.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:15:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BBL 2024-2025: Match 21, HEA vs SIX Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between HEA vs SIX? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxOeEs0bWZzZWV5cmhMRTVlOGpLcDBnaVZOYmh3MVViSUtjTnRtYkRvUWxsVzNCVnI4c0NaaGxtVkVUOUtoNjNTOTlvMnBkbG56NkRDck1mVEZBZDdJRjdQSFZ2YXNlcmtHUjVkZ3NEd0Q0dFpqeVVPVk9MU2FpeC1fakU2NGsyN0oxWUV4VTAxdV9PUEFvTDllRHVnMWFaWjNIN05nQzR5enJjRk5kZldPMjlSU2RIQk9VcXRyMUpHSTV3YjlVLUc0TVJOaFRJeHVHcXFPbkx0dndSR2N5YTQxejFqMWlsVDJSU2fSAfIBQVVfeXFMTld0b19hQzNqZm9MbWNhVl9OM19WcHRULWtkQ2lFVURVeHh6THdRNVEtQ1QycVRJbHVUTzU4NHF1M3hGdFRxenZTMUJnUzc0TlVYMi1Xai1CekVSS09jOHdGaWhBTHJUMHpSX3AyaTZrcXZ4NllNRHRNdU45R0VIQ3RlSm5MRjJ2M0Z1SU9hZ0VqOHVJOUxNbHR3WlhMZmI0dk5JUEN4ZGJ3bUNGdURKV1MxZW10S0pJYW9CbWtJZlVFUEdFcnRVM2VmM2pKZ1RnakFVUFhZS2dScHAxeXYySGlPdXlXekIzTm5zenJ5bUgwcHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxOeEs0bWZzZWV5cmhMRTVlOGpLcDBnaVZOYmh3MVViSUtjTnRtYkRvUWxsVzNCVnI4c0NaaGxtVkVUOUtoNjNTOTlvMnBkbG56NkRDck1mVEZBZDdJRjdQSFZ2YXNlcmtHUjVkZ3NEd0Q0dFpqeVVPVk9MU2FpeC1fakU2NGsyN0oxWUV4VTAxdV9PUEFvTDllRHVnMWFaWjNIN05nQzR5enJjRk5kZldPMjlSU2RIQk9VcXRyMUpHSTV3YjlVLUc0TVJOaFRJeHVHcXFPbkx0dndSR2N5YTQxejFqMWlsVDJSU2fSAfIBQVVfeXFMTld0b19hQzNqZm9MbWNhVl9OM19WcHRULWtkQ2lFVURVeHh6THdRNVEtQ1QycVRJbHVUTzU4NHF1M3hGdFRxenZTMUJnUzc0TlVYMi1Xai1CekVSS09jOHdGaWhBTHJUMHpSX3AyaTZrcXZ4NllNRHRNdU45R0VIQ3RlSm5MRjJ2M0Z1SU9hZ0VqOHVJOUxNbHR3WlhMZmI0dk5JUEN4ZGJ3bUNGdURKV1MxZW10S0pJYW9CbWtJZlVFUEdFcnRVM2VmM2pKZ1RnakFVUFhZS2dScHAxeXYySGlPdXlXekIzTm5zenJ5bUgwcHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma should fight out this phase: Irfan Pathan - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Irfan Pathan Backs Rohit Sharma to Overcome Current Challenges</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116882661,imgsize-31326,width-400,resizemode-4/116882661.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma should fight out this phase: Irfan Pathan" title="Rohit Sharma (AP Photo) " decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>Former Indian all-rounder Irfan Pathan expresses his support for Rohit Sharma, urging him to combat the difficulties he's facing in his performance and captaincy as India prepares for the final Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma is facing criticism over his recent form and captaincy ahead of the final Test in Sydney.</li><li>Opinions are divided among critics and former players regarding his future; some suggest retirement, while others support his retention.</li><li>Irfan Pathan believes Rohit should not walk away from this challenge and has confidence in his ability to turn things around.</li><li>Pathan emphasizes that Rohit's experience will be crucial in the upcoming final Test.</li><li>Rohit's current batting average in 2024 is concerning at 24.76, with a stark decline in performance during recent matches.</li><li>As captain, Rohit's overseas record shows only two wins in eight matches, raising questions on his leadership capabilities.</li></ul><blockquote>“Rohit Sharma should fight out this phase. I don’t want him to walk away from this challenge. He has done enough for Indian cricket, and I’m sure he has the ability to turn things around.” - Irfan Pathan</blockquote><p>The conclusion is that Rohit Sharma's performance under pressure and ability to adapt in critical situations are being closely observed, with the final Test set to be a decisive moment for his future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rohit-sharma-should-fight-out-this-phase-irfan-pathan/articleshow/116880902.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rohit-sharma-should-fight-out-this-phase-irfan-pathan/articleshow/116880902.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma set to be ‘rested’ for Sydney Test, Jasprit Bumrah likely to lead India in BGT finale - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma opts to ‘rest’ for Sydney Test, Jasprit Bumrah to lead India in BGT finale</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/rohit-sharma-2.jpg?w=640" alt="Rohit Sharma" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>India's captain Rohit Sharma walks off the field after losing his wicket during play on the last day of the fourth cricket test.</figcaption><p>Rohit Sharma, the captain of India's Test team, has decided to rest for the fifth and final Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy against Australia, allowing Jasprit Bumrah to lead the team in his absence.</p><ul><li>Rohit informed head coach Gautam Gambhir and chairman of selectors Ajit Agarkar about his decision.</li><li>Shubman Gill returns to the playing eleven, filling in for Rohit at number three.</li><li>KL Rahul will open the innings with Yashasvi Jaiswal.</li><li>Rohit's recent form has raised concerns, with an average of 6.2 in the last three Tests in Australia.</li><li>Bumrah will captain the crucial match, which India must win to level the series and retain the trophy.</li></ul><blockquote>“Everything is fine with Rohit. We are going to have a look at the wicket and announce the playing XI tomorrow.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>Rohit's resting raises questions about his future involvement in the team, especially with the upcoming World Test Championship cycle.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-set-to-be-rested-for-sydney-test-jasprit-bumrah-likely-to-lead-india-in-bgt-finale-9756410/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-set-to-be-rested-for-sydney-test-jasprit-bumrah-likely-to-lead-india-in-bgt-finale-9756410/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker, Gukesh among four athletes to get Khel Ratna award - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manu Bhaker, Gukesh among four athletes to get Khel Ratna award</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/xq0dw2/article69053225.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/IMG_Felicitation_for_D_G_2_1_KVDO6OKD.jpg" alt="18-year-old Gukesh became the youngest ever World Chess Champion. File" title="18-year-old Gukesh became the youngest ever World Chess Champion. File"><figcaption>18-year-old Gukesh became the youngest ever World Chess Champion. File | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>Double Olympic-medallist Manu Bhaker and chess world champion D Gukesh were among four winners of the Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna award announced by the Sports Ministry, which also named an unprecedented 17 para-athletes in the list of 32 Arjuna awardees.</p><ul><li>The Khel Ratna award was awarded to Manu Bhaker, D Gukesh, Harmanpreet Singh, and Praveen Kumar.</li><li>The awards ceremony is scheduled for January 17, 2025, at Rashtrapati Bhavan.</li><li>Manu Bhaker won two medals in the last Olympics, becoming a significant figure in shooting.</li><li>D Gukesh became the youngest ever World Chess Champion and contributed to India's success at the Chess Olympiad.</li><li>The list of Arjuna awardees includes a record number of para-athletes due to their exceptional performance in the Paris Paralympics.</li></ul><blockquote>“The awardees will receive their awards from the President of India at a specially organised function at Rashtrapati Bhavan on 17th January, 2025.”</blockquote><p>The Khel Ratna awardees receive a cash prize of Rs 25 lakh along with a citation and a medallion, highlighting their significant contributions to Indian sports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sport/manu-bhaker-gukesh-among-four-athletes-to-get-khel-ratna-award/article69053207.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sport/manu-bhaker-gukesh-among-four-athletes-to-get-khel-ratna-award/article69053207.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker to receive Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna after week-long confusion over nomination, Gukesh among four recipients - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manu Bhaker awarded Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna amid nomination confusion</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/Paris-Games-double-medallist-Manu-Bhaker---EPA-EFE_1735809572589_1735809578932.jpg" alt="Paris Games double medallist Manu Bhaker" title="Paris Games double medallist Manu Bhaker"><figcaption>Paris Games double medallist Manu Bhaker. (EPA-EFE)(HT_PRINT)</figcaption><p>Manu Bhaker and D Gukesh are among the four recipients of the prestigious Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna Award, confirmed by the sports ministry following a week of confusion regarding Bhaker's nomination.</p><ul><li>Manu Bhaker made history as the first athlete from independent India to win two medals in a single Olympic Games.</li><li>Along with Bhaker, Harmanpreet Singh and para-athlete Praveen Kumar also received the award.</li><li>Gukesh became the youngest-ever World Champion in chess.</li><li>The award ceremony will take place at Rashtrapati Bhavan on January 17, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“I believe there has been a lapse, possibly on my part, while filing for the nomination, which is being corrected. Irrespective of the award, I shall remain motivated to win more medals for my country.” - Manu Bhaker</blockquote><p>This year's Khel Ratna award not only honors excellence in sports but also highlights the dedication of these athletes to inspire future generations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/manu-bhaker-to-receive-dhyan-chand-khel-ratna-after-week-long-confusion-over-nomination-gukesh-among-four-recipients-101735809074039.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/manu-bhaker-to-receive-dhyan-chand-khel-ratna-after-week-long-confusion-over-nomination-gukesh-among-four-recipients-101735809074039.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:20:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Won't be shocked' if Rohit Sharma retires: Shastri sets record straight, tells IND captain to 'have a blast' in Sydney - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma's Retirement Speculation: Shastri Urges Aggressive Play</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/MixCollage-02-Jan-2025-02-24-PM-6826_1735808073040_1735808078798.jpg" alt="Ravi Shastri didn't mince his words as he talked about Rohit Sharma's future (Files/AP)">
<figcaption>Ravi Shastri didn't mince his words as he talked about Rohit Sharma's future (Files/AP)</figcaption>
<p>The speculation surrounding Rohit Sharma's Test career has intensified due to his poor form and questions about his captaincy. Shastri advises him to play aggressively as the team prepares for a crucial match in Sydney.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rohit Sharma has registered four single-digit scores in five innings during the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li>
  <li>His captaincy is under scrutiny as India trails 1-2 in the series against Australia.</li>
  <li>Shastri suggests that if Rohit does not improve, retirement could be a possibility.</li>
  <li>He emphasizes the need for Rohit to play freely and aggressively to regain form.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If I was anywhere near Rohit Sharma, I'll tell him, ‘Just go and smash it. Just go out there and have a blast,’” - Ravi Shastri</blockquote>
<p>Shastri's insights point to the urgency for Rohit to reconsider his approach as the team faces critical matches ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/wont-be-shocked-if-rohit-sharma-retires-shastri-sets-record-straight-tells-ind-captain-to-have-a-blast-in-sydney-101735802916516.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/wont-be-shocked-if-rohit-sharma-retires-shastri-sets-record-straight-tells-ind-captain-to-have-a-blast-in-sydney-101735802916516.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:56:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coach Gautam Gambhir says he had used ‘honest words’ when talking to Rohit Sharma and Co. a day after The Indian Express reported of him cracking the whip - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir's Honest Talk with Indian Cricket Team After Loss</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/gambhir-2-1.jpg?w=640" alt="Indian Head Coach Gautam Gambhir." width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Indian Head Coach Gautam Gambhir. (FILE Photo)</figcaption>
<p>After a reported stern talk post the Indian team's loss in Melbourne, Coach Gautam Gambhir emphasized the importance of honest communication within the team.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gambhir acknowledged giving a serious address to players about the need for a unified approach.</li>
  <li>He stressed that team interests must take priority over individual play, especially in team sports.</li>
  <li>Gambhir noted a lack of fight from the Indian side in the current series, trailing 1-2 before the final Test.</li>
  <li>Honesty and effective communication are pivotal for achieving success as a team.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Honesty is extremely important if you want to probably go on and achieve some great things.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote>
<p>This communication aims to help bolster the team's performance and unity as they head into a crucial match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/gautam-gambhir-rohit-sharma-border-gavaskar-trophy-9756338/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/gautam-gambhir-rohit-sharma-border-gavaskar-trophy-9756338/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>