<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 20:19:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 20:19:45 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Disservice to the game": Ravichandran Ashwin makes a strong statement on not getting farewell after his retirement - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>“Disservice to the game”: Ravichandran Ashwin makes a strong statement on not getting farewell after his retirement</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> September 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Crictoday</p><img width="1200" height="675" src="https://crictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/R-Ashwin.webp" alt="R Ashwin"><figcaption>He doesn't believe in grand farewells and recently responded to Kapil Dev's remark that Ashwin deserved a grand send-off, considering his performances for the country over the years.</figcaption><p>Ravichandran Ashwin revealed that he does not believe in grand farewells following his retirement from international cricket, which surprised many in the cricket community.</p><ul><li>Ashwin announced his retirement after the third Test against Australia.</li><li>He responded to Kapil Dev's suggestion of a grand farewell, stating he does not want such recognition.</li><li>Ashwin's decision was sudden and caught even his close teammates off guard.</li><li>He emphasized that farewells are a disservice to the game.</li><li>Ashwin plans to remain connected with cricket and will play for Chennai Super Kings in IPL 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“For me, farewells are wrong... I never wanted a grand farewell for myself.”</blockquote><p>Ashwin expressed no regrets about his retirement and affirmed he values his achievements as a cricketer.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/disservice-to-the-game-ravichandran-ashwin-makes-a-strong-statement-on-not-getting-farewell-after-his-retirement/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/disservice-to-the-game-ravichandran-ashwin-makes-a-strong-statement-on-not-getting-farewell-after-his-retirement/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 17:28:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Second to none' Mohammad Abbas ready for his redemption arc - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Second to none: Mohammad Abbas ready for his redemption arc</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source: </strong> ESPNcricinfo</p>
<div>
  <img src='https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg' alt='Story Image'>
  <figcaption>No, no way! You cannot do that, Mohammad Abbas!</figcaption>
</div>
<p>Mohammad Abbas, returning to the Pakistan Test team after a three-year absence, showcases his exceptional bowling skills and team spirit as he prepares for the upcoming series in South Africa. Despite the mystery surrounding his exclusion from the team, his consistent performances at Hampshire have earned him this much-deserved opportunity.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Abbas has taken 180 wickets at an average of 19.26 over the past three seasons with Hampshire.</li>
  <li>He last played for Pakistan in August 2021, demonstrating his prowess with a ten-wicket haul against Australia.</li>
  <li>Coaches and teammates believe his skillset is crucial for the team’s success in South Africa.</li>
  <li>During his absence, other fast bowlers have emerged, but Abbas remains the most prolific bowler in first-class cricket since his last Test match.</li>
  <li>His return is seen as a chance to correct past mistakes and showcase his talent on the international stage.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>"His skill is second to none." - Shan Masood, Pakistan Test captain</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The cricket community awaits Abbas’s performance as he returns to represent Pakistan, hopeful for a successful redemption.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa-vs-pak-centurion-boxing-day-test-second-to-none-mohammad-abbas-all-set-for-second-coming-1466530</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa-vs-pak-centurion-boxing-day-test-second-to-none-mohammad-abbas-all-set-for-second-coming-1466530</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:56:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MS Dhoni Finds Mention In Australia Great's Take On Ravindra Jadeja Row: "Didn't Do One..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxQYmFxZ3dpSUY2NURmWVpFREUzZ0Eydjl0Z1Raa2VmS1BveDdtVUx5eXJBSE1oSWV5bkN3VU80RVdKVkczX1lZTWNEZXgwbWFMd3lNem0tc0F3OU1MVTA4ekhqV0J0bjJGTEhjNG50VU1tYWNZMmlpd1dkbWZmaFdPVFNLZnBSSmxVcnBUQUJ6SFU3R0pWTm91UUpUOWxycnNrLTl5UmJVVUprM2k1YVBBekRTdjNkdUdRak0wMUJiWWU1UTFZWW43SVV6dWYtcEducG5fbV9TaW1qQdIB4gFBVV95cUxNZ2FrNlNtSjNpNU40ZVVPUmZPUWJJRkYwbE4wUmluNk5pWWVOSlRyTFcyRVBfR3dlcE1pcFZpX2ZRU3RHMGpickZJaWlCWUl6cHB3VEsyYm9rRkYyb0R4R29aTXRRdVZTaWpDa1FxSmIwUjFkOHA2VFJ4dkN6TGtlR0p3bDBaa0x6ekxvLVduTlZ0ejg0SGN0THJOZ1NCRVNMSmo4cnNxWFpTaWZLazUzdkJDbzJ3QlVNRDE2U3dLc0dEYi1RSUlOUDRFN3cta3V5TkFta3V2bWFWTURuZnZSWTlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxQYmFxZ3dpSUY2NURmWVpFREUzZ0Eydjl0Z1Raa2VmS1BveDdtVUx5eXJBSE1oSWV5bkN3VU80RVdKVkczX1lZTWNEZXgwbWFMd3lNem0tc0F3OU1MVTA4ekhqV0J0bjJGTEhjNG50VU1tYWNZMmlpd1dkbWZmaFdPVFNLZnBSSmxVcnBUQUJ6SFU3R0pWTm91UUpUOWxycnNrLTl5UmJVVUprM2k1YVBBekRTdjNkdUdRak0wMUJiWWU1UTFZWW43SVV6dWYtcEducG5fbV9TaW1qQdIB4gFBVV95cUxNZ2FrNlNtSjNpNU40ZVVPUmZPUWJJRkYwbE4wUmluNk5pWWVOSlRyTFcyRVBfR3dlcE1pcFZpX2ZRU3RHMGpickZJaWlCWUl6cHB3VEsyYm9rRkYyb0R4R29aTXRRdVZTaWpDa1FxSmIwUjFkOHA2VFJ4dkN6TGtlR0p3bDBaa0x6ekxvLVduTlZ0ejg0SGN0THJOZ1NCRVNMSmo4cnNxWFpTaWZLazUzdkJDbzJ3QlVNRDE2U3dLc0dEYi1RSUlOUDRFN3cta3V5TkFta3V2bWFWTURuZnZSWTlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 16:20:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yasir and Ali star as ABL Stallions trump UMT Markhors to win Bahria Town Champions T20 Cup - PCB]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yasir and Ali star as ABL Stallions trump UMT Markhors to win Bahria Town Champions T20 Cup</h1><p><strong>Date: 25 December 2024, Source: PCB</strong></p><p>A swashbuckling hundred from opener Yasir Ali and a brilliant bowling display by Mohammad Ali led ABL Stallions to a 75-run victory over UMT Markhors in the Bahria Town Champions T20 Cup final held at Rawalpindi Cricket Stadium.</p><ul><li>Yasir scored 100 runs off 57 balls, hitting seven sixes and five boundaries.</li><li>ABL Stallions set a target of 200 runs, finishing their innings at 199-5.</li><li>UMT Markhors were bowled out for 124 runs in 19.1 overs.</li><li>Mohammad Ali took 3 wickets for 19 runs, while Usman Tariq took 2 wickets for just 10 runs.</li><li>This victory marks another title for ABL Stallions in Pakistan’s T20 history.</li></ul><blockquote>Player of the Final - Yasir Khan (ABL Stallions)</blockquote><blockquote>Player of the Tournament - Mohammad Ali (ABL Stallions)</blockquote><p>The ABL Stallions celebrate another championship win, dominating throughout the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pcb.com.pk/news-detail/yasir-and-ali-star-as-abl-stallions-trump-umt-markhors-to-win-bahria-town-champions-t20-cup.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pcb.com.pk/news-detail/yasir-and-ali-star-as-abl-stallions-trump-umt-markhors-to-win-bahria-town-champions-t20-cup.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:12:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 4th Test, Melbourne weather forecast: Will MCG suffer Gabba fate with WTC final spot at stake? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia 4th Test, Melbourne Weather Forecast: Will MCG Suffer Gabba Fate with WTC Final Spot at Stake?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 08:42 PM IST<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-10_1735137965625_1735137983262.jpg" alt="Ground staff work on the wicket at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG) in Melbourne on December 25, 2024, ahead of the fourth cricket Test match between Australia and India(AFP)" />
<figcaption>Ground staff work on the wicket at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG) in Melbourne on December 25, 2024, ahead of the fourth cricket Test match between Australia and India(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>As the fourth Test match of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy series approaches, the spotlight is on both the teams and the Melbourne weather, particularly with World Test Championship (WTC) qualification at stake.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The previous game in Brisbane ended in a draw, keeping the series tied at 1-1 after three matches.</li>
  <li>Australia lost Josh Hazlewood to injury and replaced him with Scott Boland, while India has named uncapped Tanush Kotian to replace retiree Ravichandran Ashwin.</li>
  <li>The Melbourne weather forecast predicts minimal rain for the first three days, with only a 24% chance of rain expected on Day 3.</li>
  <li>India's hopes of qualifying for the WTC final hinge on the outcome of this match, as a loss or draw would eliminate them.</li>
  <li>Australia also has upcoming matches that impact their qualification chances.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>If India loses or draws, they could be eliminated from the race to the WTC final.</blockquote>
<p>The outcome of this Test match is crucial for both teams as they aim for a spot in the WTC final, with weather conditions also playing a significant role in the proceedings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-4th-test-melbourne-weather-forecast-will-mcg-suffer-gabba-fate-with-wtc-final-spot-at-stake-101735137908260.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-4th-test-melbourne-weather-forecast-will-mcg-suffer-gabba-fate-with-wtc-final-spot-at-stake-101735137908260.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:12:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star, Who Last Played In 2021, Returns As Pakistan Name Playing XI For Boxing Day Test vs South Afri.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNQ1JSUThuMEpHYlhrM2lUMWY0ZFlRQ01laHhPQVlVdUVBZ3JOVkU0a19kYl9Td25tZ05GaXRmVmtGaVdsSUtKMF9ndVB5SGFjZU1ZdnphTG1ueDJfQV9WMllGVjZwdnNhWHA1TXIwZVJLa2RRYW5ScUZZMjlhamJoMnpQUnBRQXczWGxuZ2hQRjl2aU4yMTBjVnRrMUFCNzZCdjJDTU12c1lKeVo4ZzVpb2VNRVhmWDQ3TVVyOHVuVl95bGRIbmo2bVU2XzNtMTN2cHlKRnU3RdIB3wFBVV95cUxNdGgtVDdyeGl5ZGJYUFQ1TGdoQzkzbjlHWmdUWWNPVURmVWF0dUtTY1lsQXV1OE1DLUxheHlmbEVYZG5DVmZCNFVsaTFiajZIeTUzYWJHc1JHa2QzWWhSbW8ySXFQUHZwcy16UnExVEEyREx4c09IUTR1bWpHcVVqckNkcWZIMmh0NGQzTVhqR0h0WTU5T0g2SG9LSnd6Z2ZYaDlUY3lBRFNvUlg3NGh2c3lxZVR1VDJpeS1MbjYxRHBIZEhMZ2xLWmlOTUM0WmJsNng3QkhjcHJjWE5fOEhZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxNQ1JSUThuMEpHYlhrM2lUMWY0ZFlRQ01laHhPQVlVdUVBZ3JOVkU0a19kYl9Td25tZ05GaXRmVmtGaVdsSUtKMF9ndVB5SGFjZU1ZdnphTG1ueDJfQV9WMllGVjZwdnNhWHA1TXIwZVJLa2RRYW5ScUZZMjlhamJoMnpQUnBRQXczWGxuZ2hQRjl2aU4yMTBjVnRrMUFCNzZCdjJDTU12c1lKeVo4ZzVpb2VNRVhmWDQ3TVVyOHVuVl95bGRIbmo2bVU2XzNtMTN2cHlKRnU3RdIB3wFBVV95cUxNdGgtVDdyeGl5ZGJYUFQ1TGdoQzkzbjlHWmdUWWNPVURmVWF0dUtTY1lsQXV1OE1DLUxheHlmbEVYZG5DVmZCNFVsaTFiajZIeTUzYWJHc1JHa2QzWWhSbW8ySXFQUHZwcy16UnExVEEyREx4c09IUTR1bWpHcVVqckNkcWZIMmh0NGQzTVhqR0h0WTU5T0g2SG9LSnd6Z2ZYaDlUY3lBRFNvUlg3NGh2c3lxZVR1VDJpeS1MbjYxRHBIZEhMZ2xLWmlOTUM0WmJsNng3QkhjcHJjWE5fOEhZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:58:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Grand farewells are wrong': Ashwin reacts to Kapil Dev's remark - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Grand Farewells Are Wrong': Ashwin Reacts to Kapil Dev's Remark</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<p>In a new statement, Indian cricketer Ravichandran Ashwin has expressed his disagreement with Kapil Dev's remarks regarding grand farewells for cricketers, suggesting a more humble approach.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Ashwin believes that cricket is a team sport and does not support the notion of extravagant farewells.</li>
  <li>Kapil Dev had previously shared his thoughts on how cricketers deserve a grand send-off.</li>
  <li>The debate highlights differing perspectives on how players should be honored following their careers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Ashwin stated, "Every player's contribution to the game is important, but we are here to play cricket, not to make a spectacle of farewells."</blockquote>
<p>This discussion opens up questions about the future of cricket farewells and how they resonate with fans and players alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/grand-farewells-are-wrong-ashwin-reacts-to-kapil-devs-remark/articleshow/116658466.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/grand-farewells-are-wrong-ashwin-reacts-to-kapil-devs-remark/articleshow/116658466.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan bring back Babar and go with four pacers for Centurion Test - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan Bring Back Babar and Opt for Four Pacers in Centurion Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 25, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p>Pakistan will face South Africa in the Boxing Day Test at Centurion with a bowling attack featuring four pacers and no specialist spinner, marking the return of Babar Azam to the lineup.</p><img src="https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg" alt="Story Image"><figcaption>Intriguing Boxing Day beckons with SA in sight of WTC final</figcaption><p>Key Points:</p><ul><li>Babar Azam returns to the team after being dropped from the previous Tests against England.</li><li>Pakistan selects four seamers: Aamer Jamal, Naseem Shah, Mohammad Abbas, and Khurram Shahzad.</li><li>Shan Masood will open alongside Saim Ayub, while Abdullah Shafique has been left out due to poor form.</li><li>The team has opted for an all-pace attack, considering the seam-friendly conditions of the Centurion pitch.</li></ul><blockquote>“Since the Australia series, we've backed Aamer Jamal... He’s handy when it reverses and useful at being the enforcer.” - Shan Masood</blockquote><p>This match will be critical as both teams rely on seam bowling, highlighting the importance of pitch conditions for the upcoming Test.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa-vs-pak-2024-pakistan-bring-back-babar-azam-go-with-four-pacers-for-boxing-day-test-in-centurion-1466526</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa-vs-pak-2024-pakistan-bring-back-babar-azam-go-with-four-pacers-for-boxing-day-test-in-centurion-1466526</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:35:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MS Dhoni turns Santa Claus for daughter Ziva, wife Sakshi and Kriti Sanon, photos go viral - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MS Dhoni turns Santa Claus for daughter Ziva, wife Sakshi and Kriti Sanon, photos go viral</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/ms-dhoni-turns-santa-claus-for-daughter-ziva-wife-sakshi-and-kriti-sanon-photos-go-viral-202412-1735136308.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="MS Dhoni turns Santa Claus for daughter Ziva wife Sakshi and Kriti Sanon photos go viral">
<figcaption>Image credit: Instagram</figcaption>
<p>MS Dhoni brought holiday cheer to his home by dressing as Santa Claus for Christmas 2024, delighting his daughter Ziva, wife Sakshi, and actress Kriti Sanon, with photos from their celebration quickly going viral.</p>
<ul>
<li>Dhoni's Santa outfit featured his nickname 'Mahi' on the hat.</li>
<li>The social media post accumulated over 500,000 likes within hours.</li>
<li>Kriti Sanon also participated in the joyous celebrations, sharing moments with fans.</li>
<li>Dhoni remains a beloved sports icon even after his retirement.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The ex-India captain is seen dressed as Santa Claus, with his wife and daughter Ziva by his side.”</blockquote>
<p>This festive occasion highlighted Dhoni's family values and ability to connect with fans through social media, reinforcing his status as a beloved figure in Indian cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/ms-dhoni-turns-santa-claus-for-daughter-ziva-wife-sakshi-and-kriti-sanon-photos-go-viral-416299/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/ms-dhoni-turns-santa-claus-for-daughter-ziva-wife-sakshi-and-kriti-sanon-photos-go-viral-416299/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:21:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R Ashwin Watches Travis Head's Training Video, Pinpoints His Exact Game Plan - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>R Ashwin Analyzes Travis Head's Training Techniques Ahead of Crucial Test</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/gqu1ts5_ashwin-head_625x300_25_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="R Ashwin Analyzes Travis Head's Training Techniques" /><figcaption>File image of R Ashwin. © AFP</figcaption><p>Travis Head has emerged as a major challenge for India in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy, having scored two centuries already. R Ashwin reviews Head's recent net practice video, noting his strategic focus on addressing weaknesses against specific deliveries.</p><ul><li>Travis Head's performance has been crucial for Australia in the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li><li>He has scored 152 and 140 in the second and third Tests, respectively.</li><li>Ashwin analyzes a video of Head training to defend against deliveries from round the wicket.</li><li>Head is currently the highest run-scorer in the series, with 409 runs in three Tests.</li></ul><blockquote>“Omg! He is getting to the off stump? Is that the ploy for round the stumps?” — Ashwin (@ashwinravi99)</blockquote><p>Ashwin's insights reflect his continued engagement with cricket, despite his recent retirement from international play.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/r-ashwin-watches-travis-heads-training-video-pinpoints-his-exact-game-plan-7329213</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/r-ashwin-watches-travis-heads-training-video-pinpoints-his-exact-game-plan-7329213</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 14:01:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hansi Flick identifies the critical issue behind Barcelona’s recent poor streak – report - Barca Universal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxQTG5DV1U4Ujh3RC1JMWE4Z25YQ0pEdC00ODY4SHNwMHVjVE9pNVh3cTlxWUU3dS1QdWNXNW9MelNTUFhKSWRqSzlXUk9IOU9PdUpQUEVPbUJSXzRFaWtCY21semdnazBUVkc4Q0VEeWlpSThSNjlQbDVYaG1hbk5leUo3RXlEalp0QnNzeEoyQmQyU1pwMjdGWU9MRy1JNEw1bmJlakdLYnBZY2o1d1VnNmhkTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxQTG5DV1U4Ujh3RC1JMWE4Z25YQ0pEdC00ODY4SHNwMHVjVE9pNVh3cTlxWUU3dS1QdWNXNW9MelNTUFhKSWRqSzlXUk9IOU9PdUpQUEVPbUJSXzRFaWtCY21semdnazBUVkc4Q0VEeWlpSThSNjlQbDVYaG1hbk5leUo3RXlEalp0QnNzeEoyQmQyU1pwMjdGWU9MRy1JNEw1bmJlakdLYnBZY2o1d1VnNmhkTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:47:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can struggling Virat Kohli overcome batting blues at favourite MCG? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can Virat Kohli Overcome Recent Batting Struggles at MCG?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> <time datetime="2023-12-26">December 26, 2023</time> <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116657292,imgsize-31346,width-400,resizemode-4/116657292.jpg" alt="Can struggling Virat Kohli overcome batting blues at favourite MCG?" title="Virat Kohli. (Pic Credit - X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Virat Kohli. (Pic Credit - X)</figcaption><p>As the Boxing Day Test at the iconic MCG approaches, Virat Kohli seeks to recover from recent batting inconsistency during the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Kohli's recent performance shows scores of 5, 100*, 7, 11, and 3, accumulating 126 runs with an average of 31.50.</li><li>Historically, Kohli has performed well at MCG, with an average of 52.66 and a highest score of 169.</li><li>Ravi Shastri comments on Kohli's form, suggesting patience and discipline are key to overcoming challenges.</li><li>Matthew Hayden advises Kohli to take cues from Sachin Tendulkar's strategy during his 2004 Sydney Test innings.</li></ul><blockquote>“If Virat gets over that first 30, 40 minutes, with serious application and discipline, I don't think he's (out of form).” - Ravi Shastri</blockquote><p>Fans are hopeful that the festive atmosphere of the Boxing Day Test will help Kohli rediscover his batting prowess and silence his critics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/can-struggling-virat-kohli-overcome-batting-blues-at-favourite-mcg/articleshow/116657337.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/can-struggling-virat-kohli-overcome-batting-blues-at-favourite-mcg/articleshow/116657337.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MS Dhoni Sets Internet Ablaze With New 'Santa Claus' Look, Poses With Wife Sakshi And Daughter Ziva - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MS Dhoni Sets Internet Ablaze With New 'Santa Claus' Look, Poses With Wife Sakshi And Daughter Ziva</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/89orf04_ms-dhoni-santa-claus_625x300_25_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="MS Dhoni in Santa Claus outfit"><figcaption>MS Dhoni in his new look. © Instagram</figcaption><p>Legendary India captain MS Dhoni has delighted fans with a new festive look as Santa Claus shared by his wife Sakshi. The post has gone viral, gathering over 500,000 likes shortly after being posted.</p><ul><li>Dhoni disguised as Santa Claus with wife Sakshi and daughter Ziva.</li><li>The Instagram post quickly gained massive traction online.</li><li>Dhoni remains a beloved figure in Indian cricket despite his retirement from international cricket over five years ago.</li><li>He will be playing for Chennai Super Kings (CSK) in the IPL 2025 season.</li><li>Dhoni was retained for Rs 4 crore under a new rule benefiting players who haven't played internationally for over five years.</li></ul><blockquote>"Glimpses of the legendary captain send fans into a frenzy."</blockquote><p>Dhoni continues to maintain a strong connection with his fans, showcasing his charismatic personality even during the holiday season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/ms-dhoni-sets-internet-ablaze-with-new-santa-claus-look-poses-with-wife-sakshi-and-daughter-ziva-7329822</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/ms-dhoni-sets-internet-ablaze-with-new-santa-claus-look-poses-with-wife-sakshi-and-daughter-ziva-7329822</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:22:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli to Prithvi Shaw: Top Indian cricketers who disappeared all of sudden - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli to Prithvi Shaw: Top Indian cricketers who disappeared all of sudden</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/vinod-kambli-to-prithvi-shaw-top-indian-cricketers-who-disappeared-all-of-sudden-202412-1735132604.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Vinod Kambli to Prithvi Shaw Top Indian cricketers who disappeared all of sudden"><figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption><p>Numerous Indian cricketers have shown immense promise but have suddenly faded from the forefront of the sport. Various factors, including injuries and off-field troubles, have derailed their careers.</p><ul><li>Players like Vinod Kambli and Prithvi Shaw had early success but faced challenges that limited their time in the spotlight.</li><li>Others, such as S. Sreesanth, gained fame from notable achievements, only for controversies to hinder their career progression.</li><li>Intense competition has seen promising talents like Mayank Agarwal and Manish Pandey struggle to maintain their places in the national team.</li><li>Injuries have significantly impacted cricketers like Varun Aaron, who showcased potential but ultimately could not sustain their performance.</li><li>Fitness issues have also played a role in Prithvi Shaw's recent career struggles.</li></ul><blockquote>“He had the potential to become one of the game's greatest players.” - Insights on Prithvi Shaw's career potential.</blockquote><p>This examination of Indian cricketers illustrates how factors beyond talent can significantly affect a player's career trajectory.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/vinod-kambli-to-prithvi-shaw-top-indian-cricketers-who-disappeared-all-of-sudden-416276/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/vinod-kambli-to-prithvi-shaw-top-indian-cricketers-who-disappeared-all-of-sudden-416276/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:20:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revealed: Manchester United’s new plan for Harry Amass amid Aston Villa transfer interest - UtdDistrict]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manchester United's Future Plans for Harry Amass Amid Aston Villa Interest</h1>
<p><strong>Date: November 15, 2024</strong><br><strong>Source: UtdDistrict</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://smartframe.io/embedding-support" alt="Harry Amass" /><figcaption>Harry Amass in action for Manchester United</figcaption></p>
<p>Manchester United's 17-year-old talent Harry Amass is poised for a new chapter as the club plans to send him on loan due to limited first-team opportunities under new head coach Ruben Amorim.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Amass showed promise during pre-season and was included on the bench for several matches, including an FA Cup semi-final.</li>
  <li>After joining United from Watford in 2023, he has been a standout for the club's youth teams, including a key role in their treble-winning U18 campaign.</li>
  <li>Erik ten Hag had envisioned a breakthrough for Amass, but recent coaching changes have shifted priorities towards experienced players.</li>
  <li>United plans to loan Amass in January to give him competitive playing time.</li>
  <li>Aston Villa is interested in a permanent deal for Amass, but United is currently not considering any approaches.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A loan deal makes the most sense for Amass, allowing him to prove himself in a competitive first-team environment.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, as Manchester United seeks to balance youth development with team performance, Harry Amass's potential loan signifies a strategic shift to enhance his growth and performance prospects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://utddistrict.co.uk/man-utd-harry-amass-aston-villa-transfer-plan/25/12/2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://utddistrict.co.uk/man-utd-harry-amass-aston-villa-transfer-plan/25/12/2024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Closer Look At PV Sindhu’s Wedding Saree - NDTV Movies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu's Wedding Saree Designed by Manish Malhotra</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> February 3, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Swirlster</p><p>Badminton champion PV Sindhu is set to marry Venkata Datta Sai, showcasing a stunning wedding saree designed by celebrated designer Manish Malhotra.</p><ul><li>PV Sindhu's elegant wedding attire is a highlight of her upcoming nuptials.</li><li>The saree reflects a blend of traditional elements and modern fashion.</li><li>Manish Malhotra continues to create a buzz with his designer collections for bridal wear.</li></ul><blockquote>“A perfect blend of tradition and modernity,” said a fashion critic.</blockquote><p>This wedding saree not only emphasizes Sindhu's personal style but also highlights the collaboration between sports and fashion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/webstories/a-closer-look-at-badminton-champion-pv-sindhu-s-manish-malhotra-wedding-saree-to-marry-venkata-datta-sai-29748</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/webstories/a-closer-look-at-badminton-champion-pv-sindhu-s-manish-malhotra-wedding-saree-to-marry-venkata-datta-sai-29748</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:07:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohammed Shami, Sania Mirza Marry Each Other? Here's Truth About Viral Nikaah Photos - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammed Shami and Sania Mirza: Viral Wedding Photos Debunked</h1><p><strong>Updated: December 25, 2024 [IST]</strong> | <strong>Source: OneIndia</strong></p><img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2024/12/mohammedshami3-1735130983.jpg" alt="Mohammed Shami and Sania Mirza" width="600" height="338"><figcaption>Mohammed Shami and Sania Mirza</figcaption><p>The internet buzzes with rumors as photographs of cricketer Mohammed Shami and Tennis star Sania Mirza dressed as a bride and groom went viral. However, these images have been fact-checked and proven to be AI-generated.</p><ul><li>The viral photos depict Mohammed Shami in a cream indo-western outfit and Sania Mirza in a pink lehenga.</li><li>Claims suggest the images were taken at their wedding ceremony, leading to widespread speculation.</li><li>Fact-checking revealed no evidence from social media or family confirming their marriage.</li><li>AI technology was identified as the source of the morphed images, previously connected to fake Christmas celebrations.</li><li>Social media users are warned to be cautious of deepfake technology.</li></ul><blockquote>No! Mohammed Shami and Sania Mirza have not married each other and the viral photos are AI generated.</blockquote><p>The rumor surrounding Mohammed Shami and Sania Mirza's alleged marriage has been debunked, with the viral images dismissed as fake.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/fact-check/mohammed-shami-sania-mirza-marry-each-other-heres-truth-about-viral-nikaah-photos-4025717.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/fact-check/mohammed-shami-sania-mirza-marry-each-other-heres-truth-about-viral-nikaah-photos-4025717.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:52:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma Replaces KL Rahul; Shubman Gill OUT: India Likely Playing XI For Boxing Day Test - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Replaces KL Rahul; Shubman Gill OUT: India Likely Playing XI For Boxing Day Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116656339,thumbsize-79100,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116656339.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma Replaces KL Rahul; Shubman Gill OUT: India Likely Playing XI For Boxing Day Test" title="Rohit Sharma Replaces KL Rahul; Shubman Gill OUT: India Likely Playing XI For Boxing Day Test"><figcaption>Photo: AP</figcaption><p>India are currently level 1-1 in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy and seek to take a lead in the series during the Boxing Day Test at the MCG. Changes in the lineup are expected to improve their chances for World Test Championship qualification.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma returns to open the batting, replacing KL Rahul.</li><li>Shubman Gill dropped; Dhruv Jurel slated to bat at no.6.</li><li>Washington Sundar replaces Nitish Kumar Reddy in the all-rounder slot.</li><li>Virat Kohli and Rishabh Pant remain at positions 4 and 5.</li><li>India's likely playing XI: Rohit Sharma (c), Yashasvi Jaiswal, KL Rahul, Virat Kohli, Rishabh Pant (wk), Dhruv Jurel, Ravindra Jadeja, Washington Sundar, Akash Deep, Jasprit Bumrah, Mohammed Siraj.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-replaces-kl-rahul-shubman-gill-out-india-likely-playing-xi-for-boxing-day-test-article-116654778</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-replaces-kl-rahul-shubman-gill-out-india-likely-playing-xi-for-boxing-day-test-article-116654778</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:24:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunil Gavaskar explains why India should not drop Nitish Reddy for Boxing Day Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunil Gavaskar explains why India should not drop Nitish Reddy for Boxing Day Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116656284,imgsize-27618,width-400,resizemode-4/116656284.jpg" alt="Sunil Gavaskar explains why India should not drop Nitish Reddy for Boxing Day Test" title="Nitish Reddy (PTI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Nitish Reddy (PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>The Border-Gavaskar Trophy is at a crucial point, tied at 1-1, as India prepares for the Boxing Day Test in Melbourne. Key discussions revolve around player selections, particularly concerning Nitish Kumar Reddy.</p><ul><li>Ravichandran Ashwin's retirement creates a gap, leading to Tanush Kotian's selection as a replacement.</li><li>Sunil Gavaskar argues against dropping Nitish Reddy, emphasizing his role as a fourth seamer.</li><li>Reddy's performance has been lackluster, but his batting is seen as vital for team balance.</li><li>Adjustments to the top order include Rohit Sharma returning as an opener and K.L. Rahul possibly batting at number three.</li><li>Akash Deep's place is considered secure after his performance at the Gabba.</li></ul><blockquote>“They can’t drop Nitish Kumar Reddy. He is the fourth seamer. I can’t see India going in with just two pacers and Nitish. For me, it is pretty much this XI that plays in Melbourne,” - Sunil Gavaskar.</blockquote><p>The upcoming Boxing Day Test is crucial for India's chances in the series, with significant discussions around player formations and their potential impacts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/sunil-gavaskar-explains-why-india-should-not-drop-nitish-reddy-for-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116656047.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/sunil-gavaskar-explains-why-india-should-not-drop-nitish-reddy-for-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116656047.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saim Ayub, Salman Agha rise in ICC ODI rankings - The Express Tribune]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saim Ayub, Agha Salman rise in ICC ODI rankings</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Express Tribune</p><img src="https://i.tribune.com.pk/media/thumbs/logo-tribune1588976358-0-450x300.webp" alt="saim ayub and salman agha put on 141 for the fifth wicket photo afp" title="saim ayub and salman agha put on 141 for the fifth wicket photo afp"><figcaption>Saim Ayub and Salman Agha put on 141 for the fifth wicket. Photo: AFP</figcaption><p>Pakistan’s cricketers Agha Salman and Saim Ayub have made significant progress in the latest ICC ODI rankings, following their remarkable performances in recent matches.</p><ul><li>Saim Ayub climbed 57 places to secure the 23rd position with 603 points, awarded Player of the Series against South Africa.</li><li>Agha Salman moved up 28 places to claim the 80th position with 468 points, showcasing his growing importance to the team.</li><li>Babar Azam retained his position as the world’s top-ranked batter for the fourth consecutive year.</li><li>Naseem Shah jumped 10 places in the ODI bowling rankings to the 51st spot.</li><li>Saim Ayub became one of few cricketers to score three ODI centuries before turning 23.</li></ul><blockquote>Saim now has his sights set on climbing even further, as the Champions Trophy approaches in February and the upcoming ODI series against New Zealand in March offers him more opportunities.</blockquote><p>The latest ICC rankings highlight the continued evolution of Pakistan’s cricketing talents, with emerging stars like Saim Ayub and Agha Salman complementing seasoned players like Babar Azam.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tribune.com.pk/story/2518166/saim-ayub-agha-salman-rise-in-icc-odi-rankings</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tribune.com.pk/story/2518166/saim-ayub-agha-salman-rise-in-icc-odi-rankings</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:10:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Won't Be Surprised If...": Pat Cummins' Big Verdict On MCG Pitch For 4th Test Against India - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pat Cummins Discusses MCG Pitch Ahead of Boxing Day Test Against India</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vq7bbk3_asc_625x300_25_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="&quot;Won't Be Surprised If...&quot;: Pat Cummins' Big Verdict On MCG Pitch For 4th Test Against India">
<figcaption>Pat Cummins discusses the pitch conditions at MCG.</figcaption>
<p>Australian cricket captain Pat Cummins shared thoughts on the Melbourne Cricket Ground pitch ahead of the crucial fourth Test against India, highlighting its suitability for spinners and good condition.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The MCG pitch appears 'nice and firm' with some grass coverage.</li>
  <li>Both teams are tied 1-1 in the series heading into the Boxing Day Test.</li>
  <li>Cummins praised the curators for maintaining pitch quality over the years.</li>
  <li>Bowling may be challenging due to high temperatures reaching 39 degrees Celsius.</li>
  <li>He expressed confidence in spinner Nathan Lyon’s performance on this pitch.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Pitch looks really good, quite consistent... a bit of grass coverage, feels nice and firm.” - Pat Cummins</blockquote>
<p>This Test is crucial for both teams as they vie for a lead going into the ICC World Test Championship final consideration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/wont-be-surprised-if-pat-cummins-big-verdict-on-mcg-pitch-for-4th-test-against-india-7326916</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/wont-be-surprised-if-pat-cummins-big-verdict-on-mcg-pitch-for-4th-test-against-india-7326916</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anushka Sharma, Virat Kohli Get Out On Christmas Date After R Ashwin's Cryptic Comment About Their PDA - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli Enjoy Christmas Date Amid R Ashwin's Comments</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli are on a date." title="Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli are on a date."><figcaption>Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli are on a date.</figcaption></figure><p>Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli were spotted on a date on Christmas Day in Australia. The couple was seen enjoying a casual day out in Melbourne, sans their children.</p><ul><li>Anushka and Virat walked through Melbourne streets on Christmas Day.</li><li>They dressed casually and appeared to enjoy a quick snack together.</li><li>The couple is in Australia for Virat’s cricket schedule, with a match scheduled for December 26.</li><li>R Ashwin recently made a cryptic comment regarding Virat's on-field PDA during an interview.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’m never a serious person... a lot of who I am got diluted in the fact of what I’ve become.” - R Ashwin</blockquote><p>The couple has not yet publicly responded to Ashwin's remarks. They recently celebrated their wedding anniversary privately.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/anushka-sharma-virat-kohli-get-out-on-christmas-date-after-r-ashwins-cryptic-comment-about-their-pda-9167910.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/anushka-sharma-virat-kohli-get-out-on-christmas-date-after-r-ashwins-cryptic-comment-about-their-pda-9167910.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:53:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["You can't drop a player who saved you from follow-on": Sunil Gavaskar reacts to Team India's likely changes in the fourth Test against Australia - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gavaskar's Stance on Team India Changes for Fourth Test Against Australia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Crictoday</p><figure><img width="1200" height="675" src="https://crictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Sunil-Gavaskar.webp" alt="Sunil Gavaskar"><figcaption>Sunil Gavaskar has rejected such stories, saying the team management can't remove a player who saved a follow-on in the third Test.</figcaption></figure><p>Sunil Gavaskar expresses his disbelief at reports suggesting Akash Deep may be replaced in the fourth Test against Australia, emphasizing the importance of players who deliver in critical moments.</p><ul><li>India's cricket team is contemplating changes ahead of the fourth Test against Australia.</li><li>Gavaskar argues against dropping Akash Deep, who played a crucial role in avoiding a follow-on in the previous match.</li><li>The series is currently tied at 1-1, heightening the stakes for the remaining matches.</li><li>Comments on the potential inclusion of Ravindra Jadeja and Washington Sundar, depending on pitch conditions.</li><li>Gavaskar is against India playing with only two seamers, suggesting the retention of their current bowling lineup.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is highly unlikely that Harshit will replace Akash Deep. Why would you drop a player who saved you from follow-on in the previous Test?”</blockquote><p>The former cricketer believes in maintaining a consistent team structure to ensure the best possible performance as India seeks to win the series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://crictoday.com/cricket/daily-cricket-news/you-cant-drop-a-player-who-saved-you-from-follow-on-sunil-gavaskar-reacts-to-team-indias-likely-changes-in-the-fourth-test-against-australia/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crictoday.com/cricket/daily-cricket-news/you-cant-drop-a-player-who-saved-you-from-follow-on-sunil-gavaskar-reacts-to-team-indias-likely-changes-in-the-fourth-test-against-australia/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:42:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan's schedule for ICC Champions Trophy 2025, Men in Green to take on India on... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan's ICC Champions Trophy 2025 Schedule: Key Matches Against India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/big-chance-of-pakistan-202412-1735126592.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Big chance of Pakistan">
<figcaption><p>Image credit: X</p><h2>Big chance of Pakistan</h2><p>Pakistan is bracing itself to be the venue of an ICC Championship after an extensive gap of 28 years. Fans are spirited about the anticipated return of the Champions Trophy which hasn't taken place for the last 8 years.</p></figcaption>
<p>Pakistan's national cricket team is set for an exciting schedule in the ICC Champions Trophy 2025, highlighted by a highly anticipated match against India.</p>
<ul>
<li>Pakistan's opening game will be against New Zealand on February 19 in Karachi.</li>
<li>The much-awaited match against India will be on February 23 in Dubai.</li>
<li>Pakistan's last group game will be against Bangladesh on February 27 in Rawalpindi.</li>
<li>This tournament marks the first time Pakistan will host the event in nearly three decades.</li>
<li>Pakistan heads into the tournament as the defending champions, having won the title in 2017 against India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>"Heading into the tournament as the current victors from their 2017 title win over India, Pakistan is all set to show its prowess once again."</p></blockquote>
<p>The ICC Champions Trophy 2025 is generating excitement among cricket fans worldwide, and Pakistan's performance will be closely watched as they strive to defend their title.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/pakistans-schedule-for-icc-champions-trophy-2025-men-in-green-to-take-on-india-on-416266/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/pakistans-schedule-for-icc-champions-trophy-2025-men-in-green-to-take-on-india-on-416266/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:40:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Father of ex-India cricketer, who made debut with R Ashwin, sentenced to 7 years in embezzlement case - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/father-of-ex-india-cricketer-naman-ojha-who-made-debut-with-r-ashwin-sentenced-to-7-years-embezzlement-case-101735123296690.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/father-of-ex-india-cricketer-naman-ojha-who-made-debut-with-r-ashwin-sentenced-to-7-years-embezzlement-case-101735123296690.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:13:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boxing Day Test Weather Forecast: Rain Drama Likely On These Days - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Boxing Day Test Weather Forecast: Rain Drama Likely On These Days</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rg655neo_mcg_625x300_25_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Boxing Day Test Weather Forecast: Rain Drama Likely On These Days"><figcaption>The weather is most likely to remain clear in Melbourne during the five days of the Test. © AFP</figcaption><p>The Boxing Day Test between India and Australia begins on December 26 at the Melbourne Cricket Ground with weather forecasts suggesting generally clear conditions, though some rain is expected on the third and fourth days.</p><ul><li>The series is currently tied at 1-1 after three Tests.</li><li>India is expected to make strategic changes to their lineup, introducing new players while adjusting batting order.</li><li>Australia has also confirmed their playing XI with two changes due to injuries.</li><li>There is a 25% chance of rain on Days 3 and 4, while the overall weather remains hot and humid.</li></ul><blockquote>“The 19-year-old Konstas will become Australia's youngest Test debutant since Cummins took the field against South Africa at Johannesburg in 2011.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the weather plays a crucial role in the Boxing Day Test, and teams will be watching closely for any changes that could impact play.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/boxing-day-test-weather-forecast-rain-drama-likely-on-these-days-of-mcg-test-7328875</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/boxing-day-test-weather-forecast-rain-drama-likely-on-these-days-of-mcg-test-7328875</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:00:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ashwin decodes Travis Head's masterplan against Jasprit Bumrah and Co. ahead of Boxing Day Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashwin decodes Travis Head's masterplan against Jasprit Bumrah and Co. ahead of Boxing Day Test</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Not specified</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116654254,imgsize-40706,width-400,resizemode-4/116654254.jpg" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin and Travis Head. (Pic Credit - X)" title="Ravichandran Ashwin and Travis Head. (Pic Credit - X)"><figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin and Travis Head. (Pic Credit - X)</figcaption><p>Former Indian spinner Ravichandran Ashwin analyzed Travis Head's strategies to counter Jasprit Bumrah and the Indian bowling attack during the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Ashwin highlights Head's clever use of crease and footwork to neutralize Bumrah's pace.</li><li>Head has performed outstandingly, including two centuries, contributing to Australia's win in the series.</li><li>Despite his success, Head has vulnerabilities against fast bowlers from around the wicket.</li><li>Head is confirmed fit for the upcoming Boxing Day Test after recovering from a quad injury.</li></ul><blockquote>"Omg! He is getting to the off stump? Is that the ploy for round the stumps?" - Ravichandran Ashwin on Head's practice sessions.</blockquote><p>Travis Head's ability to adjust his techniques signifies his preparation for the challenging matches ahead, marking him as a pivotal player for Australia in the series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ashwin-decodes-travis-heads-masterplan-against-jasprit-bumrah-and-co-ahead-of-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116654287.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ashwin-decodes-travis-heads-masterplan-against-jasprit-bumrah-and-co-ahead-of-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116654287.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MS Dhoni turns Santa for Sakshi and Ziva, fans can’t stop gushing: ‘Thalaclaus’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MS Dhoni, dressed up as Santa Claus, delighted fans worldwide with the heartwarming moment captured with his family.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 25, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/dhoni_1735121881781_1735121891845.jpg" alt="Sakshi shared images of MS Dhoni dressed as Santa, with daughter Ziva(Instagram/sakshisingh_r)" title="Sakshi shared images of MS Dhoni dressed as Santa, with daughter Ziva(Instagram/sakshisingh_r)"><figcaption>Sakshi shared images of MS Dhoni dressed as Santa, with daughter Ziva(Instagram/sakshisingh_r)</figcaption><p>In a heartwarming gesture this Christmas, cricket legend MS Dhoni brought festive joy by dressing up as Santa Claus alongside his family, a moment shared by his wife Sakshi on Instagram.</p><ul><li>Dhoni was seen with his daughter Ziva and wife Sakshi, in front of a beautifully decorated Christmas tree.</li><li>The post became a sensation, with fans expressing their excitement and admiration through comments filled with heart emojis.</li><li>Many fans described Dhoni as 'Thalaclaus' in their responses.</li><li>A previous viral video showed Dhoni performing a traditional dance with Sakshi in Rishikesh, offering fans a glimpse into his personal life.</li></ul><blockquote>“He turned a Santa for his daughter, Awwww.”</blockquote><p>The festive moment has resonated with fans, showcasing Dhoni's charming side as he embraces the Christmas spirit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/ms-turns-santa-for-sakshi-and-ziva-dhoni-fans-can-t-stop-gushing-thalaclaus-101735121243647.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/ms-turns-santa-for-sakshi-and-ziva-dhoni-fans-can-t-stop-gushing-thalaclaus-101735121243647.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:24:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arjun Tendulkar overcomes setback, reaches first career milestone weeks after being dropped from Goa team - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arjun Tendulkar Achieves First Milestone in Cricket After Recent Setback</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 25, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/Mumbai-Indians--Arjun-Tendulkar-at-the-Wankhede-St_1682080363356_1735120491508.jpg" alt="Arjun Tendulkar at the Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai(HT_PRINT)" title="Arjun Tendulkar at the Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai(HT_PRINT)">
<figcaption>Arjun Tendulkar at the Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai(HT_PRINT)</figcaption>
<p>Weeks after being dropped from Goa's Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy squad, Arjun Tendulkar achieved his first career milestone as a bowler, picking three wickets against Odisha in the ongoing Vijay Hazare Trophy match and completing 50 wickets in white-ball cricket.</p>
<ul>
<li>Arjun Tendulkar picked three wickets in a crucial match.</li>
<li>He reached the milestone of 50 wickets in white-ball cricket.</li>
<li>The left-handed fast bowler made his T20 debut for Mumbai in 2021.</li>
<li>He has achieved 51 wickets in 41 white-ball games.</li>
<li>Arjun faced a setback being dropped from the Goa team after poor performances.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Arjun suffered a major setback earlier this month, when he was dropped from the Goa cricket team for the remaining matches of the Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy 2024.”</blockquote>
<p>Arjun Tendulkar's journey showcases resilience and determination, highlighting his potential to bounce back stronger in his cricketing career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/arjun-tendulkar-overcomes-setback-first-career-milestone-after-being-dropped-from-goa-team-vijay-hazare-trophy-101735120384463.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/arjun-tendulkar-overcomes-setback-first-career-milestone-after-being-dropped-from-goa-team-vijay-hazare-trophy-101735120384463.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:16:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five must-watch matches at the ICC Champions Trophy 2025 - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Five Must-Watch Matches at the ICC Champions Trophy 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>The ICC Champions Trophy returns on 19 February 2025 after eight years, featuring 15 thrilling matches over 19 days. Here are five exciting match-ups to look forward to:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Pakistan v India, Dubai (23 February)</strong> - This iconic rivalry sees Pakistan leading in Champions Trophy history, though recent performances favor India.</li>
<li><strong>Australia v South Africa, Rawalpindi (25 February)</strong> - Following a dramatic semi-final, this encounter promises high stakes and fierce competition.</li>
<li><strong>Afghanistan v Australia, Lahore (28 February)</strong> - Afghanistan aims to build on their T20 success against the Australians in this ODI clash.</li>
<li><strong>South Africa v England, Karachi (1 March)</strong> - Featuring two teams with rich talent, this match is expected to be a showcase of competitive cricket.</li>
<li><strong>New Zealand v India, Dubai (2 March)</strong> - A rematch where India recently bested New Zealand, setting the stage for another thrilling face-off.</li>
</ul>
<p>Fans are eagerly awaiting these matches as they promise to be filled with excitement and high-performance cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/champions-trophy-2025/news/five-must-watch-matches-at-the-icc-champions-trophy-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/champions-trophy-2025/news/five-must-watch-matches-at-the-icc-champions-trophy-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:08:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>