<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 21:20:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 21:20:13 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk, Sundar Pichai react to Jasprit Bumrah's 'Google it' remark on his batting skills - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk and Sundar Pichai React to Jasprit Bumrah's 'Google It' Remark</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/X_Viral_Chandrayaan_3_Sundar_Pichai_Elon_Musk_1692882157808_1734460724345.png" alt="Sundar Pichai and Elon Musk responded to the viral video of Jasprit Bumrah.(Reuters)" title="Sundar Pichai and Elon Musk responded to the viral video of Jasprit Bumrah.(Reuters)"><figcaption>Sundar Pichai and Elon Musk responded to the viral video of Jasprit Bumrah.(Reuters)</figcaption></figure><p>After Jasprit Bumrah's witty remark about his batting, Google CEO Sundar Pichai praised him on X, while Elon Musk added a brief compliment.</p><ul><li>Jasprit Bumrah humorously suggested that a journalist should use Google to assess his batting skills.</li><li>Sundar Pichai praised Bumrah's batting performance, referencing a specific instance of his ability.</li><li>Elon Musk responded positively to Pichai's compliment.</li><li>Pichai suggested they watch a cricket match together in the future.</li></ul><blockquote>“I did Google it. Anyone who can hook Cummins for a six knows how to bat!” – Sundar Pichai</blockquote><p>This exchange highlights the intersection of sports, technology, and celebrity, showcasing how public figures engage with culture.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/elon-musk-sundar-pichai-react-to-jasprit-bumrah-use-google-remark-on-batting-prowess-101734432140958.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/elon-musk-sundar-pichai-react-to-jasprit-bumrah-use-google-remark-on-batting-prowess-101734432140958.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 19:01:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sanju Samson excluded from Kerala’s Vijay Hazare Trophy squad after not attending camp - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sanju Samson Excluded from Kerala’s Vijay Hazare Trophy Squad</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 12, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/10/samson_fd9082.jpg?w=640" alt="Sanju Samson" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>India's Sanju Samson during a practice session before the third and final T20 International cricket match between India and Bangladesh.</figcaption><p>India's wicket-keeper Sanju Samson has been left out of Kerala's squad for the upcoming Vijay Hazare Trophy after failing to attend the team's preparatory camp.</p><ul><li>Samson led Kerala to a third-place finish in the Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy but did not report for the subsequent team camp.</li><li>The squad was formed after a brief camp in Wayanad, which Samson missed due to an email stating his unavailability.</li><li>Salman Nizar will captain the team in Samson's absence.</li><li>Samson's last 50-over game was during India's tour of South Africa in December 2023, where he scored an unbeaten century.</li></ul><blockquote>“Sanju had sent an email stating that he would not be available for the camp. Naturally, we only considered those who were part of the sessions for selection.” - Vinod S Kumar, KCA Secretary</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Sanju Samson's absence from the camp has resulted in his exclusion from the upcoming tournament, with the team moving forward with new leadership under Salman Nizar.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/sanju-samson-excluded-kerala-vijay-hazare-trophy-squad-9730668/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/sanju-samson-excluded-kerala-vijay-hazare-trophy-squad-9730668/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:50:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man Utd release Alejandro Garnacho statement as star follows Cristiano Ronaldo's footsteps - Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxQSkZ3UTU2d3pORGVpaDVDVWJucVczQU9hSVRPUk1PWlAxY2xUMVlCYkxSeVYyNHltcVM4WmxaNkpMb3VBZ2toRlVJRkxJTVI2TWRpX1J6cjZvc3lENXJlWVBieEZMS3FtU3BkSXRHREx4R1RMUmlkcEhKRldMSTllWGZLYWF4aG9wQjM4SFJDWHoxeW84WkJzSmtMdmNuZ1pzbmZQY1VGajlSVzZBaXFoWNIBtgFBVV95cUxQSXJ3d29vcmFfcmpwNWY3ODRuWE1CZG9TM0J4SEViUXA4Y1FJQVdqTGJfbXFUZ29PQkxiV3pGWm9NdmhSQUlnUjExQ0ZQdnFzOEpVUUtxRDM2UGlzMGRYLV8tUHB4eXVReC1CN1QxSXNrY3hvaTJSZFZWci1LVmJMcnBVVHlNODY2cXBGcElwbm8zZGotdWl1OEFVR1dWN1k1dVhHbzN0RHJ3U2ctX3I5b3RjTW95dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxQSkZ3UTU2d3pORGVpaDVDVWJucVczQU9hSVRPUk1PWlAxY2xUMVlCYkxSeVYyNHltcVM4WmxaNkpMb3VBZ2toRlVJRkxJTVI2TWRpX1J6cjZvc3lENXJlWVBieEZMS3FtU3BkSXRHREx4R1RMUmlkcEhKRldMSTllWGZLYWF4aG9wQjM4SFJDWHoxeW84WkJzSmtMdmNuZ1pzbmZQY1VGajlSVzZBaXFoWNIBtgFBVV95cUxQSXJ3d29vcmFfcmpwNWY3ODRuWE1CZG9TM0J4SEViUXA4Y1FJQVdqTGJfbXFUZ29PQkxiV3pGWm9NdmhSQUlnUjExQ0ZQdnFzOEpVUUtxRDM2UGlzMGRYLV8tUHB4eXVReC1CN1QxSXNrY3hvaTJSZFZWci1LVmJMcnBVVHlNODY2cXBGcElwbm8zZGotdWl1OEFVR1dWN1k1dVhHbzN0RHJ3U2ctX3I5b3RjTW95dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rs 5 crore award for Gukesh! Tamil Nadu CM felicitates World Chess Champion - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rs 5 crore award for Gukesh! Tamil Nadu CM felicitates World Chess Champion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Tamil Nadu's Chief Minister has honored chess prodigy Gukesh D for his remarkable victory in the World Chess Championship, presenting him with a generous award of Rs 5 crore.</p><ul><li>Gukesh D emerged as a global champion, showcasing exceptional skill.</li><li>The state government acknowledged his achievement by offering financial support as a token of appreciation.</li><li>This accolade highlights the rising popularity of chess in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“This award is a testament to Gukesh's dedication and brilliance in chess,” said the Chief Minister.</blockquote><p>The event underscores India's growing prominence in the chess world, celebrating young talents who are making significant strides.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/chess/rs-5-crore-award-for-gukesh-tamil-nadu-cm-felicitates-world-chess-champion/articleshow/116407901.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/chess/rs-5-crore-award-for-gukesh-tamil-nadu-cm-felicitates-world-chess-champion/articleshow/116407901.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 16:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai Techie, 31, Dies Of Heart Attack While Playing Cricket - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Techie, 31, Dies Of Heart Attack While Playing Cricket</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent News</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img title="Mumbai Techie, 31, Dies Of Heart Attack While Playing Cricket" alt="Mumbai Techie, 31, Dies Of Heart Attack While Playing Cricket" src="https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/cricket-generic_650x400_51505906667.jpg"><figcaption>Vikram Ashok Deshmukh collapsed during a cricket match.</figcaption><p>A 31-year-old software engineer, Vikram Ashok Deshmukh, tragically passed away due to a heart attack while playing cricket in Mumbai.</p><ul><li>Deshmukh was playing a 25-over practice match at Azad Maidan.</li><li>He complained of chest pain in the 10th over but continued playing.</li><li>He collapsed after taking a run in the 17th over and was later pronounced dead in the hospital.</li><li>He is survived by his wife, parents, and a one-year-old son.</li><li>The police have filed an Accidental Death Report and initiated an investigation.</li></ul><blockquote>“He collapsed during the game and could not be revived,” said a witness.</blockquote><p>This unfortunate incident highlights the unpredictability of health emergencies, even during seemingly regular activities like sports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/mumbai-techie-31-dies-of-heart-attack-while-playing-cricket-7271421</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/mumbai-techie-31-dies-of-heart-attack-while-playing-cricket-7271421</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:53:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ancelotti talks Mbappe, Vinicius, criticism, January plans ahead of Real Madrid vs Pachuca - Madrid Universal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOeHM1UEVVZUdZc1RFb3cxNWlRUDZOVWJpbFVZcjF5TGlyZXNIQzVreXFKT0s5QXlyOW5SWDRhNVN2RE1uZU5xdXFTYzVIbjM4MVdGY0VtU1ZkNUIzV2M4eUhyX3Z0MGJ5TVFQY2pUUmhFWXR0U01pSU1JdEhZUXk4ZDFWQjQ3QkctZXhhUUMyVExXM2JCcEFUN0dJeGlmVm5fWFRQRWlHeWZSZmFEU2lvdUtITVFmM28?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOeHM1UEVVZUdZc1RFb3cxNWlRUDZOVWJpbFVZcjF5TGlyZXNIQzVreXFKT0s5QXlyOW5SWDRhNVN2RE1uZU5xdXFTYzVIbjM4MVdGY0VtU1ZkNUIzV2M4eUhyX3Z0MGJ5TVFQY2pUUmhFWXR0U01pSU1JdEhZUXk4ZDFWQjQ3QkctZXhhUUMyVExXM2JCcEFUN0dJeGlmVm5fWFRQRWlHeWZSZmFEU2lvdUtITVFmM28?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:47:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google comes up with a witty reply to Jasprit Bumrah’s 'search it' remark - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Google Delivers a Clever Comeback to Jasprit Bumrah’s 'Search It' Comment</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116407103,imgsize-42578,width-400,resizemode-4/116407103.jpg" alt="Google comes up with a witty reply to Jasprit Bumrah’s 'search it' remark" title="Jasprit Bumrah. (Pic Credit - X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah. (Pic Credit - X)</figcaption>
<p>The article discusses a humorous exchange between Indian cricketer Jasprit Bumrah and Google, sparked by Bumrah's cheeky remark during a press conference about his batting skills.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jasprit Bumrah made a light-hearted comment regarding his batting prowess, urging the reporter to 'search it' on Google.</li>
<li>The banter occurred after Bumrah's notable performance where he helped India avoid a follow-on in a match against Australia.</li>
<li>Google responded humorously on their X platform, elevating the playful interaction.</li>
<li>The moment quickly gained traction on social media, showcasing Bumrah's blend of skill and humor.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“But, you are questioning my batting ability. You should use Google and see who has got the most number of runs in a Test over.” - Jasprit Bumrah</blockquote>
<p>This exchange illustrates how Bumrah's personality resonates with fans, while also demonstrating the engaging nature of social media interactions between public figures and tech companies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/google-comes-up-with-a-witty-reply-to-jasprit-bumrahs-search-it-remark/articleshow/116407133.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/google-comes-up-with-a-witty-reply-to-jasprit-bumrahs-search-it-remark/articleshow/116407133.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli Goes Through Many Emotions As India Avoid Follow-On In 3rd Australia Test - Video Is Vir.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli Goes Through Many Emotions As India Avoid Follow-On In 3rd Australia Test - Video Is Viral</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/sacb4i9_virat-kohli_625x300_17_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Virat Kohli Goes Through Many Emotions As India Avoid Follow-On In 3rd Australia Test - Video Is Viral" pinger-seen="true"><figcaption>Virat Kohli reacts during India's last wicket stand. © X/Twitter</figcaption><p>This article covers India's tense final session on Day 4 of the third Test against Australia, where a critical 10th-wicket partnership helped India avoid a follow-on, highlighting Kohli's emotional response to the moment.</p><ul><li>Jasprit Bumrah and Akash Deep formed a resilient 10th-wicket partnership to thwart Australia.</li><li>The partnership ensured India did not have to bat again immediately, with the match heading towards a draw.</li><li>Virat Kohli displayed a range of emotions captured in a viral video during the match.</li><li>KL Rahul praised the effort of the lower-order batsmen, emphasizing its importance in the match.</li><li>The five-match series is currently tied at 1-1.</li></ul><blockquote>“To avoid that follow-on makes a huge difference.” - KL Rahul</blockquote><p>India displayed great resilience, showcasing their determination in a match that will likely influence the rest of the series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/virat-kohli-goes-through-many-emotions-as-india-avoid-follow-on-in-3rd-australia-test-video-is-viral-7269536</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/virat-kohli-goes-through-many-emotions-as-india-avoid-follow-on-in-3rd-australia-test-video-is-viral-7269536</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:34:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 4 Highlights: IND 252/9 vs AUS at stumps in Brisbane - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 4 Highlights: IND 252/9 vs AUS at stumps in Brisbane</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Tuesday, Publication: Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/India-vs-Australia_3rd-Test_Day-4.jpg?w=750" alt="India vs Australia 3rd Test Live" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>India vs Australia 3rd Test Live: Day 4 action is upon us from Gabba.</figcaption><p>After Day 4 of the third Test at Gabba, India scored 252/9, avoiding follow-on against Australia. KL Rahul and Ravindra Jadeja made significant contributions to keep the match competitive.</p><ul><li>India trails by 193 runs but has crossed the 246 run mark, preventing Australia from enforcing a follow-on.</li><li>Josh Hazlewood is out of the Test due to injury.</li><li>The series stands at 1-1 after India won the first Test and Australia claimed victory in Adelaide.</li></ul><blockquote>“Raining Indian wickets at Gabba” - A difficult day for Indian batters.</blockquote><p>The match remains open for a draw as India seeks to recover in the ongoing series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/india-vs-australia-3rd-test-day-4-live-cricket-score-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-gabba-brisbane-weather-9728501/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/india-vs-australia-3rd-test-day-4-live-cricket-score-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-gabba-brisbane-weather-9728501/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['He's done it for so many years': KL Rahul shows what India miss without Ravindra Jadeja in their Playing XI - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>KL Rahul Highlights Importance of Ravindra Jadeja in India's XI</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/KL_Rahul_Ravindra_Jadeja_1734445430726_1734445431016.jpg" alt="Ravindra Jadeja (L) and KL Rahul bump gloves between the overs on day four of the third cricket Test match between Australia and India.(AFP)"><figcaption>Ravindra Jadeja (L) and KL Rahul bump gloves between the overs on day four of the third cricket Test match between Australia and India.(AFP)</figcaption><p>In a recent cricket match, KL Rahul praised Ravindra Jadeja for his impressive batting performance that played a crucial role in India's innings during the Brisbane Test against Australia.</p><ul><li>Jadeja scored 77 runs off 123 balls, helping stabilize the innings after early wickets.</li><li>Rahul and Jadeja shared a vital 67-run stand for the sixth wicket.</li><li>Jadeja's contribution helped India avoid follow-on and set a competitive score.</li></ul><blockquote>“Jadeja was brilliant today. He has been brilliant batting down the order for us for many, many years,” said Rahul.</blockquote><p>Rahul emphasized that Jadeja’s consistent performance is key to India’s success, highlighting how he often delivers under pressure with not only his bowling but also his batting skills.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/kl-rahul-shows-what-india-miss-without-ravindra-jadeja-in-their-playing-xi-hes-done-it-for-so-many-years-101734444528184.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/kl-rahul-shows-what-india-miss-without-ravindra-jadeja-in-their-playing-xi-hes-done-it-for-so-many-years-101734444528184.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:53:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rain To Ruin Action-Packed Day 5 Of India vs Australia 3rd Test In Brisbane? Report Says... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rain To Ruin Action-Packed Day 5 Of India vs Australia 3rd Test In Brisbane? Report Says...</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fjb9s338_brisbane-rain_625x300_16_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Rain To Ruin Action-Packed Day 5 Of India vs Australia 3rd Test In Brisbane?" /><figcaption>Rain has impacted India vs Australia third Test in Brisbane. © AFP</figcaption><p>The third Test match between India and Australia at the Gabba is under threat from rain, with a high chance of showers expected on the final day of the match. India has put up a strong fight, but the weather may impact their chances of making a comeback.</p><ul><li>Australia's Bureau of Meteorology forecasts high chances of rain and possible severe thunderstorms on the last day.</li><li>India ended day four at 252/9, trailing by 193 runs, after notable performances from KL Rahul and Ravindra Jadeja.</li><li>KL Rahul expressed frustration over the interruptions due to the rain.</li><li>With the series tied at 1-1, this match's outcome is crucial.</li></ul><blockquote>“I think I got more tired running up and down from the dressing room than I did being in the middle.” - KL Rahul</blockquote><p>With rain looming, both teams face a challenging end to the match which could shift the momentum at a critical point in the series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rain-to-ruin-action-packed-day-5-of-india-vs-australia-3rd-test-in-brisbane-report-says-7270288</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rain-to-ruin-action-packed-day-5-of-india-vs-australia-3rd-test-in-brisbane-report-says-7270288</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:36:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Virat Kohli Stunned, Gautam Gambhir Delighted As Akash Deep Hits Pat Cummins For Mammoth Six - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watch: Virat Kohli Stunned, Gautam Gambhir Delighted As Akash Deep Hits Pat Cummins For Mammoth Six</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p><img src='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/eak4iih8_sda_625x300_17_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605' alt='Watch: Virat Kohli Stunned, Gautam Gambhir Delighted As Akash Deep Hits Pat Cummins For Mammoth Six'><figcaption>Virat Kohli was left stunned by Akash Deep's mammoth six.</figcaption><p>In an exhilarating moment during the third Test between India and Australia, Akash Deep hit a massive six off Pat Cummins, leaving Virat Kohli stunned and Gautam Gambhir delighted. This moment followed a pivotal partnership that helped India avoid a follow-on.</p><ul><li>Akash Deep hit a six over deep mid-wicket against Cummins.</li><li>The Indian dressing room celebrated avoiding follow-on after Deep's explosive hit.</li><li>Jadeja and Rahul contributed significantly with their fighting fifties.</li><li>The match is significantly affected by inclement weather and is leaning towards a draw.</li></ul><blockquote>"Rohit, Gambhir and Kohli's reaction on Akash deep six against Pat Cummins" — Kuljot (@Kuljot__)</blockquote><p>India's batting performance showcased resilience despite challenging conditions, with a close call caused by weather disruptions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/virat-kohli-stunned-gautam-gambhir-delighted-as-akash-deep-hits-pat-cummins-for-mammoth-six-watch-7268141</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/virat-kohli-stunned-gautam-gambhir-delighted-as-akash-deep-hits-pat-cummins-for-mammoth-six-watch-7268141</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:18:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravindra Jadeja refuses to be ignored after Gabba rescue act; Gambhir, Rohit forced to think twice before benching him - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravindra Jadeja once again proved to be India's crisis man, forcing the team management to think about their decision to bench him in SENA nations.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-148_1734444207715_1734444228642.jpg" alt="Three of Ravindra Jadeja's 4 Test centuries have come in last five years(AFP)"><figcaption>Three of Ravindra Jadeja's 4 Test centuries have come in last five years(AFP)</figcaption><p>Ravindra Jadeja showcased his pivotal role in the Indian cricket team at the Gabba, leading to a reevaluation of his status as a key player after previously being benched.</p><ul><li>Jadeja has been a part of the top six since October 2019, averaging 38.93 in 35 Tests.</li><li>He has shown a significant improvement in his batting, scoring three of his four Test centuries in the last five years.</li><li>His performance at the Gabba included a vital 77 runs contributing to India's follow-on efforts.</li><li>His batting style emphasizes patience and minimalism, focusing on the task rather than flamboyance.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am a Rajput but I can’t bring a sword to the ground, so I use my bat as a sword.”</blockquote><p>Jadeja's impressive performance reinforces his value to the team, making it clear that he cannot be sidelined again in future matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ravindra-jadeja-refuses-to-be-ignored-after-gabba-rescue-act-gambhir-rohit-forced-to-think-twice-before-benching-him-101734444082141.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ravindra-jadeja-refuses-to-be-ignored-after-gabba-rescue-act-gambhir-rohit-forced-to-think-twice-before-benching-him-101734444082141.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:09:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australian team to offer 'care and love,' Nathan Lyon remarks, as Josh Hazlewood is expected to miss rest - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australian team to offer 'care and love,' Nathan Lyon remarks, as Josh Hazlewood is expected to miss rest of series</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Time of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116404954,imgsize-42504,width-400,resizemode-4/116404954.jpg" alt="Nathon Lyon and Josh Hazlewood (PTI Photo)" title="Nathon Lyon and Josh Hazlewood (PTI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Nathon Lyon and Josh Hazlewood (PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>Josh Hazlewood is likely to be absent for the remaining Border-Gavaskar Trophy matches due to a right calf strain sustained during the third Test.</p><ul><li>Hazlewood's injury occurred at the Gabba, impacting Australia's bowling strength.</li><li>Nathan Lyon expressed concern, stating the team will support Hazlewood emotionally.</li><li>Cricket Australia confirmed Hazlewood's unavailability for the remainder of the series.</li><li>Assistant coach Daniel Vettori described Hazlewood as despondent, highlighting the difficult timing of the injury.</li><li>Scott Boland is expected to return to the playing eleven to replace Hazlewood.</li></ul><blockquote>“He's pretty flat, But we'll get around him, put our arm around him and show a bit of care and love for the big fella.” - Nathan Lyon</blockquote><p>The Australian team is rallying around Josh Hazlewood as he faces an extended period out due to injury, emphasizing the support and camaraderie within the squad.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/australian-team-to-offer-care-and-love-nathan-lyon-remarks-as-josh-hazlewood-is-expected-to-miss-rest-of-series/articleshow/116404538.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/australian-team-to-offer-care-and-love-nathan-lyon-remarks-as-josh-hazlewood-is-expected-to-miss-rest-of-series/articleshow/116404538.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shaw left out of Mumbai squad for start of Vijay Hazare Trophy - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prithvi Shaw Left Out of Mumbai Squad for Vijay Hazare Trophy</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Tue, Dec 17, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c588518/prithvi-shaw-has-been-left-out.jpg" alt="Prithvi Shaw has been left out of the Mumbai squad for the start of the Vijay Hazare Trophy">
<figcaption>Prithvi Shaw has been left out of the Mumbai squad for the start of the Vijay Hazare Trophy © BCCI/IPL</figcaption>
<p>Prithvi Shaw has been omitted from the Mumbai squad announced for the first three matches of the Vijay Hazare Trophy, drawing attention due to his impressive performance record.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shaw boasts an average of 55.72 from 65 List A matches and was integral to Mumbai's recent Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy victory.</li>
  <li>His exclusion sparked an emotional response on social media, expressing his determination to return.</li>
  <li>Captain Shreyas Iyer praised Shaw's talent but emphasized the need for improvement in work ethics.</li>
  <li>The selectors have opted for 17-year-old Ayush Mhatre and other players for the opening spot.</li>
  <li>Notable omissions from the squad include Rahane, Mohit Awasthi due to injury, and Shams Mulani.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Tell me god, what more do I have to see... if 65 innings, 3399 runs at an average of 55.7 with a strike rate of 126, I'm not good enough..." - Prithvi Shaw</blockquote>
<p>The Mumbai squad aims to kick off the Vijay Hazare Trophy without some experienced players, focusing on youth and potential.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132812/shaw-left-out-of-mumbai-squad-for-start-of-vijay-hazare-trophy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132812/shaw-left-out-of-mumbai-squad-for-start-of-vijay-hazare-trophy</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:34:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Responds After Jasprit Bumrah Mentions Tech Giant To Shut Down Tricky Question In Australia - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Google Responds To Jasprit Bumrah's Witty Reply During Test Match Press Conference</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 - <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/39psoq5_bumrah-google_625x300_17_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Google Responds After Jasprit Bumrah Mentions Tech Giant" /><figcaption>Google's playful reply to Jasprit Bumrah's comment.</figcaption><p>After an amusing press conference, Jasprit Bumrah cleverly responded to a reporter's challenging question about India's batting performance against Australia, prompting a light-hearted response from Google India.</p><ul><li>Bumrah was questioned about India's batting struggles after Day 3 of the Test match in Brisbane.</li><li>He humorously suggested the reporter check Google for batting statistics, highlighting his own record of 35 runs in an over.</li><li>Google India quoted Bumrah's comment in a social media post, stating, "I only believe in Jassi Bhai." </li><li>Bumrah leads the wicket tally in the ongoing Border Gavaskar Trophy with 18 wickets.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“I always look to solve it rather than complaining.” - Jasprit Bumrah</p></blockquote><p>This exchange not only showcases Bumrah's wit but also highlights the connection between sports and digital platforms in today’s media landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/google-responds-after-jasprit-bumrah-mentions-tech-giant-to-shut-down-tricky-question-in-australia-7270412</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/google-responds-after-jasprit-bumrah-mentions-tech-giant-to-shut-down-tricky-question-in-australia-7270412</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:32:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prithvi Shaw dropped from Mumbai squad for Vijay Hazare Trophy - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Prithvi Shaw Dropped from Mumbai Squad for Vijay Hazare Trophy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p>Prithvi Shaw has been dropped from the Mumbai squad for the Vijay Hazare Trophy amid concerns regarding his form and fitness.</p><ul><li>Ajinkya Rahane, top scorer in the SMAT, has been rested at his request.</li><li>Shaw's performance has been under scrutiny after failing to score a half-century in nine innings.</li><li>Shaw surprised by his exclusion and expressed frustration on social media.</li><li>Shreyas Iyer emphasizes that players must maintain a strong work ethic.</li></ul><blockquote>“He needs to get his work ethics right, and if he does that, the sky is the limit for him,” - Shreyas Iyer</blockquote><p>The Mumbai squad looks strong with key players returning, but Shaw's absence raises questions about his future in the team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/prithvi-shaw-dropped-from-mumbai-squad-for-vijay-hazare-trophy-1465550</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/prithvi-shaw-dropped-from-mumbai-squad-for-vijay-hazare-trophy-1465550</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:55:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunil Gavaskar Fumes At Mohammed Siraj's 'Risky' Act, Questions His 'Cricketing Awareness' - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunil Gavaskar Fumes At Mohammed Siraj's 'Risky' Act, Questions His 'Cricketing Awareness'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/dee8hpi_sad_625x300_17_December_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Sunil Gavaskar Fumes At Mohammed Siraj's 'Risky' Act, Questions His 'Cricketing Awareness'"><figcaption>Sunil Gavaskar Fumes At Mohammed Siraj's 'Risky' Act</figcaption><p>Legendary Indian cricket team skipper Sunil Gavaskar expressed his frustration towards Mohammed Siraj after a mix-up during a critical moment in the third Test against Australia.</p><ul><li>Siraj walked in at No. 9 with India needing runs to avoid follow-on.</li><li>A mix-up occurred when Siraj took a risky single, prompting concern from Gavaskar.</li><li>Gavaskar questioned Siraj's cricketing awareness during such an important phase of the game.</li><li>India managed to avoid follow-on thanks to a solid 10th-wicket partnership between Jasprit Bumrah and Akash Deep.</li><li>The match is currently tied in the five-match series at 1-1.</li></ul><blockquote>"Look at that. There's got to be some cricketing awareness. You are a no.9 batter. You cannot think of taking risky singles," said Gavaskar.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the pressure of Test cricket and the need for strategic thinking in crucial moments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/sunil-gavaskar-fumes-at-mohammed-sirajs-risky-act-questions-his-cricketing-awareness-7269146</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/sunil-gavaskar-fumes-at-mohammed-sirajs-risky-act-questions-his-cricketing-awareness-7269146</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:54:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google delivers million-dollar reply to Jasprit Bumrah's 'search it' remark flaunting his batting skills - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Google delivers million-dollar reply to Jasprit Bumrah's 'search it' remark flaunting his batting skills</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/Jasprit_Bumrah_Akash_Deep_1734439029472_1734439029800.jpg" alt="India's Akash Deep, left, fist bumps with batting partner Jasprit Bumrah during play on day four of the third cricket test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane.(AP)">
<figcaption>India's Akash Deep, left, fist bumps with batting partner Jasprit Bumrah during play on day four of the third cricket test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane.(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Jasprit Bumrah showcased his batting skills in a crucial moment for India during the third Test against Australia, helping his team avoid a follow-on with an unbeaten score. His performance drew attention and a witty response from Google India.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bumrah scored an unbeaten 10 runs, contributing to a critical 39-run partnership for the 10th wicket.</li>
  <li>His batting skills are highlighted by his record of the most runs in an over in Test history, with 35 runs off Stuart Broad.</li>
  <li>Rahul and Jadeja also played significant roles in India's fightback, scoring 84 and 77 runs, respectively.</li>
  <li>Google India humorously responded to Bumrah’s press conference comments after his batting performance.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It's an interesting question. But, you are questioning my batting ability. You should use Google and see who has got the most number of runs in a Test over.” - Jasprit Bumrah</blockquote>
<p>This match showcased Bumrah's all-round capabilities and highlighted the ongoing series dynamics, where he has also excelled as a bowler.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/google-delivers-million-dollar-reply-to-jasprit-bumrah-search-it-remark-flaunting-his-batting-skills-101734437833376.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/google-delivers-million-dollar-reply-to-jasprit-bumrah-search-it-remark-flaunting-his-batting-skills-101734437833376.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:49:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[European Super League returns with new twist as Manchester United and Man City watch on - Manchester Evening News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNeU5TdFVydDMwcW9sTWZqanZJRTltS3c0bTZOanFkUXp6bW83c0o5MUJHR25XN1NFQjFaV2R0eUVMQ3RoMjR5TEtXSTl6T01FSF94aFNQV05Tdm16OTRXcEMxa0hWZE1xaTBmWW9CY3lLU3h1SmJoQlFUcFU5YUdZdWc5c0dZOXI4blpiRnp6dU90bE9YVGl3ZkU1YWtrdngyVE1YMzdrVkpPd2o0eGZHTNIBtgFBVV95cUxNWXFRM256cjFnMzFsVW0xTHBCSk9zQTNxazJERkxSRW9XdWY5UlhKWloxb1F5VGdzY0JGbktDOHVHbGVzbDV2UkZ3b0NTbTFnNXVkVEM3d3k2RWhTcnc5TUFoUW54X2lxNVpnLUNHUmFxUkFMU3JPeFZwYl8ybjFHUlZXQm9lUWNGR0trZ1NCc3J6Wk4zMzNsS3JFUmMzdGd2cTEwRlk5cXJMQi1tNDZIYi1UWkF3dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxNeU5TdFVydDMwcW9sTWZqanZJRTltS3c0bTZOanFkUXp6bW83c0o5MUJHR25XN1NFQjFaV2R0eUVMQ3RoMjR5TEtXSTl6T01FSF94aFNQV05Tdm16OTRXcEMxa0hWZE1xaTBmWW9CY3lLU3h1SmJoQlFUcFU5YUdZdWc5c0dZOXI4blpiRnp6dU90bE9YVGl3ZkU1YWtrdngyVE1YMzdrVkpPd2o0eGZHTNIBtgFBVV95cUxNWXFRM256cjFnMzFsVW0xTHBCSk9zQTNxazJERkxSRW9XdWY5UlhKWloxb1F5VGdzY0JGbktDOHVHbGVzbDV2UkZ3b0NTbTFnNXVkVEM3d3k2RWhTcnc5TUFoUW54X2lxNVpnLUNHUmFxUkFMU3JPeFZwYl8ybjFHUlZXQm9lUWNGR0trZ1NCc3J6Wk4zMzNsS3JFUmMzdGd2cTEwRlk5cXJMQi1tNDZIYi1UWkF3dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['What more do I have to see': Frustrated Mumbai batter Prithvi Shaw reacts after Vijay Hazare Trophy snub - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What more do I have to see: Frustrated Mumbai batter Prithvi Shaw reacts after Vijay Hazare Trophy snub</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Prithvi Shaw expressed his frustration regarding his exclusion from the Vijay Hazare Trophy squad, questioning what more he needs to do to be considered.</p><ul><li>Shaw has been performing consistently but feels overlooked.</li><li>The snub has raised questions among fans and analysts about team selection criteria.</li><li>He conveyed his sentiments on social media, highlighting his dedication and hard work.</li></ul><blockquote>“What more do I have to see?”</blockquote><p>The ongoing debates about team selection indicate a larger discussion about fairness and performance in cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/what-more-do-i-have-to-see-frustrated-mumbai-batter-prithvi-shaw-reacts-after-vijay-hazare-trophy-snub/articleshow/116402314.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/what-more-do-i-have-to-see-frustrated-mumbai-batter-prithvi-shaw-reacts-after-vijay-hazare-trophy-snub/articleshow/116402314.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When PV Sindhu, who got engaged to Venkata Datta Sai, revealed her idea of an ideal partner - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu Engaged: What She Looks for in an Ideal Partner</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 2024-12-22</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://example.com/image.jpg" alt="PV Sindhu Engagement" /><figcaption>PV Sindhu celebrating her engagement.</figcaption><p>PV Sindhu recently got engaged to Venkata Datta Sai, a Hyderabad-based IT professional. In her engagement announcement, she reflected on love and the qualities she seeks in a partner.</p><ul><li>Sindhu got engaged to Venkata Datta Sai, Executive Director at Posidex Technologies.</li><li>She expressed her thoughts on an ideal partner during a past interview, emphasizing the importance of understanding and a pure heart.</li><li>Friends and industry colleagues congratulated her on social media.</li><li>The couple plans to marry in December 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>“I want a person with a pure heart and a pure soul – someone who is very understanding because, for me, it’s not like I need a rich guy.” - PV Sindhu</blockquote><p>This engagement marks a significant milestone in Sindhu's personal life as she continues to focus on her career and relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/feelings/pv-sindhu-engaged-fiance-venkata-datta-sai-ideal-partner-9727320/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/feelings/pv-sindhu-engaged-fiance-venkata-datta-sai-ideal-partner-9727320/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:30:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Women vs West Indies Women Match Prediction - Who will win today’s 2nd T20I match between IND-W vs WI-W? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxNMzFYXzBtQi1SSHRlTVp3eUtWblRkWlFYTXp3TnRHRjZybzhSb3ozMkRHb3c4bWc3bUQxSmtIS0txT2pObnJ0WDNObk85MW1NTlM3aWRZZUNlNU50a0kxMVhiSHZNTVBXZVh5ZEV0LTkxelo5b3h6M2k1YTVleVpZemZydmIwaXZOVWFoMHFRUkUweXNWVWVlcjhsYTRMUHlrVVlEdGRvRWRNVzlpbjZEMHRRM0E5dmpNN1FPcm5rZjJ1SE5vengyaTdzbmFqMWVoeDJRMUY1bmwxcTQxWm0yYkZDdmxhXzRfbnBZeFFsS3M4Q1c0N3pWOTVn0gGCAkFVX3lxTE9tQVZTRXdlVWoxSG1EZEVObHpneEZnV3dlVExwT3dDOVNrdHFwWmxWbHl6eGdETTIxSHdxMXlob2NvLXN4VEZJLXIybWVqSWNTUnh1U3FnZ3djYXpKd0JzZktSd3VnWVZxb0kwYlNrWTlNbTZUOXgySVBkdnp4ZFJsT1NQekhISUJ4dDJ5ZWQ4WWYySXlCNGZzRC11NzB0Q194YlFBMWN2N3FVMmY5WldTQ05rbVpxYjZ5MmVWeTcySFNsR1RFMTV3T1NTdVFjdnNDc0p1Y3RxYzUtRlJ0c1hyY01veEwyWGE2ZXkzNDNBb2phQmlQc0tzWHF1YVNzTU1VZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxNMzFYXzBtQi1SSHRlTVp3eUtWblRkWlFYTXp3TnRHRjZybzhSb3ozMkRHb3c4bWc3bUQxSmtIS0txT2pObnJ0WDNObk85MW1NTlM3aWRZZUNlNU50a0kxMVhiSHZNTVBXZVh5ZEV0LTkxelo5b3h6M2k1YTVleVpZemZydmIwaXZOVWFoMHFRUkUweXNWVWVlcjhsYTRMUHlrVVlEdGRvRWRNVzlpbjZEMHRRM0E5dmpNN1FPcm5rZjJ1SE5vengyaTdzbmFqMWVoeDJRMUY1bmwxcTQxWm0yYkZDdmxhXzRfbnBZeFFsS3M4Q1c0N3pWOTVn0gGCAkFVX3lxTE9tQVZTRXdlVWoxSG1EZEVObHpneEZnV3dlVExwT3dDOVNrdHFwWmxWbHl6eGdETTIxSHdxMXlob2NvLXN4VEZJLXIybWVqSWNTUnh1U3FnZ3djYXpKd0JzZktSd3VnWVZxb0kwYlNrWTlNbTZUOXgySVBkdnp4ZFJsT1NQekhISUJ4dDJ5ZWQ4WWYySXlCNGZzRC11NzB0Q194YlFBMWN2N3FVMmY5WldTQ05rbVpxYjZ5MmVWeTcySFNsR1RFMTV3T1NTdVFjdnNDc0p1Y3RxYzUtRlJ0c1hyY01veEwyWGE2ZXkzNDNBb2phQmlQc0tzWHF1YVNzTU1VZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prithvi Shaw Shocked After Getting Sacked From BCCI Event, Says: "Tell Me God..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxNQnVNeFFSdDQ3dzV0d1c0UnlmVDJMc3hVdXNCUmpSUl9wUEFMQ0ZvZk1xVzEtS2tTeXpGUlZNT1Y0TFltQlkzSFJRUHdhYXBsbk1mSXhGTnduSWc3dkVxelI3Q0thb3pzNWpmTXhHTzRBc0R3MzBpRVVVTks1V0F1UjB1WnRRampnZWx5RW9WZUlmS05MVF9FZFBzYVVybDRCWFJlV0pMQmlDZW9kQ1ZwN2FWZkxmSWc4NnhiOUlNdG51eUJfM29SekVqR3F3SWtoWThMLWtVQjdnZ3dtdEHSAeYBQVVfeXFMTnJWbEtGQjA5aDZBaVZTc3NUTkRxd0JmUF93R2xxeE1xLVBIVnVyMWE4T1FDUWs4MTE3LTI3TXdRSHpRaVI3NVhZdlFGMVotcXU0UmE4anRvaW1yMndhRk9abExBTUE0VjhWbU44UlRDUDN5YXhRUDFOU2VfN1MwLVZ1d3c0TTVyQkVSc0o2OXo4bTJOajh3NkMzeGNqMkxuVHNIMzVxTnhCVjh2aUoweXk2RU9SSVNwVTdDb05XbHR5TDc3RnVJYks1YnJLcndzZDl1eS1QbnJTX1gzSm96U0otRUJuc0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxNQnVNeFFSdDQ3dzV0d1c0UnlmVDJMc3hVdXNCUmpSUl9wUEFMQ0ZvZk1xVzEtS2tTeXpGUlZNT1Y0TFltQlkzSFJRUHdhYXBsbk1mSXhGTnduSWc3dkVxelI3Q0thb3pzNWpmTXhHTzRBc0R3MzBpRVVVTks1V0F1UjB1WnRRampnZWx5RW9WZUlmS05MVF9FZFBzYVVybDRCWFJlV0pMQmlDZW9kQ1ZwN2FWZkxmSWc4NnhiOUlNdG51eUJfM29SekVqR3F3SWtoWThMLWtVQjdnZ3dtdEHSAeYBQVVfeXFMTnJWbEtGQjA5aDZBaVZTc3NUTkRxd0JmUF93R2xxeE1xLVBIVnVyMWE4T1FDUWs4MTE3LTI3TXdRSHpRaVI3NVhZdlFGMVotcXU0UmE4anRvaW1yMndhRk9abExBTUE0VjhWbU44UlRDUDN5YXhRUDFOU2VfN1MwLVZ1d3c0TTVyQkVSc0o2OXo4bTJOajh3NkMzeGNqMkxuVHNIMzVxTnhCVjh2aUoweXk2RU9SSVNwVTdDb05XbHR5TDc3RnVJYks1YnJLcndzZDl1eS1QbnJTX1gzSm96U0otRUJuc0E?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:00:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BBL 2024-2025: Match 4, STA vs HEA Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between STA vs HEA? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Match Prediction for BBL 2024-2025: Melbourne Stars vs Brisbane Heat</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><figure><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1734431369063_image_2024_12_17T09_55_04_194Z.png" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Melbourne Stars (STA) will face Brisbane Heat (HEA) in Match 4 of the BBL 2024-25 at the Melbourne Cricket Ground. This will be the first match of the season for Brisbane Heat.</p><ul><li>Melbourne Stars suffered a six-wicket defeat in their opener against Perth Scorchers.</li><li>Cooper Connolly was a standout performer for Perth, scoring 64 runs.</li><li>Brisbane Heat are defending champions, lifting their second title in the previous season.</li><li>The pitch favors both batters and bowlers, making for an exciting contest.</li></ul><blockquote>“Today's Match Prediction: Team Batting First to win the match.”</blockquote><p>The predicted line-ups include notable players like Marcus Stoinis and Xavier Bartlett, with Stoinis expected to perform well again after a solid showing in the opener.</p><p>This match is likely to generate significant interest given the star power and the defending champions' return.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-4-sta-vs-hea-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-sta-vs-hea-3058/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-4-sta-vs-hea-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-sta-vs-hea-3058/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Africa vs Pakistan Match Prediction - Who will win today’s 1st ODI match between SA vs PAK? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxPcmdwMlFBOVFiZ0lNeFo4TlZJZ2Nvd2dQT2F0a0lzdTE3OWZyMU81ajVfdUg5UnB4SENKYnpVNXc1N1NUcDAyRE8tcG9fOGMxSzJHVV94Rk83OWZTME1PNTBBSUJPcVFyNzNrbXR1dE5DWmIzam8ycEYzNlkxSHVMQWRHRXA2Y2RpWXE1Wnh5VlJ6cEo2b01pWnVhUlVsYmN6QWp3X1N4WW9GZ1NaMTU0WklRZHQwQjdkQXdfUlNIczNUQU1uc2dfNmhaS3VGNjN5N2VJZGZwT2s0LXRRQ0FiNFRB0gHqAUFVX3lxTE84LWdtVEUyWm5kSi1FNEdXS0JlN1k1MXN3ZXBMdkt0dHY0b1ZVVUdxVnpjSmlUYWRjOWhBYnNiZXBUT2ZZTUFsWVBaM1lDalh0UkxxdmRoNDJybG4zVWprWk1TY2dvdWoxVjhQS2QxZzFYSmRsTnN3QnRReDEyRVY5N1l2MWlqNmN5eVpnR0hxcWZ3MEhRUFJiRkU1UXdvOG1QYnY1Tkd6X2FFZXk3OHZ3QmFFbUJrZFVMdV9KSDI4SWI0LXhJZEhjMXQ2TndITjdUbjdxS2Rzb0NySjVuR1BZMTg1a2tiaWZlUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxPcmdwMlFBOVFiZ0lNeFo4TlZJZ2Nvd2dQT2F0a0lzdTE3OWZyMU81ajVfdUg5UnB4SENKYnpVNXc1N1NUcDAyRE8tcG9fOGMxSzJHVV94Rk83OWZTME1PNTBBSUJPcVFyNzNrbXR1dE5DWmIzam8ycEYzNlkxSHVMQWRHRXA2Y2RpWXE1Wnh5VlJ6cEo2b01pWnVhUlVsYmN6QWp3X1N4WW9GZ1NaMTU0WklRZHQwQjdkQXdfUlNIczNUQU1uc2dfNmhaS3VGNjN5N2VJZGZwT2s0LXRRQ0FiNFRB0gHqAUFVX3lxTE84LWdtVEUyWm5kSi1FNEdXS0JlN1k1MXN3ZXBMdkt0dHY0b1ZVVUdxVnpjSmlUYWRjOWhBYnNiZXBUT2ZZTUFsWVBaM1lDalh0UkxxdmRoNDJybG4zVWprWk1TY2dvdWoxVjhQS2QxZzFYSmRsTnN3QnRReDEyRVY5N1l2MWlqNmN5eVpnR0hxcWZ3MEhRUFJiRkU1UXdvOG1QYnY1Tkd6X2FFZXk3OHZ3QmFFbUJrZFVMdV9KSDI4SWI0LXhJZEhjMXQ2TndITjdUbjdxS2Rzb0NySjVuR1BZMTg1a2tiaWZlUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Official: Mykhailo Mudryk flagged for ‘adverse finding’ in doping test - We Ain't Got No History]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chelsea's Mudryk Tests Positive for Doping, Denies Wrongdoing</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Chelsea FC</p><p>Mykhailo Mudryk has been flagged for a positive doping test following a routine check. Both he and Chelsea FC deny any wrongdoing and are cooperating with authorities.</p><blockquote><p>Both the Club and Mykhailo fully support The FA’s testing programme and all our players, including Mykhailo, are regularly tested. Mykhailo has confirmed categorically that he has never knowingly used any banned substances.</p><p>-Source: <a href="https://www.chelseafc.com/en/news/article/club-statement-mykhailo-mudryk">Chelsea FC</a></p></blockquote><ul><li>The positive sample was collected in late October.</li><li>Mudryk has been suspended provisionally until the B-sample results are announced.</li><li>The substance detected is meldonium, banned since 2016, which could lead to a four-year ban if the B-sample is also positive.</li></ul><blockquote><p>I can confirm that I have been notified that a sample I provided to The FA contained a banned substance.</p><p>This has come as a complete shock as I have never knowingly used any banned substances or broken any rules, and am working closely with my team to investigate how this could have happened.</p><p>-Mykhailo Mudryk; source: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DDrPYUbORMw/?hl=en">Instagram</a></p></blockquote><p>Both Chelsea and Mudryk are expected to refrain from further comments until the B-sample results are available.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/2024/12/17/24323221/official-chelsea-winger-mykhailo-mudryk-flagged-for-adverse-finding-in-doping-test</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/2024/12/17/24323221/official-chelsea-winger-mykhailo-mudryk-flagged-for-adverse-finding-in-doping-test</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:26:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Youngest ever chess world champion Gukesh Dommaraju returns home to rock star welcome in India - CNN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/17/sport/gukesh-returns-india-chess-world-champion-spt/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/17/sport/gukesh-returns-india-chess-world-champion-spt/index.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Conor McGregor inks preliminary deal with Ambani family for Logan Paul showdown in India - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Conor McGregor inks preliminary deal with Ambani family for Logan Paul showdown in India</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Conor McGregor" width="300" height="150"><figcaption>Conor McGregor, the MMA superstar.</figcaption><p>In a major development, UFC star Conor McGregor has reached a preliminary agreement with the Ambani family to face Logan Paul in a high-profile match scheduled to take place in India.</p><ul><li>The event is expected to attract significant media attention.</li><li>Details about the venue and date are yet to be finalized.</li><li>This collaboration reflects the growing popularity of mixed martial arts and boxing in India.</li></ul><blockquote>“This fight could be one of the biggest events in combat sports this year,” a source familiar with the negotiations stated.</blockquote><p>This matchup promises to be a landmark event, not only for fans of McGregor and Paul but also for the sport's growing audience in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/boxing/conor-mcgregor-inks-preliminary-deal-with-ambani-family-for-logan-paul-showdown-in-india/articleshow/116399576.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/boxing/conor-mcgregor-inks-preliminary-deal-with-ambani-family-for-logan-paul-showdown-in-india/articleshow/116399576.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World Test Championship Final Qualification Scenarios For All Teams And Updated Table After NZ's Win.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxPSVY1MXJyM3JKMjJqLTJab0ZVRFdiSFdTMzVBUUtvVXVqcnppZ0JfWlJJVFBDNUlkTzZFbzJHcXVOWjVaUERxVDFRQXhRck5vRVFCQ0thNTNra1hYZ1BnREtoaU1zWm9rcVR1aUxScWFhRzAyUFRlSVlieDluVUtlcmtFWmFBTFY0S0FEbmhYUWFqeFo2UVl3d2JXWXN1cUtEdzcxeWo0TnUtMlZ3OU1YOEtoY2wzV0diZTRMMHhsQnVidFdyalViYkE0cnpaby1RZ0NPTnIyU1RWUmdyVnNJc2dQLU9KZXPSAe8BQVVfeXFMUDdrMWw1QmY2aWV1T2RraTMzc1RLczl3d2lmYVAwMU9ZQkZOa29uVUhqVVBnN0gtUzJIRlhjeUdFY1hXZFVCcVZqbzFlUkZPUnZwR0kxTjBVRk9nOTlIRGx1T1BOTWYxSUJMLXRxaDhFY0NHdnZJdzA0LUNVUjJmd3p2TGpudEpfSnhiOUlhVkhpM1pzMExpV0dORFV0VmM4QXI3ZDVRZnYxRjRYeElhN0o0TEVkakxTcENLNW1rNWdQQjdpalduR1V4MG9LUVNtNVk0VG92RlZpRko3RDVZQUhtdnlXdGNsV202MkJaUXM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxPSVY1MXJyM3JKMjJqLTJab0ZVRFdiSFdTMzVBUUtvVXVqcnppZ0JfWlJJVFBDNUlkTzZFbzJHcXVOWjVaUERxVDFRQXhRck5vRVFCQ0thNTNra1hYZ1BnREtoaU1zWm9rcVR1aUxScWFhRzAyUFRlSVlieDluVUtlcmtFWmFBTFY0S0FEbmhYUWFqeFo2UVl3d2JXWXN1cUtEdzcxeWo0TnUtMlZ3OU1YOEtoY2wzV0diZTRMMHhsQnVidFdyalViYkE0cnpaby1RZ0NPTnIyU1RWUmdyVnNJc2dQLU9KZXPSAe8BQVVfeXFMUDdrMWw1QmY2aWV1T2RraTMzc1RLczl3d2lmYVAwMU9ZQkZOa29uVUhqVVBnN0gtUzJIRlhjeUdFY1hXZFVCcVZqbzFlUkZPUnZwR0kxTjBVRk9nOTlIRGx1T1BOTWYxSUJMLXRxaDhFY0NHdnZJdzA0LUNVUjJmd3p2TGpudEpfSnhiOUlhVkhpM1pzMExpV0dORFV0VmM4QXI3ZDVRZnYxRjRYeElhN0o0TEVkakxTcENLNW1rNWdQQjdpalduR1V4MG9LUVNtNVk0VG92RlZpRko3RDVZQUhtdnlXdGNsV202MkJaUXM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:50:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>