<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:21:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:21:55 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Miss to Mrs! PV Sindhu gets engaged to Venkata Datta Sai. First Pic Out - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/badminton/miss-to-mrs-pv-sindhu-gets-engaged-to-venkata-datta-sai-first-pic-out/articleshow/116318325.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/badminton/miss-to-mrs-pv-sindhu-gets-engaged-to-venkata-datta-sai-first-pic-out/articleshow/116318325.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Kane Williamson Gets Out In Bizarre Fashion vs England, New Zealand Star's Reaction Is Viral - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watch: Kane Williamson Gets Out In Bizarre Fashion vs England, New Zealand Star's Reaction Is Viral</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/9jsnu7uo_kane-williamson_625x300_14_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Kane Williamson reacts after his dismissal." width="639" height="479">
<figcaption>Kane Williamson reacts after his dismissal. © AFP</figcaption>
<p>New Zealand cricketer Kane Williamson faced an unusual dismissal during the first day of the third Test against England, which has since gone viral due to his reaction.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kane Williamson was well set on 44 runs when he made an error attempting to block a delivery from Matthew Potts.</li>
    <li>The ball bounced and he inadvertently kicked it onto the stumps, resulting in his dismissal.</li>
    <li>This mistake was pivotal as it led to New Zealand losing three wickets for just 34 runs.</li>
    <li>Despite Williamson’s dismissal, New Zealand finished Day 1 at a reasonable score of 315/9.</li>
    <li>Tom Latham contributed with a half-century, scoring 63 runs, while Mitchell Santner provided a quick 50 late in the innings.</li>
    <li>Matthew Potts achieved three wickets, and his partner Gus Atkinson also took three, making history in his debut year.</li>
    <li>Both teams are currently out of contention for the World Test Championship finals.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>UNLUCKY KANE WILLIAMSON! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NZvENG?src=hash&ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NZvENG</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/KaneWilliamson?src=hash&ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#KaneWilliamson</a> <a href="https://t.co/1yuKrON9ye">pic.twitter.com/1yuKrON9ye</a></p>
    — CricketInfo (@cricketinfo2024) <a href="https://twitter.com/cricketinfo2024/status/1867824140574708019?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 14, 2024</a>
</blockquote>
<p>The incident serves as a reminder of the unpredictable nature of cricket, showcasing how even experienced players can make critical errors under pressure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/kane-williamson-gets-out-in-bizarre-fashion-in-3rd-test-vs-england-new-zealand-stars-reaction-is-viral-7246564</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/kane-williamson-gets-out-in-bizarre-fashion-in-3rd-test-vs-england-new-zealand-stars-reaction-is-viral-7246564</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:49:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ashwin or Jadeja? Australian cricketers settle the debate with a clear answer - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashwin or Jadeja? Australian cricketers settle the debate with a clear answer</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Provided</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116317695,imgsize-45208,width-400,resizemode-4/116317695.jpg" alt="Ashwin or Jadeja? Australian cricketers settle the debate with a clear answer" title="Ravichandran Ashwin and Ravindra Jadeja. (Pic Credit - X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin and Ravindra Jadeja. (Pic Credit - X)</figcaption>
<p>Australian cricketers recently weighed in on the debate between Ravichandran Ashwin and Ravindra Jadeja, declaring Ashwin as the tougher bowler to face due to his tactical brilliance and adaptability.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Ashwin is noted for his mastery of variations and ability to exploit turn.</li>
    <li>Travis Head and other Australian players praised Ashwin's skills over Jadeja's accuracy.</li>
    <li>Steve Smith highlighted Ashwin's exceptional adaptability across different pitches.</li>
    <li>Players like Josh Hazlewood and Usman Khawaja acknowledged Ashwin's cleverness and competitive nature.</li>
    <li>Cameron Green emphasized how Ashwin and Jadeja complement each other's skills.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Probably for me, Ashwin, someone with a couple more tricks and being a lot taller and a lot quicker. Yeah, I think he's probably the hardest," - Travis Head.</blockquote>
<blockquote>"I think what makes them great is that they just complement each other. Ashwin, he's always feels like he's one step ahead." - Cameron Green.</blockquote>
<p>The consensus among Australian players suggests that while both spinners are formidable, Ashwin's psychological edge and varied approach make him the more difficult opponent in the eyes of the cricketers.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ashwin-or-jadeja-australian-cricketers-settle-the-debate-with-a-clear-answer/articleshow/116317699.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ashwin-or-jadeja-australian-cricketers-settle-the-debate-with-a-clear-answer/articleshow/116317699.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Africa vs Pakistan Match Prediction - Who will win today’s 3rd T20I match between SA vs PAK? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Africa vs Pakistan Match Prediction - Who will win today’s 3rd T20I match between SA vs PAK?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1734157615576_imgpsh_fullsize_anim---2024-12-14T115646.png" loading="lazy">
    <figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>South Africa has emerged victorious in the first two matches of the ongoing T20I series against Pakistan, leading to a highly anticipated 3rd T20I clash, which is set to take place at the Wanderers Stadium in Johannesburg.</p>
<ul>
    <li>South Africa defeated Pakistan in the first two T20Is of the series.</li>
    <li>Captain Mohammad Rizwan of Pakistan needs to step up for his team’s success.</li>
    <li>Notable performances from South Africa include David Miller, Reeza Hendricks, and Rassie van der Dussen.</li>
    <li>The match will be held on December 14, at 9:30 PM IST.</li>
    <li>The pitch at Wanderers Stadium favors batters, with a good total considered to be above 200 runs.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“South Africa to win the match” - Today's Match Prediction</blockquote>
<p>The competition promises high excitement as both teams vie for dominance in this tight series, with South Africa favored to continue their winning streak.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/south-africa-vs-pakistan-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-3rd-t20i-match-between-sa-vs-pak/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/south-africa-vs-pakistan-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-3rd-t20i-match-between-sa-vs-pak/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 11:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘When Magnus won…’: D Gukesh recalls how Viswanathan Anand's 2013 World C'ship loss vs Carlsen motivated him as a child - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘When Magnus won…’: D Gukesh recalls how Viswanathan Anand's 2013 World C'ship loss vs Carlsen motivated him as a child</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/1000000937_1734171652891_1734171667245.jpg" alt="D Gukesh recalled Magnus Carlsen's 2013 World C'ship win vs India legend Viswanathan Anand." title="D Gukesh recalled Magnus Carlsen's 2013 World C'ship win vs India legend Viswanathan Anand.">
<figcaption>D Gukesh recalled Magnus Carlsen's 2013 World C'ship win vs India legend Viswanathan Anand.</figcaption>
<p>D Gukesh, at 18, became the youngest-ever world chess champion, motivated by the memory of Viswanathan Anand's 2013 World Championship loss to Magnus Carlsen.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Gukesh won the World Chess Championship in Singapore against defending champion Ding Liren.</li>
    <li>He acknowledged Carlsen's 2013 victory over Anand, which inspired him to aim for the title himself.</li>
    <li>Gukesh became the second Indian Grandmaster to win the title, after Anand.</li>
    <li>He achieved significant milestones at a young age, including being the youngest to surpass a FIDE rating of 2750.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When Magnus won I thought, I really want to be the one to bring back the title to India. This dream that I had for more than 10 years ago has been the single most important thing in my life so far.”</blockquote>
<p>Gukesh’s achievement reflects his dedication to chess and his aspiration to honor Indian chess history, showcasing the impact of Anand's legacy on future generations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/when-magnus-won-d-gukesh-recalls-how-viswanathan-anands-2013-world-cship-loss-vs-carlsen-motivated-him-as-a-child-101734171356350.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/when-magnus-won-d-gukesh-recalls-how-viswanathan-anands-2013-world-cship-loss-vs-carlsen-motivated-him-as-a-child-101734171356350.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 10:24:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli Responds After Kapil Dev Offers To Help Him: "Have No Hesitation..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli Responds After Kapil Dev Offers To Help Him: "Have No Hesitation..."</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/u7eograg_vinod-kambli-kapil-dev_625x300_13_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Vinod Kambli" width="639" height="479">
<figcaption>Vinod Kambli has agreed to enter rehab amid concerns over his health and financial crisis. © X (Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>Vinod Kambli, the former Indian cricketer, is set to enter rehab following a financial and health crisis, with support from notable cricket figures including Kapil Dev and Sunil Gavaskar.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kambli has agreed to enter rehab, acknowledging his previous 14 attempts.</li>
    <li>Kapil Dev offered to cover treatment costs on the condition that Kambli agrees to rehabilitate.</li>
    <li>Sunil Gavaskar has also extended help and support to Kambli.</li>
    <li>Kambli stated he has no hesitation about going to rehab, crediting his wife for managing their financial situation.</li>
    <li>His only income currently comes from a BCCI pension of Rs 30,000 per month.</li>
    <li>Other former cricketers, including Ajay Jadeja and Abey Kuruvilla, have reached out to Kambli for support.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "Bad (on his financial condition). But the manner in which my wife has handled everything, hats off to her. ... Sure, I have no hesitation (to enter rehab), because until I have my family with me, I'm not afraid of anything, anybody." - Vinod Kambli
</blockquote>
<p>Kambli expressed optimism about his situation, believing that the BCCI would help him if needed. His recent public appearance raised concerns about his condition, and he is grateful for the support from his peers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/vinod-kambli-responds-after-kapil-dev-offers-to-help-him-have-no-hesitation-7240365</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/vinod-kambli-responds-after-kapil-dev-offers-to-help-him-have-no-hesitation-7240365</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:51:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli Responds After Kapil Dev Offers To Help Him: "Have No Hesitation..." | Cricket News - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli Responds After Kapil Dev Offers To Help Him: "Have No Hesitation..."</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/u7eograg_vinod-kambli-kapil-dev_625x300_13_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Vinod Kambli" width="639" height="479">
<figcaption>Vinod Kambli has agreed to enter rehab amid concerns over his health and financial crisis. © X (Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>Vinod Kambli, the former Indian cricketer, is set to enter rehab following a financial and health crisis, with support from notable cricket figures including Kapil Dev and Sunil Gavaskar.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kambli has agreed to enter rehab, acknowledging his previous 14 attempts.</li>
    <li>Kapil Dev offered to cover treatment costs on the condition that Kambli agrees to rehabilitate.</li>
    <li>Sunil Gavaskar has also extended help and support to Kambli.</li>
    <li>Kambli stated he has no hesitation about going to rehab, crediting his wife for managing their financial situation.</li>
    <li>His only income currently comes from a BCCI pension of Rs 30,000 per month.</li>
    <li>Other former cricketers, including Ajay Jadeja and Abey Kuruvilla, have reached out to Kambli for support.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "Bad (on his financial condition). But the manner in which my wife has handled everything, hats off to her. ... Sure, I have no hesitation (to enter rehab), because until I have my family with me, I'm not afraid of anything, anybody." - Vinod Kambli
</blockquote>
<p>Kambli expressed optimism about his situation, believing that the BCCI would help him if needed. His recent public appearance raised concerns about his condition, and he is grateful for the support from his peers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/vinod-kambli-responds-after-kapil-dev-offers-to-help-him-have-no-hesitation-7240365</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/vinod-kambli-responds-after-kapil-dev-offers-to-help-him-have-no-hesitation-7240365</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:51:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohammad Amir and Imad Wasim go back to international retirement - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammad Amir and Imad Wasim go back to international retirement</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/placeholder-16-9.png" alt="Mohammad Amir and Imad Wasim celebrate a wicket, Providence, April 7, 2017">
    <figcaption>Mohammad Amir and Imad Wasim first unretired and have now re-retired pretty much together • AFP/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Imad Wasim and Mohammad Amir, who had recently returned from international retirement to participate in the T20 World Cup 2024, have announced their decision to retire again.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The players had rejoined the national team to compete in the T20 World Cup held in the USA and the Caribbean.</li>
    <li>Imad announced the end of his chapter on Friday, followed by Amir's announcement on Saturday.</li>
    <li>Amir stated: "After much thought and reflection, I have decided to retire from international cricket." </li>
    <li>Both cricketers played their last international match against Ireland in June 2024.</li>
    <li>Pakistan did not progress beyond the group stage in the tournament, which was claimed by India.</li>
    <li>Amir and Imad had commendable individual performances despite the team's early exit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>“To all fans & supporters: After much thought and reflection, I have decided to retire from international cricket. Representing Pakistan on the world stage has been the greatest honor of my life, and every moment wearing the green jersey has been unforgettable.” — Imad Wasim</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The two players remain popular in the T20 franchise circuit, recently participating in the Abu Dhabi T10 tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/pakistan-news-mohammad-amir-and-imad-wasim-go-back-to-international-retirement-1464981</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/pakistan-news-mohammad-amir-and-imad-wasim-go-back-to-international-retirement-1464981</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:38:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Really surprised': Matthew Hayden reacts to Rohit's bold decision on Day 1 of Gabba Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Really surprised': Matthew Hayden reacts to Rohit's bold decision on Day 1 of Gabba Test</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> NEW DELHI</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116314598,imgsize-37904,width-400,resizemode-4/116314598.jpg" alt="'Really surprised': Matthew Hayden reacts to Rohit's bold decision on Day 1 of Gabba Test" title="Matthew Hayden and Rohit Sharma. (File Pic: Image Credit - X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Matthew Hayden and Rohit Sharma. (File Pic: Image Credit - X)</figcaption>
<p>Former Australian opener Matthew Hayden expressed surprise at Rohit Sharma's bold decision to bowl first on the opening day of the Gabba Test, given that the pitch conditions seemed more suited for batting.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Hayden was taken aback by Rohit's toss decision, stating that the pitch favored batters.</li>
    <li>He noted that the groundsman had likely prepared the pitch earlier due to recent rain, affecting its behavior.</li>
    <li>India's bowlers struggled against Australia, who ended the day at 28/0 in 13.2 overs.</li>
    <li>Hayden believes that the pitch will deteriorate over the next couple of days, making spinners more effective.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I was really surprised that actually, Rohit won the toss and decided to bowl, because I felt like it was over-prepared... Almost 12 inches of rain in the past two weeks." - Matthew Hayden</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Hayden emphasized that opting to bat first would have been a wiser choice, considering the expected changes in pitch conditions over the course of the match.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/really-surprised-matthew-hayden-reacts-to-rohits-bold-decision-on-day-1-of-gabba-test/articleshow/116314612.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/really-surprised-matthew-hayden-reacts-to-rohits-bold-decision-on-day-1-of-gabba-test/articleshow/116314612.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Viswanathan Anand Responds As Ex-World Champion Criticises D Gukesh's Title Triumph - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Viswanathan Anand Responds As Ex-World Champion Criticises D Gukesh's Title Triumph</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/82fkn5no_d-gukesh-afp_625x300_13_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Viswanathan Anand Responds As Ex-World Champion Criticises D Gukesh's Title Triumph">
<figcaption>D Gukesh became the youngest chess world champion © AFP</figcaption>
<p>Legendary chess player Viswanathan Anand promised support for D. Gukesh, who faced criticism regarding his World Championship victory over Ding Liren. Anand emphasized that criticism is part of achieving success and praised Gukesh's historic triumph.</p>
<ul>
    <li>D. Gukesh becomes the youngest chess world champion by defeating Ding Liren.</li>
    <li>Critiques from former champion Vladimir Kramnik question the quality of the match.</li>
    <li>Magnus Carlsen also criticizes the earlier rounds, calling them uncharacteristic for World Championship contenders.</li>
    <li>Anand advises Gukesh to ignore the criticism and reflects on the importance of his achievement.</li>
    <li>Anand highlights Gukesh's strong performance in recent competitions leading to his championship win.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "To be honest, I think it just comes with the territory. You ignore it and that's all." - Viswanathan Anand
</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Anand views Gukesh's victory as a significant milestone in Indian chess, celebrating the new generation's achievements despite the surrounding criticism.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/chess/viswanathan-anand-responds-as-ex-world-champion-criticises-d-gukeshs-title-triumph-7239007</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/chess/viswanathan-anand-responds-as-ex-world-champion-criticises-d-gukeshs-title-triumph-7239007</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:54:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There is a younger ‘world champion’ than D Gukesh: The story of Ukraine's forgotten chess prodigy Ruslan Ponomariov - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>There is a younger ‘world champion’ than D Gukesh: The story of Ukraine's forgotten chess prodigy Ruslan Ponomariov</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/ruslan_gukesh_1734166029833_1734166038766.jpg" alt="Ruslan Ponomariov or D Gukesh, who is the youngest chess world champion?" title="Ruslan Ponomariov or D Gukesh, who is the youngest chess world champion?">
<figcaption>Ruslan Ponomariov or D Gukesh, who is the youngest chess world champion?</figcaption>
<p>Former FIDE champion Ruslan Ponomariov, who won his title in 2002, is often overshadowed by D Gukesh, the current undisputed youngest world champion. This article explores the historical context and implications of their respective victories.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Ponomariov became the FIDE World Champion in 2002 at just 18 years old, making him the youngest to do so at the time.</li>
    <li>The chess world saw a split between the classical title and the FIDE title from 1993 to 2006, leading to two recognized champions.</li>
    <li>D Gukesh became the youngest undisputed FIDE world champion at 18 years and six months.</li>
    <li>Ponomariov's victory is often not recognized as Undisputed, which is key for the title debate.</li>
    <li>Despite the split, Ponomariov continued to have a successful career, remaining active in high-level competitions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Ever since 1993, there have been two titles, the phoney one controlled and organised by FIDE and the real one organised outside FIDE’s control.” - IM David Levy</blockquote>
<p>In summary, while D Gukesh is officially recognized as the youngest world champion, Ruslan Ponomariov's achievement in a challenging format highlights the complexities of chess titles during a divided era in the sport.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/there-is-a-younger-world-champion-than-d-gukesh-the-story-of-ukraines-forgotten-chess-prodigy-ruslan-ponomariov-101734165378476.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/there-is-a-younger-world-champion-than-d-gukesh-the-story-of-ukraines-forgotten-chess-prodigy-ruslan-ponomariov-101734165378476.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:51:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Nahi ho raha swing' - Jasprit Bumrah's frustration an early worry for India in Gabba Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nahi ho raha swing - Jasprit Bumrah's frustration an early worry for India in Gabba Test</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116314093,imgsize-29074,width-400,resizemode-4/116314093.jpg" alt="'Nahi ho raha swing' - Jasprit Bumrah's frustration an early worry for India in Gabba Test" title="Jasprit Bumrah (Photo Source: X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah (Photo Source: X)</figcaption>
<p>In the third Test against Australia at the Gabba, Indian captain Rohit Sharma opted to bowl first under cloudy conditions. However, Jasprit Bumrah expressed his frustration over the lack of swing during the early overs.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Rohit Sharma chose to bowl first despite expectations of a favorable pitch for fast bowlers.</li>
    <li>Bumrah was heard on the stump microphone saying, "Nahin ho raha swing aise bhi; kahin bhi kar lo", indicating the ball was not swinging.</li>
    <li>The first day was disrupted by rain, with only 13.2 overs bowled, leaving Australia at 28 for 0 by the end.</li>
    <li>Indian bowlers experimented with different lines but failed to get swing or seam movement.</li>
    <li>Former players and commentators expressed concerns about the decision to bowl first at the Gabba, citing historical context.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"You bat at the Gabba. If you face Australia, you want them to bat second and fourth." - Kerry O'Keeffe</blockquote>
<p>This situation highlights ongoing challenges for India in the Test series and raises questions about their bowling strategy in conditions that did not provide the expected advantages.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/nahi-ho-raha-swing-jasprit-bumrahs-frustration-an-early-worry-for-india-in-gabba-test/articleshow/116314004.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/nahi-ho-raha-swing-jasprit-bumrahs-frustration-an-early-worry-for-india-in-gabba-test/articleshow/116314004.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Imad, Amir announce retirement from international cricket - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxOQ0NYbUczRUZyUkFReGZxT2MxYlN0aHh4d2lIc25TM3ZwM3FfUG5DNkQzMHNfR0ZWTkdDM3pLZlFKRExmeFFRblJVTjZnbXZGSGRSQlUwN09pd19wb3hzWFd2RDRCcU5FdGJtUjhJZWZRX2tFMlJPYURRTFk4czdIbmZHcEEzRHFtOVA2dEtHZjFaMHI5R2duNXpB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxOQ0NYbUczRUZyUkFReGZxT2MxYlN0aHh4d2lIc25TM3ZwM3FfUG5DNkQzMHNfR0ZWTkdDM3pLZlFKRExmeFFRblJVTjZnbXZGSGRSQlUwN09pd19wb3hzWFd2RDRCcU5FdGJtUjhJZWZRX2tFMlJPYURRTFk4czdIbmZHcEEzRHFtOVA2dEtHZjFaMHI5R2duNXpB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 08:37:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Cringe, Need Downfall": Pat Cummins' One-Word Description For Virat Kohli Irks Indian Fans - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"Cringe, Need Downfall": Pat Cummins' One-Word Description For Virat Kohli Irks Indian Fans</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-03/cbnm5pj8_virat-kohli-pat-cummins-afp_625x300_22_March_22.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Pat Cummins and Virat Kohli" width="639" height="479">
<figcaption>File image of Pat Cummins and Virat Kohli. © AFP</figcaption>
<p>A viral video featuring Australian cricket team members describing Virat Kohli resulted in backlash from Indian fans, particularly regarding Pat Cummins' one-word response.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Pat Cummins described Virat Kohli simply as "batter," drawing criticism from fans.</li>
    <li>Other Australian players praised Kohli with terms like "superstar," "classy," and "freak."</li>
    <li>The video has caused social media outrage, with users calling for Cummins' "downfall."</li>
    <li>Kohli's performance in 2024 has been inconsistent, with only 373 runs in 8 Tests and an average of 26.64.</li>
    <li>India needs to win the Border-Gavaskar Trophy to qualify for the World Test Championship final in 2025.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>“Need Pat Cummins' downfall” — User on social media</blockquote>
<blockquote>“Not going to lie, this is becoming quite cringe now” — User on social media</blockquote>

<p>Despite receiving harsh words from Cummins, Kohli's contribution in crucial matches will be vital for India's future successes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/cringe-need-downfall-pat-cummins-one-word-description-for-virat-kohli-irks-india-fans-7246098</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/cringe-need-downfall-pat-cummins-one-word-description-for-virat-kohli-irks-india-fans-7246098</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 07:49:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Nahi ho raha...': Jasprit Bumrah's anguish caught on stump mic before rain crashes Day 1 of India vs Australia 3rd Test - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Nahi ho raha...': Jasprit Bumrah's anguish caught on stump mic before rain crashes Day 1 of India vs Australia 3rd Test</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-27_1734159859199_1734159883727.jpg" alt="India's paceman Jasprit Bumrah reacts after a delivery to Australia's Usman Khawaja (C) on the first day of the third cricket Test match. (Photo by David GRAY / AFP)(AFP)" title="India's paceman Jasprit Bumrah reacts after a delivery to Australia's Usman Khawaja (C) on the first day of the third cricket Test match. (Photo by David GRAY / AFP)(AFP)">
<figcaption>India's paceman Jasprit Bumrah reacts after a delivery to Australia's Usman Khawaja (C) on the first day of the third cricket Test match. (Photo by David GRAY / AFP)(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Rain disrupted Day 1 of the third Test between India and Australia at the Gabba, allowing only 13.2 overs of play. The highlight was a moment captured on the stump mic featuring Jasprit Bumrah expressing his frustration.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Rohit Sharma won the toss and opted to bowl first under overcast conditions.</li>
    <li>Jasprit Bumrah struggled to find swing and indicated to Shubman Gill during play that the ball wasn't swinging as expected.</li>
    <li>Usman Khawaja and Nathan McSweeney faced the Indian bowlers comfortably, contributing to Australia's score of 28/0 before rain halted play.</li>
    <li>The play is scheduled to resume with adjusted timings at 5:20 AM IST, contingent on weather conditions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>“Nahi ho raha swing aise bhi (The ball isn't swinging),” Jasprit Bumrah expressed to Shubman Gill after his delivery.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As both teams prepare for the resumption, memories of India's historic win at the Gabba in 2020-21 loom large, with Rishabh Pant sharing his positive outlook about returning to the venue.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/nahi-ho-raha-jasprit-bumrahs-anguish-caught-on-stump-mic-before-rain-crashes-day-1-of-india-vs-australia-3rd-test-101734159788152.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/nahi-ho-raha-jasprit-bumrahs-anguish-caught-on-stump-mic-before-rain-crashes-day-1-of-india-vs-australia-3rd-test-101734159788152.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 07:18:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia Highlights, 3rd Test Day 1: Rain Forces Stumps; India's WTC Final Hopes Hang In Balance - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxOcjhSTWVvS2ZiM2gxcHRiVDNrNVUxc2NidnY0bVZyVlFRVldNU3VxT3hrNlJvWkJTUy0yMWxVTTBxU1ROdTUyeTBpS21CVXJxZDBudHZBNnZhTm1uZ0FrRUpXU1AzR0t5eHBYdHhyVnpqM25FRWlFN3JNZVN4WjVNeG1NV0R5bkZhblhiZDJfYzMwR2FSUnBPdFQ1WGhDc1BScFdzN1F0bmgzREcxei1KTGNqLXFRSEhwSG9VU2llaFdvYUV3Wmd1MzBrMmhXb05Bc1BfVE5WMkpURUHSAeMBQVVfeXFMTndJb215RGdnWEZmMUpNUnIyeUxVcmV5WDRTZW1mWFhlaHkyZ2dfSE92VHFZdllqVm15c2N2T2JyY2I4eGNXOTJlbDBaT2c2a0xuRlFfcFJTYlluMlVUQ0Y5emt6UnpQVjZKTFFERjNNeTdySE1yVVlwdkluRFJOcjQ0R2VOU0I0dXJEUkdRaC1wUkNnMUFDTE9iOWRGdE5Xd1FDOHZ0TE11R3BlVk5ndE53RDhDcFM3Z0FKdkMxXzlHcFB3LXZ2T3BnNnFxZUs5cjBmUjRBZG1hQjVIa2RsejhJbkk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxOcjhSTWVvS2ZiM2gxcHRiVDNrNVUxc2NidnY0bVZyVlFRVldNU3VxT3hrNlJvWkJTUy0yMWxVTTBxU1ROdTUyeTBpS21CVXJxZDBudHZBNnZhTm1uZ0FrRUpXU1AzR0t5eHBYdHhyVnpqM25FRWlFN3JNZVN4WjVNeG1NV0R5bkZhblhiZDJfYzMwR2FSUnBPdFQ1WGhDc1BScFdzN1F0bmgzREcxei1KTGNqLXFRSEhwSG9VU2llaFdvYUV3Wmd1MzBrMmhXb05Bc1BfVE5WMkpURUHSAeMBQVVfeXFMTndJb215RGdnWEZmMUpNUnIyeUxVcmV5WDRTZW1mWFhlaHkyZ2dfSE92VHFZdllqVm15c2N2T2JyY2I4eGNXOTJlbDBaT2c2a0xuRlFfcFJTYlluMlVUQ0Y5emt6UnpQVjZKTFFERjNNeTdySE1yVVlwdkluRFJOcjQ0R2VOU0I0dXJEUkdRaC1wUkNnMUFDTE9iOWRGdE5Xd1FDOHZ0TE11R3BlVk5ndE53RDhDcFM3Z0FKdkMxXzlHcFB3LXZ2T3BnNnFxZUs5cjBmUjRBZG1hQjVIa2RsejhJbkk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:25:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honours even in Hamilton as England, New Zealand trade blows - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxPZnl6TlpiaUVPYUQxNWUwQTNvZkVpS2JONDVHT2JnYjJCQk0xRFZDWlFDQlRZQW5BeW9WX1pEeTBxYnRIV1ZHWk9Yby1DeUxNbDk3RW8xT1dWcjgycFp2dnJfUlYtSUs2bnlwZ0htVEZHdFRIOFFpLXc2VW1TTFJHdnRoclBJQmU1RnpPdXlfWjhpMFBveHJqTlpvSVRfSmwxQmtRZjNqRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxPZnl6TlpiaUVPYUQxNWUwQTNvZkVpS2JONDVHT2JnYjJCQk0xRFZDWlFDQlRZQW5BeW9WX1pEeTBxYnRIV1ZHWk9Yby1DeUxNbDk3RW8xT1dWcjgycFp2dnJfUlYtSUs2bnlwZ0htVEZHdFRIOFFpLXc2VW1TTFJHdnRoclBJQmU1RnpPdXlfWjhpMFBveHJqTlpvSVRfSmwxQmtRZjNqRQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 06:00:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive | Meet Matthew Hayden's daughter Grace who loves dal, is a big fan of Rishabh Pant - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Exclusive | Meet Matthew Hayden's daughter Grace who loves dal, is a big fan of Rishabh Pant</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> (Date Not Provided) | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116309421,imgsize-98226,width-400,resizemode-4/116309421.jpg" alt="Exclusive | Meet Matthew Hayden's daughter Grace who loves dal, is a big fan of Rishabh Pant" title="Matthew Hayden's daughter Grace and Rishabh Pant" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Matthew Hayden's daughter Grace and Rishabh Pant</figcaption>
<p>Matthew Hayden's daughter, Grace, shares her love for India and cricket, particularly highlighting her admiration for cricketer Rishabh Pant amid a rain-interrupted Test match in Brisbane.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Only 13.2 overs were played on the opening day of the third India-Australia Test due to heavy rain.</li>
    <li>Grace Hayden enjoys Indian cuisine, particularly dal curry and roti, thanks to her father's influence.</li>
    <li>She names Rishabh Pant as her favorite cricketer and admires his inspiring comeback story after a serious car accident.</li>
    <li>Grace believes that despite players' familiarity through the IPL, national pride prevails when playing for one's country.</li>
    <li>She predicts Australia will win the remaining Tests in the series, which is currently tied at 1-1.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "His comeback story has been sensational... he's definitely an inspiring player," said Grace about Rishabh Pant.
</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy has generated significant interest, with Grace optimistic about Australia's chances despite a rain-affected start to the match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/exclusive-meet-matthew-haydens-daughter-grace-who-loves-dal-is-a-big-fan-of-rishabh-pant/articleshow/116309315.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/exclusive-meet-matthew-haydens-daughter-grace-who-loves-dal-is-a-big-fan-of-rishabh-pant/articleshow/116309315.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 05:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Now Physically Weak, Vinod Kambli Was Once Super Fit As Virat Kohli & Jadeja, Here's A Proof: Watch - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Now Physically Weak, Vinod Kambli Was Once Super Fit As Virat Kohli & Jadeja, Here's A Proof: Watch</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024, 14:57 IST</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Vinod Kambli's old video goes viral on social media" title="Vinod Kambli's old video goes viral on social media" loading="eager">
<figcaption>Vinod Kambli's old video goes viral on social media</figcaption>
<p>Vinod Kambli’s deteriorating health has raised concerns among fans following his recent frail appearance at a memorial event in Mumbai. An old video from 1994 showcasing a fit Kambli has surfaced, contrasting his current condition.</p>
<ul>
    <li>An old 1994 video shows a young, athletic Vinod Kambli endorsing a glucose supplement.</li>
    <li>The 1983 World Cup-winning team, led by Kapil Dev, has offered to help Kambli, but only if he seeks rehabilitation.</li>
    <li>Kambli has expressed willingness to enter rehab to improve his health.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “We can’t look after him if he does not want to look after himself," - Kapil Dev.
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
    “I’m ready to go for rehab. I want to go there because I don’t fear anything. My family is with me," - Vinod Kambli.
</blockquote>
<p>The contrasting imagery of Kambli's past athleticism and his current struggles highlights the importance of support and self-care in overcoming personal challenges.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/now-physically-weak-vinod-kambli-was-once-super-fit-as-kohli-jadeja-old-video-goes-viral-watch-ws-b-9155843.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/now-physically-weak-vinod-kambli-was-once-super-fit-as-kohli-jadeja-old-video-goes-viral-watch-ws-b-9155843.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 03:56:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FIDE reacts to ‘deliberately lost’ allegations on Gukesh vs Ding World Championship final, counters Carlsen, Kramnik - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FIDE reacts to ‘deliberately lost’ allegations on Gukesh vs Ding World Championship final, counters Carlsen, Kramnik</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/PTI12-13-2024-000509A-0_1734147732625_1734147841264.jpg" alt="India's D Gukesh poses for photographs with the FIDE World Chess Championship 2024 trophy, in Singapore(PTI)">
<figcaption>India's D Gukesh poses for photographs with the FIDE World Chess Championship 2024 trophy, in Singapore(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Amid heavy criticism from former World Champions regarding the quality of the Gukesh vs Ding World Championship final, FIDE President Arkady Dvorkovich stated that mistakes in sports are natural and should not be attributed to players of such high caliber.</p>
<ul>
    <li>FIDE President Arkady Dvorkovich commented on the criticism regarding the players' performance in the final, stating that mistakes are an inherent part of sports.</li>
    <li>Defending champion Ding made a critical error in the final match, leading to an unexpected victory for 18-year-old Gukesh.</li>
    <li>Former champion Vladimir Kramnik criticized Ding's mistake, labeling it "childish" and calling for an investigation.</li>
    <li>Kramnik expressed disappointment over the match quality, calling it "the end of chess as we know it."</li>
    <li>Magnus Carlsen also questioned the standard of play, stating it resembled early rounds of an open tournament.</li>
    <li>Viswanathan Anand advised Gukesh to ignore criticism, emphasizing that it accompanies success.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Sports is about mistakes, without mistakes, there would be no goals in football. Every sportsman makes mistakes but that's what we are excited about, whether the opponent can find the way to use a mistake." - Arkady Dvorkovich</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing debate highlights the intense scrutiny faced by young champions like Gukesh and the differing opinions within the chess community regarding the evolving standards of the game.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/fide-reacts-to-deliberately-lost-allegations-on-gukesh-vs-ding-world-championship-final-counters-carlsen-kramnik-101734147141365.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/fide-reacts-to-deliberately-lost-allegations-on-gukesh-vs-ding-world-championship-final-counters-carlsen-kramnik-101734147141365.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 03:52:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australia Star Responsible For Lights Going Off During 2nd Test Against India? Big Reason Revealed - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxORWloYU10TWUtUGdDVF9ad1BhbVhyc1Joc0ZGMVI1NTRuZmlMUTFGZnBKZ0JfNk0zSmdkTnlYQjlrRW5RU191X01xVUNzd3BVV1VGdDBDclFWX0RkZnFyQ1MtWXh4R3huRENJdFFzTFZzYWRIanRVZDRXVWl5d2FUOC1uSUhkMkctTEFKTkRNWEtaVHhrWFhwbVoyRlhPV2xmMjVtSHptMXVzU2pfUkRwQm9PT3NFMjNVNGo2OUpoeVlrcmhSOHlYR2o2MUlja2R0dWRrbzVHU18zckMwc203ZE03ckJ3OUU4N2liYklnM3BoSENj0gH8AUFVX3lxTE5EZGJ4b012NVZBa1YxbHZONzJpeDRWRGtKYUpSLUpRVWR2U0g0WGhMeWtENzNOOXlwN3o1RDViZmtWQ0VIUzlNTmhWR1BoZVRQZkE0U29QME1HMVZWTjBmdlJ0V0RQWnhWV0tMTlVlY0gzYVBEVmxtU25NVG1vYVJKc19SbjVwSFU5WXM3TTRqNnBCT2dsMmNkT1ZVcTFLbUg4MkhibmVqa3Rjb2FrU2ExdlZVWDVQaEVBbHVoWHJhMjhjQm92eUJaM0tnaC1qT3N4cDBuc3pURGRMQ0lEOVhqWlZXV2FuQUtuVEtENTJFVlU1ZDBjdFExS2JVYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxORWloYU10TWUtUGdDVF9ad1BhbVhyc1Joc0ZGMVI1NTRuZmlMUTFGZnBKZ0JfNk0zSmdkTnlYQjlrRW5RU191X01xVUNzd3BVV1VGdDBDclFWX0RkZnFyQ1MtWXh4R3huRENJdFFzTFZzYWRIanRVZDRXVWl5d2FUOC1uSUhkMkctTEFKTkRNWEtaVHhrWFhwbVoyRlhPV2xmMjVtSHptMXVzU2pfUkRwQm9PT3NFMjNVNGo2OUpoeVlrcmhSOHlYR2o2MUlja2R0dWRrbzVHU18zckMwc203ZE03ckJ3OUU4N2liYklnM3BoSENj0gH8AUFVX3lxTE5EZGJ4b012NVZBa1YxbHZONzJpeDRWRGtKYUpSLUpRVWR2U0g0WGhMeWtENzNOOXlwN3o1RDViZmtWQ0VIUzlNTmhWR1BoZVRQZkE0U29QME1HMVZWTjBmdlJ0V0RQWnhWV0tMTlVlY0gzYVBEVmxtU25NVG1vYVJKc19SbjVwSFU5WXM3TTRqNnBCT2dsMmNkT1ZVcTFLbUg4MkhibmVqa3Rjb2FrU2ExdlZVWDVQaEVBbHVoWHJhMjhjQm92eUJaM0tnaC1qT3N4cDBuc3pURGRMQ0lEOVhqWlZXV2FuQUtuVEtENTJFVlU1ZDBjdFExS2JVYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 03:40:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WPL 2025 auction: Dottin, Bell, Bist and others to watch out for - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxQcTZtcTg0VTFQeVJlVEZQd1FheTJWUHlDaUFES2Rka1M2cjBUQjEwbmtidVBRZk5BSk5wY1loQTRmMTllMXU2d05FdzFDOWNiRmhNR0xsQ2Y0X3VSUnBJemt5SjluLUhBR1JJa3k4b2RkR2xqQ1hoQU5GbEhubGV5Q2pBUTl1eFRfTFN4UXlyNGtzX0ZIM3Q3MVZyTE1Xd0pKWUxhNERCSkNQWEh3YjNvRWZlbnd1bmhtWXE1MHRMRll0T2VC0gHWAUFVX3lxTE5pNUNBX1FfZHRlMlZmRzdCSzR5UjZtVkU0bmd1MDdXNTN6X05kYXgyY2E2V0dWSENzSUlkMnU1a1haUXNaYWVGR25ZZXRoTnhyNHlrSXRzLUdpUDFidVBWclR5WHl0RWV5WHI5bV9WZzFYWFlfdThtVlVGWHpMa2FnTkdWc01ibml6NXpfV2RsVWJWa0RQUUE0c1dfa2JvaF8xb1RvdVdsRE5jakFEVlVjSWZUTE9PUW42eXg1eEJkb0hQT1lsRDQ2bHB0b3p2ZTVaV3ZJanc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxQcTZtcTg0VTFQeVJlVEZQd1FheTJWUHlDaUFES2Rka1M2cjBUQjEwbmtidVBRZk5BSk5wY1loQTRmMTllMXU2d05FdzFDOWNiRmhNR0xsQ2Y0X3VSUnBJemt5SjluLUhBR1JJa3k4b2RkR2xqQ1hoQU5GbEhubGV5Q2pBUTl1eFRfTFN4UXlyNGtzX0ZIM3Q3MVZyTE1Xd0pKWUxhNERCSkNQWEh3YjNvRWZlbnd1bmhtWXE1MHRMRll0T2VC0gHWAUFVX3lxTE5pNUNBX1FfZHRlMlZmRzdCSzR5UjZtVkU0bmd1MDdXNTN6X05kYXgyY2E2V0dWSENzSUlkMnU1a1haUXNaYWVGR25ZZXRoTnhyNHlrSXRzLUdpUDFidVBWclR5WHl0RWV5WHI5bV9WZzFYWFlfdThtVlVGWHpMa2FnTkdWc01ibml6NXpfV2RsVWJWa0RQUUE0c1dfa2JvaF8xb1RvdVdsRE5jakFEVlVjSWZUTE9PUW42eXg1eEJkb0hQT1lsRDQ2bHB0b3p2ZTVaV3ZJanc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 03:01:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohammed Siraj Receives Harsh Treatment From Gabba Crowd Over Travis Head Controversy - Watch - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxNaGc2a3BNT1FMREJyS0stSFlONlZHbEFzZjRxMWFUamNaYmhoOXBaeWtQeGtHQVptSGI3RGQ2SkJFYkJGOGp0aUNuRTlxMjRBYy1CdWtGR0tLVXJnRmlYREgzMVJrRGVmZEt4TTUxZ2dYX1dSY253SDFDREplUHNjR2QxNHZuZDJBcFFabEFEYVdhbjFTamxBWWtQZ045ZjdWdW5tbEZXbGJJb1U0VkdaMTE0YnZYNGdBS1dLbXJMNDVRbV9CeWFVTWdqOS1haDVTSGZCOVVNM3lKZXRhSWfSAeYBQVVfeXFMTTVpRFhkdEFFWVVuX0VqN3QwaWd0NHVUOHdYRkg4bzZOS2FIOHg1WFFqX2lQS05XX2NBMnVLbkoxZ1pUaHR0YU45LUpEOFhGR1Mwdm13VDVhQmZQTHlZUkFTdkhDb3h4aDVWa2RHRmhhSnlweTlwbkNxV1FTZGpYRG1UMmpoMDZaNC1heTNIcTM0WkRLR09JVkdQcW1sSXlwUlNHV2pRbG9Ebzh0blFQLVVQTVVnQVA0NXNtTWk1c21GV0ZnM05zUmc5U1A5NE5DN20yWG5lMFdjaGVqY1BlNzUxeGFvSUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxNaGc2a3BNT1FMREJyS0stSFlONlZHbEFzZjRxMWFUamNaYmhoOXBaeWtQeGtHQVptSGI3RGQ2SkJFYkJGOGp0aUNuRTlxMjRBYy1CdWtGR0tLVXJnRmlYREgzMVJrRGVmZEt4TTUxZ2dYX1dSY253SDFDREplUHNjR2QxNHZuZDJBcFFabEFEYVdhbjFTamxBWWtQZ045ZjdWdW5tbEZXbGJJb1U0VkdaMTE0YnZYNGdBS1dLbXJMNDVRbV9CeWFVTWdqOS1haDVTSGZCOVVNM3lKZXRhSWfSAeYBQVVfeXFMTTVpRFhkdEFFWVVuX0VqN3QwaWd0NHVUOHdYRkg4bzZOS2FIOHg1WFFqX2lQS05XX2NBMnVLbkoxZ1pUaHR0YU45LUpEOFhGR1Mwdm13VDVhQmZQTHlZUkFTdkhDb3h4aDVWa2RHRmhhSnlweTlwbkNxV1FTZGpYRG1UMmpoMDZaNC1heTNIcTM0WkRLR09JVkdQcW1sSXlwUlNHV2pRbG9Ebzh0blFQLVVQTVVnQVA0NXNtTWk1c21GV0ZnM05zUmc5U1A5NE5DN20yWG5lMFdjaGVqY1BlNzUxeGFvSUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 02:33:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICC To Finalise Hybrid Model For Champions Trophy 2025 On Saturday: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICC To Finalise Hybrid Model For Champions Trophy 2025 On Saturday: Report</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024, 13:13 IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="According to reports, ICC will finalise hybrid model for Champions Trophy 2025 on Saturday." title="According to reports, ICC will finalise hybrid model for Champions Trophy 2025 on Saturday." loading="eager">
    <figcaption>According to reports, ICC will finalise hybrid model for Champions Trophy 2025 on Saturday. (Picture Credit: X/@TheRealPCB)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The International Cricket Council (ICC) is set to finalise the hybrid model for the 2025 edition of the Champions Trophy on Saturday, with significant details emerging regarding the hosting arrangements.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Pakistan is likely to host the Champions Trophy with matches held across three venues.</li>
    <li>India's matches, including three group games, a semi-final, and a final, will take place in the UAE.</li>
    <li>The ICC Board meeting will include new chairman Jay Shah, attending virtually from Brisbane.</li>
    <li>A consensus has reportedly been reached among the ICC, BCCI, and PCB regarding the hybrid model.</li>
    <li>Discussions are ongoing about similar hosting arrangements for future ICC events in India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “It is not clear if the BCCI has agreed to the PCB demand for a similar hybrid model for the ICC events conducted in India over the next few years—a bone of contention between the parties."
</blockquote>
<p>This development marks a significant step for international cricket, especially given the historical context of India and Pakistan's cricketing relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/icc-to-finalise-hybrid-model-for-champions-trophy-2025-on-saturday-report-9155788.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/icc-to-finalise-hybrid-model-for-champions-trophy-2025-on-saturday-report-9155788.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 02:13:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stamp on Champions Trophy hybrid model likely today - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/stamp-on-champions-trophy-hybrid-model-likely-today/articleshow/116304962.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/stamp-on-champions-trophy-hybrid-model-likely-today/articleshow/116304962.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 01:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia: Steve Smith's Dressing Room Activity During 3rd Test Viral, Leaves Internet Intr.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxQOWpuMU9WdGJaM0FTODZGUzBZX2E2aDRKc0tYbUhyRDlyTWZocFFiaC0wV2drOUZGRHpkT3pzb0ZyZUtNOFhzZGxvT2Z6YmJOQXd2VEQ3WTUyNEtlMFBseUpaWHl1WWt5LTZZbUJjTGFVTy04QkVWOUwzU0NZXzdrWGEya2VTdFMybGc0LS1pWm9WanJkbkJjVERGUHU0eHpTa0FyQW5lRjRKRGVDdWczVHVFYUo5bkFUd19zX1ItbEY0QThubUFudkhxdWZYOENtQWdVYlliLUQ1R0lHMDN5RVMycl9UcUdOWm5zS21BNkxyRWvSAfsBQVVfeXFMT184dkxIdDd6blVnMnFweUFRNlNBYWtOcVJNUnVFeUU2MmZUODFldDFEbEVRN19LS2Q2eVNyM1lCTDJLV050enFGUmZsNmt1T1lMd3lQdXBqZThrRHMteFpFSFNUOGNVd3FxQUZ3X19pSS1FRXYxZ1E3ZUJCanRaZzFZTko0MWd0di1RVGV3cTRqU2JfV3hEQWhYNUp2WFRrcDZYdXRtSjZNQlhJOF9sRjBtbVV1dTZ4M3NwR3QxU1JadzNuemU2OU1RRzhmN2doVURPemEyWWtFMktrb3VHS0tmc1psaHhuc1owbTk2UXlBQ2F5SEZSRkc3MlU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxQOWpuMU9WdGJaM0FTODZGUzBZX2E2aDRKc0tYbUhyRDlyTWZocFFiaC0wV2drOUZGRHpkT3pzb0ZyZUtNOFhzZGxvT2Z6YmJOQXd2VEQ3WTUyNEtlMFBseUpaWHl1WWt5LTZZbUJjTGFVTy04QkVWOUwzU0NZXzdrWGEya2VTdFMybGc0LS1pWm9WanJkbkJjVERGUHU0eHpTa0FyQW5lRjRKRGVDdWczVHVFYUo5bkFUd19zX1ItbEY0QThubUFudkhxdWZYOENtQWdVYlliLUQ1R0lHMDN5RVMycl9UcUdOWm5zS21BNkxyRWvSAfsBQVVfeXFMT184dkxIdDd6blVnMnFweUFRNlNBYWtOcVJNUnVFeUU2MmZUODFldDFEbEVRN19LS2Q2eVNyM1lCTDJLV050enFGUmZsNmt1T1lMd3lQdXBqZThrRHMteFpFSFNUOGNVd3FxQUZ3X19pSS1FRXYxZ1E3ZUJCanRaZzFZTko0MWd0di1RVGV3cTRqU2JfV3hEQWhYNUp2WFRrcDZYdXRtSjZNQlhJOF9sRjBtbVV1dTZ4M3NwR3QxU1JadzNuemU2OU1RRzhmN2doVURPemEyWWtFMktrb3VHS0tmc1psaHhuc1owbTk2UXlBQ2F5SEZSRkc3MlU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 01:37:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli earns more pension than Yuvraj Singh, star all-rounder gets only Rs 22500, while Kambli earns Rs... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli earns more pension than Yuvraj Singh, star all-rounder gets only Rs 22500, while Kambli earns Rs...</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/pension-202412-1734138868.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Pension">
<figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption>
<p>Vinod Kambli and Yuvraj Singh, both retired cricket players, receive different pensions from BCCI, with Kambli earning significantly more despite his financial challenges.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Yuvraj Singh receives a pension of ₹22,500 from the BCCI post-retirement.</li>
    <li>Vinod Kambli earns ₹30,000 as a pension, which is his sole source of income.</li>
    <li>Kambli's cricket career spanned from 1991 to 2000, playing in 17 Tests and 104 ODIs.</li>
    <li>Yuvraj Singh had a successful career from 2000 to 2017, known for his contributions to India's T20 and ODI World Cup victories.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "According to media reports, Vinod Kambli, who has no savings, relies completely on his pension from the BCCI."
</blockquote>
<p>This stark difference in pension highlights the varying financial situations of retired athletes, underscoring the necessity for better financial planning and support for sports professionals after retirement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/vinod-kambli-earns-more-pension-than-yuvraj-singh-star-all-rounder-gets-only-rs-22500-while-kambli-earns-rs-414193/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/vinod-kambli-earns-more-pension-than-yuvraj-singh-star-all-rounder-gets-only-rs-22500-while-kambli-earns-rs-414193/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 01:24:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australia’s booing crowd should know Mohammed Siraj’s back story - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australia’s booing crowd should know Mohammed Siraj’s back story</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Mohammed-Siraj-2.jpg?w=640" alt="Mohammed Siraj, Siraj" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>India's Mohammed Siraj tosses the ball as he prepares to bowl on the day one of the third cricket test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane, Australia. (AP)</figcaption>
<p>Mohammed Siraj showcased his determination in a recent match despite facing challenges during his performance against Australia, emphasizing his potential as a key player.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Siraj took his first wicket after 21 overs in the second Test at Adelaide.</li>
    <li>He achieved figures of 4/98 in 24.4 overs during the match.</li>
    <li>Throughout his initial overs, Siraj displayed impressive pace and rhythm but struggled to secure wickets.</li>
    <li>His performance characterized by a mix of frustration and charm highlighted his amateurish yet endearing style.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Siraj would look exasperated, he would wipe the sweat on his face with his untucked shirt. There has always been something charmingly amateurish about Siraj.”</blockquote>
<p>Siraj's story serves as a reminder of the challenges athletes face and the perseverance required to succeed in competitive sports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/australias-booing-crowd-should-know-mohammed-sirajs-back-story-9724123/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/australias-booing-crowd-should-know-mohammed-sirajs-back-story-9724123/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:54:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India drop Reddy; Kashyap, Bist, Rawal get maiden call-ups for West Indies series - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India drop Reddy; Kashyap, Bist, Rawal get maiden call-ups for West Indies series</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p>
<p>Opener Shafali Verma continues to miss out from both squads after being dropped for the ODIs against Australia, and several new players have been called up for the upcoming West Indies series.</p>
<ul>
    <li>D Hemalatha out from the T20I squad, Radha Yadav misses out in ODIs despite being the highest wicket-taker against New Zealand.</li>
    <li>Injuries keep Yastika Bhatia, Shreyanka Patil, and Priya Punia off the squad.</li>
    <li>Nandini Kashyap, Raghvi Bist, and Pratika Rawal receive their first call-ups.</li>
    <li>Kashyap was the top scorer for Uttarakhand with 247 runs in the Senior Women's T20 Trophy.</li>
    <li>Bist impressed with consistent performances in domestic cricket and India A series.</li>
    <li>Rawal made headlines with an unbeaten 161 runs in a domestic one-day match.</li>
    <li>The West Indies series consists of three T20Is and three ODIs starting December 15.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Reddy has been left out of the squad despite finishing as India's joint-highest wicket-taker in the T20 World Cup, with seven wickets in four games."</blockquote>
<p>The West Indies series marks an important opportunity for emerging players, while notable performers like Reddy will continue to play in domestic tournaments to regain their spots.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/ind-vs-wi-women-2024-arundhati-reddy-dropped-kashyap-bist-rawal-handed-maiden-call-ups-1464853</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/ind-vs-wi-women-2024-arundhati-reddy-dropped-kashyap-bist-rawal-handed-maiden-call-ups-1464853</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 18:22:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Babar Azam Creates History, Becomes First Player In The World To... - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Babar Azam Creates History, Becomes First Player In The World To....</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified | <strong>Source: </strong>Times Now News</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116298189,thumbsize-1457674,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116298189.jpg" alt="Babar Azam T20I vs SA 2024 AP" title="Babar Azam T20I vs SA 2024 AP">
<figcaption>Babar Azam set a massive world record. Photo: AP</figcaption>
<p>Babar Azam made headlines by breaking a significant T20 cricket milestone, becoming the fastest player to reach 11,000 runs in the format in less than 300 innings.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Babar Azam registered a massive world record.</li>
    <li>Babar became the first player to achieve a unique feat.</li>
    <li>Babar joined Shoaib Malik in a rare club as the second Pakistani to reach 11,000 T20 runs.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Babar became the fastest player in history to achieve 11,000 T20 runs in just 298 innings.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Babar Azam's remarkable achievement solidifies his place in cricket history, showcasing his skill and consistency in the T20 format.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/babar-azam-creates-history-becomes-first-player-in-the-world-to-score-11000-t20-runs-in-less-than-300-innings-article-116297570</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/babar-azam-creates-history-becomes-first-player-in-the-world-to-score-11000-t20-runs-in-less-than-300-innings-article-116297570</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 17:47:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>