<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:26:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:26:49 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smriti Mandhana breaks record, smashes fastest ODI century by an Indian woman - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Smriti Mandhana breaks record, smashes fastest ODI century by an Indian woman</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Smriti Mandhana has made history by scoring the fastest century in One Day Internationals by an Indian woman.</p><ul><li>Mandhana reached her century in just 50 balls.</li><li>This record-breaking performance highlights her exceptional skills in women's cricket.</li><li>The achievement has garnered widespread recognition and praise within the cricketing community.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a proud moment for Indian women's cricket,” said a cricket expert.</blockquote><p>Mandhana's accomplishment not only sets a new benchmark but also inspires upcoming female cricketers across the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/smriti-mandhana-breaks-record-smashes-fastest-odi-century-by-an-indian-woman/articleshow/117259192.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/smriti-mandhana-breaks-record-smashes-fastest-odi-century-by-an-indian-woman/articleshow/117259192.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Djokovic battles past another Grand Slam debutant - ATP Tour]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Novak Djokovic battles past another Grand Slam debutant to reach the Australian Open third round</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ATP Tour</p>
<img src="/-/media/images/news/2025/01/15/06/44/djokovic-australian-open-2025-r2-celebration.jpg" alt="Novak Djokovic claims sole ownership of the all-time record for Grand Slam singles matches played with 430.">
<figcaption>Novak Djokovic celebrates his victory during the match.</figcaption>
<p>Novak Djokovic fought through a challenging match against Grand Slam debutant Jaime Faria, securing his spot in the third round of the Australian Open after winning in four sets.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Djokovic displayed resilience after dropping a set to Faria.</li>
  <li>The match lasted over three hours, showcasing Djokovic's experience and skill.</li>
  <li>This victory marks Djokovic's 430th Grand Slam singles match, setting a new all-time record.</li>
  <li>Next, he will face 26th seed Tomas Machac, who won his previous match in a five-set thriller.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I try to give my best every single time. It's been over 20 years that I've been competing in Grand Slams at the highest level." - Novak Djokovic</blockquote>
<p>Djokovic continues his pursuit of a 25th major singles title and aims to become the oldest player in the Open Era to win a Grand Slam.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.atptour.com/en/news/djokovic-faria-australian-open-2025-r2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atptour.com/en/news/djokovic-faria-australian-open-2025-r2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:03:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SA20 2025: Match 9, PR vs MICT Match Prediction – Who will win today’s SA20 match between PR vs MICT? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SA20 2025: Match 9, PR vs MICT Match Prediction</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><figure><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736848216200_image_2025_01_14T09_49_52_220Z.png" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>Paarl Royals (PR) will face MI Cape Town (MICT) in the ninth match of SA20 2025 at Boland Park, Paarl. MICT emerged victorious in their last encounter, and they are currently leading the points table while PR is looking to improve their position.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li><strong>Previous Encounter:</strong> MICT won by 33 runs.</li><li><strong>Points Table:</strong> PR has 2 points; MICT is at the top.</li><li><strong>Venue:</strong> Boland Park, Paarl</li><li><strong>Match Time:</strong> 9:00 PM (IST)</li><li><strong>Live Broadcast:</strong> Star Sports, Sports18 Network, Disney+ Hotstar</li></ul><h3>Pitch Report:</h3><p>The pitch at Boland Park is expected to favor batters, but bowlers will need to adjust to the low bounce and lack of pace. Spinners might find turn, making them crucial in the match.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Today's Match Prediction:</strong> The team bowling first is likely to win.</p></blockquote><p>Scenarios depend on the toss: PR may post scores around 140-150 if batting first, while MICT might reach 135-145.</p><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> With MICT riding high on confidence and a recent win, they are the favorites against PR, who need to secure a victory to boost their standings in the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-9-pr-vs-mict-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-pr-vs-mict-2852/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-9-pr-vs-mict-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-pr-vs-mict-2852/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI Grills Gautam Gambhir, Rohit Sharma On Test Slump, Gets 'IPL Salaries' As Answer - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Grills Gautam Gambhir, Rohit Sharma On Test Slump, Gets 'IPL Salaries' As Answer</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 27, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dsts7h3g_gautam-gambhir-rohit-sharma-afp_625x300_27_October_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="BCCI Meeting" />
<figcaption>File photo of Gautam Gambhir and Rohit Sharma © BCCI/Sportzpics</figcaption>
<p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) recently held a meeting with chief selector Ajit Agarkar, head coach Gautam Gambhir, and Test captain Rohit Sharma concerning India's poor performance in Test cricket.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The team management was questioned about recent Test losses, particularly against Australia and New Zealand.</li>
  <li>A member of the management attributed the poor performances to high salaries from the IPL affecting players' commitment to Test cricket.</li>
  <li>Changes are being implemented by the BCCI, including restrictions on family time during tours and transport regulations for players.</li>
  <li>For long tours, players can have family with them for a maximum of 14 days.</li>
  <li>During shorter tours abroad, immediate family can stay for one week.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The BCCI will limit the players spending time with their families on tours.</blockquote>
<p>This recent meeting aims to address the issues surrounding the Indian Test cricket team's performance and find ways to improve in the upcoming series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/asked-about-test-slump-gautam-gambhir-led-team-management-blames-big-ipl-salaries-report-7476303</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/asked-about-test-slump-gautam-gambhir-led-team-management-blames-big-ipl-salaries-report-7476303</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:30:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Team Was Without Captain, Vice-captain, Coach": Gavaskar Blasts Rohit, Gambhir In Message To BCCI - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"Team Was Without Captain, Vice-captain, Coach": Gavaskar Blasts Rohit, Gambhir In Message To BCCI</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> [Publication Date] | NDTV</p>
<p>Sunil Gavaskar has expressed his frustration regarding the absence of the team captain, vice-captain, and coach during a crucial match, calling it a significant oversight by the BCCI.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gavaskar criticized the leadership structure of the team.</li>
  <li>Highlighted the need for consistent leadership in sports.</li>
  <li>Stressed that such decisions can impact team morale.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"It was unacceptable for the team to be without its leadership during such a pivotal moment." - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote>
<p>This situation raises critical questions about the management decisions leading up to important matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/team-was-without-captain-vice-captain-coach-sunil-gavaskar-blasts-rohit-sharma-gautam-gambhir-in-message-to-bcci-7471599</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/team-was-without-captain-vice-captain-coach-sunil-gavaskar-blasts-rohit-sharma-gautam-gambhir-in-message-to-bcci-7471599</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BBL 2024-2025: Match 35, STR vs SIX Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between STR vs SIX? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BBL 2024-2025: Match 35 Prediction – STR vs SIX</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736844575276_image_2025_01_14T08_48_38_105Z.png" alt="Match Prediction" width="700" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Match Prediction Image</figcaption><p>Today, the Adelaide Strikers (STR) will face off against the Sydney Sixers (SIX) at the Adelaide Oval in match 35 of the BBL 2024-25 season. STR seeks redemption as they fight to improve their standings, while SIX aims to maintain their position near the top.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>STR is currently 6th on the points table with 3 wins and 5 losses.</li><li>SIX is 2nd with 5 wins, 2 losses, and 1 no result.</li><li>The match will take place at Adelaide Oval at 2:00 PM IST.</li><li>STR's last few games show improvement, needing to capitalize on this momentum.</li><li>SIX's Steven Smith is expected to be a key player after scoring 121 runs in his last match.</li><li>Pitch conditions will favor batting, as shown by previous matches at this venue.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Sydney Sixers to win the match,” according to match predictions.</p></blockquote><p>In conclusion, the match promises to be exciting as both teams fight for crucial points</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-35-str-vs-six-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-str-vs-six/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-35-str-vs-six-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-str-vs-six/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 05:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Silent' Virat Kohli Sent Blunt Ranji Trophy Message By Delhi State Body - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxQRGtHbG93YUdDNVZoZ2h0YXNiU2k2X2tCb3pxMnE0cENvOXFlanJzY2J5a2VNOTZYOVVDRlhKVWk3b2pGdnRwMVFRazlCbXdoN01Fd3phM0xpU0ZPbVFyUF9IQVVjRDBhTTVYY2JWUmpabWFhMXI1YUIyUFctWjNja3JBM1M1bVVDWGFXUGdOeGFrdW4weVpQZnI0M0VWWlVza1kxcXhuem0xQTdOT1V3Mmd5WXhFdFE1QjJsbnN6NDFLX241N0praTFrUdIB0wFBVV95cUxNWEhJTGtkQ3RFbzJFVURJc0M1LTRpMF9KWTAzMDdXV0JsSnVfLWlJLXVOeW9sWURRQXZrb0dhZldtRE1wXy1CTnMwVXlGQl9PNkNwUGI5VjVnNzIyMEZJNUdNSEZ3TC1kUy1EdVNGRU0yb0NoeEhKdVB6NUFKRkM3bVlmMlF2TmloU0Q1a01lX0RHV0l6TTNtWFZFNjgwbGp2eUZUdDM2YVRONjRNLWJRaDJmbjljTk9xVDBiMi1RX0dHUW92UlFKbVRBcFZ6MG9XY3Iw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxQRGtHbG93YUdDNVZoZ2h0YXNiU2k2X2tCb3pxMnE0cENvOXFlanJzY2J5a2VNOTZYOVVDRlhKVWk3b2pGdnRwMVFRazlCbXdoN01Fd3phM0xpU0ZPbVFyUF9IQVVjRDBhTTVYY2JWUmpabWFhMXI1YUIyUFctWjNja3JBM1M1bVVDWGFXUGdOeGFrdW4weVpQZnI0M0VWWlVza1kxcXhuem0xQTdOT1V3Mmd5WXhFdFE1QjJsbnN6NDFLX241N0praTFrUdIB0wFBVV95cUxNWEhJTGtkQ3RFbzJFVURJc0M1LTRpMF9KWTAzMDdXV0JsSnVfLWlJLXVOeW9sWURRQXZrb0dhZldtRE1wXy1CTnMwVXlGQl9PNkNwUGI5VjVnNzIyMEZJNUdNSEZ3TC1kUy1EdVNGRU0yb0NoeEhKdVB6NUFKRkM3bVlmMlF2TmloU0Q1a01lX0RHV0l6TTNtWFZFNjgwbGp2eUZUdDM2YVRONjRNLWJRaDJmbjljTk9xVDBiMi1RX0dHUW92UlFKbVRBcFZ6MG9XY3Iw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 05:44:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Big fan of Tendulkar doesn't mean I will talk poorly of Dravid': Ashwin criticises fan wars on social me - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashwin Critiques Social Media Fan Wars Over Cricket Legends</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><p>Ashwin addresses the toxic nature of fan rivalries on social media, emphasizing that admiration for one cricket legend shouldn't lead to disparagement of another.</p><ul><li>Ashwin highlights his respect for both Sachin Tendulkar and Rahul Dravid.</li><li>He criticizes the divisive nature of fan cultures online.</li><li>The cricket star advocates for a more respectful environment for discussions about athletes.</li></ul><blockquote>"Being a big fan of Tendulkar doesn't mean I will talk poorly of Dravid."</blockquote><p>Ashwin's comments call for a culture of appreciation over competition in cricket fandom.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/big-fan-of-tendulkar-doesnt-mean-i-will-talk-poorly-of-dravid-ashwin-criticises-fan-wars-on-social-media/articleshow/117255218.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/big-fan-of-tendulkar-doesnt-mean-i-will-talk-poorly-of-dravid-ashwin-criticises-fan-wars-on-social-media/articleshow/117255218.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 05:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inside photos of Vinod Kambli's luxurious Rs 80000000 home in Mumbai - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Inside photos of Vinod Kambli's luxurious Rs 80000000 home in Mumbai</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/inside-photos-of-vinod-kamblis-luxurious-rs-80000000-home-in-mumbai-202501-1736917203.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Inside photos of Vinod Kambli's luxurious Rs 80000000 home in Mumbai">
<figcaption>Image credit: X (Formerly Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>Vinod Kambli, a former Indian cricketer, owns a lavish 3 BHK flat in Mumbai's Jewel Tower, valued at approximately Rs 8 crore. The residence is decorated with beautifully done up interiors and spaces dedicated to his memories.</p>
<ul>
<li>The flat measures about 1600 square feet.</li>
<li>Kambli's home features a wall dedicated to his friendship with Sachin Tendulkar, showcasing many portraits together.</li>
<li>It includes a modular kitchen and a large living area for hosting family and friends.</li>
<li>Kambli faces a financial issue, owing about Rs 18 lakh for maintenance, marking him as a defaulter in the society's lobby.</li>
<li>He celebrated Christmas with his family in a grand manner, highlighting the familial ties.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Vinod Kambli converted to Christianity in 2012 on the insistence of his wife.”</blockquote>
<p>The opulent lifestyle of Vinod Kambli reflects both his illustrious cricketing career and current life challenges, painting a complete picture of his journey.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/inside-photos-of-vinod-kambli-luxurious-rs-80000000-home-in-mumbai-420045/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/inside-photos-of-vinod-kambli-luxurious-rs-80000000-home-in-mumbai-420045/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 05:24:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shami is set to return to the T20I format against England after a lengthy absence of 14 months. The nation will be optimistic about his fitness and hopes he will be included in India's team for the upcoming ICC Champions Trophy 2025. - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammed Shami Set to Return to T20I Format Against England</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/mohammed-shami-202501-1736917163.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Mohammed Shami">
<figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption>
<p>After a lengthy absence of 14 months, Mohammed Shami is poised to make his comeback in the T20I format for India against England. The nation is hopeful regarding his fitness ahead of the ICC Champions Trophy 2025.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shami's return is highly anticipated after a significant gap due to injuries.</li>
  <li>His performance could be crucial for India's prospects in the upcoming ICC Champions Trophy.</li>
  <li>The cricketing community is optimistic about his readiness to compete at the highest level once again.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Shami is literally a machine in ODI format. He is no less than Bumrah in the 50 over format." - Cricket expert</blockquote>
<p>Shami's comeback not only relieves pressure on the bowling line-up but also offers renewed hope to fans and teammates alike as the national team gears up for a busy tournament season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/shami-is-set-to-return-to-the-t20i-format-against-england-after-a-lengthy-absence-of-14-months-the-nation-will-be-optimistic-about-his-fitness-and-hopes-he-will-be-included-in-indias-team-for-the-u-420044/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/shami-is-set-to-return-to-the-t20i-format-against-england-after-a-lengthy-absence-of-14-months-the-nation-will-be-optimistic-about-his-fitness-and-hopes-he-will-be-included-in-indias-team-for-the-u-420044/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 05:05:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['If he hadn't played, we would have won': R Ashwin credits Scott Boland as game-changer in India's BGT lo - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/if-he-hadnt-played-we-would-have-won-r-ashwin-credits-scott-boland-as-game-changer-in-indias-bgt-loss/articleshow/117254232.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/if-he-hadnt-played-we-would-have-won-r-ashwin-credits-scott-boland-as-game-changer-in-indias-bgt-loss/articleshow/117254232.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 05:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On this day: India crush Sri Lanka by 317 runs to record biggest ODI win - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India achieved a record ODI victory, defeating Sri Lanka by 317 runs, the largest margin in ODI history.</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> HT Sports Desk</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/CRICKET-ICC-MENS-WC-2023-IND-SRI-ODI-37_1698916771135_1736916861661.jpg" alt="Shubman Gill and Virat Kohli scored centuries in India's record ODI win against Sri Lanka at Thiruvananthapuram.(AFP)"><figcaption>Shubman Gill and Virat Kohli scored centuries in India's record ODI win against Sri Lanka at Thiruvananthapuram.(AFP)</figcaption><p>On this day in 2023, India put up a historic display of dominance with both bat and ball by securing the largest victory margin in One Day International (ODI) cricket history, defeating Sri Lanka by 317 runs at the Greenfield International Stadium in Thiruvananthapuram.</p><ul><li>India batted first, scoring 390 for 5 in 50 overs.</li><li>Shubman Gill scored 116 runs, and Virat Kohli scored 166 runs.</li><li>Sri Lanka was bowled out for 73 runs in 22 overs.</li><li>India's bowling attack featured Mohammed Siraj taking 4 wickets for 32 runs.</li><li>This match secured a 3-0 series whitewash for India.</li></ul><blockquote>India's 317-run victory surpassed the previous record for the largest run-margin of victory in ODIs.</blockquote><p>This remarkable win not only signifies India's cricketing prowess but also establishes a new benchmark in ODI history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/on-this-day-india-crush-sri-lanka-by-317-runs-to-record-biggest-odi-win-101736915817822.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/on-this-day-india-crush-sri-lanka-by-317-runs-to-record-biggest-odi-win-101736915817822.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:59:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Takeaways: Osaka engineers gutsy comeback to set Bencic clash in Melbourne - WTA Tennis]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Osaka's Gutsy Comeback Sets Up Bencic Clash at Australian Open</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 3 hours ago | <strong>Source:</strong> WTA Tennis</p>
<p><img src='IMAGE_URL' alt='Naomi Osaka in action' />
<figcaption>Naomi Osaka celebrates her victory at Australian Open.</figcaption></p>
<p>Naomi Osaka makes a significant comeback from a set down to defeat Karolina Muchova, proceeding to the third round of the Australian Open for the first time since her return from maternity leave.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Osaka defeated Muchova 1-6, 6-1, 6-3 in the second round.</li>
  <li>This marks her first Grand Slam third-round appearance since returning from maternity leave.</li>
  <li>Osaka emphasized the importance of her mental game in her comeback efforts.</li>
  <li>Next, she faces Belinda Bencic, who has a competitive record against her.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"After the first set, I just told myself, fight for every point," said Osaka.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Osaka showcases resilience and determination, setting the stage for an exciting match against fellow mother Bencic.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wtatennis.com/news/4198752/takeaways-osaka-engineers-gutsy-comeback-to-set-bencic-clash-in-melbourne</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wtatennis.com/news/4198752/takeaways-osaka-engineers-gutsy-comeback-to-set-bencic-clash-in-melbourne</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:47:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Stars Carrying Over 150 Kg Luggage Sent Strong Message By BCCI, "Red Flag" Raised For This Act.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Implements New Travel Rules for Indian Cricket Team Following Australia Tour</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 25, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/9sbda6io_rohit-kohli-bumrah-kl-rahul_625x300_14_January_25.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="India Stars Carrying Over 150 Kg Luggage Sent Strong Message By BCCI, &quot;Red Flag&quot; Raised For This Act">
<figcaption>File photo of the Indian cricket team in Australia © X/Twitter</figcaption>
<p>The BCCI is instituting strict new rules for the Indian cricket team's travel following a disappointing tour of Australia, which resulted in a 1-3 series loss. Key changes include restrictions on family members’ attendance and luggage weight limits.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Limitations on the presence of spouses during tours: two weeks for tours over 45 days, one week for shorter tours.</li>
  <li>Mandatory use of team bus for all players and support staff during tours.</li>
  <li>Players to bear costs for any luggage exceeding 150 kg; BCCI will only cover up to that amount.</li>
  <li>Concerns over personal managers traveling on the team bus highlighted by a board official.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The other interesting thing that caught my eye is BCCI will pay till 150kgs for a player baggage. Over and above to be paid by the player. Why would anyone need over 150 kgs of luggage on a cricket tour?? No cricket kit-bag can exceed 40 kgs. — Aakash Chopra (@cricketaakash) <a href="https://twitter.com/cricketaakash/status/1879111317522641352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 14, 2025</a></blockquote>
<p>The changes were discussed during a review meeting which included team management and follow serious performance concerns after the recent tour. The BCCI aims to enhance team discipline and streamline travel protocols.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/india-stars-carrying-over-150-kg-luggage-sent-strong-message-by-bcci-red-flag-raised-for-this-act-7472838</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/india-stars-carrying-over-150-kg-luggage-sent-strong-message-by-bcci-red-flag-raised-for-this-act-7472838</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:45:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma To Attend Champions Trophy Opening Ceremony In Pakistan: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxPN21lMGlBSnBwWVZKcERXX3RoLUhMLVNkdnduS1NocHd6LUpmbng4dXJ2T1haRUh6bU5MVE9DZkZkZmRILURXNFk5OEpiRmVqVXFXQTJobzNfb1BFS0hjdTRMdHNEaEJ2NXZ3MmNLWXhFTkdmemdzSWd2azk5aGtMMGJBRUEzdnVIcWowX0s1M1hvamJUSzR1VEl5QUVGMXVKNVVEdTRFeDBxTVBtLXZBRExBQUpxYlotWHA00gHAAUFVX3lxTE9hZ1RwMTJ3VjVGRnoxdU8tOE1jNjNPNUVSYmIwakJTd1hOTHpMSjNUaUM1SkpoWTUxQU9EVFZmLU53X0Z3QVgxVGlGNTFERGRENnRrREJrSjFuNEZ4N291cVBuU0VmSXAyWmtWbi1oX2xMblRGc2dOWGNmaEk5a2xRZjRxVzlhb3ZwTzJDY3hGVk1BZGRTS0U1NUh1bVViN0FGUmJiM3FmU0l0TmI2TTI0MzdpWFZmT0Z0QVBkTlpXdA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxPN21lMGlBSnBwWVZKcERXX3RoLUhMLVNkdnduS1NocHd6LUpmbng4dXJ2T1haRUh6bU5MVE9DZkZkZmRILURXNFk5OEpiRmVqVXFXQTJobzNfb1BFS0hjdTRMdHNEaEJ2NXZ3MmNLWXhFTkdmemdzSWd2azk5aGtMMGJBRUEzdnVIcWowX0s1M1hvamJUSzR1VEl5QUVGMXVKNVVEdTRFeDBxTVBtLXZBRExBQUpxYlotWHA00gHAAUFVX3lxTE9hZ1RwMTJ3VjVGRnoxdU8tOE1jNjNPNUVSYmIwakJTd1hOTHpMSjNUaUM1SkpoWTUxQU9EVFZmLU53X0Z3QVgxVGlGNTFERGRENnRrREJrSjFuNEZ4N291cVBuU0VmSXAyWmtWbi1oX2xMblRGc2dOWGNmaEk5a2xRZjRxVzlhb3ZwTzJDY3hGVk1BZGRTS0U1NUh1bVViN0FGUmJiM3FmU0l0TmI2TTI0MzdpWFZmT0Z0QVBkTlpXdA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:33:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli struggles to walk, touches Sunil Gavaskar's feet - WATCH - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli struggles to walk, touches Sunil Gavaskar's feet - WATCH</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Available | <strong>Source:</strong> Not Available</p><p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli was seen struggling to walk but managed to touch the feet of legendary cricketer Sunil Gavaskar during a recent event, highlighting his respect and admiration for the cricketing icon.</p><ul><li>Vinod Kambli, once a celebrated cricketer, is facing mobility challenges.</li><li>He touched the feet of Sunil Gavaskar, showcasing a gesture of respect.</li><li>The public was moved by the sight, drawing sympathy and support for Kambli.</li></ul><blockquote>"It's heartwarming to see such respect, even in tough times."</blockquote><p>The incident serves as a reminder of Kambli's illustrious career and the struggles he faces now.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-struggles-to-walk-touches-sunil-gavaskars-feet-watch/articleshow/117252705.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-struggles-to-walk-touches-sunil-gavaskars-feet-watch/articleshow/117252705.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Captain Rohit Sharma To Visit Pakistan Ahead Of Champions Trophy, Report Explains Reason - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxQdV9Ic2xxbWpRTEdRQzNoMzEzVzFxbTNfLUpLREZGMHlkc1NqM2Nabkk0WUJrVnBmYmRNV2tsZUFKTGE0SlpzWndhNC0tV3VhM3lvZHRnWnlwUjl0aWxfeFlpRm5rMnlheHJGaFY0dWZYVDB5S3I4US1SNlZnOGVUWVZvQ2VFd2lGN2V4Qm54NmFwRXhlZm1IdW42TkdtcjdMRElYcmtqNzFET0liRmQ0VXZFU3NDNTA3R2c4ektzdEc0a2NlN2dFU0JnOFhVUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxQdV9Ic2xxbWpRTEdRQzNoMzEzVzFxbTNfLUpLREZGMHlkc1NqM2Nabkk0WUJrVnBmYmRNV2tsZUFKTGE0SlpzWndhNC0tV3VhM3lvZHRnWnlwUjl0aWxfeFlpRm5rMnlheHJGaFY0dWZYVDB5S3I4US1SNlZnOGVUWVZvQ2VFd2lGN2V4Qm54NmFwRXhlZm1IdW42TkdtcjdMRElYcmtqNzFET0liRmQ0VXZFU3NDNTA3R2c4ektzdEc0a2NlN2dFU0JnOFhVUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:04:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man City have got £63m transfer priority right after late Brentford collapse - Manchester Evening News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxNbGhZOVg3OGJJbUVZY3F0Z3NhOEhkenhmSFRQNC1BR1ZIQTRib0x1eF9uUUk0cnZxSnhObzM4MzFYZGlHNXBMTmloX2R0blBMNXlXWU1tZi0tQVdFT0dzSGo2dW9YWmV2MUk2UG1OaGNoYjJ4WndVMUNzZ0lvZ1g5ejl4MEhpczRkOXRaRjFTRzYwT1RaNVJ0bUxB0gGfAUFVX3lxTE1adkZyT01qODdjRHhKTVFUWHhHazZ5U2pXcG9VYVNDZVU0aF9YZ1dmMHBWZTM2VnhXZDlXQlk2SzdBaEZxN09mY3RwUGVtRk5WUjV6LWpUTE1FajVxSG5fVXIwSWpfYmU2bWljNWRXc0txcTNvWGx3TXRzUHo4QVllRTMtZ0x3TGpTWFo0bXlQM0x6Q20yX3lvcHptdEZocw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxNbGhZOVg3OGJJbUVZY3F0Z3NhOEhkenhmSFRQNC1BR1ZIQTRib0x1eF9uUUk0cnZxSnhObzM4MzFYZGlHNXBMTmloX2R0blBMNXlXWU1tZi0tQVdFT0dzSGo2dW9YWmV2MUk2UG1OaGNoYjJ4WndVMUNzZ0lvZ1g5ejl4MEhpczRkOXRaRjFTRzYwT1RaNVJ0bUxB0gGfAUFVX3lxTE1adkZyT01qODdjRHhKTVFUWHhHazZ5U2pXcG9VYVNDZVU0aF9YZ1dmMHBWZTM2VnhXZDlXQlk2SzdBaEZxN09mY3RwUGVtRk5WUjV6LWpUTE1FajVxSG5fVXIwSWpfYmU2bWljNWRXc0txcTNvWGx3TXRzUHo4QVllRTMtZ0x3TGpTWFo0bXlQM0x6Q20yX3lvcHptdEZocw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chess Icons Anand, Gukesh, Praggnanandhaa, And Vidit Celebrate Pongal With Dance; Fans Go Crazy - Pune Pulse]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQcG5fa3M4NEJhRHdMOFRzdVJfU195VVJqZENfekx2VlhsQmEyRnBuNFhZeVpVTEdIU3R5YTZuMklmU21rZ2w1TWprWWI3QzE2VWxEcHR1NTl4ay11a0FLM1ByRHNLLUFESkJrU0ZJUWRpclU2cFZacWNuTXN2WGx5VGtjd2lESHI4ckh2WVBVZncxajROdHlXQnhEaG5qS205YzFCcU4tTTFISlQzMnBoTFgyLUQ1Q2JLLXVwTw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQcG5fa3M4NEJhRHdMOFRzdVJfU195VVJqZENfekx2VlhsQmEyRnBuNFhZeVpVTEdIU3R5YTZuMklmU21rZ2w1TWprWWI3QzE2VWxEcHR1NTl4ay11a0FLM1ByRHNLLUFESkJrU0ZJUWRpclU2cFZacWNuTXN2WGx5VGtjd2lESHI4ckh2WVBVZncxajROdHlXQnhEaG5qS205YzFCcU4tTTFISlQzMnBoTFgyLUQ1Q2JLLXVwTw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 03:55:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Series Digest - Pakistan Super League, 2025 - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOVFVtbmJyUndZcWg0d2dIVkJHRGNUdm9vT2xjYXVqQ3FVYnFPdXBzazhDNUZqelplWGVBa3NKV3g3OWZTVGNqOWVqMVNBcDJRMnFZMVZ1XzVZSk95T0FONHlkemU5M0tTckpKNHU2OEdaTWt5UkN1dFFnV3dhX3hRU19zWnRWM3FPYUFQNXVn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxOVFVtbmJyUndZcWg0d2dIVkJHRGNUdm9vT2xjYXVqQ3FVYnFPdXBzazhDNUZqelplWGVBa3NKV3g3OWZTVGNqOWVqMVNBcDJRMnFZMVZ1XzVZSk95T0FONHlkemU5M0tTckpKNHU2OEdaTWt5UkN1dFFnV3dhX3hRU19zWnRWM3FPYUFQNXVn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 03:50:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After debacle Down Under, BCCI may cap stay of wives - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After debacle Down Under, BCCI may cap stay of wives</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date of publication not available]</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="BCCI Image" width="300" height="200">
<figcaption>BCCI's latest considerations following their Australian tour</figcaption>
<p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) is contemplating imposing restrictions on the duration spouses can accompany players during overseas tours due to recent controversies and performance issues faced in Australia.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The decision comes after a disappointing tour where the team underperformed.</li>
  <li>Concerns have been raised regarding distractions caused by player’s families during overseas matches.</li>
  <li>BCCI aims to enhance focus and discipline among players in future series.</li>
  <li>Feedback from players and coaching staff is being considered to finalize the policy.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The objective is to maintain a level of professionalism that we believe is necessary for our success on the field." - BCCI Official</blockquote>
<p>This potential move reflects BCCI’s commitment to ensuring that players prioritize their performance, especially in a competitive international cricketing landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/after-debacle-down-under-bcci-may-cap-stay-of-wives/articleshow/117251471.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/after-debacle-down-under-bcci-may-cap-stay-of-wives/articleshow/117251471.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 03:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir reprimanded Morne Morkel in Australia for turning up late at training - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Reprimanded Morne Morkel in Australia for Turning Up Late at Training</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117251425,imgsize-32268,width-400,resizemode-4/117251425.jpg" alt="Gautam Gambhir and Morne Morkel (AFP Photo)" title="Gautam Gambhir and Morne Morkel (AFP Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Gautam Gambhir and Morne Morkel (AFP Photo)</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team faces challenges during its Australia tour, particularly between head coach Gautam Gambhir and bowling coach Morne Morkel over a punctuality issue.</p><ul><li>Morne Morkel arrived late to a training session due to a personal meeting.</li><li>Gautam Gambhir, known for his strict discipline, reprimanded Morkel promptly.</li><li>Reports suggest Morkel was reserved for the remainder of the tour following the incident.</li><li>BCCI is monitoring the support staff’s performance closely.</li><li>Senior players are giving feedback on the support staff’s contributions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Gambhir is very strict about discipline. He reprimanded Morkel immediately at the ground,” a BCCI source mentioned.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the internal dynamics of the coaching staff and the emphasis on discipline and accountability in the Indian team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/gautam-gambhir-reprimanded-morne-morkel-in-australia-for-turning-up-late-at-training/articleshow/117251370.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/gautam-gambhir-reprimanded-morne-morkel-in-australia-for-turning-up-late-at-training/articleshow/117251370.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 03:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yashasvi Jaiswal available to play Ranji Trophy for Mumbai - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yashasvi Jaiswal Available for Ranji Trophy Match with Mumbai</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/New-Project-2025-01-14T195057.712.jpg?w=640" alt="Yashasvi Jaiswal isn't part of the T20 squad for the five-match series against England and is set to join the Mumbai team practice session at the Wankhede Stadium on Wednesday. (PTI)" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Yashasvi Jaiswal isn't part of the T20 squad for the five-match series against England and is set to join the Mumbai team practice session at the Wankhede Stadium on Wednesday. (PTI)</figcaption>
<p>India Test opener Yashasvi Jaiswal will be participating in the next Ranji Trophy game for Mumbai against Jammu and Kashmir on January 23.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jaiswal has had a remarkable performance on his recent tour of Australia, scoring a century and a half-century.</li>
  <li>The Mumbai Cricket Association has confirmed his availability for the upcoming match.</li>
  <li>Rohit Sharma and Ajinkya Rahane are also linked with the Mumbai team for the match against Jammu.</li>
  <li>Sarfaraz Khan is ruled out of the match due to a rib injury.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Domestic cricket forms the backbone of Indian cricket and serves as the feeder line to Team India.” – Jay Shah, former BCCI Secretary</blockquote>
<p>The return of Jaiswal is a significant boost for the Mumbai team as they seek to strengthen their performance in the Ranji Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/yashasvi-jaiswal-available-mumbai-ranji-trophy-match-rohit-sharma-9778901/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/yashasvi-jaiswal-available-mumbai-ranji-trophy-match-rohit-sharma-9778901/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 02:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India’s Paris Olympics winners, including star shooters, complain about discoloured medals, want them replaced - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/sport-others/india-paris-olympics-discoloured-medals-shooters-swapnil-manu-9779124/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/sport-others/india-paris-olympics-discoloured-medals-shooters-swapnil-manu-9779124/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 02:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R Ashwin breaks silence on not receiving 'farewell': 'Always better to finish when people ask why...' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>R Ashwin Explains His Sudden Retirement from International Cricket</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/PTI12-24-2024-000264A-0_1736909052418_1736909065242.jpg" alt="R Ashwin (PTI)"><figcaption>R Ashwin (PTI)</figcaption><p>In a surprising turn, Ravichandran Ashwin announced his retirement from international cricket during the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy, shocking fans and the cricketing community.</p><ul><li>Ashwin, who retires at 38, ended his career after becoming India's second-highest wicket-taker in Tests.</li><li>He stated that he felt it was the right time to step away, citing a personal sense of completion.</li><li>Ashwin expressed that he did not desire a farewell Test and emphasized the temporary nature of such ceremonies.</li><li>His legacy includes 537 Test wickets in 106 matches, alongside 765 wickets across all formats.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is always better to finish when people ask ‘why’ and not ‘why not.”</blockquote><p>Ashwin's departure marks a significant moment in Indian cricket, leaving a profound legacy and sparking discussions about the future of the sport in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/r-ashwin-breaks-silence-on-not-receiving-farewell-always-better-to-finish-when-people-asky-why-101736904837490.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/r-ashwin-breaks-silence-on-not-receiving-farewell-always-better-to-finish-when-people-asky-why-101736904837490.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 02:45:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Ireland , free match prediction 15 January 2025 - TheTopBookies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNWWJMTHlPQVpDSXZEcG01SHZQVEJQeHU2c0R4aUVCeXBLNjY2V2pjU2NNclZQeDJ4SU1JTmVSeU10b1pFU2lHYkdrcHFSWjBKNk12SGFsdGd5SUcwRXVFR0hGOG5EUFdIQ0ZuMGhkMV96NGF3VzZtRjhLWTFMbFB1Y1lR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNWWJMTHlPQVpDSXZEcG01SHZQVEJQeHU2c0R4aUVCeXBLNjY2V2pjU2NNclZQeDJ4SU1JTmVSeU10b1pFU2lHYkdrcHFSWjBKNk12SGFsdGd5SUcwRXVFR0hGOG5EUFdIQ0ZuMGhkMV96NGF3VzZtRjhLWTFMbFB1Y1lR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 02:42:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Siegemund upsets Zheng; Sabalenka holds on at Australian Open - WTA Tennis]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Siegemund Upsets Zheng; Sabalenka Survives a Tough Match at Australian Open</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2 hours ago</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> WTA Tennis</p>
<p>Last year's Australian Open finalists Aryna Sabalenka and Zheng Qinwen faced challenges in their second-round matches. While Sabalenka secured her victory, Zheng became the first Top 10 seed to exit the tournament.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Aryna Sabalenka defeated Jessica Bouzas Maneiro 6-3, 7-5, recovering from a 5-2 deficit in the second set.</li>
  <li>Laura Siegemund made headlines by defeating No.5 seed Zheng Qinwen 7-6(3), 6-3.</li>
  <li>This match marked Siegemund's 11th career Top 10 victory.</li>
  <li>Sabalenka extended her winning streak at Melbourne Park to 16 matches.</li>
  <li>Jessica Pegula and Mirra Andreeva also advanced to the third round with contrasting performances.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"She played incredible tennis, especially in the second set," Sabalenka said. "I'm really happy I was able to turn around that set."</blockquote>
<p>Siegemund's win is notable as she becomes the first German woman to defeat a Top 5 player at the Australian Open since 2016.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wtatennis.com/news/4198740/siegemund-upsets-zheng-sabalenka-holds-on-at-australian-open</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wtatennis.com/news/4198740/siegemund-upsets-zheng-sabalenka-holds-on-at-australian-open</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 02:27:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir, Ajit Agarkar Blasted For Ignoring T20 World Cup-Winner: "Suddenly Disappeared..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aakash Chopra Questions Shivam Dube's Selection Absence</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/avuh9g4o_india-t20-world-cup-2024_625x300_14_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Gautam Gambhir, Ajit Agarkar Blasted For Ignoring T20 World Cup-Winner: 'Suddenly Disappeared...'"><figcaption>Image related to the article about the selection controversy.</figcaption><p>Aakash Chopra criticizes the omission of Shivam Dube from the T20I squad against England, questioning the selectors for not acknowledging his contribution to the T20 World Cup victory.</p><ul><li>Aakash Chopra questions the absence of Shivam Dube from the T20I squad against England.</li><li>Dube was a part of India’s T20 World Cup-winning team but has been overlooked since.</li><li>Chopra highlights Dube's decent performance in the final and reasons he deserves another chance.</li><li>Selectors are focusing on Nitish Kumar Reddy as an all-rounder option instead of Dube.</li><li>Chopra points out the lack of discussion regarding Dube's absence and calls for recognition of his contributions.</li></ul><blockquote>“If he was good enough to be a part of the World Cup squad, I am sure he would be worthy of playing for another one or two years.” - Aakash Chopra</blockquote><p>The discussion raises concerns over the selectors' criteria for team selection and the need for consistency in evaluating players post-injury.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/india-vs-england-2025/gautam-gambhir-ajit-agarkar-blasted-for-ignoring-t20-world-cup-winner-suddenly-disappeared-7472884</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/india-vs-england-2025/gautam-gambhir-ajit-agarkar-blasted-for-ignoring-t20-world-cup-winner-suddenly-disappeared-7472884</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 02:01:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The pitch boomerang: how India's rank turners are biting them, not the opposition - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Pitch Boomerang: How India's Rank Turners Are Backfiring</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><img src="https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg" alt="Do India need to revisit their pitch strategy at home?"><figcaption>Do India need to revisit their pitch strategy at home?</figcaption><p>This article discusses India's struggles in Test cricket, especially related to their pitch strategies that emphasize spin, and how these strategies have negatively impacted their performance.</p><ul><li>India has failed to qualify for the World Test Championship final after frequent losses on home spinning pitches.</li><li>Opposition spinners have performed better due to India's choice of turning pitches, which has affected Indian batter averages.</li><li>Data indicates a significant drop in batting averages against spin for Indian players in recent years.</li><li>Players and analysts attribute Indian losses to challenging pitches created under the belief that they would provide an advantage.</li></ul><blockquote>“On turning pitches, it becomes more tricky. You're expecting it to turn every time…” - Vikram Rathour</blockquote><p>The analysis indicates that India’s strategy may be backfiring, bridging the gap between home and visiting spinners and highlighting the need for revised pitch preparations to regain home advantage.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/the-pitch-boomerang-how-india-s-rank-turners-are-biting-them-not-the-opposition-1468824</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/the-pitch-boomerang-how-india-s-rank-turners-are-biting-them-not-the-opposition-1468824</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 01:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["He's A Crack, Speaks Without Thinking": Yograj Singh Tagged Over "Wanted To Shoot" Kapil Dev Remark.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPOEVGQWdLaUowaFotdVBFLVBZZjFtRmV3b28zNHpEeXRaVDNqeUVJcExLbVN6d09BTEZFNHl6b0luczloX3hfdGxwZFlPQW9NRFZrTnNyUmlwNTMtMGpqR2hfeHZ3dG1jY0QyNU8yaksyR1UzclVnaXptdUZ2Z3MzeDYtVjQtSndydEx4UTB2a0NKY0REVUg5c3BSdFY0ZHc3T091SXU2TzFiXzZNcDRwRXM2Z2w4eG5SeFFaNmY3Ui0zZVdfazUtaHRQaUdzeFJR0gHYAUFVX3lxTE5tTWt1WXZqV1pCUGl4NzR0YWZocnNfam1HYkp3UTN0Q2ZPTnRWVmJXcFM0MjBYRktSWG5PSFgxaFF4UWJkV0p4ZDZRZDE1bFp5eFRuR2VnN25oUzdDdnBpTUpFbmVEenI1TkxsVXpVb2JWNU43OFQ1R0tBUHJyOU5kN0FxcEtqV3FtWWZnSFFLSGo4MFl4ZENldE9lTUtNOF9nc1RQU2tjMkREZ3BFZ014SHBFdlRIUjZWZ2lSZTdLd24xQUxQRE11MjNmZW93dWdlVjlVdzJFUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0AFBVV95cUxPOEVGQWdLaUowaFotdVBFLVBZZjFtRmV3b28zNHpEeXRaVDNqeUVJcExLbVN6d09BTEZFNHl6b0luczloX3hfdGxwZFlPQW9NRFZrTnNyUmlwNTMtMGpqR2hfeHZ3dG1jY0QyNU8yaksyR1UzclVnaXptdUZ2Z3MzeDYtVjQtSndydEx4UTB2a0NKY0REVUg5c3BSdFY0ZHc3T091SXU2TzFiXzZNcDRwRXM2Z2w4eG5SeFFaNmY3Ui0zZVdfazUtaHRQaUdzeFJR0gHYAUFVX3lxTE5tTWt1WXZqV1pCUGl4NzR0YWZocnNfam1HYkp3UTN0Q2ZPTnRWVmJXcFM0MjBYRktSWG5PSFgxaFF4UWJkV0p4ZDZRZDE1bFp5eFRuR2VnN25oUzdDdnBpTUpFbmVEenI1TkxsVXpVb2JWNU43OFQ1R0tBUHJyOU5kN0FxcEtqV3FtWWZnSFFLSGo4MFl4ZENldE9lTUtNOF9nc1RQU2tjMkREZ3BFZ014SHBFdlRIUjZWZ2lSZTdLd24xQUxQRE11MjNmZW93dWdlVjlVdzJFUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 01:52:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>