<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:29:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:29:04 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Update on HBL PSL Player Draft - PCB]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Update on HBL PSL Player Draft Rescheduled</h1>
<p><strong>Date: 7 January 2025 | Source: Pakistan Cricket Board</strong></p>
<p><strong>Venue: Huzoori Bagh, Lahore Fort</strong></p>
<img src='image-url-here' alt='HBL PSL Player Draft' />
<figcaption>HBL PSL Players Draft Event</figcaption>
<p>The Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) has confirmed that the HBL PSL Player Draft has been rescheduled to take place on 13 January at Huzoori Bagh, Lahore Fort, due to unforeseen logistical challenges.</p>
<ul>
<li>The official hashtag for the HBL PSL Players Draft is #DECADEOFHBLPSL.</li>
<li>The event has been moved from Gwadar to Lahore.</li>
<li>The HBL PSL 2025 Trophy Tour will include Gwadar in its route across Pakistan.</li>
<li>The Player Draft ceremony will occur at a historic venue.</li>
<li>The PSL's 10th edition is scheduled from 8 April to 19 May 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The six franchises will assemble their star-studded squads on Monday, 13 January during the Player Draft ceremony.”</blockquote>
<p>This rescheduling highlights the PCB's commitment to conducting a successful draft at a historically significant location.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pcb.com.pk/press-release-detail/update-on-hbl-psl-player-draft.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pcb.com.pk/press-release-detail/update-on-hbl-psl-player-draft.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:39:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borussia Dortmund consider loan move for Marcus Rashford from Manchester United - The Athletic - The New York Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Borussia Dortmund Considering Loan Move for Marcus Rashford</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 4, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Athletic</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static01.nyt.com/athletic/uploads/wp/2025/01/03150601/GettyImages-2187354385-scaled.jpg" alt="Marcus Rashford" width="2560" height="1708"><figcaption>Rashford hasn’t featured in United’s last six games (Justin Setterfield/Getty Images)</figcaption><p>Borussia Dortmund are exploring the possibility of signing Marcus Rashford on loan from Manchester United, with several clubs showing interest in the England international.</p><ul><li>Dortmund is among clubs weighing up a move for Rashford, alongside AC Milan and Juventus.</li><li>No decisions have been made yet, and Rashford could remain at Manchester United despite his desire for a new challenge.</li><li>Financial aspects could hinder the loan, as Rashford's earnings exceed £325,000 per week.</li><li>The club has a need for a wide forward, especially with Donyell Malen likely leaving.</li><li>Rashford's experience could help young talents at Dortmund adapt to the Bundesliga.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am ready for a new challenge.” – Marcus Rashford</blockquote><p>This potential move highlights the financial and competitive complexities in football loan agreements, especially for high-earning players like Rashford.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nytimes.com/athletic/6043765/2025/01/07/manchester-united-marcus-rashford-dortmund/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/athletic/6043765/2025/01/07/manchester-united-marcus-rashford-dortmund/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:38:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stress fracture to surgery! How injuries hurt Jasprit Bumrah’s career since 2018 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stress fracture to surgery! How injuries hurt Jasprit Bumrah’s career since 2018</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117023546,imgsize-27972,width-400,resizemode-4/117023546.jpg" alt="Stress fracture to surgery! How injuries hurt Jasprit Bumrah’s career since 2018" title="Jasprit Bumrah. (Pic Credit - X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah. (Pic Credit - X)</figcaption>
<p>Jasprit Bumrah, India’s leading fast bowler, has faced numerous injuries that have significantly hindered his cricket career from 2018 onward, highlighting his extraordinary resilience.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bumrah fractured his left thumb in 2018, affecting his performance during the tour of Ireland and England.</li>
  <li>A lower-back stress fracture in 2019 kept him out for three months.</li>
  <li>In January 2021, he suffered an abdominal strain that led to missing a crucial Test in Australia.</li>
  <li>Recurring back issues in 2022 resulted in missing both the Asia Cup and T20 World Cup.</li>
  <li>Bumrah underwent back surgery in early 2023, which prevented him from participating in major tournaments like IPL 2023.</li>
  <li>He made a comeback in August 2023 and played a vital role in India’s successful campaigns in the Asia Cup and ODI World Cup.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“His ability to bounce back from potentially career-ending injuries demonstrates his remarkable strength of character and unwavering commitment to the sport.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Jasprit Bumrah's journey through injuries reflects not just individual struggles but also the impact on the team's performance. His health remains crucial as India heads into future tournaments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/stress-fracture-to-surgery-how-injuries-hurt-jasprit-bumrahs-career-since-2018/articleshow/117023594.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/stress-fracture-to-surgery-how-injuries-hurt-jasprit-bumrahs-career-since-2018/articleshow/117023594.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma "Was Waiting For India's Escape Route To...": Report's Startling Claims - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxQZmM2MWw3T2lSalRWTEtXQ19TZ2l0WmNzdnRQZTZtM2x4b2R5ZTllQnY5U3ZQa2Y0bWowbjRaaFo4QmQ4c0hpbmlhNjNDeUhZQnJoVG9jSkE4RDQ2OUJxa2NjaktpcjFta2tzR2xsNFh6U29tZ0w0SWZzZDFpdlZIXzJacWR5cXNUN1YzX196R3dCNG5Ra3VWRWhfaXpOLVBMMVJBUVZHMjl4OUlhb2hmVnlBZ9IBuwFBVV95cUxQaGZDeFg3ZUV4eDJUQWpLNzdPZVE1cWpiNmtTUnU0b0FxeVdjeEs2Zm9FVFB2Y0h2ZHg5ZkdydTU3RzlWRWxWOVZWODZQZVliUnZFdTE4WF9rdTgxRWRDQ2FHdVFlNzEwaG1DUkpLTjYzQ3RIQmpIZFNWZDJyaXdIdXI2c2RiNXNGYTZ3cWlsMUtvUEVKbVN6TDNfS3VDTndGbWxzcjlPeWxxMHN2bDZEU3hSUEJXbDVHdVBz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxQZmM2MWw3T2lSalRWTEtXQ19TZ2l0WmNzdnRQZTZtM2x4b2R5ZTllQnY5U3ZQa2Y0bWowbjRaaFo4QmQ4c0hpbmlhNjNDeUhZQnJoVG9jSkE4RDQ2OUJxa2NjaktpcjFta2tzR2xsNFh6U29tZ0w0SWZzZDFpdlZIXzJacWR5cXNUN1YzX196R3dCNG5Ra3VWRWhfaXpOLVBMMVJBUVZHMjl4OUlhb2hmVnlBZ9IBuwFBVV95cUxQaGZDeFg3ZUV4eDJUQWpLNzdPZVE1cWpiNmtTUnU0b0FxeVdjeEs2Zm9FVFB2Y0h2ZHg5ZkdydTU3RzlWRWxWOVZWODZQZVliUnZFdTE4WF9rdTgxRWRDQ2FHdVFlNzEwaG1DUkpLTjYzQ3RIQmpIZFNWZDJyaXdIdXI2c2RiNXNGYTZ3cWlsMUtvUEVKbVN6TDNfS3VDTndGbWxzcjlPeWxxMHN2bDZEU3hSUEJXbDVHdVBz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:54:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['My fault': Sam Konstas admits provoking Jasprit Bumrah, leading to Usman Khawaja’s dismissal - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'My fault': Sam Konstas admits provoking Jasprit Bumrah, leading to Usman Khawaja’s dismissal</h1><p><strong>Publication Date & Source:</strong> October 2023, Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117022200,imgsize-39570,width-400,resizemode-4/117022200.jpg' alt='Sam Konstas and Jasprit Bumrah (AP Photo)'><figcaption>Sam Konstas and Jasprit Bumrah (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>The article discusses the on-field exchange between Australian cricketer Sam Konstas and Indian captain Jasprit Bumrah during the fifth Test match, where Konstas acknowledges provoking Bumrah leading to the dismissal of Usman Khawaja.</p><ul><li>Konstas addressed the incident, explaining it stemmed from Bumrah's frustration with Khawaja's delay.</li><li>He stated, “Oh, I didn't get too fazed. Unfortunately, Uzi got out. It was probably my fault, but it happens. It's cricket.”</li><li>Despite the tension, Konstas praised Bumrah's performance and acknowledged the overall strength of the team.</li><li>Konstas reflected on his calm demeanor during his Test debut and the support from family and teammates.</li><li>His performance has raised expectations for potential inclusion in the upcoming Sri Lanka tour.</li></ul><blockquote>“But obviously, it was a packed stadium, and Uzi (Khawaja) said my adrenaline was pumped when I was batting, but I didn't feel that.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Konstas's remarks highlight the competitive spirit of cricket and the importance of maintaining composure under pressure, as well as the promising future for his career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/my-fault-sam-konstas-admits-provoking-jasprit-bumrah-leading-to-usman-khawajas-dismissal/articleshow/117021777.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/my-fault-sam-konstas-admits-provoking-jasprit-bumrah-leading-to-usman-khawajas-dismissal/articleshow/117021777.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BPL 2024-2025: Match 12, SYL vs FBA Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BPL match between SYL vs FBA? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxPTndHd3FKY3k3dTg0Sno2RjdUVGJpWVA3VUtYRjZUVmdpUk5Db1VldTk2ODNncW5GNVNVN1NJaVMydmVOUGNfTVA3U0p2b1pGVmYyMFdvUkU2bXktOERRRnVVTllpYTlna3NxaGlOYWE2Y0FhdHRZV2YwaUpfZURZZGoyWUNBNktzZkVvMzVJODY1RWtZWmpiZGtCV2NMNF80YzdYUkx6SjlBRVpUemJDbDhNRlQ2bDI4MGdiSkJXTW5zdnNXNjUxbVVkam50RTRSbkFON1IwNUtCTjVjZk5Ud2lWLVY3MGUyWVYtUTJ0N1TSAfgBQVVfeXFMTUFoUWdIdXg0SzhqMXdjZlRKMkZxWklqaUtXaGVMbktXUXl5ZUxibE5rSTVXQXpTN1lJNk1XNWJ2cV9xQ01YRk9fUXpKdlpWaWhrVVI0N3FfdmdpcjFaYURDcjBCMnFZa3NfRDJZZDM2WlZEa1VvWlQxM0J3cjVxRkR2YktzbEs0el9ZQ0hDdGdRSy1jMzdnYThsVDRGZDBkUXU2eGlzWkxnWlhfdkF3YzVYMnVvb0tITEp3UXA3NTFWeC1LTGhUMy1nN1JWQl9JY0ZrTGFOQm85YW1vOVVXNkk4UlNYRXNac213dlVqZWFLUVJraEVsT0w?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8AFBVV95cUxPTndHd3FKY3k3dTg0Sno2RjdUVGJpWVA3VUtYRjZUVmdpUk5Db1VldTk2ODNncW5GNVNVN1NJaVMydmVOUGNfTVA3U0p2b1pGVmYyMFdvUkU2bXktOERRRnVVTllpYTlna3NxaGlOYWE2Y0FhdHRZV2YwaUpfZURZZGoyWUNBNktzZkVvMzVJODY1RWtZWmpiZGtCV2NMNF80YzdYUkx6SjlBRVpUemJDbDhNRlQ2bDI4MGdiSkJXTW5zdnNXNjUxbVVkam50RTRSbkFON1IwNUtCTjVjZk5Ud2lWLVY3MGUyWVYtUTJ0N1TSAfgBQVVfeXFMTUFoUWdIdXg0SzhqMXdjZlRKMkZxWklqaUtXaGVMbktXUXl5ZUxibE5rSTVXQXpTN1lJNk1XNWJ2cV9xQ01YRk9fUXpKdlpWaWhrVVI0N3FfdmdpcjFaYURDcjBCMnFZa3NfRDJZZDM2WlZEa1VvWlQxM0J3cjVxRkR2YktzbEs0el9ZQ0hDdGdRSy1jMzdnYThsVDRGZDBkUXU2eGlzWkxnWlhfdkF3YzVYMnVvb0tITEp3UXA3NTFWeC1LTGhUMy1nN1JWQl9JY0ZrTGFOQm85YW1vOVVXNkk4UlNYRXNac213dlVqZWFLUVJraEVsT0w?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['It's confusing, puts all-rounders under pressure': AB de Villiers rejects impact player rule - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AB de Villiers Critiques Impact Player Rule in Cricket</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/AB_de_Villiers_1709738710087_1736245135308.jpg" alt="AB de Villiers says he is not a fan of the 'impact player' rule as it negates the impact of all-rounders" title="AB de Villiers says he is not a fan of the 'impact player' rule as it negates the impact of all-rounders" /><figcaption>AB de Villiers says he is not a fan of the 'impact player' rule as it negates the impact of all-rounders</figcaption></figure><p>Former South Africa cricketer AB de Villiers expresses concern over the impact player rule in cricket, stating it pressures all-rounders and alters team dynamics.</p><ul><li>De Villiers criticizes the rule for reducing the role of all-rounders in T20 formats.</li><li>He acknowledges the excitement of the rule but finds it confusing and problematic in practice.</li><li>The impact player rule allows teams to substitute players at any time, which has led to higher scores in IPL.</li><li>Despite his concerns, De Villiers supports the idea of having flexibility in team selection at the toss.</li><li>He believes SA20 can learn from the IPL while developing its own identity.</li></ul><blockquote>"I've never been a big fan, to be honest, and I did speak about it at the IPL in that last season. I feel it's a bit confusing. It also puts a bit of pressure on the all-rounders and their role in the teams." - AB de Villiers</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while AB de Villiers sees benefits in the new approaches introduced in cricket, he remains cautious about the impact player rule's long-term effects on the game.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/its-confusing-puts-all-rounders-under-pressure-ab-de-villiers-rejects-impact-player-rule-101736245117691.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/its-confusing-puts-all-rounders-under-pressure-ab-de-villiers-rejects-impact-player-rule-101736245117691.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:28:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICC Men’s Player of the Month nominees for December announced - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICC Men's Player of the Month nominees for December announced</h1><p><strong>Date: December 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: ICC Cricket</strong></p><p>Pat Cummins has been nominated for the ICC Men's Player of the Month for December due to his exceptional performances during the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Pat Cummins delivered standout performances with both bat and ball.</li><li>He secured 17 wickets across three Tests against India with an average of 17.64.</li><li>His best bowling performance was 5/57 in Adelaide, contributing to a 10-wicket victory for Australia.</li><li>He contributed crucial knocks of 49 and 41 in Melbourne, helping Australia win another important match.</li></ul><blockquote>“Cummins showcased his fine form, leading Australia to the ICC World Test Championship 2025 Final.”</blockquote><p>Pat Cummins' contributions were pivotal in securing Australia's position in the upcoming ICC World Test Championship Final.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/icc-men-s-player-of-the-month-nominees-for-december-announced</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/icc-men-s-player-of-the-month-nominees-for-december-announced</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:24:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["India could have registered a win": Former fast bowler makes a big statement after Australia's win in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy 2024-25 - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>“India could have registered a win”: Former fast bowler makes a big statement after Australia’s win in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy 2024-25</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Crictoday</p>
<img src="https://crictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Jasprit-Bumrah.webp" alt="Jasprit Bumrah" width="1200" height="675"/>
<figcaption><span>The 54-year-old also compared Jasprit Bumrah and Scott Boland, who took 10 wickets in the final game in Sydney.</span></figcaption>
<p>Damien Fleming, a former fast bowler, remarked that India might have secured a win against Australia had Jasprit Bumrah been fit during the final Test. He emphasized the impact Bumrah could have had on the match's outcome.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bumrah's injury affected India's chances in the fourth innings.</li>
  <li>Fleming highlighted the difficulties Australia's batsmen faced against quality bowling.</li>
  <li>Australia clinched the Border-Gavaskar Trophy by winning the series 3-1.</li>
  <li>Pat Cummins, the Australian captain, was praised for his leadership.</li>
  <li>Australia has qualified for the final of the World Test Championship.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If Jasprit Bumrah was fit, India could have won the Test. Batting was not easy on the third day, and Bumrah is an unbelievable bowler.” - Damien Fleming</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Flemings's remarks underline the significant role that star players like Bumrah can have in determining the outcomes of crucial matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/india-could-have-registered-a-win-former-fast-bowler-makes-a-big-statement-after-australias-win-in-the-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/india-could-have-registered-a-win-former-fast-bowler-makes-a-big-statement-after-australias-win-in-the-border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:03:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE | 'Fit' Jasprit Bumrah would have done a Kapil Dev in SCG Test: Ex-cricketer - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>EXCLUSIVE | 'Fit' Jasprit Bumrah would have done a Kapil Dev in SCG Test: Ex-cricketer</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117020283,imgsize-32836,width-400,resizemode-4/117020283.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah (Getty Images)">
<figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah (Getty Images)</figcaption>
<p>Jasprit Bumrah's absence due to back spasms severely impacted India's chances in the recent Test match, leading to a series loss against Australia and dashing hopes for the World Test Championship final.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bumrah's back injury prevented him from playing in the decisive Test match against Australia.</li>
  <li>Australia chased down the target of 162 runs with ease, losing only six wickets.</li>
  <li>Ex-cricketer Balwinder Sandhu stated that Bumrah's presence could have turned the match in India's favor.</li>
  <li>Sandhu drew parallels between Bumrah's situation and legendary bowler Kapil Dev's performance in 1981.</li>
  <li>Criticism was directed towards senior players Rohit Sharma and Virat Kohli for underperforming throughout the series.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"If Bumrah was even 1 percent fit, he would have definitely bowled. We could have won the match." - Balwinder Sandhu</blockquote>
<p>This match has highlighted the importance of key players in high-stakes situations and raised questions about the performance of senior Indian cricketers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-kapil-dev-in-scg-test-bgt-ind-vs-aus-virat-kohli-tohit-sharma-border-gavaskar-trophy/articleshow/117020242.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-kapil-dev-in-scg-test-bgt-ind-vs-aus-virat-kohli-tohit-sharma-border-gavaskar-trophy/articleshow/117020242.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Squad For Champions Trophy And England ODIs Live Updates: Big Bumrah Blow To Team India? - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Squad For Champions Trophy And England ODIs Live Updates: Big Bumrah Blow To Team India?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 06, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/lr31p6u8_jasprit-bumrah-afp_625x300_06_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="India Squad Announcement" /><figcaption>India's Squad Announcement For Champions Trophy and England ODIs.</figcaption><p>India's cricket team is preparing for the Champions Trophy and an ODI series against England, with key concerns about Jasprit Bumrah's fitness.</p><ul><li>The Champions Trophy will take place from February 19 to March 9, 2025.</li><li>The ODI series against England starts on February 6, 2025.</li><li>Bumrah is likely to miss the white-ball series, creating uncertainties for the squad selection.</li><li>Selection committee is considering both veteran players and younger talents for the squad.</li><li>Mohammed Shami and Kuldeep Yadav are also being monitored regarding their fitness for selection.</li></ul><blockquote>“Absolutely, there's no question about that,” said Ravi Shastri regarding Shami's impact if fit.</blockquote><p>The upcoming matches could be a turning point for the Indian cricket team's dynamics and squad structure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-india-vs-england-odi-t20-full-squads-announcement-live-updates-england-tour-of-india-7413646</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-india-vs-england-odi-t20-full-squads-announcement-live-updates-england-tour-of-india-7413646</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:23:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ECB rejects calls for England to boycott Afghanistan at Champions Trophy - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ECB Rejects Calls for England to Boycott Afghanistan in Champions Trophy</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> February 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Independent</p>
<p>Richard Gould, the ECB's chief executive, has rejected calls for England to boycott their Champions Trophy match against Afghanistan, emphasizing the need for a coordinated response rather than unilateral actions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The ECB is under pressure from over 160 politicians to boycott the match due to concerns over women's rights in Afghanistan.</li>
  <li>The letter highlights the situation of women's sport in Afghanistan since the Taliban's return to power.</li>
  <li>Gould confirmed that the ECB will not engage in bilateral series with Afghanistan under the current regime.</li>
  <li>The ECB aims for a unified approach with the ICC regarding international cricket and women's rights.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The ECB strongly condemns the treatment of women and girls in Afghanistan under the Taliban regime.” – Richard Gould</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while the ECB recognizes the urgent need to address the situation for women in Afghanistan, Gould advocates for a coordinated response within the ICC instead of individual boycotts, emphasizing cricket's role as a source of hope for many Afghans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/ecb-reject-calls-england-boycott-afghanistan-champions-trophy-1468113</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/ecb-reject-calls-england-boycott-afghanistan-champions-trophy-1468113</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:21:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[adidas Enters F1 With Multi-Year Mercedes-AMG PETRONAS F1 Team Partnership - Mercedes-AMG PETRONAS F1 Team]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>adidas Enters F1 With Multi-Year Mercedes-AMG PETRONAS F1 Team Partnership</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Mercedes-AMG PETRONAS F1 Team</p><p>The partnership between adidas and the Mercedes-AMG PETRONAS F1 Team marks adidas's return to motorsport, aiming to innovate in team wear and engage new fan demographics.</p><ul><li>adidas becomes the Official Team Partner of the Mercedes-AMG PETRONAS F1 Team.</li><li>CEO Bjørn Gulden emphasizes the growing interest in F1 and its cultural impact.</li><li>Team Principal Toto Wolff highlights the collaboration as a redefinition of team and fanwear.</li><li>The new apparel range will be unveiled next month, ahead of the 2025 season.</li><li>Products will be available on official websites and through various wholesale accounts.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are extremely proud to introduce the Three Stripes into F1 as Official Team Partner of the Mercedes-AMG PETRONAS F1 Team – one of the most successful teams ever.” - Bjørn Gulden</blockquote><blockquote>“Our partnership with adidas is a clear statement of intent as we begin to write our next chapter as a team.” - Toto Wolff</blockquote><p>This partnership aims to merge performance with style, anticipating a significant impact on F1 culture as it engages with a broader audience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mercedesamgf1.com/news/adidas-enters-f1-with-multi-year-mercedes-amg-petronas-f1-team-partnership</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mercedesamgf1.com/news/adidas-enters-f1-with-multi-year-mercedes-amg-petronas-f1-team-partnership</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:04:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘It was my fault’: Sam Konstas accepts mistake in riling up Jasprit Bumrah, resulting in Usman Khawaja's wicket - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sam Konstas Takes Responsibility for Incident with Jasprit Bumrah During Fifth Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Australia-India-Cricket-81_1736240093576_1736240115422.jpg" alt="Umpire Sharfuddoula Saikat, centre, gestures to India's Jasprit Bumrah, right, as he exchanges words with Australia's Sam Konstas(AP)" title="Umpire Sharfuddoula Saikat, centre, gestures to India's Jasprit Bumrah, right, as he exchanges words with Australia's Sam Konstas(AP)"><figcaption>Umpire Sharfuddoula Saikat, centre, gestures to India's Jasprit Bumrah, right, as he exchanges words with Australia's Sam Konstas(AP)</figcaption><p>Sam Konstas, a young debutant cricketer, admitted his mistake in antagonizing Jasprit Bumrah during a tense moment in Sydney's fifth Test, leading to the dismissal of Usman Khawaja.</p><ul><li>Konstas engaged in a heated exchange with Bumrah, which escalated during the match.</li><li>His actions were seen as provocations during a crucial phase of the game.</li><li>Despite his mistake, Konstas managed to celebrate his wickets with bravado.</li><li>After the match, he acknowledged his role in the incident, saying, "it was probably my fault."</li></ul><blockquote>"Oh, I didn't get too fazed. Unfortunately, Uzi got out. He was trying to buy some time a little bit. It was probably my fault, but it happens. It's cricket. Credit to Bumrah. He got the wicket, but obviously great performance from the team,” – Sam Konstas</blockquote><p>In a high-pressure environment, Konstas's response reflects the challenges young players face and the intensity of Test cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/it-was-my-fault-sam-konstas-accepts-mistake-in-riling-up-jasprit-bumrah-resulting-in-usman-khawajas-wicket-101736239957978.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/it-was-my-fault-sam-konstas-accepts-mistake-in-riling-up-jasprit-bumrah-resulting-in-usman-khawajas-wicket-101736239957978.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:59:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HBL PSL 10: Foreign players' categories unveiled - The Express Tribune]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PSL 10: Foreign Players' Categories for Draft Unveiled</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Express Tribune</p>
<img src="https://i.tribune.com.pk/attachments/speech_20250107080045774-Ezo6v.mp3" alt="Audio Article" />
<figcaption>Listen to article</figcaption>
<p>The categories for foreign players in the Pakistan Super League (PSL) 10 draft have been officially revealed.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The platinum category includes notable players such as David Warner, Matthew Short, and Shakib Al Hasan.</li>
  <li>40 foreign players are registered in the platinum category, with 6 available exclusively for selection.</li>
  <li>Other players in the diamond category include Alex Carey, while 87 foreign players are in this category.</li>
  <li>165 foreign players are available in the gold category.</li>
  <li>The PSL 10 draft is scheduled for January 11 and will now be held in Lahore instead of Gwadar due to logistical challenges.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The PSL 10 draft is scheduled for January 11.”</blockquote>
<p>This announcement is crucial for teams as they prepare for the upcoming season of PSL and strategize their player selections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tribune.com.pk/story/2520579/hbl-psl-10-foreign-players-categories-for-draft-unveiled</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tribune.com.pk/story/2520579/hbl-psl-10-foreign-players-categories-for-draft-unveiled</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:45:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kapil Dev can end Vinod Kambli's poverty in one day, here's how - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kapil Dev can end Vinod Kambli's poverty in one day, here's how</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/kapil-dev-can-end-vinod-kamblis-poverty-in-one-day-heres-how-202501-1736237673.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Kapil Dev can end Vinod Kambli s poverty in one day here s how">
<figcaption>Image credit: X (Formerly Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli is facing financial struggles due to health issues, and former captain Kapil Dev may have the means to help him out significantly.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Vinod Kambli has been hospitalized for two weeks due to brain clots and is in financial distress.</li>
  <li>Shiv Sena party has provided Rs 5 lakh for Kambli's medical treatment.</li>
  <li>Kapil Dev has promised to assist Kambli financially if he commits to rehab for alcohol addiction.</li>
  <li>Kapil Dev celebrated his 66th birthday this week and has a net worth exceeding Rs 220 crore.</li>
  <li>Kapil reportedly earns Rs 1 crore per month, which is substantially more than Kambli's pension from BCCI.</li>
  <li>Kambli has expressed willingness to seek rehab again in exchange for financial assistance from Kapil.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Kapil Dev's reported daily earning is about Rs 3.33 lakh. If he extends support for Vinod Kambli, he can end the ex-cricketer's poverty in a month.”</blockquote>
<p>This situation highlights the disparity between their financial statuses and raises questions about potential support from one legendary cricketer to another.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/kapil-dev-can-end-vinod-kambli-poverty-in-one-day-heres-how-418490/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/kapil-dev-can-end-vinod-kambli-poverty-in-one-day-heres-how-418490/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:27:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Pujara, Rahane Have Shown Hunger": Rohit Sharma Sent Blunt Domestic Cricket Message - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQR0hSeDFhejlNQVBLaVNVQ202WkVYRkpqdzUtQzR3MExmMDJxVEVCclYwN3hsRTBGUVNlMW5OYXhWUFM1UjVDaE9fUnZjNHBwSDRPS1NmZkl0cmFGRHRkVzFWX0xSc3FKbVhXbVpwbFhTV1hQWk5vajg2TDRKVGMzdmtodThmLWdLb3RWVC1NNjA2UGlJVTBNbTlhS1ppNEQ3MDF6eHp0QTgyWDBEZ1N0OGw1OHlkM1AwblkyS9IBxAFBVV95cUxPalFYWWtVaE80YTZ6NURvNnVWQ2tJUFM5b01iYVg5eV9kU0d5MFV3bEtlSEFtU1BIT3NGVWd0Tkd2dHp1dGxVemFzZU5VbVJNSDY4OVlpQVp6NzM4Q0hMX0xuSFZ0Wk1JdVB2THV4emItQ3M3YjVTVGRQaDZteDRuM2M4Nkdra29DU3QzQXFzNFZyMk41ZmU3R25SUHZRN2g4cVdlekp0WHpJX05QWWNWdUNTRmE1X2VyalRCZl9CRDFXU2l4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQR0hSeDFhejlNQVBLaVNVQ202WkVYRkpqdzUtQzR3MExmMDJxVEVCclYwN3hsRTBGUVNlMW5OYXhWUFM1UjVDaE9fUnZjNHBwSDRPS1NmZkl0cmFGRHRkVzFWX0xSc3FKbVhXbVpwbFhTV1hQWk5vajg2TDRKVGMzdmtodThmLWdLb3RWVC1NNjA2UGlJVTBNbTlhS1ppNEQ3MDF6eHp0QTgyWDBEZ1N0OGw1OHlkM1AwblkyS9IBxAFBVV95cUxPalFYWWtVaE80YTZ6NURvNnVWQ2tJUFM5b01iYVg5eV9kU0d5MFV3bEtlSEFtU1BIT3NGVWd0Tkd2dHp1dGxVemFzZU5VbVJNSDY4OVlpQVp6NzM4Q0hMX0xuSFZ0Wk1JdVB2THV4emItQ3M3YjVTVGRQaDZteDRuM2M4Nkdra29DU3QzQXFzNFZyMk41ZmU3R25SUHZRN2g4cVdlekp0WHpJX05QWWNWdUNTRmE1X2VyalRCZl9CRDFXU2l4?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:19:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hazlewood’s fate revealed in bowling shake-up; five-man spin race: Aussie state of play - Fox Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgNBVV95cUxOYlRjVV9zSGdoNG40clJ4TkdzUnFmRURpUHlXMXFnX2ZDTHZrdlNCQlpVTWhYeVc4ZExhZmJUdFRHcWExRDFuYmZfWkxId0RWNmR4dlpUYUdGMndSNG1xUzdOVGYySGdPQ2kzR2FEbWlzTU1adnFZSkt1MEFrWVcxZURvaHpvTEg3bVhROFhMcnFDTmRfSWoyT2cxQ1Ywb1ZMbjNwLWNvMnZWZzQyVXNBRVg1VTNpOTd6S1NmQzN6eHBncDJYVGZFSmpES3hzRWV4d3BlTXdwUWNsWWZiYkR0THplbjl5ck5QMGJma0VscmNCX1NEYmV6T0Q0ZW9wWnpwN1pYdTVZazBmZm9CSWFHSVU4ZVdPWi1vUEtNbkQ2Z2VscHlwUFd5RDBjMUtwOE0tZGFLU0g1XzhCc3pKZUVTdlk3NkpRWGtvSC1EcV9uakg0U1dCVjFacEV6Vy1VWlc5Y200SGVoWUMtQW5BTDNnZDVjTjJKeEFuTjdNcC1mUWYxQzRoZzI3aUloYjJvSWUwS2NtQ1lZWEx4RnhfWVVYTkFNakFRZFZ6bHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgNBVV95cUxOYlRjVV9zSGdoNG40clJ4TkdzUnFmRURpUHlXMXFnX2ZDTHZrdlNCQlpVTWhYeVc4ZExhZmJUdFRHcWExRDFuYmZfWkxId0RWNmR4dlpUYUdGMndSNG1xUzdOVGYySGdPQ2kzR2FEbWlzTU1adnFZSkt1MEFrWVcxZURvaHpvTEg3bVhROFhMcnFDTmRfSWoyT2cxQ1Ywb1ZMbjNwLWNvMnZWZzQyVXNBRVg1VTNpOTd6S1NmQzN6eHBncDJYVGZFSmpES3hzRWV4d3BlTXdwUWNsWWZiYkR0THplbjl5ck5QMGJma0VscmNCX1NEYmV6T0Q0ZW9wWnpwN1pYdTVZazBmZm9CSWFHSVU4ZVdPWi1vUEtNbkQ2Z2VscHlwUFd5RDBjMUtwOE0tZGFLU0g1XzhCc3pKZUVTdlk3NkpRWGtvSC1EcV9uakg0U1dCVjFacEV6Vy1VWlc5Y200SGVoWUMtQW5BTDNnZDVjTjJKeEFuTjdNcC1mUWYxQzRoZzI3aUloYjJvSWUwS2NtQ1lZWEx4RnhfWVVYTkFNakFRZFZ6bHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:17:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Never seen Jasprit Bumrah react like that': Former Australian pacer surprised by aggression towards Sam - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Former Australian Pacer Surprised by Jasprit Bumrah's Aggression Towards Sam Konstas</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> NEW DELHI | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117016056,imgsize-38688,width-400,resizemode-4/117016056.jpg" alt="Sam Konstas and Jasprit Bumrah (Getty Images)" title="Sam Konstas and Jasprit Bumrah (Getty Images)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Sam Konstas and Jasprit Bumrah (Getty Images)</figcaption><p>Former Australian pacer Damien Fleming expressed surprise over Jasprit Bumrah's aggressive response during the fifth Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy in Sydney. His reaction not only caught attention but also seemed to inspire his teammates.</p><ul><li>Bumrah confronted Sam Konstas during the final over of Day 1, showing unexpected aggression.</li><li>Fleming noted the incident highlighted Bumrah's role in igniting spirit among the Indian team.</li><li>Bumrah took 32 wickets in the series but did not win the Player of the Series award, which went to Travis Head for his 448 runs.</li><li>The absence of Mohammed Shami was a critical factor in India's loss, according to Fleming.</li><li>Fleming praised Prasidh Krishna's six wickets in the final Test and highlighted Nitish Kumar Reddy as a promising player for India.</li></ul><blockquote>“I've never seen Bumrah react like that. So he sparked something in the Indians that not a lot of people have.” - Damien Fleming</blockquote><p>Fleming's observations reflect not only on Bumrah's capabilities as a bowler but also on the importance of team dynamics in crucial matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/never-seen-jasprit-bumrah-react-like-that-former-australian-pacer-surprised-by-aggression-towards-sam-konstas/articleshow/117015927.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/never-seen-jasprit-bumrah-react-like-that-former-australian-pacer-surprised-by-aggression-towards-sam-konstas/articleshow/117015927.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BPL 2024-2025: Match 11, RAN vs DC Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BPL match between RAN vs DC? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BPL 2024-2025: Match 11 Prediction - Rangpur Riders vs Dhaka Capitals</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 7, 2025 - CricTracker</p><figure><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736170657377_image_2025_01_06T13_37_05_250Z.png" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The T20 cricket fever of the Bangladesh Premier League continues as Match 11 gets ready between Rangpur Riders and Dhaka Capitals. Rangpur is currently at the top of the table, while Dhaka seeks their first win.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>Match No: 11 between Rangpur Riders and Dhaka Capitals</li><li>Venue: Sylhet International Cricket Stadium</li><li>The match is scheduled for January 7, 2025, at 1 PM IST</li><li>Rangpur Riders are leading the table with four wins, while Dhaka Capitals are yet to score.</li><li>Pitch is favorable for batting, expecting a high-scoring game.</li></ul><h3>Notable Quotes or Statistics:</h3><blockquote>“Rangpur Riders won their first match against Dhaka by 40 runs.”</blockquote><h3>Conclusion:</h3><p>Based on current form, Rangpur Riders are favored to win this match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bpl-2024-2025-match-11-ran-vs-dc-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bpl-match-between-ran-vs-dc/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bpl-2024-2025-match-11-ran-vs-dc-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bpl-match-between-ran-vs-dc/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chelsea ‘actively considering’ signing Marc Guéhi from Crystal Palace — reports - We Ain't Got No History]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chelsea Considering Signing Marc Guéhi from Crystal Palace</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Sky Sports</p><p>Chelsea is reportedly looking at the possibility of signing defender Marc Guéhi from Crystal Palace instead of recalling Trevoh Chalobah. This comes as Guéhi has just 18 months left on his contract, and the club may be able to negotiate a transfer.</p><ul><li>Guéhi has made over 100 Premier League appearances.</li><li>He has 22 senior caps for the England national team.</li><li>Chelsea are still in discussions regarding strengthening their defensive line.</li></ul><blockquote>Chelsea are actively considering re-signing Marc Guehi in January. A defensive reinforcement is expected, with a recall of Trevoh Chalobah also discussed. Palace yet to have direct contact with Chelsea. Palace wanted £70m+ in the summer when Newcastle bid, but Guehi does only… — Ben Jacobs (@JacobsBen) January 6, 2025</blockquote><p>This potential move for Guéhi indicates Chelsea’s proactive approach in the January transfer window to enhance their defensive options.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/chelsea-fc-transfer-rumours-news/2025/1/7/24338010/chelsea-actively-considering-signing-marc-guehi-from-crystal-palace-reports</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/chelsea-fc-transfer-rumours-news/2025/1/7/24338010/chelsea-actively-considering-signing-marc-guehi-from-crystal-palace-reports</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:59:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli's antics make other Indians a target; Rohit Sharma out of depth: Sunil Gavaskar's unfiltered take - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gavaskar Critiques Kohli's Actions and Sharma's Form in Recent Test Series</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-48_1736232268025_1736232312318.jpg" alt="India's Rohit Sharma (R) gestures next to Virat Kohli(AFP)" title="India's Rohit Sharma (R) gestures next to Virat Kohli(AFP)"><figcaption>India's Rohit Sharma (R) gestures next to Virat Kohli(AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>Sunil Gavaskar expressed concerns over Virat Kohli's behavior that led to increased pressure on his teammates during a Test match against Australia. He also stated that Rohit Sharma appears to be struggling with his form in the series.</p><ul><li>Kohli's antics during the match have drawn criticism, impacting the team negatively.</li><li>Gavaskar emphasized that Kohli's reaction to the crowd puts undue pressure on his teammates.</li><li>Both Kohli and Sharma had poor performances throughout the Test series.</li><li>Gavaskar raised doubts about their future in Test cricket due to their recent forms.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kohli must understand that whatever he does to react to the crowd actually puts more pressure on his teammates,” said Gavaskar.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Gavaskar's critique highlights the need for Indian players to maintain composure during matches, as their actions can affect overall team performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohlis-antics-make-other-indian-cricketers-a-target-rohit-sharma-out-of-depth-sunil-gavaskar-unshackled-101736231860329.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohlis-antics-make-other-indian-cricketers-a-target-rohit-sharma-out-of-depth-sunil-gavaskar-unshackled-101736231860329.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:51:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli's antics make other Indian cricketers a target; Rohit Sharma out of depth: Sunil Gavaskar unshackled - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunil Gavaskar Critiques Virat Kohli's Behavior Amid Australian Crowd Pressure</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-48_1736232268025_1736232312318.jpg" alt="India's Rohit Sharma (R) gestures next to Virat Kohli(AFP)" title="India's Rohit Sharma (R) gestures next to Virat Kohli(AFP)">
  <figcaption>India's Rohit Sharma (R) gestures next to Virat Kohli(AFP)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Sunil Gavaskar criticized Virat Kohli's antics in response to the Australian crowd, stating that it puts additional pressure on his teammates. He pointed out that Kohli's actions make other Indian players targets during matches.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gavaskar deemed Kohli's behavior as unnecessary and harmful to team dynamics.</li>
  <li>He highlighted Kohli's recent performances, where he scored poorly in the Test series.</li>
  <li>Rohit Sharma’s performance is also under scrutiny following his struggles in the series.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Kohli must understand that whatever he does to react to the crowd actually puts more pressure on his teammates.” - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote>
<p>This situation has raised questions about the future of both players in red-ball cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohlis-antics-make-other-indian-cricketers-a-target-rohit-sharma-out-of-depth-sunil-gavaskar-unshackled-101736231860329.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohlis-antics-make-other-indian-cricketers-a-target-rohit-sharma-out-of-depth-sunil-gavaskar-unshackled-101736231860329.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:51:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fresh Jasprit Bumrah Setback For India Ahead Of Champions Trophy Squad Announcement: Report - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fresh Jasprit Bumrah Setback For India Ahead Of Champions Trophy Squad Announcement: Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/sijjsi9g_jasprit-bumrah-afp_625x300_07_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Jasprit Bumrah Injury"/><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah's injury could keep him on the sidelines for a long period © AFP</figcaption><p>Jasprit Bumrah's recent injury during a Test match against Australia poses serious concerns for his participation in the upcoming ICC Champions Trophy.</p><ul><li>Bumrah suffered a 'back spasm' during the 5th Test against Australia.</li><li>His participation in white-ball matches against England is in doubt.</li><li>The selection committee is cautious due to his injury history.</li><li>Bumrah's playing status for the Champions Trophy depends on medical clearance.</li><li>Other players are also being monitored for potential comebacks.</li></ul><blockquote>“A little frustrating (on injury) but sometimes you have to respect your body, and you can't fight your body,” said Bumrah.</blockquote><p>The situation around Bumrah highlights the challenges faced by the Indian cricket team with key players potentially missing out on significant events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/fresh-jasprit-bumrah-setback-for-india-ahead-of-champions-trophy-squad-announcement-report-7417778</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/fresh-jasprit-bumrah-setback-for-india-ahead-of-champions-trophy-squad-announcement-report-7417778</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:44:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Should have been punished far more severely': Kohli, Bumrah lambasted for 'disgraceful act' over treatment of Konstas - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kohli and Bumrah Criticized for 'Disgraceful Act' Against Sam Konstas</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/AP01-05-2025-000023A-0_1736229981279_1736229993582.jpg" alt="India's Jasprit Bumrah, right, and India's Virat Kohli react after the fifth cricket test between India and Australia at the Sydney Cricket Ground(AP)"><figcaption>India's Jasprit Bumrah, right, and India's Virat Kohli react after the fifth cricket test between India and Australia at the Sydney Cricket Ground(AP)</figcaption><p>The article discusses the criticism directed at Indian cricketers Virat Kohli and Jasprit Bumrah for their behavior towards Australia's Sam Konstas during the Border-Gavaskar Trophy series. It highlights comments from Indian head coach Gautam Gambhir and reactions from Australian coach Greg Shipperd.</p><ul><li>Kohli and Bumrah faced backlash for their treatment of Sam Konstas, who impressed during the series.</li><li>Gautam Gambhir criticized Konstas for engaging with Bumrah during the match.</li><li>NSW coach Greg Shipperd condemned Kohli and Bumrah's aggression towards Konstas.</li><li>Shipperd stated the actions should have led to harsher punishment for Bumrah.</li></ul><blockquote>“I think it was a disgraceful act and should have been punished far more severely than it was.” - Greg Shipperd</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the incident has sparked significant debate about sportsmanship and conduct in cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/should-have-been-punished-severely-virat-kohli-jasprit-bumrah-lambasted-disgraceful-act-treatment-of-sam-konstas-101736229888939.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/should-have-been-punished-severely-virat-kohli-jasprit-bumrah-lambasted-disgraceful-act-treatment-of-sam-konstas-101736229888939.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:36:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BBL 2024-2025: Match 26, SCO vs REN Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between SCO vs REN? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxOMEZvQWxGNFVrNlJ5N2sxQzV2blpBNWpDQXU3dUVrY3E2VkY5c3I4NmtwV0E2dm9RaE9KMHhjZWMzZjFvLVdjMWFHUFhsa1BkM1NyYmYzQm9xdmc2bHZOc3lrUWJDWXhXSjFCRnZ5dk1JUzhDRjFpajJEU1ZOTGF6ZVUyLXJkbk52SlJEQkdWQ0VMVHRTYnZMQmxqU3FHMmxxVnZFVy0tOElwbHZ2cGJOTElOYXpjMWxBZFZJd2ZNdkN0TktYR0ROQk16aW54RjNST2M5LUd2OG5yMm5PbWMzdzVTTTRreWo0eVHSAfIBQVVfeXFMUF93V292dFZQMzh0Rzh5eXBhUkxDNHlWSVZ6azRQZXJUMzJrUzBSWGtSR25RS1RGMDMzUG5SaVRlT0pOLXo0blBJVXgydXBURUtkcnNtREdxa2NnNWtMdVBrejZJcXBUd2N2ZEpja0owckZlLXdza2JYek5fLW5SRzA0MzBadWZMeS1fRXJ0eFlPUkRoU21WLVF6UXRsTHZvRXV4Ynl5Z3podEg2blVsVzhuaGE4NGdrb0JXWmVMUDRDd2pLa1FlM01GNDVFR1hfOVVFT1ZCUDdmbjlYNlVZbVNlalN1THVjWVVya2ZsWjU1RkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxOMEZvQWxGNFVrNlJ5N2sxQzV2blpBNWpDQXU3dUVrY3E2VkY5c3I4NmtwV0E2dm9RaE9KMHhjZWMzZjFvLVdjMWFHUFhsa1BkM1NyYmYzQm9xdmc2bHZOc3lrUWJDWXhXSjFCRnZ5dk1JUzhDRjFpajJEU1ZOTGF6ZVUyLXJkbk52SlJEQkdWQ0VMVHRTYnZMQmxqU3FHMmxxVnZFVy0tOElwbHZ2cGJOTElOYXpjMWxBZFZJd2ZNdkN0TktYR0ROQk16aW54RjNST2M5LUd2OG5yMm5PbWMzdzVTTTRreWo0eVHSAfIBQVVfeXFMUF93V292dFZQMzh0Rzh5eXBhUkxDNHlWSVZ6azRQZXJUMzJrUzBSWGtSR25RS1RGMDMzUG5SaVRlT0pOLXo0blBJVXgydXBURUtkcnNtREdxa2NnNWtMdVBrejZJcXBUd2N2ZEpja0owckZlLXdza2JYek5fLW5SRzA0MzBadWZMeS1fRXJ0eFlPUkRoU21WLVF6UXRsTHZvRXV4Ynl5Z3podEg2blVsVzhuaGE4NGdrb0JXWmVMUDRDd2pLa1FlM01GNDVFR1hfOVVFT1ZCUDdmbjlYNlVZbVNlalN1THVjWVVya2ZsWjU1RkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India have 'unfair' advantage in Champions Trophy, say unhappy ex-Pakistan players - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ex-Pakistan Players Criticize India's Advantage in Upcoming Champions Trophy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117013874,imgsize-93284,width-400,resizemode-4/117013874.jpg" alt="Indian team in a huddle (File photo - Agency)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Indian team in a huddle (File photo - Agency)</figcaption><p>The upcoming ICC Champions Trophy in 2025 is raising concerns among former Pakistan cricketers, who feel that the tournament's hybrid model gives an unfair advantage to India.</p><ul><li>The ICC Champions Trophy is set to return at the start of 2025.</li><li>India will play all its matches, including the semifinals and final if qualified, in Dubai.</li><li>Pakistan will host the remaining matches in Lahore, Karachi, and Rawalpindi.</li><li>Former players express concerns over India's favorable conditions and logistics.</li><li>The Champions Trophy will take place from February 19 to March 9, 2025, with a key match between India and Pakistan on February 23.</li></ul><blockquote>“India is the only team that knows where it will play the semi-finals and the final, while the other teams will only know that once the group stage is completed.” - Salim Altaf, former Pakistan bowler</blockquote><p>The tournament setup has sparked debate and frustration among ex-Pakistani cricketers, who argue for a more equitable competition structure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/india-have-unfair-advantage-in-champions-trophy-say-unhappy-ex-pakistan-players/articleshow/117013773.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/india-have-unfair-advantage-in-champions-trophy-say-unhappy-ex-pakistan-players/articleshow/117013773.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli says 'main BHAI ke area mein khelta tha', star cricketer opens up on early struggles - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli says 'main BHAI ke area mein khelta tha', star cricketer opens up on early struggles</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br /><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/vinod-kambli-says-main-bhai-ke-area-mein-khelta-tha-star-cricketer-opens-up-on-early-struggles-202501-1736229774.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Vinod Kambli" />
<figcaption>Image credit: X (Formerly Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>Vinod Kambli opens up about his challenging early days in cricket, playing in the notorious 'Bhindi Bazaar' area associated with gangster Dawood Ibrahim.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kambli discussed growing up in a high-risk area while developing his cricket skills.</li>
  <li>He recounted notable moments from his career, including a record six he hit on his Ranji Trophy debut.</li>
  <li>Kambli emphasized the importance of supporting his family, stating he gave all his cricket earnings to them.</li>
  <li>Recent health concerns were highlighted, as he was hospitalized with various ailments.</li>
  <li>A recent video with Sachin Tendulkar went viral, showing Kambli in frail health.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I played in gangster Dawood Ibrahim's locality at 'Bhindi Bazaar' in Mumbai,” Kambli mentioned during the interview.</blockquote>
<p>This reflection sheds light on the rough beginnings of a player who became a household name in Indian cricket, illustrating the perseverance required to succeed against all odds.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/vinod-kambli-says-main-bhai-ke-area-mein-khelta-tha-star-cricketer-opens-up-on-early-struggles-418466/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/vinod-kambli-says-main-bhai-ke-area-mein-khelta-tha-star-cricketer-opens-up-on-early-struggles-418466/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:13:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Squad For Champions Trophy And England ODIs Live Updates: BCCI To Pull Of Big Opening Surprise? - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Squad Announcement for Champions Trophy and England ODIs: Big Bumrah Blow to Team India?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/lr31p6u8_jasprit-bumrah-afp_625x300_06_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="India Squad For Champions Trophy And England ODIs" />
<figcaption>India Squad For Champions Trophy And England ODIs</figcaption>
<p>India is set to announce its squad for the upcoming Champions Trophy and ODI series against England amidst concerns over Jasprit Bumrah's fitness.</p>
<ul>
<li>Champions Trophy scheduled from February 19 to March 9, 2025.</li>
<li>ODI series against England starts on February 6, 2025.</li>
<li>Bumrah likely to miss white-ball assignments due to injury.</li>
<li>Selectors expected to decide between established players and younger talents.</li>
<li>Dinesh Karthik expresses confidence in Rohit Sharma’s inclusion.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I am sure that Rohit Sharma will be part of the ODI series vs England...” - Dinesh Karthik</blockquote>
<p>As the selection date nears, the focus is on how BCCI will manage Bumrah's potential absence and the overall squad strategy for the critical series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-india-vs-england-odi-t20-full-squads-announcement-live-updates-england-tour-of-india-7413646</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-india-vs-england-odi-t20-full-squads-announcement-live-updates-england-tour-of-india-7413646</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:11:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cricketer Yuzvendra Chahal spotted with a mystery girl amid divorce with choreographer wife Dhanashree Verma - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cricketer Yuzvendra Chahal spotted with a mystery girl amid divorce with choreographer wife Dhanashree Verma</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Firstpost</p><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2025/01/chhal-1-2025-01-84268cc7e7080526214bea928ec12abd.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Cricketer Yuzvendra Chahal spotted with a mystery girl amid divorce with choreographer wife Dhanashree Verma" title="Cricketer Yuzvendra Chahal spotted with a mystery girl amid divorce with choreographer wife Dhanashree Verma"><figcaption>Cricketer Yuzvendra Chahal spotted with a mystery girl.</figcaption><p>Cricketer Yuzvendra Chahal and choreographer Dhanashree Verma are reportedly heading for a divorce, with sources indicating it is just a matter of time before it becomes official. Chahal was recently seen with a mystery woman.</p><ul><li>A source claims the divorce is inevitable.</li><li>The exact reasons for their separation are currently unknown.</li><li>Chahal has been spotted with a mystery girl whose identity remains unclear.</li><li>There has been no official confirmation regarding the news from the couple.</li></ul><blockquote>“Dhanashree wanted fame so she married Chahal because her tik-tok career couldn’t give her that popularity.”</blockquote><blockquote>“A woman who flaunts such picture on social media with other men while being in marriage had her priorities somewhere else..”</blockquote><p>Social media reactions have highlighted the complexity of their relationship, with various comments analyzing Dhanashree's intentions and Chahal's career.</p><p>The situation has gained considerable attention, particularly following an incident where Dhanashree was seen close to another choreographer.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/entertainment/cricketer-yuzvendra-chahal-spotted-with-a-mystery-girl-amid-divorce-with-choreographer-wife-dhanashree-verma-13850548.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/entertainment/cricketer-yuzvendra-chahal-spotted-with-a-mystery-girl-amid-divorce-with-choreographer-wife-dhanashree-verma-13850548.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:03:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>