<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 23:23:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 23:23:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anushka Sharma Shares Heartfelt Reaction To Gukesh Dommaraju’s Father’s Inspiring Video; See Here - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anushka Sharma's Heartfelt Response to Gukesh Dommaraju's Father's Inspiring Video</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Anushka Sharma reacts to Gukesh Dommaraju’s father’s viral video, praising his dedication to supporting his son’s journey as the youngest world chess champion." title="Anushka Sharma reacts to Gukesh Dommaraju’s father’s viral video, praising his dedication to supporting his son’s journey as the youngest world chess champion."><figcaption>Anushka Sharma reacts to Gukesh Dommaraju’s father’s viral video, praising his dedication to supporting his son’s journey as the youngest world chess champion.</figcaption><p>Anushka Sharma shared her heartfelt reaction to a touching video of Gukesh Dommaraju’s father, Dr. Rajnikanth, who spoke about the sacrifices made to help his son achieve success as the youngest world champion in chess.</p><ul><li>Anushka praised Dr. Rajnikanth's perspective on parenting, viewing it as a responsibility rather than a sacrifice.</li><li>Dr. Rajnikanth quit his job as an ENT surgeon to support Gukesh Dommaraju's chess career after recognizing his son's potential.</li><li>Gukesh Dommaraju defeated defending champion Ding Liren to secure his title at age 18.</li><li>Anushka's recent posts indicate she balances her family life with social media, sharing moments with her children and husband, Virat Kohli.</li></ul><blockquote>“Beautiful words by a champion parent,” – Anushka Sharma.</blockquote><p>This heartfelt reaction highlights the importance of support in pursuing dreams, reflecting Anushka's values in family and dedication.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/anushka-sharma-shares-heartfelt-reaction-to-gukesh-dommarajus-fathers-inspiring-video-see-here-9156985.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/anushka-sharma-shares-heartfelt-reaction-to-gukesh-dommarajus-fathers-inspiring-video-see-here-9156985.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:33:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chelsea 2-1 Brentford, Premier League: Post-match reaction, ratings - We Ain't Got No History]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chelsea 2-1 Brentford: Match Reaction</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>In a challenging matchup, Chelsea secured a 2-1 victory against Brentford, showcasing their growth in confidence and consistency. Key players like Marc Cucurella and Nicolas Jackson played pivotal roles in the game.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Brentford has been a difficult opponent for Chelsea in recent seasons.</li>
  <li>Moisés Caicedo contributed significantly with his long passes despite his defensive role.</li>
  <li>Chelsea dominated possession and created several scoring opportunities, particularly in the first half.</li>
  <li>Marc Cucurella opened the scoring with a brilliant header.</li>
  <li>Nicolas Jackson, after a frustrating night, scored Chelsea’s second goal.</li>
  <li>Brentford managed a late goal from Mbeumo, adding tension to the match.</li>
  <li>Next, Chelsea will face Shamrock Rovers in the UEFA Conference League.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Carefree!”</blockquote>
<p>This match highlights Chelsea's progress under pressure, although they remain capable of improvement as they prepare for upcoming challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/2024/12/15/24321859/chelsea-2-1-brentford-premier-league-post-match-reaction-ratings</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/2024/12/15/24321859/chelsea-2-1-brentford-premier-league-post-match-reaction-ratings</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 20:57:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah Goes Past Zaheer & Ishant's Tally To Take No. 2 Position In Elite List Led By Kapil Dev - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Surges to No. 2 in India's Elite Five-Wicket Haul List</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Jasprit Bumrah takes No. 2 position in elite list led by Kapil Dev. (Picture Credit: AFP, AP)" title="Jasprit Bumrah takes No. 2 position in elite list led by Kapil Dev. (Picture Credit: AFP, AP)" loading="eager"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah takes No. 2 position in elite list led by Kapil Dev. (Picture Credit: AFP, AP)</figcaption></figure><p>Star Indian pacer Jasprit Bumrah shone during the second day of the third Test against Australia, taking five wickets for 72 runs, surpassing Zaheer Khan and Ishant Sharma to secure the No. 2 spot for most five-wicket hauls among Indian pacers in Test history.</p><ul><li>Bumrah achieved his 12th five-wicket haul in Tests, moving past Zaheer and Ishant's 11.</li><li>He dismissed notable players including Steve Smith (101) and Travis Head (152) in a single over.</li><li>Bumrah is now the leading bowler with eight five-wicket hauls in SENA countries, surpassing Kapil Dev's seven.</li><li>He has equaled Anil Kumble's tally of 49 wickets in Australia, aiming to break Kapil Dev’s record of 51 in the ongoing series.</li><li>This fifer is Bumrah's 9th in the World Test Championship, tying with Pat Cummins for the most by a fast bowler.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bumrah has displayed extraordinary bowling skills, becoming a crucial asset for the Indian cricket team.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Jasprit Bumrah's recent performance not only cements his status among India's elite bowlers but also makes him a pivotal figure in the future landscape of Test cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-goes-past-zaheer-ishants-tally-to-take-no-2-position-in-elite-list-led-by-kapil-dev-9156862.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-goes-past-zaheer-ishants-tally-to-take-no-2-position-in-elite-list-led-by-kapil-dev-9156862.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 19:31:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manchester City vs Manchester United Highlights, Premier League: Man City Stunned As Man Utd Come From Behind To Win Derby - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxPbTgwWGZXVFBhVVVrTkJtS1dfMTNWOEtKOEtfcXBYSXczN1ByRk9weEZUYjRmMm9FZUZiOE5WMDBMTWZTNlFtNG5OdTRTSzduVllERGFTX3k2V1NqZ3A5Q0NVZXV4UG9najNtLVhrVFM4RjgxcHhKSWszc0p0WG9iZjRxNlJXWlJfUS1WRGlIRGI2TUZsaW95Mmk1elZsaGpCbWdsQzFRUk05WWNJVEZzSDd5N1diWTc2V010c25lTzAzNjdBaTJ3emt6bGVZem5vU2R5UmxwempISkFUWHJNeEU4Zmd2aFZoS0RCTVVpZ3phMUxHamfSAf4BQVVfeXFMTW5Jbk83V2ZHQ2h3U3RUOFFGLXVsanJKNjhsa0YtdUZPc0lpQ0xMS2hpU0tOM1dwM1VER2FiTERTZFc4TXI0OElnZVVLM0pQU2dsRjhWQWpCN2pOZF9jUnEwS0dhSDUwUW1tUWp0Z0ZnNkdvaG5qclZVeU1CZDlqSDFLWVUxb0Q0MFNoQVhQQUo0cHZmMW0wdGFESkdlNG9PdHk5QnVRS0c0ZVQ1WlZyUEp5UjVBV09PTU1HZl92akRJb3dFUVFDMHdqTHVCRk13RXAxcVdXTl9NdjMxUmhQUjVRTFRGenRaUUgyc0NqYldOWEtCdmJQM3UzbmVPOEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxPbTgwWGZXVFBhVVVrTkJtS1dfMTNWOEtKOEtfcXBYSXczN1ByRk9weEZUYjRmMm9FZUZiOE5WMDBMTWZTNlFtNG5OdTRTSzduVllERGFTX3k2V1NqZ3A5Q0NVZXV4UG9najNtLVhrVFM4RjgxcHhKSWszc0p0WG9iZjRxNlJXWlJfUS1WRGlIRGI2TUZsaW95Mmk1elZsaGpCbWdsQzFRUk05WWNJVEZzSDd5N1diWTc2V010c25lTzAzNjdBaTJ3emt6bGVZem5vU2R5UmxwempISkFUWHJNeEU4Zmd2aFZoS0RCTVVpZ3phMUxHamfSAf4BQVVfeXFMTW5Jbk83V2ZHQ2h3U3RUOFFGLXVsanJKNjhsa0YtdUZPc0lpQ0xMS2hpU0tOM1dwM1VER2FiTERTZFc4TXI0OElnZVVLM0pQU2dsRjhWQWpCN2pOZF9jUnEwS0dhSDUwUW1tUWp0Z0ZnNkdvaG5qclZVeU1CZDlqSDFLWVUxb0Q0MFNoQVhQQUo0cHZmMW0wdGFESkdlNG9PdHk5QnVRS0c0ZVQ1WlZyUEp5UjVBV09PTU1HZl92akRJb3dFUVFDMHdqTHVCRk13RXAxcVdXTl9NdjMxUmhQUjVRTFRGenRaUUgyc0NqYldOWEtCdmJQM3UzbmVPOEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 18:34:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI in need of new treasurer as Ashish Shelar set to step down - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNSk9Cd3R4QUdtY3RBbFZSR2tWOXlNUjdfaXBMVFpoZnlVcVhVVV9GYkhQQjFWcTJQbHRRdjlXZHZvUHRwMmtQODFDWEd0aEVvekpSM0U2YUpmdTU3Y3B4MmFGVjB3OUw2RVRERXdiMkY0V3VUdmYwdThuZXAzWHJqRzRsVTBDb0hsZXJ2U3h5RFpmUTU3Sjh4clFYSHViRUN6cjJrYnBvT1djNDlH?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNSk9Cd3R4QUdtY3RBbFZSR2tWOXlNUjdfaXBMVFpoZnlVcVhVVV9GYkhQQjFWcTJQbHRRdjlXZHZvUHRwMmtQODFDWEd0aEVvekpSM0U2YUpmdTU3Y3B4MmFGVjB3OUw2RVRERXdiMkY0V3VUdmYwdThuZXAzWHJqRzRsVTBDb0hsZXJ2U3h5RFpmUTU3Sjh4clFYSHViRUN6cjJrYnBvT1djNDlH?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI in need of new treasurer with Ashish Shelar set to step down - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI in Need of New Treasurer as Ashish Shelar Set to Step Down</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Sun, Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c587438/shelar-has-been-the-treasurer.jpg" alt="Shelar has been the treasurer of the BCCI since September 2022." title="Shelar has been the treasurer of the BCCI since September 2022." />
<figcaption>Shelar has been the treasurer of the BCCI since September 2022. © Getty</figcaption>
<p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) is set to find a new treasurer as Ashish Shelar, currently in the position, will step down after taking a ministerial role in the Maharashtra Cabinet, which is against BCCI’s constitutional rules.</p>
<ul>
<li>Shelar has served as treasurer since September 2022.</li>
<li>His resignation is the second departure of a BCCI office-bearer in two weeks.</li>
<li>The BCCI constitution disqualifies individuals from office if they hold a ministerial position.</li>
<li>Shelar previously confirmed he would not be taking on a more demanding role within BCCI due to his political commitments.</li>
<li>Questions remain on whether BCCI will elect a new treasurer or if responsibilities will be delegated.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A person shall be disqualified from being an office-bearer... if he or she is: a Minister or a Government Servant.”</blockquote>
<p>This transition within the BCCI comes at a pivotal time, influencing its governance as it navigates future leadership and responsibilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132779/bcci-in-need-of-new-treasurer-with-ashish-shelar-set-to-step-down</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132779/bcci-in-need-of-new-treasurer-with-ashish-shelar-set-to-step-down</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:38:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nidhi stands tall as India retain Women’s Asia Cup with victory over three-time champs China - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nidhi stands tall as India retain Women’s Asia Cup with victory over three-time champs China</h1><p><strong>Published on: Dec 15, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://images.hindustantimes.com/default/550x309.jpg" alt="HT Image" title="HT Image"><figcaption>HT Image</figcaption></figure><p>Nidhi's remarkable performance in the penalty shootout helped India defeat China 3-2, securing their second consecutive Women's Junior Asia Cup title.</p><ul><li>India's goalkeeper Nidhi made three crucial saves in the shootout.</li><li>The match ended in a 1-1 draw after regulation time.</li><li>India's goals came from Kanika Siwach in the second half and Sunelita Toppo in the shootout.</li><li>Nidhi denied penalty attempts from China, showcasing her skills throughout the game.</li></ul><blockquote>Nidhi's heroics capped off a stellar performance, making crucial saves in both regulation and the shootout.</blockquote><p>This victory not only highlights India's growing prowess in women's hockey but also showcases the talent of emerging players like Nidhi.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/nidhi-stands-tall-as-india-retain-women-s-asia-cup-with-victory-over-three-time-champs-china-101734284043568.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/nidhi-stands-tall-as-india-retain-women-s-asia-cup-with-victory-over-three-time-champs-china-101734284043568.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:34:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manchester City vs Manchester United LIVE Score, Premier League: Josko Gvardiol Puts Man City 1-0 Up vs Man Utd At Half-Time - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manchester City vs Manchester United LIVE Score, Premier League: Man Utd Stun Man City With Quick Goals, Lead 2-1</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>In an exciting Premier League matchup, Manchester United shocked Manchester City by taking an early lead with two quick goals, bringing the score to 2-1.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Manchester United scored two goals quickly in the first half.</li>
  <li>Manchester City is trailing 1-2 at home.</li>
  <li>The match is crucial for both teams in the title race.</li>
  <li>Live updates are being provided as the game unfolds.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is a vital match for both sides, and United is putting on a brilliant performance.”</blockquote>
<p>The match remains intense with the potential for more goals as both teams fight for dominance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/english-premier-league/manchester-city-vs-manchester-united-live-score-premier-league-2024-25-football-match-live-scorecard-updates-7254782</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/english-premier-league/manchester-city-vs-manchester-united-live-score-premier-league-2024-25-football-match-live-scorecard-updates-7254782</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:29:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rodrigues, Sadhu hand India big win on belter - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Secures a 49-Run Victory Over West Indies in T20I Series Opener</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p>An aggressive performance with key partnerships gave India a 1-0 lead in the three-match T20I series against West Indies.</p><ul><li>India scored 195 runs for 4 wickets, with Jemimah Rodrigues contributing a remarkable 73 runs off 35 balls.</li><li>Smriti Mandhana supported with a solid 54 runs, forming an 81-run partnership with Rodrigues.</li><li>West Indies managed 146 runs for 7 wickets, with Deandra Dottin scoring 52 runs.</li><li>Titas Sadhu took three important wickets, cementing her impact in the match.</li><li>The match showcased innovative batting strategies and strong fielding by India.</li></ul><blockquote>“Rodrigues stuck to her strengths, sweeping and reverse-sweeping from the get-go.”</blockquote><p>India demonstrated strong batting and bowling, setting a challenging target for West Indies, ultimately leading to their victory.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/west-indies-women-in-india-2024-25-1459886/india-women-vs-west-indies-women-1st-t20i-1459891/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/west-indies-women-in-india-2024-25-1459886/india-women-vs-west-indies-women-1st-t20i-1459891/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:25:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah targeted with the racially sensitive remark in the third Test against Australia - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Faces Racist Remark During Third Test Against Australia</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Cricket Today</p><img width="1200" height="675" src="https://crictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Team-India-Bumrah.webp" alt="Jasprit Bumrah"><figcaption>The incident happened on Day 2 of the Gabba match in Brisbane. Guha's remark came after the right-arm seamer dismissed the two openers of the host nation.</figcaption><p>Jasprit Bumrah's historic bowling performance was marred by a racially insensitive comment from former cricketer Isa Guha during the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy 2024-25.</p><ul><li>Bumrah took five wickets in Australia's first innings of the third Test.</li><li>Isa Guha made a controversial remark likening Bumrah to a primate after his exceptional performance.</li><li>Guha's comment has sparked widespread criticism on social media.</li><li>This incident draws parallels to a past racial controversy involving Indian cricketer Harbhajan Singh.</li></ul><blockquote>“He’s the MVP and the most valuable Primate. He is going to do all the taking for his team.” - Isa Guha</blockquote><p>The response to Guha's comment has been significant, highlighting ongoing issues of racism in sports commentary.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/jasprit-bumrah-targeted-with-the-racially-sensitive-remark-in-the-third-test-against-australia/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/jasprit-bumrah-targeted-with-the-racially-sensitive-remark-in-the-third-test-against-australia/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:23:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shakib's bowling suspension by ECB extends to international cricket, confirms BCB - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shakib's Bowling Suspension by ECB Extends to International Cricket, Confirms BCB</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Sun, Dec 15, 2024, 05:16 PM | <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p><img height="396" width="595" alt="The veteran allrounder is set to appear soon for reassessment at an accredited testing centre" title="The veteran allrounder is set to appear soon for reassessment at an accredited testing centre" src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c586608/the-veteran-allrounder-is-set.jpg"><figcaption>The veteran allrounder is set to appear soon for reassessment at an accredited testing centre © Getty</figcaption><p>Shakib Al Hasan faces a new setback as the Bangladesh Cricket Board announced that his suspension from bowling in ECB competitions now applies to all domestic and international cricket.</p><ul><li>Shakib's suspension was confirmed by the BCB following his reported bowling action in a match for Surrey.</li><li>The ICC automatically recognizes and enforces suspensions by national cricket federations.</li><li>This is the first scrutiny of Shakib's bowling action in his 17-year career, having taken 712 international wickets.</li><li>Shakib had announced his retirement from T20Is and has expressed intentions to quit ODIs after the Champions Trophy.</li><li>He remains eligible to play purely as a batsman and will seek reassessment of his bowling action at an accredited center.</li></ul><blockquote>“When a National Cricket Federation suspends a player from bowling in its domestic cricket competitions, the suspension is automatically recognised and enforced by the ICC.”</blockquote><p>Shakib’s future in cricket may hinge on the outcome of his reassessment and the reinstatement of his bowling privileges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132777/shakibs-bowling-suspension-by-ecb-extends-to-international-cricket-confirms-bcb</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132777/shakibs-bowling-suspension-by-ecb-extends-to-international-cricket-confirms-bcb</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:19:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Rightly Went Unsold": Prithvi Shaw Once Again Under Fire After Disappointing Show - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rightly Went Unsold: Prithvi Shaw Once Again Under Fire After Disappointing Show</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/fmp0m1k8_cas_625x300_15_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Rightly Went Unsold: Prithvi Shaw Once Again Under Fire After Disappointing Show"><figcaption>Prithvi Shaw departs during Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy © AFP</figcaption><p>Prithvi Shaw faced heavy criticism after a disappointing performance in the Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy final, contributing to growing concerns regarding his form and fitness as he went unsold in the IPL 2025 auction.</p><ul><li>Prithvi Shaw scored only 10 runs off 6 balls in the final against Madhya Pradesh.</li><li>Mumbai secured the SMAT title, defeating Madhya Pradesh by five wickets.</li><li>Shaw's poor performance followed a year without significant scores, raising doubts about his future.</li><li>Suryakumar Yadav's performance (48 runs) helped stabilize the innings for Mumbai.</li></ul><blockquote>"Prithvi Shaw rightly went unsold at the auction. No fitness. No fielding. No discipline. Cameos at best with the bat." — Vipul Ghatol 🇮🇳 (@Vipul_Espeaks)</blockquote><p>The match highlighted Shaw's struggles while showcasing Mumbai's strength in depth, leading to speculation about his professional future and fitness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/rightly-went-unsold-prithvi-shaw-once-again-under-fire-after-disappointing-show-7255704</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/rightly-went-unsold-prithvi-shaw-once-again-under-fire-after-disappointing-show-7255704</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 16:42:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gukesh crowned 18th world champion: "I'm still this kid who loves chess" - Chess News | ChessBase]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTFBkakZlN251MjkwNHFDS0RZdFJWRnRPelFOZUFpMVNPZ0NUb2JfeVZZS2pNT0lkMGs2dy1NRmlVbTFfNWNzY3ROMjRSVGc1ajVoSkprN0tVVHZUVXlrMjdXdDVWWWRFejNieDlMM1pGd21xU2JKWEVFS3hR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTFBkakZlN251MjkwNHFDS0RZdFJWRnRPelFOZUFpMVNPZ0NUb2JfeVZZS2pNT0lkMGs2dy1NRmlVbTFfNWNzY3ROMjRSVGc1ajVoSkprN0tVVHZUVXlrMjdXdDVWWWRFejNieDlMM1pGd21xU2JKWEVFS3hR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 16:27:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BBL 2024-2025: Match 2, SIX vs REN Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between SIX vs REN? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxNUWQwS2pPeEEwaUVGTHRESDJjRzQzYVFPRkdMS3p0V0hIMGc3U3FDdWpucUZ5VzZNdHFfQUZMU3E3SE1jS3I1U1VFX0Zfc3JxdFhUUG5TOVF5ZFNmU0tuUVdFSk4xQ2p2TENvTHhSZ0hwb2V0ZWNXb0dSTUEyVUREWmJCVjF2cmV0dlFpN08yaElMZThjaDNPZ29LRGJjOTNxNWJHbFRJYWVhY2xMRk5Ydk1MZ2lydmo5OXVlTGtvNzRLcnpEWmxRV1Q1RW9MUWJ0aHhCLWtjbWNYYTY4REtEUkxWMENZZ0hu0gHwAUFVX3lxTE1BcXR5MjVnQnRFUU5jdWVQQkotOElWUWhNSUxxNDQwczB6UjJCUjFrQ1BmNjR4RnQwUnp0RmtIUWJnWFU2eHVxdGhBdEVBVjlNSlVfLTBpTUIzU1JGSFVURnRYNmEyRTVyTENTNVpIZF9mS0toczREWU9aQnR6UHdHWDl6T2NESlN5THRnMU1ZTzlDeDdtd2M4T0hnSUxlYXVPcnNpb25fSi1aT3M1YjZfNHdoQ3NvV1pCVVNLNnVGa3RBcnBBQk9Eakg1eUE3QU5rWllJS25sQ3pGVWVhRDItWUotU3hpaTlZVE1KejBIdQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxNUWQwS2pPeEEwaUVGTHRESDJjRzQzYVFPRkdMS3p0V0hIMGc3U3FDdWpucUZ5VzZNdHFfQUZMU3E3SE1jS3I1U1VFX0Zfc3JxdFhUUG5TOVF5ZFNmU0tuUVdFSk4xQ2p2TENvTHhSZ0hwb2V0ZWNXb0dSTUEyVUREWmJCVjF2cmV0dlFpN08yaElMZThjaDNPZ29LRGJjOTNxNWJHbFRJYWVhY2xMRk5Ydk1MZ2lydmo5OXVlTGtvNzRLcnpEWmxRV1Q1RW9MUWJ0aHhCLWtjbWNYYTY4REtEUkxWMENZZ0hu0gHwAUFVX3lxTE1BcXR5MjVnQnRFUU5jdWVQQkotOElWUWhNSUxxNDQwczB6UjJCUjFrQ1BmNjR4RnQwUnp0RmtIUWJnWFU2eHVxdGhBdEVBVjlNSlVfLTBpTUIzU1JGSFVURnRYNmEyRTVyTENTNVpIZF9mS0toczREWU9aQnR6UHdHWDl6T2NESlN5THRnMU1ZTzlDeDdtd2M4T0hnSUxlYXVPcnNpb25fSi1aT3M1YjZfNHdoQ3NvV1pCVVNLNnVGa3RBcnBBQk9Eakg1eUE3QU5rWllJS25sQ3pGVWVhRDItWUotU3hpaTlZVE1KejBIdQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 16:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brain teaser: If you crack this challenging puzzle, you are definitely a maths wizard - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A maths brain teaser on X left users puzzled, sparking debates over its solution and gaining over 11.5k views with diverse reactions.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/15/550x309/Screenshot_2024-12-15_165546_1734261972238_1734261985815.png" alt="On X, a brain teaser went viral, sparking debate with users sharing their reactions. (X/@jitendra789789)" title="On X, a brain teaser went viral, sparking debate with users sharing their reactions. (X/@jitendra789789)"><figcaption>On X, a brain teaser went viral, sparking debate with users sharing their reactions. (X/@jitendra789789)</figcaption><p>Brain teasers are a fantastic way to challenge your mind and test your problem-solving skills, particularly if you're a fan of mathematical riddles. A new puzzle making the rounds on social media is leaving users scratching their heads, and it's perfect for those who enjoy decoding logical mysteries.</p><h2>The puzzle that has everyone talking</h2><p>Shared on X (formerly Twitter) by the account "Maths/Technology &amp; Other Facts," the teaser reads:</p><p>"A + A = 2, A + B = 3, A + B + C = 6, A + B + C x 4 = ?"</p><p>At first glance, the equation seems straightforward, but it’s the twist in the last line that has left many perplexed. The post has already garnered over 11,500 views, with users flooding the comments section to share their thoughts, theories, and solutions.</p><h2>Here's how the internet reaction:</h2><p>Reactions to the puzzle have been varied, with some users confidently declaring their answers and others debating the interpretation of the equation.</p><p><blockquote>"The answer has to be 24 because A + B + C equals 6, and multiplying it by 4 gives 24. Simple!"</blockquote><p>Another replied, "But wait—doesn’t the order of operations matter here? Shouldn’t it be solved differently?"</p><p>Some users took a more sceptical approach, questioning the logic behind the equation. <blockquote>"Are we sure this even makes sense? What’s the actual rule for C?"</blockquote></p><p>Meanwhile, others seemed more amused than analytical. "I give up! Maths wasn’t my favourite subject in school," joked another.</p><p>A few creative thinkers suggested alternative solutions, saying, "What if C is undefined? That changes everything!" and "This is more philosophical than mathematical—what does X really mean here?"</p><h2>The verdict</h2><p>Whether you solve it or not, this brain teaser has achieved its purpose: sparking conversation and engaging users in a fun mathematical debate. The puzzle is a testament to how a simple post can capture the curiosity of thousands, encouraging both logical reasoning and a bit of lighthearted fun.</p><p>Do you think you have the answer? Dive into the comments and join the conversation—it might just be your turn to crack the code!</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/brain-teaser-if-you-crack-this-challenging-puzzle-you-are-definitely-a-maths-wizard-101734261405352.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/brain-teaser-if-you-crack-this-challenging-puzzle-you-are-definitely-a-maths-wizard-101734261405352.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 16:00:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Pakistan women's U-19 T20 Asia Cup Highlights: G Kamilini, Sonam Yadav star as IND beat PAK by 9 wickets | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwJBVV95cUxQR2I4SmJ2RVZRYUh5a0hsd29XZ2xGZHNtUXBiQVdFcy03VE9kOUpqN3RPZ2hCSVI0WVRoMlhwQzQ1ZXFQanVYNTNOQjBXVVRhdkgxdktUeWdDdDk4YUNRS0pRU0dUV29OdU1kWjNBM3R4ckFhWVQ2XzVxTF8zOUR6dVVMZ0dfbFI5UVZEQzcybFAwaG9nT3JkM0JFVzlUVENiZWVCeXpNYlRMNVBCNXdHQUxYMlMyMEptbF9lS0VMdWxVMWg3dmlsUXU1aTFpX1piNjB5WkJHZy1nMGotVnV0b2JDRlJQNE9wZEJRWUQ4eW1GZjhDWHYwN3JJd2hwdUtTdkRNRjZVdW1WT1dPbkNZLVZsSdIBmAJBVV95cUxPbTdQODJLOFo3eGgxT05Vc3JTaGU2R3ZNNHVyMUpBdWl4dzE3SE0yQkNDekYyMlM0LTdaR1ZXcUpBY1hhOVBxT2R1djVQTnUwdkNYNjhBSTQ4dnRHT1VxQ3M4WGJ0cERLQUgtN3FWNDQtSlR1eDg0eUp4Z3FSYl9xRmRkSzE1WHZIcmVmM1E3dkdZNkJMVXR2S3RVREVaUTRmRFpHUVJqdzh6NDJpMnFvdmRCUS1TYlNXRG1KcThEbVBHQk5KalpZem9BTU8tYWRxOXJxSmpXd3RET0ZfaGFOOEMwNzJZcENOTDc4ZkdGOXB1eVdiMFlvNUxZemEyOTFQbzVDaUZtRVVja1FYTFdhYmJqRlVpVUtq?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwJBVV95cUxQR2I4SmJ2RVZRYUh5a0hsd29XZ2xGZHNtUXBiQVdFcy03VE9kOUpqN3RPZ2hCSVI0WVRoMlhwQzQ1ZXFQanVYNTNOQjBXVVRhdkgxdktUeWdDdDk4YUNRS0pRU0dUV29OdU1kWjNBM3R4ckFhWVQ2XzVxTF8zOUR6dVVMZ0dfbFI5UVZEQzcybFAwaG9nT3JkM0JFVzlUVENiZWVCeXpNYlRMNVBCNXdHQUxYMlMyMEptbF9lS0VMdWxVMWg3dmlsUXU1aTFpX1piNjB5WkJHZy1nMGotVnV0b2JDRlJQNE9wZEJRWUQ4eW1GZjhDWHYwN3JJd2hwdUtTdkRNRjZVdW1WT1dPbkNZLVZsSdIBmAJBVV95cUxPbTdQODJLOFo3eGgxT05Vc3JTaGU2R3ZNNHVyMUpBdWl4dzE3SE0yQkNDekYyMlM0LTdaR1ZXcUpBY1hhOVBxT2R1djVQTnUwdkNYNjhBSTQ4dnRHT1VxQ3M4WGJ0cERLQUgtN3FWNDQtSlR1eDg0eUp4Z3FSYl9xRmRkSzE1WHZIcmVmM1E3dkdZNkJMVXR2S3RVREVaUTRmRFpHUVJqdzh6NDJpMnFvdmRCUS1TYlNXRG1KcThEbVBHQk5KalpZem9BTU8tYWRxOXJxSmpXd3RET0ZfaGFOOEMwNzJZcENOTDc4ZkdGOXB1eVdiMFlvNUxZemEyOTFQbzVDaUZtRVVja1FYTFdhYmJqRlVpVUtq?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:41:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Rúben Amorim omitted Rashford and Garnacho from Man Utd squad vs Man City - UtdDistrict]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rúben Amorim Excludes Rashford and Garnacho from Squad for Manchester City Clash</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Published on December 15, 2024 by UtdDistrict</p>
<p>Rúben Amorim, head coach of Manchester United, has made the controversial decision to leave out wingers Marcus Rashford and Alejandro Garnacho from the squad facing Manchester City. This decision comes in light of their recent performances.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rashford and Garnacho are not injured and trained well leading up to the match.</li>
  <li>Amorim's decisions were based on evaluations of training performances and recent game contributions.</li>
  <li>City has struggled recently, winning only one of their last ten matches.</li>
  <li>The match is critical for both teams as they navigate a challenging Premier League season.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We try to evaluate everything training performance, game performances, engagement with teammates.” - Rúben Amorim</blockquote>
<p>This match is pivotal as Manchester United aims to climb the Premier League table while also aiming to capitalize on Manchester City's struggles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://utddistrict.co.uk/marcus-rashford-man-utd-injury-news-man-city/15/12/2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://utddistrict.co.uk/marcus-rashford-man-utd-injury-news-man-city/15/12/2024/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:40:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai vs Madhya Pradesh Highlights, SMAT 2024 Final: Shedge wins it for MUM as they claim second title - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai vs Madhya Pradesh Highlights, SMAT 2024 Final: Shedge wins it for MUM as they claim second title</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Mumbai-vs-Madhya-Pradesh-MUM-vs-MP-MUM-vs-MP-Final-live-score-MUM-vs-MP-SMAT-2024-25-live-score-MUM-vs-MP-Final-match-MUM-vs-MP-Final-match-live-score-Mumbai-vs-Madhya-Pradesh-live-score-Mumbai-vs-Madhya-Pradesh-live.jpg?w=750" alt="Mumbai vs Madhya Pradesh" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>MUM vs MP Final SMAT 2024-25 Live: Mumbai will take on Madhya Pradesh</figcaption><p>Mumbai's star-studded batting lineup successfully chased down a target of 175 runs set by Madhya Pradesh, winning the SMAT 2024 final.</p><ul><li>Rajat Patidar scored an unbeaten 81 runs for Madhya Pradesh, helping them post a competitive total.</li><li>Mumbai, opting to field first, restricted MP to 175 runs in 20 overs.</li><li>Suryansh Shedge played a pivotal role by scoring a quick 36 runs off just 15 balls, leading Mumbai to victory in 18 overs.</li><li>Suryakumar Yadav contributed 48 runs, maintaining control over the innings.</li><li>This match marked Mumbai's second title in the tournament’s history.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite batting at No 3 for RCB in the past, Rajat Patidar has been batting at No 5 for Madhya Pradesh.”</blockquote><p>This thrilling final showcased Mumbai’s dominance in the Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy, further solidifying their status in Indian cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/mumbai-vs-madhya-pradesh-live-cricket-score-smat-2024-final-toss-playing-xi-updates-can-patidar-lead-mp-to-first-title-at-chinnaswamy-9725832/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/mumbai-vs-madhya-pradesh-live-cricket-score-smat-2024-final-toss-playing-xi-updates-can-patidar-lead-mp-to-first-title-at-chinnaswamy-9725832/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man Utd stars Rashford and Garnacho ruthlessly DROPPED by Amorim over WhatsApp for Manchester derby... - The Sun]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rashford and Garnacho Dropped for Manchester Derby Over WhatsApp</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> The Sun</p>
<img src="https://www.thesun.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/manchester-uniteds-marcus-rashford-celebrates-933745030.jpg?strip=all&amp;w=960" alt="Marcus Rashford Alejandro Garnacho have been left out of Manchester United's derby">
<figcaption>Marcus Rashford Alejandro Garnacho have been left out of Manchester United's derby<br>Credit: AP</figcaption>
<p>Manchester United's Marcus Rashford and Alejandro Garnacho were unexpectedly dropped from the squad traveling for the derby against Manchester City, with the decision communicated through the club's WhatsApp chat.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Both players were not included in the starting eleven or on the substitutes' bench.</li>
  <li>United's coach, Ruben Amorim, stated his selection is based on comprehensive evaluations including training and game performances.</li>
  <li>Rashford's recent performances and attitude have come under criticism from former players like Roy Keane.</li>
  <li>Amad Diallo turned the game around for United, which highlights the intense competition for positions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p>I pay attention to everything, the way you eat, the way you put your clothes to go to a game. Everything. I make my evaluation and then I decide.<br><cite>Ruben Amorim</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This decision signals a critical moment for both players as they navigate the current challenges with the team's performance and their own careers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thesun.co.uk/sport/32315843/marcus-rashford-manchester-derby-man-utd-city/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thesun.co.uk/sport/32315843/marcus-rashford-manchester-derby-man-utd-city/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:21:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life-changing day: Dharavi’s Simran Shaikh, daughter of a wireman, fetches Rs 1.90 crore bid at WPL auction - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dharavi's Simran Shaikh Achieves Historic Bid at WPL Auction</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Simran-Shaikh-FAMILY-CROP.jpg" alt="Simran Shaikh's family celebrating her achievement">
<figcaption>Simran Shaikh's family celebrates her becoming the most expensive player in WPL 2025.</figcaption>
<p>Simran Shaikh, a resident of Dharavi, was sold for Rs 1.90 crore to Gujarat Giants at the Women's Premier League auction, showcasing her incredible journey from facing discouragement to achieving success.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Simran was initially discouraged from playing cricket due to societal expectations.</li>
  <li>She is now the second-highest paid uncapped player after Kashvee Gautam.</li>
  <li>Simran plans to use her earnings to improve her family's living situation.</li>
  <li>Multiple uncapped Indian players received significant bids during the auction.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I have no words to express my joy... Today the same people have come to congratulate our family.” – Simran Shaikh</blockquote>
<p>Simran's success at the auction not only uplifts her family but also serves as an inspiration for aspiring athletes from underprivileged backgrounds.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/dharavi-simran-shaikh-daughter-wireman-rs-1-90-crore-wpl-auction-9726507/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/dharavi-simran-shaikh-daughter-wireman-rs-1-90-crore-wpl-auction-9726507/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:16:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Travis Head reveals secret behind tackling India pacer Jasprit Bumrah: ‘More about being proactive with my…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxOSGtVNjBSTkowSC1fMmFpSGotLVJLcWFnbmV0S0dvZXFFM1ZodzdnMmpnaWplVHl4aFdqMjlBbWMyM1dVZElLYkF6NldiNDk4Q3h5VldnbjBNT2lFVXN2dF96b0hlUm5FTm5WcjJjX3dLcGprLTV3c0h3VnpZTnVuWUp1c0lqdGdUSk9XWVJvdlZuekszVTJaRUlHb2pZZ0l2OU0tZVRsVklaMXItcWFJRkItVTYwTlJkcTAzTnk1ckp2YXIxUldVWFZyNWViSkNnU01keHVDbW5rYjZnWF85dEktTlBnVFEwUTR4Q0ZzZ3o0WXpLN0dv0gH8AUFVX3lxTE13aVpwMDB2Zk5ILTBpc29IZEZyczRDRlZZSENMWlFiWnU0X244ZHplemd6R0p1RV9MWEtSZFozdjRNUTlLMlhfdFNla294cVpZTnEwaDBjY2IzRkh4eGlhU1RKRGRmY1JDdS1ULVlVb053b2NTNkxBWFVhNVlzdFVuN3lrMGVKaFc3TmxiZWpMWEJqUjdQVjMyZjFaMk5DZVR4Y3VWc01iVUtRTkNXcG5Vc2dlaHNXaU0yOHpXM3F3VXdxazFZY1BweXZLVWRkaGVjWEtFUTVGTE5jOW1DUXZHVjlMcEFlYTFuWHlRVHZYcG1zSzFGdEl3Nzd6eg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxOSGtVNjBSTkowSC1fMmFpSGotLVJLcWFnbmV0S0dvZXFFM1ZodzdnMmpnaWplVHl4aFdqMjlBbWMyM1dVZElLYkF6NldiNDk4Q3h5VldnbjBNT2lFVXN2dF96b0hlUm5FTm5WcjJjX3dLcGprLTV3c0h3VnpZTnVuWUp1c0lqdGdUSk9XWVJvdlZuekszVTJaRUlHb2pZZ0l2OU0tZVRsVklaMXItcWFJRkItVTYwTlJkcTAzTnk1ckp2YXIxUldVWFZyNWViSkNnU01keHVDbW5rYjZnWF85dEktTlBnVFEwUTR4Q0ZzZ3o0WXpLN0dv0gH8AUFVX3lxTE13aVpwMDB2Zk5ILTBpc29IZEZyczRDRlZZSENMWlFiWnU0X244ZHplemd6R0p1RV9MWEtSZFozdjRNUTlLMlhfdFNla294cVpZTnEwaDBjY2IzRkh4eGlhU1RKRGRmY1JDdS1ULVlVb053b2NTNkxBWFVhNVlzdFVuN3lrMGVKaFc3TmxiZWpMWEJqUjdQVjMyZjFaMk5DZVR4Y3VWc01iVUtRTkNXcG5Vc2dlaHNXaU0yOHpXM3F3VXdxazFZY1BweXZLVWRkaGVjWEtFUTVGTE5jOW1DUXZHVjlMcEFlYTFuWHlRVHZYcG1zSzFGdEl3Nzd6eg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:53:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai vs Madhya Pradesh LIVE Cricket Score, SMAT 2024 Final: Shedge wins it for MUM as they claim their second SMAT title - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwJBVV95cUxQTER2RlJaVzVaWDYzdi1DSzlHLTdGTndVNnF4Ti0zcU51d1NGbzRqZHVGZzMtM1k3blZxS0lvWXZKM3ZZaFpfeFZFZ2gtQmdSTURUY2JGVWhSLTVraGZsLThkd1VPTWtpNzVkSHFXR1I5d1hTY29PWXZ2RE1zSm1VOGpDX2VvNVZHQzYwWFQ2djlOWnJzMUJGdWtQcVJpd1U5VEJKSHBhakp3WHNGZGUxLVRhX0p0bGlkRi1hM0g4WnVzMllTQUFqX2tDUnpwMkk5SERIOERqRTJqSzk4Mm5ibnVaRGhJSXJSLW93RGpSb1VVYU1jNjVzOUFDTTdXT292Z2NvYm5qNWZuMnFYX2RxMDViWnQ1Q2dmTGVN0gGiAkFVX3lxTFBZZk1GNUtJWWlraExBbGRZT1ZyekNvbW1saTg4T3BCOGlSRkhsZ3lVc0pjUnV6OC1Nd2ljYnhGbVktaG1pVlZNYjBJVUQycHctWjdwem5ER0xlR3Foc1p4Q0pIWTFTR2xZVzd4ekticTZWWjd2YnM0YmxYWHR3NW5ybUtmQl9HRWdHaHJLWXNIb2RNSUs3TTF5ZjdQNDRyOGlSeGg2OVZoTnMxeHNSOElTUXdQQWcyRlpQekRIM3dwR0tGRUxObjE3ZEpBTDYtTXhmZ2Y2WFd4ZnpZdDJDbHFVcm5vYXJ0SG1RcG9mTWFVci1LVVd6LU9tMHNLTjFZNjQ4OS1wQ29BVUU4TGE4d1kxMG9jRGpxR2ctVmlOV0JPRElB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwJBVV95cUxQTER2RlJaVzVaWDYzdi1DSzlHLTdGTndVNnF4Ti0zcU51d1NGbzRqZHVGZzMtM1k3blZxS0lvWXZKM3ZZaFpfeFZFZ2gtQmdSTURUY2JGVWhSLTVraGZsLThkd1VPTWtpNzVkSHFXR1I5d1hTY29PWXZ2RE1zSm1VOGpDX2VvNVZHQzYwWFQ2djlOWnJzMUJGdWtQcVJpd1U5VEJKSHBhakp3WHNGZGUxLVRhX0p0bGlkRi1hM0g4WnVzMllTQUFqX2tDUnpwMkk5SERIOERqRTJqSzk4Mm5ibnVaRGhJSXJSLW93RGpSb1VVYU1jNjVzOUFDTTdXT292Z2NvYm5qNWZuMnFYX2RxMDViWnQ1Q2dmTGVN0gGiAkFVX3lxTFBZZk1GNUtJWWlraExBbGRZT1ZyekNvbW1saTg4T3BCOGlSRkhsZ3lVc0pjUnV6OC1Nd2ljYnhGbVktaG1pVlZNYjBJVUQycHctWjdwem5ER0xlR3Foc1p4Q0pIWTFTR2xZVzd4ekticTZWWjd2YnM0YmxYWHR3NW5ybUtmQl9HRWdHaHJLWXNIb2RNSUs3TTF5ZjdQNDRyOGlSeGg2OVZoTnMxeHNSOElTUXdQQWcyRlpQekRIM3dwR0tGRUxObjE3ZEpBTDYtTXhmZ2Y2WFd4ZnpZdDJDbHFVcm5vYXJ0SG1RcG9mTWFVci1LVVd6LU9tMHNLTjFZNjQ4OS1wQ29BVUU4TGE4d1kxMG9jRGpxR2ctVmlOV0JPRElB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:41:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Morkel calls for better control with the older ball - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxPS2xYU2JWZzlDUXVDdzQyYXNyMUxsX1lUZnAtbXBWczJrdlRxYmRUS05mQ1dRbXV3SGtPWUdkZGpGZEZVcHRtWXU1TndvTEI4WVlGMUxRYTdGODJScVNhaHRyd0NxV2Q5bmF3ejJDemFGbHBYdmpONmQzLTVIRVh0STBFemJQbzExQjdNTG1xZ1FIWXMyUFNtemQtMng?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxPS2xYU2JWZzlDUXVDdzQyYXNyMUxsX1lUZnAtbXBWczJrdlRxYmRUS05mQ1dRbXV3SGtPWUdkZGpGZEZVcHRtWXU1TndvTEI4WVlGMUxRYTdGODJScVNhaHRyd0NxV2Q5bmF3ejJDemFGbHBYdmpONmQzLTVIRVh0STBFemJQbzExQjdNTG1xZ1FIWXMyUFNtemQtMng?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:08:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PCB accepts to host ICC Champions Trophy in hybrid model, Colombo emerges as India vs Pakistan match venue - InsideSport]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PCB Agrees to Host ICC Champions Trophy in Hybrid Model</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> InsideSport</p>
<img src="https://d16f573ilcot6q.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/India-vs-Pakistan-Champions-Trophy-e1732928587669-390x234.webp" alt="PCB accepts to host ICC Champions Trophy in hybrid model, Colombo emerges as India vs Pakistan match venue">
<figcaption>PCB accepts to host ICC Champions Trophy in hybrid model, Colombo emerges as India vs Pakistan match venue</figcaption>
<p>The BCCI and PCB have finalized an agreement to host the ICC Champions Trophy 2025 in a hybrid model.</p>
<ul>
  <li>India will play all matches at a neutral venue.</li>
  <li>If India doesn't qualify for the knockout stage, Pakistan will host the semifinals and final.</li>
  <li>BCCI will not require PCB to send their team to India for the Men's T20 World Cup 2026.</li>
  <li>Pakistan will host a Women's World Cup post-2026.</li>
  <li>Official announcement expected from ICC on December 16, 2024.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There has already been a significant delay as the schedule for the tournament was to be announced by November 11.”</blockquote>
<p>Colombo has emerged as a contender for the venue of the India vs Pakistan match in 2026, although Dubai remains a strong candidate.</p>
<p>Organizers aim to finalize arrangements to avoid further complications in planning.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.insidesport.in/cricket/pcb-accepts-to-host-icc-champions-trophy-in-hybrid-model-colombo-emerges-as-india-vs-pakistan-match-venue/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.insidesport.in/cricket/pcb-accepts-to-host-icc-champions-trophy-in-hybrid-model-colombo-emerges-as-india-vs-pakistan-match-venue/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:05:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Is this a joke?': Bizarre scenes in SMAT final as 3rd umpire makes blunder, apologises after Rajat Patidar's protest - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxQNHJJeUJMMzEzNWhhaGxOTFk4NVpXVGVBTFp6SFJtekU4QzVva3NzaWtJbEJhLS1adklIZklzbGtZR3VDT1czRkpVTEtRYUFzWVY2ZXg2Vl9JdlBrYkozb2lXUVVHUzA4TExFbHNEenp5M2VWVlBfZ25DMFBnT1VMb0lpeXhkbHFXMmp3X2tJN0VDMFo1ZDFSNWFsQVpXb2RSc3RDQTRFWGNDeTNjRXZ3RGg5cmFtdllyS04yMWc2eFFmQ1V6U0haWDFHLVVQSktkcEtDQUFiSURPamxRdDBxY0c1TGZpQm9IT0ZYSjFpbmJlTWMxcTBLYV9BeFE3WEs40gGGAkFVX3lxTE9kNnFzZEgxcHNYVmxNWkg2X0owY09MQUVsN2g3Y0gxcmZSSy1HMjNuZDlKbVJrcXZwRGVLM1RoaWhma3RrbUN4eHJRZXhjNlFrMDNzd2JodUV6Y0dTMDNqeG9uZFJUNUpYcGNJaTNmeHg2MEQ5ZnE4cUQ3UFp3bGZUcUUzekVjR3lQenktaWhWV3BkNjBjeGRWV25LbW1Cc3BnN0laZGhVNGZtZzdycnpJMEpSSUR5UE42bWExQl9sMEtnVlItUW1VVXF2bzVVQXBabDlhSktmNjdOUENBVEtOWHVkV1NQSk1IcDN1NU5Tc2hkZksxRWpIR3NYcXlzU2JKMWVuMmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxQNHJJeUJMMzEzNWhhaGxOTFk4NVpXVGVBTFp6SFJtekU4QzVva3NzaWtJbEJhLS1adklIZklzbGtZR3VDT1czRkpVTEtRYUFzWVY2ZXg2Vl9JdlBrYkozb2lXUVVHUzA4TExFbHNEenp5M2VWVlBfZ25DMFBnT1VMb0lpeXhkbHFXMmp3X2tJN0VDMFo1ZDFSNWFsQVpXb2RSc3RDQTRFWGNDeTNjRXZ3RGg5cmFtdllyS04yMWc2eFFmQ1V6U0haWDFHLVVQSktkcEtDQUFiSURPamxRdDBxY0c1TGZpQm9IT0ZYSjFpbmJlTWMxcTBLYV9BeFE3WEs40gGGAkFVX3lxTE9kNnFzZEgxcHNYVmxNWkg2X0owY09MQUVsN2g3Y0gxcmZSSy1HMjNuZDlKbVJrcXZwRGVLM1RoaWhma3RrbUN4eHJRZXhjNlFrMDNzd2JodUV6Y0dTMDNqeG9uZFJUNUpYcGNJaTNmeHg2MEQ5ZnE4cUQ3UFp3bGZUcUUzekVjR3lQenktaWhWV3BkNjBjeGRWV25LbW1Cc3BnN0laZGhVNGZtZzdycnpJMEpSSUR5UE42bWExQl9sMEtnVlItUW1VVXF2bzVVQXBabDlhSktmNjdOUENBVEtOWHVkV1NQSk1IcDN1NU5Tc2hkZksxRWpIR3NYcXlzU2JKMWVuMmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:51:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How New Zealand flipped the script with Test crowds - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOOWZFYzVlbUk5bXI4eEdNTlVhQ2h4ai1Vc1ZrNVlCazVRN3VUMWRwUGZkREg5T2tFRjNXdVBObnNhbjhJcV9DdGl4T2lKandnTldwcFVyZTNheXZyVlBqSjlyVndLTjhrMENRb0lQQVRZMmpkclBBbFlPWlBIX1BYTS15bHpDZkJWcHU4ekZUdmxaOHNWclNSWmF4bDc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOOWZFYzVlbUk5bXI4eEdNTlVhQ2h4ai1Vc1ZrNVlCazVRN3VUMWRwUGZkREg5T2tFRjNXdVBObnNhbjhJcV9DdGl4T2lKandnTldwcFVyZTNheXZyVlBqSjlyVndLTjhrMENRb0lQQVRZMmpkclBBbFlPWlBIX1BYTS15bHpDZkJWcHU4ekZUdmxaOHNWclNSWmF4bDc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:44:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Morne Morkel reveals one area where Indian bowlers need to get better at - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Morne Morkel reveals one area where Indian bowlers need to get better at</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> NEW DELHI <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116340229,imgsize-40048,width-400,resizemode-4/116340229.jpg" alt="Morne Morkel reveals one area where Indian bowlers need to get better at" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Akash Deep and Mohammed Siraj. (Pic Credit - X)</figcaption><p>Morne Morkel, India’s bowling coach, emphasized the need for improvement among Indian bowlers, particularly during the overs 50 to 80 against Australian batter Travis Head.</p><ul><li>Morkel noted that the Indian bowlers struggled to execute their strategies effectively.</li><li>He highlighted the impact of the partnership between Travis Head and Steve Smith, which scored 171 runs in 31 overs.</li><li>Morkel indicated the need to improve execution during crucial phases of the match with a softer ball.</li><li>He defended the performance of other bowlers like Mohammed Siraj and Akash Deep, commending their efforts despite challenges.</li><li>Morkel backed Ravindra Jadeja, emphasizing his status as a world-class player despite a tough outing.</li></ul><blockquote>“First of all, we can say he's (Head) in pretty good form... but I think for us with the ball... that's one area I think we need to get better at.” - Morne Morkel</blockquote><p>The Indian bowling team is looking to enhance their game strategy to perform better in upcoming sessions, aiming to contain the scoring rate efficiently.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/morne-morkel-reveals-one-area-where-indian-bowlers-need-to-get-better-at/articleshow/116340254.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/morne-morkel-reveals-one-area-where-indian-bowlers-need-to-get-better-at/articleshow/116340254.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Barcelona legend confirms intentions to take on coaching role – ‘I am working on it’ - Barca Universal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxOU1VKSDNKZWllN28tNHZTOU1rT3hGTnpNSlp5Vy1CTjdaQ2pxdXFMX0VBY0lyMjlVd1Znay1ob1h1bDB4RTBfdC14endNMUNlYzUtNnZfdjItZXdXQkNIZkhBanhycS1lOUwzcEI1bzJlZ1AwTFVYQnUtRDVDSXQtckp5b01yOG9BQWdBUlNnR1E5OVRSQzVncjFwbVlfa1hfQWQxenNOVFBzb2lu?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxOU1VKSDNKZWllN28tNHZTOU1rT3hGTnpNSlp5Vy1CTjdaQ2pxdXFMX0VBY0lyMjlVd1Znay1ob1h1bDB4RTBfdC14endNMUNlYzUtNnZfdjItZXdXQkNIZkhBanhycS1lOUwzcEI1bzJlZ1AwTFVYQnUtRDVDSXQtckp5b01yOG9BQWdBUlNnR1E5OVRSQzVncjFwbVlfa1hfQWQxenNOVFBzb2lu?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:19:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Bowled Really Nicely": Steve Smith's Big Praise For Star India Pacer. It's Not Jasprit Bumrah - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"Bowled Really Nicely": Steve Smith's Big Praise For Star India Pacer. It's Not Jasprit Bumrah</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/s9gkebdo_steve-smith-jasprit-bumrah-afp_625x300_15_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Steve Smith praising Akash Deep" width="639" height="479">
<figcaption>Steve Smith praising Akash Deep after the Test match.</figcaption>
<p>In a commendable performance during the third Test match, Indian pacer Akash Deep caught the attention of Australia’s Steve Smith, who noted Deep's remarkable bowling skills despite not taking any wickets.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Akash Deep received high praise from Steve Smith for his impressive bowling on the second day of the third Test.</li>
  <li>Smith scored his 33rd Test hundred, contributing to Australia's strong position with 405 for seven at stumps, while facing tough spells from Jasprit Bumrah and Akash Deep.</li>
  <li>Smith described Deep's first spell as having significant movement and excellent length, showcasing his skills as a bowler.</li>
  <li>Travis Head also made a notable contribution with 152 runs from 160 balls, impressing both Smith and spectators.</li>
  <li>Smith referenced past performance struggles against India, calling the series opener in Perth an anomaly.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I thought Akash bowled really nicely. He has got some skill there for sure." - Steve Smith</blockquote>
<p>This match highlights both the skill of Akash Deep and the competitive nature of the ongoing series, providing an exciting display of cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/bowled-really-nicely-steve-smiths-big-praise-for-star-india-pacer-its-not-jasprit-bumrah-7253699</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/bowled-really-nicely-steve-smiths-big-praise-for-star-india-pacer-its-not-jasprit-bumrah-7253699</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:14:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nahid Rana added to Bangladesh T20I squad against West Indies - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nahid Rana Added to Bangladesh T20I Squad Against West Indies</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Sun, Dec 15, 2024, 01:06 PM <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c587416/rana-has-already-appeared-in-s.jpg" alt="Rana has already appeared in six Tests and three ODIs for Bangladesh" />
<figcaption>Rana has already appeared in six Tests and three ODIs for Bangladesh © AFP</figcaption>
<p>The Bangladesh Cricket Board has included pace bowler Nahid Rana in the squad for the T20 international series against West Indies, set to begin soon in St Vincent.</p>
<ul>
<li>Nahid Rana joins the T20 squad for upcoming matches against West Indies.</li>
<li>The matches are scheduled on 16, 18, and 20 December.</li>
<li>Rana has played six Tests and three ODIs but has yet to debut in T20 internationals.</li>
<li>Bangladesh skipper Litton Kumar Das expresses confidence in the squad's readiness.</li>
<li>The team aims to bounce back after being defeated in their recent ODI series.</li>
<li>Litton acknowledges West Indies will be a tough opponent in T20s.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Usually, T20 matches are challenging for us. We will try to figure out how to overcome this and focus on playing a good series." – Litton Kumar Das</blockquote>
<p>This addition to the squad signals Bangladesh's strategy to improve their T20 performance against a tough West Indies team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132770/nahid-rana-added-to-bangladesh-t20i-squad-against-west-indies</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132770/nahid-rana-added-to-bangladesh-t20i-squad-against-west-indies</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 13:08:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>