<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:20:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 15:20:01 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MS Dhoni Sets Internet Ablaze With New 'Santa Claus' Look, Poses With Wife Sakshi And Daughter Ziva - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MS Dhoni Sets Internet Ablaze With New 'Santa Claus' Look, Poses With Wife Sakshi And Daughter Ziva</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/89orf04_ms-dhoni-santa-claus_625x300_25_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="MS Dhoni in Santa Claus outfit"><figcaption>MS Dhoni in his new look. © Instagram</figcaption><p>Legendary India captain MS Dhoni has delighted fans with a new festive look as Santa Claus shared by his wife Sakshi. The post has gone viral, gathering over 500,000 likes shortly after being posted.</p><ul><li>Dhoni disguised as Santa Claus with wife Sakshi and daughter Ziva.</li><li>The Instagram post quickly gained massive traction online.</li><li>Dhoni remains a beloved figure in Indian cricket despite his retirement from international cricket over five years ago.</li><li>He will be playing for Chennai Super Kings (CSK) in the IPL 2025 season.</li><li>Dhoni was retained for Rs 4 crore under a new rule benefiting players who haven't played internationally for over five years.</li></ul><blockquote>"Glimpses of the legendary captain send fans into a frenzy."</blockquote><p>Dhoni continues to maintain a strong connection with his fans, showcasing his charismatic personality even during the holiday season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/ms-dhoni-sets-internet-ablaze-with-new-santa-claus-look-poses-with-wife-sakshi-and-daughter-ziva-7329822</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/ms-dhoni-sets-internet-ablaze-with-new-santa-claus-look-poses-with-wife-sakshi-and-daughter-ziva-7329822</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:22:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli to Prithvi Shaw: Top Indian cricketers who disappeared all of sudden - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli to Prithvi Shaw: Top Indian cricketers who disappeared all of sudden</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/vinod-kambli-to-prithvi-shaw-top-indian-cricketers-who-disappeared-all-of-sudden-202412-1735132604.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Vinod Kambli to Prithvi Shaw Top Indian cricketers who disappeared all of sudden"><figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption><p>Numerous Indian cricketers have shown immense promise but have suddenly faded from the forefront of the sport. Various factors, including injuries and off-field troubles, have derailed their careers.</p><ul><li>Players like Vinod Kambli and Prithvi Shaw had early success but faced challenges that limited their time in the spotlight.</li><li>Others, such as S. Sreesanth, gained fame from notable achievements, only for controversies to hinder their career progression.</li><li>Intense competition has seen promising talents like Mayank Agarwal and Manish Pandey struggle to maintain their places in the national team.</li><li>Injuries have significantly impacted cricketers like Varun Aaron, who showcased potential but ultimately could not sustain their performance.</li><li>Fitness issues have also played a role in Prithvi Shaw's recent career struggles.</li></ul><blockquote>“He had the potential to become one of the game's greatest players.” - Insights on Prithvi Shaw's career potential.</blockquote><p>This examination of Indian cricketers illustrates how factors beyond talent can significantly affect a player's career trajectory.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/vinod-kambli-to-prithvi-shaw-top-indian-cricketers-who-disappeared-all-of-sudden-416276/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/vinod-kambli-to-prithvi-shaw-top-indian-cricketers-who-disappeared-all-of-sudden-416276/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:20:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma Replaces KL Rahul; Shubman Gill OUT: India Likely Playing XI For Boxing Day Test - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Replaces KL Rahul; Shubman Gill OUT: India Likely Playing XI For Boxing Day Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116656339,thumbsize-79100,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116656339.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma Replaces KL Rahul; Shubman Gill OUT: India Likely Playing XI For Boxing Day Test" title="Rohit Sharma Replaces KL Rahul; Shubman Gill OUT: India Likely Playing XI For Boxing Day Test"><figcaption>Photo: AP</figcaption><p>India are currently level 1-1 in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy and seek to take a lead in the series during the Boxing Day Test at the MCG. Changes in the lineup are expected to improve their chances for World Test Championship qualification.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma returns to open the batting, replacing KL Rahul.</li><li>Shubman Gill dropped; Dhruv Jurel slated to bat at no.6.</li><li>Washington Sundar replaces Nitish Kumar Reddy in the all-rounder slot.</li><li>Virat Kohli and Rishabh Pant remain at positions 4 and 5.</li><li>India's likely playing XI: Rohit Sharma (c), Yashasvi Jaiswal, KL Rahul, Virat Kohli, Rishabh Pant (wk), Dhruv Jurel, Ravindra Jadeja, Washington Sundar, Akash Deep, Jasprit Bumrah, Mohammed Siraj.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-replaces-kl-rahul-shubman-gill-out-india-likely-playing-xi-for-boxing-day-test-article-116654778</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-replaces-kl-rahul-shubman-gill-out-india-likely-playing-xi-for-boxing-day-test-article-116654778</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:24:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunil Gavaskar explains why India should not drop Nitish Reddy for Boxing Day Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunil Gavaskar explains why India should not drop Nitish Reddy for Boxing Day Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116656284,imgsize-27618,width-400,resizemode-4/116656284.jpg" alt="Sunil Gavaskar explains why India should not drop Nitish Reddy for Boxing Day Test" title="Nitish Reddy (PTI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Nitish Reddy (PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>The Border-Gavaskar Trophy is at a crucial point, tied at 1-1, as India prepares for the Boxing Day Test in Melbourne. Key discussions revolve around player selections, particularly concerning Nitish Kumar Reddy.</p><ul><li>Ravichandran Ashwin's retirement creates a gap, leading to Tanush Kotian's selection as a replacement.</li><li>Sunil Gavaskar argues against dropping Nitish Reddy, emphasizing his role as a fourth seamer.</li><li>Reddy's performance has been lackluster, but his batting is seen as vital for team balance.</li><li>Adjustments to the top order include Rohit Sharma returning as an opener and K.L. Rahul possibly batting at number three.</li><li>Akash Deep's place is considered secure after his performance at the Gabba.</li></ul><blockquote>“They can’t drop Nitish Kumar Reddy. He is the fourth seamer. I can’t see India going in with just two pacers and Nitish. For me, it is pretty much this XI that plays in Melbourne,” - Sunil Gavaskar.</blockquote><p>The upcoming Boxing Day Test is crucial for India's chances in the series, with significant discussions around player formations and their potential impacts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/sunil-gavaskar-explains-why-india-should-not-drop-nitish-reddy-for-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116656047.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/sunil-gavaskar-explains-why-india-should-not-drop-nitish-reddy-for-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116656047.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Won't Be Surprised If...": Pat Cummins' Big Verdict On MCG Pitch For 4th Test Against India - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pat Cummins Discusses MCG Pitch Ahead of Boxing Day Test Against India</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vq7bbk3_asc_625x300_25_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="&quot;Won't Be Surprised If...&quot;: Pat Cummins' Big Verdict On MCG Pitch For 4th Test Against India">
<figcaption>Pat Cummins discusses the pitch conditions at MCG.</figcaption>
<p>Australian cricket captain Pat Cummins shared thoughts on the Melbourne Cricket Ground pitch ahead of the crucial fourth Test against India, highlighting its suitability for spinners and good condition.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The MCG pitch appears 'nice and firm' with some grass coverage.</li>
  <li>Both teams are tied 1-1 in the series heading into the Boxing Day Test.</li>
  <li>Cummins praised the curators for maintaining pitch quality over the years.</li>
  <li>Bowling may be challenging due to high temperatures reaching 39 degrees Celsius.</li>
  <li>He expressed confidence in spinner Nathan Lyon’s performance on this pitch.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Pitch looks really good, quite consistent... a bit of grass coverage, feels nice and firm.” - Pat Cummins</blockquote>
<p>This Test is crucial for both teams as they vie for a lead going into the ICC World Test Championship final consideration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/wont-be-surprised-if-pat-cummins-big-verdict-on-mcg-pitch-for-4th-test-against-india-7326916</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/wont-be-surprised-if-pat-cummins-big-verdict-on-mcg-pitch-for-4th-test-against-india-7326916</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 12:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anushka Sharma, Virat Kohli Get Out On Christmas Date After R Ashwin's Cryptic Comment About Their PDA - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli Enjoy Christmas Date Amid R Ashwin's Comments</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli are on a date." title="Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli are on a date."><figcaption>Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli are on a date.</figcaption></figure><p>Anushka Sharma and Virat Kohli were spotted on a date on Christmas Day in Australia. The couple was seen enjoying a casual day out in Melbourne, sans their children.</p><ul><li>Anushka and Virat walked through Melbourne streets on Christmas Day.</li><li>They dressed casually and appeared to enjoy a quick snack together.</li><li>The couple is in Australia for Virat’s cricket schedule, with a match scheduled for December 26.</li><li>R Ashwin recently made a cryptic comment regarding Virat's on-field PDA during an interview.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’m never a serious person... a lot of who I am got diluted in the fact of what I’ve become.” - R Ashwin</blockquote><p>The couple has not yet publicly responded to Ashwin's remarks. They recently celebrated their wedding anniversary privately.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/anushka-sharma-virat-kohli-get-out-on-christmas-date-after-r-ashwins-cryptic-comment-about-their-pda-9167910.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/anushka-sharma-virat-kohli-get-out-on-christmas-date-after-r-ashwins-cryptic-comment-about-their-pda-9167910.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:53:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan's schedule for ICC Champions Trophy 2025, Men in Green to take on India on... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan's ICC Champions Trophy 2025 Schedule: Key Matches Against India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/big-chance-of-pakistan-202412-1735126592.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Big chance of Pakistan">
<figcaption><p>Image credit: X</p><h2>Big chance of Pakistan</h2><p>Pakistan is bracing itself to be the venue of an ICC Championship after an extensive gap of 28 years. Fans are spirited about the anticipated return of the Champions Trophy which hasn't taken place for the last 8 years.</p></figcaption>
<p>Pakistan's national cricket team is set for an exciting schedule in the ICC Champions Trophy 2025, highlighted by a highly anticipated match against India.</p>
<ul>
<li>Pakistan's opening game will be against New Zealand on February 19 in Karachi.</li>
<li>The much-awaited match against India will be on February 23 in Dubai.</li>
<li>Pakistan's last group game will be against Bangladesh on February 27 in Rawalpindi.</li>
<li>This tournament marks the first time Pakistan will host the event in nearly three decades.</li>
<li>Pakistan heads into the tournament as the defending champions, having won the title in 2017 against India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>"Heading into the tournament as the current victors from their 2017 title win over India, Pakistan is all set to show its prowess once again."</p></blockquote>
<p>The ICC Champions Trophy 2025 is generating excitement among cricket fans worldwide, and Pakistan's performance will be closely watched as they strive to defend their title.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/pakistans-schedule-for-icc-champions-trophy-2025-men-in-green-to-take-on-india-on-416266/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/pakistans-schedule-for-icc-champions-trophy-2025-men-in-green-to-take-on-india-on-416266/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:40:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Father of ex-India cricketer, who made debut with R Ashwin, sentenced to 7 years in embezzlement case - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/father-of-ex-india-cricketer-naman-ojha-who-made-debut-with-r-ashwin-sentenced-to-7-years-embezzlement-case-101735123296690.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/father-of-ex-india-cricketer-naman-ojha-who-made-debut-with-r-ashwin-sentenced-to-7-years-embezzlement-case-101735123296690.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:13:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boxing Day Test Weather Forecast: Rain Drama Likely On These Days - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Boxing Day Test Weather Forecast: Rain Drama Likely On These Days</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/rg655neo_mcg_625x300_25_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Boxing Day Test Weather Forecast: Rain Drama Likely On These Days"><figcaption>The weather is most likely to remain clear in Melbourne during the five days of the Test. © AFP</figcaption><p>The Boxing Day Test between India and Australia begins on December 26 at the Melbourne Cricket Ground with weather forecasts suggesting generally clear conditions, though some rain is expected on the third and fourth days.</p><ul><li>The series is currently tied at 1-1 after three Tests.</li><li>India is expected to make strategic changes to their lineup, introducing new players while adjusting batting order.</li><li>Australia has also confirmed their playing XI with two changes due to injuries.</li><li>There is a 25% chance of rain on Days 3 and 4, while the overall weather remains hot and humid.</li></ul><blockquote>“The 19-year-old Konstas will become Australia's youngest Test debutant since Cummins took the field against South Africa at Johannesburg in 2011.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the weather plays a crucial role in the Boxing Day Test, and teams will be watching closely for any changes that could impact play.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/boxing-day-test-weather-forecast-rain-drama-likely-on-these-days-of-mcg-test-7328875</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/boxing-day-test-weather-forecast-rain-drama-likely-on-these-days-of-mcg-test-7328875</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:00:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ashwin decodes Travis Head's masterplan against Jasprit Bumrah and Co. ahead of Boxing Day Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashwin decodes Travis Head's masterplan against Jasprit Bumrah and Co. ahead of Boxing Day Test</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Not specified</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116654254,imgsize-40706,width-400,resizemode-4/116654254.jpg" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin and Travis Head. (Pic Credit - X)" title="Ravichandran Ashwin and Travis Head. (Pic Credit - X)"><figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin and Travis Head. (Pic Credit - X)</figcaption><p>Former Indian spinner Ravichandran Ashwin analyzed Travis Head's strategies to counter Jasprit Bumrah and the Indian bowling attack during the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Ashwin highlights Head's clever use of crease and footwork to neutralize Bumrah's pace.</li><li>Head has performed outstandingly, including two centuries, contributing to Australia's win in the series.</li><li>Despite his success, Head has vulnerabilities against fast bowlers from around the wicket.</li><li>Head is confirmed fit for the upcoming Boxing Day Test after recovering from a quad injury.</li></ul><blockquote>"Omg! He is getting to the off stump? Is that the ploy for round the stumps?" - Ravichandran Ashwin on Head's practice sessions.</blockquote><p>Travis Head's ability to adjust his techniques signifies his preparation for the challenging matches ahead, marking him as a pivotal player for Australia in the series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ashwin-decodes-travis-heads-masterplan-against-jasprit-bumrah-and-co-ahead-of-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116654287.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ashwin-decodes-travis-heads-masterplan-against-jasprit-bumrah-and-co-ahead-of-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116654287.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arjun Tendulkar overcomes setback, reaches first career milestone weeks after being dropped from Goa team - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arjun Tendulkar Achieves First Milestone in Cricket After Recent Setback</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 25, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/Mumbai-Indians--Arjun-Tendulkar-at-the-Wankhede-St_1682080363356_1735120491508.jpg" alt="Arjun Tendulkar at the Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai(HT_PRINT)" title="Arjun Tendulkar at the Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai(HT_PRINT)">
<figcaption>Arjun Tendulkar at the Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai(HT_PRINT)</figcaption>
<p>Weeks after being dropped from Goa's Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy squad, Arjun Tendulkar achieved his first career milestone as a bowler, picking three wickets against Odisha in the ongoing Vijay Hazare Trophy match and completing 50 wickets in white-ball cricket.</p>
<ul>
<li>Arjun Tendulkar picked three wickets in a crucial match.</li>
<li>He reached the milestone of 50 wickets in white-ball cricket.</li>
<li>The left-handed fast bowler made his T20 debut for Mumbai in 2021.</li>
<li>He has achieved 51 wickets in 41 white-ball games.</li>
<li>Arjun faced a setback being dropped from the Goa team after poor performances.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Arjun suffered a major setback earlier this month, when he was dropped from the Goa cricket team for the remaining matches of the Syed Mushtaq Ali Trophy 2024.”</blockquote>
<p>Arjun Tendulkar's journey showcases resilience and determination, highlighting his potential to bounce back stronger in his cricketing career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/arjun-tendulkar-overcomes-setback-first-career-milestone-after-being-dropped-from-goa-team-vijay-hazare-trophy-101735120384463.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/arjun-tendulkar-overcomes-setback-first-career-milestone-after-being-dropped-from-goa-team-vijay-hazare-trophy-101735120384463.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:16:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five must-watch matches at the ICC Champions Trophy 2025 - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Five Must-Watch Matches at the ICC Champions Trophy 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>The ICC Champions Trophy returns on 19 February 2025 after eight years, featuring 15 thrilling matches over 19 days. Here are five exciting match-ups to look forward to:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Pakistan v India, Dubai (23 February)</strong> - This iconic rivalry sees Pakistan leading in Champions Trophy history, though recent performances favor India.</li>
<li><strong>Australia v South Africa, Rawalpindi (25 February)</strong> - Following a dramatic semi-final, this encounter promises high stakes and fierce competition.</li>
<li><strong>Afghanistan v Australia, Lahore (28 February)</strong> - Afghanistan aims to build on their T20 success against the Australians in this ODI clash.</li>
<li><strong>South Africa v England, Karachi (1 March)</strong> - Featuring two teams with rich talent, this match is expected to be a showcase of competitive cricket.</li>
<li><strong>New Zealand v India, Dubai (2 March)</strong> - A rematch where India recently bested New Zealand, setting the stage for another thrilling face-off.</li>
</ul>
<p>Fans are eagerly awaiting these matches as they promise to be filled with excitement and high-performance cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/champions-trophy-2025/news/five-must-watch-matches-at-the-icc-champions-trophy-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/champions-trophy-2025/news/five-must-watch-matches-at-the-icc-champions-trophy-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:08:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arjun Tendulkar reaches landmark in white-ball cricket - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/arjun-tendulkar-reaches-landmark-in-white-ball-cricket/articleshow/116653400.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/arjun-tendulkar-reaches-landmark-in-white-ball-cricket/articleshow/116653400.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah achieves historic ICC Rankings feat, equals all time Indian record - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Achieves Historic ICC Rankings Feat, Matches All-Time Indian Record</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116653265,imgsize-51906,width-400,resizemode-4/116653265.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah" decoding="async"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah. (Pic Credit - X)</figcaption><p>Jasprit Bumrah, India’s leading fast bowler, has reached an impressive milestone in the ICC Men's Test Bowling Rankings with 904 rating points, equaling the highest rating ever achieved by an Indian bowler.</p><ul><li>Bumrah's performance in Brisbane contributed to his elevation in the rankings, as he took 9 wickets for 94 runs, earning 14 rating points.</li><li>The record previously held by Ravichandran Ashwin has now been matched, and Bumrah has a chance to surpass it in the upcoming Melbourne Test.</li><li>Travis Head has moved closer to the top three in the ICC Men's Test Batting Rankings following recent outstanding performances.</li><li>Notable changes in men's rankings have occurred stemming from various matches across formats.</li><li>Other players like Kagiso Rabada, Josh Hazlewood, and Pat Cummins have also seen significant movements in their rankings.</li></ul><blockquote>“Jasprit Bumrah's outstanding performance has solidified his top position in the Test Bowling Rankings.”</blockquote><p>The ongoing Test series is witnessing remarkable individual performances, significantly influencing player rankings across international cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-achieves-historic-icc-rankings-feat-equals-all-time-indian-record/articleshow/116653106.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-achieves-historic-icc-rankings-feat-equals-all-time-indian-record/articleshow/116653106.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heroes and villains head for Centurion - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxPZ1EzOVJSX3VBdm54OTcwRHpRN1dlVTVrNHQ4cU84Vmd4Tmw2N0g5d3I2elMzTnNmdllDdGRWV0ZQUmlvT0JINWdiZWNxSUYxbUl0TjVmdDVUc01mRHNYamJtQnpmUVNTdzBaU3RNUGJWSHJXRUxNWUJkbDE3Uk9FS0FnVDRwUzBybTBz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxPZ1EzOVJSX3VBdm54OTcwRHpRN1dlVTVrNHQ4cU84Vmd4Tmw2N0g5d3I2elMzTnNmdllDdGRWV0ZQUmlvT0JINWdiZWNxSUYxbUl0TjVmdDVUc01mRHNYamJtQnpmUVNTdzBaU3RNUGJWSHJXRUxNWUJkbDE3Uk9FS0FnVDRwUzBybTBz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:50:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rishabh Pant Receives Mammoth Warning From Sunil Gavaskar : 'Respect A Little Bit...' - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rishabh-pant-receives-mammoth-warning-from-sunil-gavaskar-respect-a-little-bit-7321943</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rishabh-pant-receives-mammoth-warning-from-sunil-gavaskar-respect-a-little-bit-7321943</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:33:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arjun Tendulkar makes father Sachin Tendulkar proud, achieves key milestone by... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxPMGNpdkNFYzJTZUIyQkFuSUpYYnZJOS1wdzR5Q1lDbFpYek5MNkh4Q0pENmZGQVpkZ2Q5VEwzemMyWXVQLTRFcVdfTGNWeTVKa1BsMEtxSTNEVmo0M3N6OVE1WUtNYzhDbEVwanFHM1JBY3BVVlpFUjl5aWhJNDEyYmZjbGFLZnlnbmFoMGhyYXhiS2szRmZKVVd1YWZLeUZWUFZZeUJKQ0M0Y2tJX1JJUjlaUUMtT05aNGd2TGRB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxPMGNpdkNFYzJTZUIyQkFuSUpYYnZJOS1wdzR5Q1lDbFpYek5MNkh4Q0pENmZGQVpkZ2Q5VEwzemMyWXVQLTRFcVdfTGNWeTVKa1BsMEtxSTNEVmo0M3N6OVE1WUtNYzhDbEVwanFHM1JBY3BVVlpFUjl5aWhJNDEyYmZjbGFLZnlnbmFoMGhyYXhiS2szRmZKVVd1YWZLeUZWUFZZeUJKQ0M0Y2tJX1JJUjlaUUMtT05aNGd2TGRB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:19:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bumrah attains highest-ever rating points for an India bowler after Brisbane exploits - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxNTUFrNGQ5Z3NrcEJpQUZobFpBQTZTUi1ucklrYU9aT1FnMk15c0hMd2EyNXlINmNyeS10MUNNOFZXb2JlOTJ4aktqZHY3UUcyMUhvQWIydzA5aGk1aFlLdU51a0p4bjBZQjVfVmdTOXUyYzQwVTJUVEN0dE50UjhQcXFoTmZPakJXek9ELXR2WUhFU0s3MWVrRkRNZ1Rvb3FQX0dpQXBVYUdnbXJNczlOajhEODRTSkJZY3J4dW90OWtLdEFzekxEeGFtMF8yWndmMXfSAeMBQVVfeXFMUE9RN2J3Z3VNRVRCSEhYc1JxRG1qdUlTU3R2UWJTSVZRNF80Tk9pWGZSSHFvVG5tdExzMk15VXF4MC15alZxMzI2d3lKN0RMUGpKSmVuSkFqYlI4c3BsRVgxOU9BTGpTMkNxeXJzWkhRRG5yN3dwZF96MVBZSG5TSTYxZzdIUS1OR2xkcncwX2dINGFGR2Jmc2ptRjVOTFhSc1I0V29oZlJFSVJkNnIxdFdFaks3MFFBZ2M2OUlaRjFXQWl5d01LTmJkRWs2cUVadDVpUzNoMmZIZVRpa0F1MkpaN2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxNTUFrNGQ5Z3NrcEJpQUZobFpBQTZTUi1ucklrYU9aT1FnMk15c0hMd2EyNXlINmNyeS10MUNNOFZXb2JlOTJ4aktqZHY3UUcyMUhvQWIydzA5aGk1aFlLdU51a0p4bjBZQjVfVmdTOXUyYzQwVTJUVEN0dE50UjhQcXFoTmZPakJXek9ELXR2WUhFU0s3MWVrRkRNZ1Rvb3FQX0dpQXBVYUdnbXJNczlOajhEODRTSkJZY3J4dW90OWtLdEFzekxEeGFtMF8yWndmMXfSAeMBQVVfeXFMUE9RN2J3Z3VNRVRCSEhYc1JxRG1qdUlTU3R2UWJTSVZRNF80Tk9pWGZSSHFvVG5tdExzMk15VXF4MC15alZxMzI2d3lKN0RMUGpKSmVuSkFqYlI4c3BsRVgxOU9BTGpTMkNxeXJzWkhRRG5yN3dwZF96MVBZSG5TSTYxZzdIUS1OR2xkcncwX2dINGFGR2Jmc2ptRjVOTFhSc1I0V29oZlJFSVJkNnIxdFdFaks3MFFBZ2M2OUlaRjFXQWl5d01LTmJkRWs2cUVadDVpUzNoMmZIZVRpa0F1MkpaN2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 09:10:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Homage to romance and heritage’: PV Sindhu wore headveil bearing her and husband Venkata Datta Sai’s names for wedding - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Homage to romance and heritage’: PV Sindhu wore headveil bearing her and husband Venkata Datta Sai’s names for wedding</h1><p><strong>Date: December 2024 &nbsp; Source: Indian Express</strong></p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/pv-sindhu_16000_manish.jpg?w=640' alt='PV Sindhu' width='640' height='360'><figcaption>PV Sindhu and Venkata Datta Sai got married in Udaipur (Source: Manish Malhotra/Instagram)</figcaption><p>PV Sindhu is married! The badminton champ shared a glimpse of her special day, posting photos with her husband Venkata Datta Sai.</p><ul><li>The wedding ceremony took place in Udaipur, attended by close family and friends.</li><li>Sindhu wore an ivory sari designed by Manish Malhotra, with intricate detailing and a multi-tiered heirloom necklace.</li><li>Her headveil was adorned with her and her husband's names as a tribute to romance and heritage.</li><li>For the varmala ceremony, Sindhu wore a crimson red lehenga by Sabyasachi Mukherjee, complemented by Sai's ivory sherwani.</li></ul><blockquote>“Her ensemble is completed with an ethereal headveil bordered in zari, bearing her and her husband’s names—an homage to romance and heritage.” - Manish Malhotra</blockquote><p>The wedding seems to represent a beautiful blend of personal significance and cultural heritage, showcasing traditional attire and modern love.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/fashion/pv-sindhu-bridal-look-first-reaction-social-media-marriage-venkata-datta-sai-manish-malhotra-18k-gold-necklace-headveil-homage-9743426/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/lifestyle/fashion/pv-sindhu-bridal-look-first-reaction-social-media-marriage-venkata-datta-sai-manish-malhotra-18k-gold-necklace-headveil-homage-9743426/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:30:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Border-Gavaskar Trophy: How Indian openers have fared in Boxing Day Tests at MCG - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Border-Gavaskar Trophy: How Indian openers have fared in Boxing Day Tests at MCG</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116651651,imgsize-45486,width-400,resizemode-4/116651651.jpg" alt="Border-Gavaskar Trophy: How Indian openers have fared in Boxing Day Tests at MCG" title="Virender Sehwag and Aakash Chopra have the highest opening stand to their name in Boxing Day Tests at the MCG. (Photo by Mark Dadswell/Getty Images)"><figcaption>Virender Sehwag and Aakash Chopra have the highest opening stand to their name in Boxing Day Tests at the MCG. (Photo by Mark Dadswell/Getty Images)</figcaption><p>In the upcoming Boxing Day Test against Australia at the MCG, Indian captain Rohit Sharma returns to the opening position hoping to regain form.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma has struggled with just 19 runs in the two Tests of this series.</li><li>No Indian opener except Virender Sehwag has scored a hundred at MCG against Australia.</li><li>Sehwag had a record 195 runs at MCG in 2003-04, alongside Aakash Chopra who formed a 141-run opening partnership with him.</li><li>Recent performances include a 40-run opening stand by Mayank Agarwal and Hanuma Vihari in December 2018.</li></ul><blockquote>"I would play the same shot again irrespective of the score I might be on." - Virender Sehwag</blockquote><p>The upcoming match includes high stakes as India looks to continue strong performances against Australia, particularly in the historical context of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/border-gavaskar-trophy-how-indian-openers-have-fared-in-boxing-day-tests-at-mcg/articleshow/116651679.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/border-gavaskar-trophy-how-indian-openers-have-fared-in-boxing-day-tests-at-mcg/articleshow/116651679.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arjun Tendulkar Achieves Key Career Milestone During Vijay Hazare Trophy - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arjun Tendulkar Achieves Key Career Milestone During Vijay Hazare Trophy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>November 13, 2024</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>NDTV Sports</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c2830gmg_arjun-tendulkar-ranji-trophy_625x300_13_November_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Arjun Tendulkar Achieves Key Career Milestone During Vijay Hazare Trophy"><figcaption>File photo of Arjun Tendulkar © X (Twitter)</figcaption><p>Arjun Tendulkar, the son of legendary cricketer Sachin Tendulkar, has completed 50 wickets in white-ball cricket during the ongoing Vijay Hazare Trophy. He achieved this milestone while playing for Goa.</p><ul><li>Arjun went wicketless in the game against Haryana but took three wickets against Odisha.</li><li>He has a total of 51 wickets in 41 white-ball matches, including 24 in List A and 27 in T20 cricket.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah and Ravindra Jadeja are also pursuing milestones in the fourth Test against Australia.</li><li>Bumrah is six wickets away from reaching 200 Test scalps, and Jadeja is seven wickets away from 600 international wickets.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bumrah is just six wickets away from achieving 200 Test scalps and becoming the 12th Indian bowler to do so.”</blockquote><p>This milestone is significant for Arjun, showcasing his growth in the sport and following in his father's legendary footsteps.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/arjun-tendulkar-achieves-key-career-milestone-during-vijay-hazare-trophy-7328093</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/arjun-tendulkar-achieves-key-career-milestone-during-vijay-hazare-trophy-7328093</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:00:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah proving bigger threat than Hadlee, Ambrose, Holding, Kapil in Australia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Proving Bigger Threat Than Hadlee, Ambrose, Holding, Kapil in Australia</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Not provided</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116650853,imgsize-49678,width-400,resizemode-4/116650853.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah celebrates after dismissing Travis Head (Agency Photo)"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah celebrates after dismissing Travis Head (Agency Photo)</figcaption><p>Jasprit Bumrah has emerged as a formidable threat during India’s cricket tours in Australia, surpassing legendary bowlers and contributing significantly to India's success.</p><ul><li>Bumrah has taken 21 wickets in three Tests of the ongoing Border Gavaskar Trophy at an average of 10.90.</li><li>He crossed 50 Test wickets in Australia, with a strike rate of 41.0, the best among his peers.</li><li>Historic series wins by India align with Bumrah's impressive performance during these tours.</li><li>He has taken two five-wicket hauls this tour, showcasing exceptional skill.</li><li>Bumrah's performance outshines cricket legends like Richard Hadlee and Curtly Ambrose, with statistics proving his dominance.</li></ul><blockquote>“Virat Kohli is a modern-day great. He will figure it out.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Jasprit Bumrah's outstanding bowling against Australia has not only redefined standards but also potentially set new benchmarks in Test cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-proving-bigger-threat-than-hadlee-ambrose-holding-kapil-in-australia/articleshow/116650811.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-proving-bigger-threat-than-hadlee-ambrose-holding-kapil-in-australia/articleshow/116650811.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli develops fever as MRI procedure delayed, remains in ICU; doctor says condition 'stable' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli develops fever as MRI procedure delayed, remains in ICU; doctor says condition 'stable'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/20241224-MTH-PGD-MN-Vinod-kambali-001012-0_1735112917872_1735112934553.JPG" alt="Vinod Kambli at Aakruti Hospital in Kopar village in Bhiwandi" title="Vinod Kambli at Aakruti Hospital in Kopar village in Bhiwandi"><figcaption>Vinod Kambli at Aakruti Hospital in Kopar village in Bhiwandi</figcaption><p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli has been admitted to the ICU for treatment of a urinary tract infection and developed a fever on Tuesday. Doctors report his condition remains stable.</p><ul><li>Kambli was admitted to ICU on Saturday for a severe urinary tract infection.</li><li>He is responding well to treatment, according to Dr. Vivek Trivedi.</li><li>His upcoming MRI procedure has been postponed due to a fever.</li><li>Maharashtra Deputy Chief Minister Eknath Shinde offered financial support of ₹5 lakh for Kambli.</li><li>Kambli is expected to be moved out of ICU in a few days, with a likely discharge in about four days.</li></ul><blockquote>“I want to personally meet the Deputy CM to thank him for his help during this difficult time.” – Vinod Kambli</blockquote><p>The medical team remains optimistic about Kambli's recovery, while his health continues to be closely monitored.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/vinod-kambli-develops-fever-as-mri-procedure-delayed-remains-in-icu-doctor-says-condition-stable-101735110736916.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/vinod-kambli-develops-fever-as-mri-procedure-delayed-remains-in-icu-doctor-says-condition-stable-101735110736916.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 07:50:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Same gold, same pride, why not same award?’: Amid Manu Bhaker controversy, India's paralympic champion cries foul - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Same gold, same pride, why not same award?’: Amid Manu Bhaker controversy, India's paralympic champion cries foul</h1><p><strong>Date: December 25, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/TOPSHOT-ARCHERY-OLY-PARIS-2024-PARALYMPICS-2_1725625390194_1735112722433.jpg" alt="Harvinder Singh got gold in the archery Men's individual recurve category.(AFP)" title="Harvinder Singh got gold in the archery Men's individual recurve category.(AFP)"><figcaption>Harvinder Singh got gold in the archery Men's individual recurve category.(AFP)</figcaption><p>Paralympics gold medallist archer Harvinder Singh raised concerns about inconsistency in sports awards after missing out on the Khel Ratna award nomination despite his achievements. His comments come after the omission of notable athlete Manu Bhaker from early consideration sparked controversy in the sports community.</p><ul><li>Harvinder Singh won India’s first Paralympic gold medal in archery at the Paris Games.</li><li>He expressed frustration over different standards applied to athletes in award nominations.</li><li>Singh stated, “Same competition, same gold, same pride, why not same award?”</li><li>His coach supported his claim, stating he deserved recognition for his achievements.</li><li>The award selection committee includes notable sports figures and has the power to consider additional names.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tokyo 2020 Paralympic gold medallists were awarded Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna Award, but what about Paris 2024 Paralympic gold medallists?” - Harvinder Singh</blockquote><p>The issue highlights ongoing discussions about equality and recognition in sports awards, particularly for differently-abled athletes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/same-gold-same-pride-why-not-same-award-amid-manu-bhaker-controversy-indias-paralympic-champion-cries-foul-101735112447036.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/same-gold-same-pride-why-not-same-award-amid-manu-bhaker-controversy-indias-paralympic-champion-cries-foul-101735112447036.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 07:46:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intriguing Boxing Day beckons with SA in sight of WTC final - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Intriguing Boxing Day beckons with South Africa in sight of WTC final</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p><p>As South Africa and Pakistan prepare for their Boxing Day Test, South Africa is on the brink of securing a place in the World Test Championship final, while Pakistan aims to keep its slim hopes alive.</p><img src="https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg" alt="Story Image"><figcaption>Key players return for South Africa Tests</figcaption><p>This high-stakes match is significant with South Africa needing only one more win from their next two Tests, while Pakistan hopes to capitalize on pressure and momentum gained from a recent ODI series.</p><ul><li>South Africa requires one win to guarantee a WTC final spot.</li><li>Pakistan needs a win but also requires external factors to remain in contention.</li><li>Recent performance statistics show contrasting forms between the two teams.</li></ul><blockquote>Temba Bavuma stated, "We accept and acknowledge the fact that many expectations would have risen on the team. There'll be pressure that comes with that... But we're here now."</blockquote><p>This Boxing Day Test is not just another match; it's a decisive encounter with potential implications for the World Test Championship and both teams' futures in the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/south-africa-vs-pakistan-2024-25-1432205/south-africa-vs-pakistan-1st-test-1432217/match-preview</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/south-africa-vs-pakistan-2024-25-1432205/south-africa-vs-pakistan-1st-test-1432217/match-preview</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 07:24:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SA vs PAK 2024/25, SA vs PAK 1st Test Match Preview - Intriguing Boxing Day beckons with SA in sight of WTC final - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Intriguing Boxing Day beckons with South Africa in sight of WTC final</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p><p>As South Africa and Pakistan prepare for their Boxing Day Test, South Africa is on the brink of securing a place in the World Test Championship final, while Pakistan aims to keep its slim hopes alive.</p><img src="https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg" alt="Story Image"><figcaption>Key players return for South Africa Tests</figcaption><p>This high-stakes match is significant with South Africa needing only one more win from their next two Tests, while Pakistan hopes to capitalize on pressure and momentum gained from a recent ODI series.</p><ul><li>South Africa requires one win to guarantee a WTC final spot.</li><li>Pakistan needs a win but also requires external factors to remain in contention.</li><li>Recent performance statistics show contrasting forms between the two teams.</li></ul><blockquote>Temba Bavuma stated, "We accept and acknowledge the fact that many expectations would have risen on the team. There'll be pressure that comes with that... But we're here now."</blockquote><p>This Boxing Day Test is not just another match; it's a decisive encounter with potential implications for the World Test Championship and both teams' futures in the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/south-africa-vs-pakistan-2024-25-1432205/south-africa-vs-pakistan-1st-test-1432217/match-preview</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/south-africa-vs-pakistan-2024-25-1432205/south-africa-vs-pakistan-1st-test-1432217/match-preview</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 07:24:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli assured of Rs 5 lakh assistance by Shiv Sena - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli Assured Rs 5 Lakh Assistance by Shiv Sena</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli has received a promise of Rs 5 lakh assistance from the Shiv Sena for his medical expenses, acknowledging his recent health challenges and the need for financial support.</p><ul><li>Vinod Kambli has been facing health issues.</li><li>Shiv Sena has stepped in to provide financial aid.</li><li>This support is aimed at easing his medical expenses.</li></ul><blockquote>“I appreciate the support from Shiv Sena during this challenging time.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Kambli's situation has caught the attention of the public and his plea for help has led to this financial backing from Shiv Sena, showcasing community support for sports figures in need.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-assured-of-all-possible-help-by-shiv-sena/articleshow/116650461.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-assured-of-all-possible-help-by-shiv-sena/articleshow/116650461.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 07:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravichandran Ashwin uncovers Travis Head's clever 'ploy' to outsmart Jasprit Bumrah and co. - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravichandran Ashwin uncovers Travis Head's clever 'ploy' to outsmart Jasprit Bumrah and co.</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 25, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/25/550x309/ashwin_head_1735110054567_1735110065076.jpg" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin identified Travis Head's batting approach ahead of the MCG Test(AP)" title="Ravichandran Ashwin identified Travis Head's batting approach ahead of the MCG Test(AP)">
<figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin identified Travis Head's batting approach ahead of the MCG Test(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Ravichandran Ashwin highlights Travis Head's strategic adjustments in batting drills to tackle Indian pacers ahead of the upcoming Boxing Day Test in Melbourne.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Ashwin shares insights into Head's batting practice aimed at addressing pacers bowling from around the wicket.</li>
    <li>Head has been a key player for Australia, scoring over 400 runs in the series, including two centuries.</li>
    <li>Head is coming off a series of impressive performances, significant for Australia's momentum after a recent win.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Head seemed to guard his off-stump to ensure he cleared a higher area around the off-stump to negate the round-the-wicket threat.” - Ravichandran Ashwin</blockquote>
<p>Head's performance continues to stand out in the series amidst struggles from other Australian batters, underscoring his importance for the team's success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ravichandran-ashwin-uncovers-travis-heads-clever-ploy-to-outsmart-jasprit-bumrah-and-co-101735107190279.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ravichandran-ashwin-uncovers-travis-heads-clever-ploy-to-outsmart-jasprit-bumrah-and-co-101735107190279.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 07:07:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma To Open, India To Make Big Playing XI Change For 4th Australia Test: Report - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma To Open, India To Make Big Playing XI Change For 4th Australia Test: Report</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/klhqigog_dsa_625x300_25_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Rohit Sharma To Open, India To Make Big Playing XI Change For 4th Australia Test: Report" />
<figcaption>Indian cricket team skipper Rohit Sharma in action © AFP</figcaption>
<p>Indian cricket team skipper Rohit Sharma is set to open the innings while KL Rahul will bat at No. 3 in the Boxing Day Test in Melbourne against Australia. Rohit will return as an opener after previously batting at No. 6, with uncertainty surrounding Shubman Gill's position.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Rohit Sharma confirmed to open the batting.</li>
    <li>KL Rahul to bat at No. 3.</li>
    <li>India may play two spinners, with Washington Sundar and Ravindra Jadeja potentially included.</li>
    <li>Nitish Kumar Reddy may be dropped despite good performance in the series.</li>
    <li>Mitchell Starc is on the verge of reaching 700 international wickets.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Mitchell Starc has taken 695 wickets in 284 matches, with 372 in Test matches alone.</blockquote>
<p>This shift in lineup showcases India's strategy to tackle the Australian bowling attack effectively, especially during a critical match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharma-to-open-for-india-in-boxing-day-test-against-australia-report-says-kl-rahul-to-bat-at-7327204</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharma-to-open-for-india-in-boxing-day-test-against-australia-report-says-kl-rahul-to-bat-at-7327204</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 06:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India have all but foiled Australia's 'smart-scheduling' plan - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Have Foiled Australia's Scheduling Strategy in Border Gavaskar Trophy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116649191,imgsize-64932,width-400,resizemode-4/116649191.jpg" alt="India have all but foiled Australia's 'smart-scheduling' plan" title="ANI Photo"><figcaption>India have all but foiled Australia's 'smart-scheduling' plan</figcaption><p>This article discusses how India has countered Australia’s strategic scheduling in the Border Gavaskar Trophy, showcasing noteworthy performances and pivotal moments throughout the series.</p><ul><li>Australia's scheduling aimed to leverage fast pitches to gain an early lead in the series.</li><li>India's Jasprit Bumrah has excelled, taking 21 wickets at an impressive average of 10.90.</li><li>Despite a strong start from India, Australian tactics have affected the morale of Indian batters.</li><li>Virat Kohli delivered a solid performance, with specific reference to his century in the second innings at Perth.</li><li>Looking ahead, the focus will be on the last two Tests in Melbourne and Sydney.</li></ul><blockquote>Rohit Sharma: 'Virat Kohli is a modern day great. He will figure it out'</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while Australia initially had the scheduling advantage, India's strong bowling performance led by Bumrah and crucial batting efforts have put the series in a competitive light as they approach the final matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/india-have-all-but-foiled-australias-smart-scheduling-plan-for-border-gavaskar-trophy/articleshow/116649124.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/india-have-all-but-foiled-australias-smart-scheduling-plan-for-border-gavaskar-trophy/articleshow/116649124.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 06:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>