<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 01:27:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 01:27:31 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drama at MCG! Pat Cummins denied review on Mohammed Siraj call; Ravi Shastri, Adam Gilchrist left stunned - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Drama at MCG! Pat Cummins denied review on Mohammed Siraj call; Ravi Shastri, Adam Gilchrist left stunned</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116755932,imgsize-52110,width-400,resizemode-4/116755932.jpg" alt="Drama at MCG! Pat Cummins denied review on Mohammed Siraj call; Ravi Shastri, Adam Gilchrist left stunned" title="Image credit: X" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption><p>Australian captain Pat Cummins was perplexed after the third umpire overturned what appeared to be a legitimate dismissal during the Boxing Day Test at the MCG.</p><ul><li>Cummins delivered a full-length delivery to Mohammed Siraj, leading to a contentious call on a catch by Steve Smith.</li><li>The third umpire ruled Siraj not out, citing unclear evidence of a bump ball.</li><li>Cummins requested a review of the decision but was denied by the on-field umpires.</li><li>The decision confused commentators Adam Gilchrist and Ravi Shastri, who questioned the umpiring process.</li><li>Australia dismissed Nitish Kumar Reddy shortly after the controversy.</li></ul><blockquote>This is very interesting. I have never seen this before. - Adam Gilchrist</blockquote><blockquote>The umpire said I've seen the ball bounce after it hit the bat. That was a very quick call. - Ravi Shastri</blockquote><p>The controversial call had little impact on the match outcome, with India trailing Australia by 105 runs after their first innings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/drama-at-mcg-pat-cummins-denied-review-on-mohammed-siraj-call-ravi-shastri-adam-gilchrist-left-stunned/articleshow/116755908.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/drama-at-mcg-pat-cummins-denied-review-on-mohammed-siraj-call-ravi-shastri-adam-gilchrist-left-stunned/articleshow/116755908.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Calm down': Ravi Shastri on Rishabh Pant's bizarre dismissal at MCG - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Calm down: Ravi Shastri on Rishabh Pant's bizarre dismissal at MCG</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>NEW DELHI</p>
<p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116753493,imgsize-47222,width-400,resizemode-4/116753493.jpg" alt="Rishabh Pant (Getty Images)" title="Rishabh Pant (Getty Images)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Rishabh Pant (Getty Images)</figcaption>
<p>In a crucial phase of Day 3 at the MCG, Rishabh Pant's risky shot selection led to his dismissal, sparking debate among fans and experts about his aggressive playing style.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pant attempted a scoop shot against Scott Boland but was caught out, leaving India at 191/5.</li>
  <li>Criticism of Pant's shot selection included comments from cricketer Sunil Gavaskar, who labeled it “stupid.”</li>
  <li>Ravi Shastri defended Pant, suggesting that it’s important to assess the context of his dismissals across innings.</li>
  <li>Shastri emphasized the need for Pant to adapt his approach during matches and play with maturity.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It's not in every innings he has attempted that shot... Let’s calm down here, guys. It’s not every time he’s throwing it away.” - Ravi Shastri</blockquote>
<p>Shastri also remarked on Pant's propensity for high-risk shots, noting that while they can be effective, they must be executed wisely in changing game situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ravi-shastri-on-rishabh-pants-bizarre-dismissal-at-mcg/articleshow/116753502.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ravi-shastri-on-rishabh-pants-bizarre-dismissal-at-mcg/articleshow/116753502.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 22:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nitish Kumar Reddy blossoms to give India hope as century stalls Australia - The Guardian]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitish Kumar Reddy's Century Offers Hope for India Against Australia</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Guardian</p>
<img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/f79a07010e986b1f64434b81c0ca0fec875435ce/0_265_4157_2496/master/4157.jpg?width=445&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none" alt="India’s Nitish Kumar Reddy smashes a six straight down the ground on his way to a century on day three of the third Test against Australia." loading="lazy">
<figcaption>India’s Nitish Kumar Reddy smashes Nathan Lyon for six on day three of the fourth Test against Australia. Photograph: Santanu Banik/Speed Media/REX/Shutterstock</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the remarkable performance of 21-year-old Nitish Kumar Reddy during India's Test series against Australia, particularly highlighting his significant inning that helped India regain hope in a challenging match.</p>
<ul>
<li>Reddy scored his first Test century during a vital moment in the fourth Test in Melbourne.</li>
<li>Despite the focus on veteran players, the contribution of young talents like Reddy is reshaping the narrative of the series.</li>
<li>His inning of 105 showcased not only skill but also composure in a high-pressure environment.</li>
<li>Reddy's innings was marked by aggressive running and resilience against Australia's pace attack.</li>
<li>He was able to fight through tough situations, demonstrating maturity beyond his years.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Reddy's work on this day was astonishing, a kid who recently received his 21st birthday key using it to unlock his method."</blockquote>
<p>Reddy's impressive debut indicates a hopeful future for Indian cricket, showcasing a bright new talent ready to rise in the ranks of cricket legends.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2024/dec/28/cricket-australia-india-fourth-test-day-three-report-nitish-kumar-reddy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2024/dec/28/cricket-australia-india-fourth-test-day-three-report-nitish-kumar-reddy</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Africa stumbles to 27-3 in pursuit of tricky 148-run target in 1st test against Pakistan - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Africa stumbles to 27-3 in pursuit of tricky 148-run target in 1st test against Pakistan</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Dec 28, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/09/30/550x309/Cricket_3_1727677442716_1727677564058.jpg" alt="South Africa stumbles to 27-3 in pursuit of tricky 148-run target in 1st test against Pakistan" title="South Africa stumbles to 27-3 in pursuit of tricky 148-run target in 1st test against Pakistan" />
<figcaption>South Africa stumbles to 27-3 in pursuit of tricky 148-run target in 1st test against Pakistan</figcaption>
<p>South Africa's top-order struggled against Pakistan's pace attack, heading towards an exciting finish as they pursue a tricky target of 148 runs set by Pakistan.</p>
<ul>
<li>Marco Jansen took six wickets, ensuring South Africa bowled out Pakistan for 237 runs.</li>
<li>South Africa is under pressure, currently at 27-3 at stumps, needing a win in one of the two matches to secure a spot in the World Test Championship final.</li>
<li>Fast bowler Mohammad Abbas made a significant impact returning to test cricket after a three-year absence.</li>
<li>Aiden Markram remains unbeaten on 22, while captain Temba Bavuma is yet to score.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“South Africa needs to secure a win in one of the two tests against Pakistan to make it to the World Test Championship final.”</blockquote>
<p>This match proves pivotal for South Africa as they face a challenging second innings against Pakistan's formidable bowling attack.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/south-africa-stumbles-to-27-3-in-pursuit-of-tricky-148-run-target-in-1st-test-against-pakistan-101735404389595.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/south-africa-stumbles-to-27-3-in-pursuit-of-tricky-148-run-target-in-1st-test-against-pakistan-101735404389595.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:46:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['The run out played on his mind': Madan Lal on Virat Kohli’s dismissal in Boxing Day Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'The run out played on his mind': Madan Lal on Virat Kohli’s dismissal in Boxing Day Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>In a recent discussion, former cricketer Madan Lal expressed his thoughts on Virat Kohli's performance and the impact of his run-out during the Boxing Day Test.</p><ul><li>Madan Lal highlights the psychological effect on Kohli following the dismissal.</li><li>The analysis brings attention to the importance of mental resilience in cricket.</li><li>Discussions around player mental health in high-pressure situations are emphasized.</li></ul><blockquote>“The run out played on his mind.”</blockquote><p>The discussion sheds light on the unseen pressures faced by cricketers, particularly during significant matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/the-run-out-played-on-his-mind-madan-lal-on-virat-kohlis-dismissal-in-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116747845.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/the-run-out-played-on-his-mind-madan-lal-on-virat-kohlis-dismissal-in-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116747845.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Carlsen Quits Rapid & Blitz Championships; Murzin, Duda, Arjun, Grischuk Lead Open - Chess.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Carlsen Withdraws from Rapid & Blitz Championships Amid Dress Code Dispute</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Chess.com</p>
<figure><img src="https://images.chesscomfiles.com/uploads/v1/images_users/tiny_mce/AnthonyLevin/phpk4p23f.jpg" alt="" width="2500" height="1667"> <figcaption>Holowczak explains the decision. Photo: Maria Emelianova/Chess.com.</figcaption></figure>
<p>In a surprising turn of events, GM <a href="https://www.chess.com/players/magnus-carlsen" target="_blank">Magnus Carlsen</a> announced he will no longer compete in the <a href="https://www.chess.com/events/info/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championships" target="_blank">2024 FIDE World Rapid Chess Championship</a> due to a disagreement with the dress code enforced by FIDE.</p>
<ul>
<li>Carlsen finished the rapid tournament with a score of 5/8.</li>
<li>This exit guarantees the crowning of new champions in both rapid and blitz formats.</li>
<li>Four players, including <a href="https://www.chess.com/players/volodar-murzin" target="_blank">Volodar Murzin</a>, <a href="https://www.chess.com/players/jan-krzysztof-duda" target="_blank">Jan-Krzysztof Duda</a>, <a href="https://www.chess.com/players/arjun-erigaisi" target="_blank">Arjun Erigaisi</a>, and <a href="https://www.chess.com/players/alexander-grischuk" target="_blank">Alexander Grischuk</a>, lead the open championship with scores of 7/9.</li>
<li>Disputes over fines were reported, highlighting inconsistencies in dress code enforcement.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"My patience with them was not very big to begin with... then I'm out, then f**k you." — <a href="https://twitter.com/MagnusCarlsen">Magnus Carlsen</a></blockquote>
<p>As the championships move forward, all eyes will be on the new emerging talents in rapid and blitz chess.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championship-day-2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championship-day-2</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magnus Carlsen breaks silence after quitting World Chess Championship over shocking jeans row: ‘Honestly, I am…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Magnus Carlsen Walks Out of Championship Over Jeans Controversy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/CHESS-IND-17_1735348010577_1735403481308.jpg" alt="Magnus Carlsen, the Norway's chess grandmaster, stated that he will not challenge the ruling, stating: “Honestly, I am too old at this point to care too much.”(AFP)" /><figcaption>Magnus Carlsen, the Norway's chess grandmaster, stated that he will not challenge the ruling, stating: “Honestly, I am too old at this point to care too much.”(AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>The world champion Magnus Carlsen left the World Rapid and Blitz Chess Championships after being told he could not compete in jeans.</p><ul><li>Carlsen was in New York for the championship when he was informed about the dress code violation.</li><li>He initially offered to change his jeans for the next day but was fined and told to change immediately.</li><li>After being prohibited from participating, Carlsen famously expressed his frustration and walked out.</li><li>Carlsen stated he would not appeal the ruling, citing his age and indifference to the situation.</li><li>The head of FIDE clarified that Carlsen was not disqualified and could continue in the tournament the next day.</li></ul><blockquote>“Honestly, I am too old at this point to care too much.” – Magnus Carlsen</blockquote><p>Carlsen’s departure adds a dramatic twist to this year’s championship and raises questions about the enforcement of dress codes in professional chess.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/magnus-carlsen-breaks-silence-after-quitting-world-chess-championship-over-shocking-jeans-row-honestly-i-am-101735401712485.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/magnus-carlsen-breaks-silence-after-quitting-world-chess-championship-over-shocking-jeans-row-honestly-i-am-101735401712485.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:34:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World rapid & blitz: Arjun Erigaisi joins the leaders - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arjun Erigaisi Joins Leaders at World Rapid and Blitz Chess Tournament</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/Indian-GM-Arjun-Erigaisi-is-in-joint-lead-going-in_1735402005052.jpg" alt="Indian GM Arjun Erigaisi is in joint lead going into the final day of the rapid event at the World Rapid and Blitz Chess tournament in New York. (HT Photo)" title="Indian GM Arjun Erigaisi is in joint lead going into the final day of the rapid event at the World Rapid and Blitz Chess tournament in New York. (HT Photo)">
<figcaption>Indian GM Arjun Erigaisi is in joint lead going into the final day of the rapid event at the World Rapid and Blitz Chess tournament in New York. (HT Photo)</figcaption>
<p>Arjun Erigaisi, a 21-year-old chess prodigy, is among the leaders at the World Rapid and Blitz tournament in New York, aiming to qualify for the Candidates tournament.</p>
<ul>
<li>After nine rounds, Arjun has 7/9 points, sharing the lead with other top players.</li>
<li>He achieved two wins and two draws during the last four rounds.</li>
<li>Defending champion Magnus Carlsen withdrew after a dress code dispute and a poor performance.</li>
<li>18-year-old Volodar Murzin is having a standout tournament, upsetting strong opponents.</li>
<li>In the women’s section, Harika Dronavalli and Koneru Humpy are leading with reigning champion Ju Wenjun.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It turned out to be a tense affair and ended in a draw.”</blockquote>
<p>As the tournament approaches its conclusion, the competition remains fierce with several top players vying for the top spots.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/world-rapid-blitz-arjun-erigaisi-joins-the-leaders-101735402008575.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/world-rapid-blitz-arjun-erigaisi-joins-the-leaders-101735402008575.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:06:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Sam Konstas Teases India Fans At MCG, Mimics Shoulder-Barge Incident With Virat Kohli - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNckV0bmtxMENtdG9PUEI0aWtUay0tTHdLUmg1dHZ6aWJxZVRFTkQ4VTNzTExZMXN6UWVIb212U3B6b0hLcDRPb0ZBWGd5QTUtSEpuSUNvWHBrM0lUR0VveTZmTG5vRm16ZVFUZkJlbTN4eU9FVklBcjVqczlwY0RGRVpfWlVkdldJaHZDLWJnLVFQVlhWYkY0Qk5UdEdwcUxsRGRaOE1HQXVwbzRWQVVZX2tGT0ZvMy1QRnk0X19lR2EwdGpxMW9NN0Y1cGR3TkE0M05xTjVMLXozLW96WE1mY1M3NNIB6wFBVV95cUxOTVF4ZnRvRmlfcFZlSkFIVDZtbjlldF9PN2tDX0k2M0dEYWlsUzV3ZTlIRzRjTExZbXY2Z3B0TGlZaTZBY2szMFZsODNTaUR5NkhFRWVZZVVIMFRlNDJWRGNoT0RndTlfZHRsNVdTMkhTM2wtamJYLU9RanFoXzU1QlZyU0Q3cXF4QWhlQ09XVUR1YkpKZDdNZ2pkT01ZeEVtZXByWV9CY1NBa2o2bW1UWEVrSkloUXF4RWVfVXJ2SWp3Y0pmZHRhNGlNVlNPQlFqQ1dMYWFrX2ctWERZZDdEUF9UY1JsY0hMZFRr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxNckV0bmtxMENtdG9PUEI0aWtUay0tTHdLUmg1dHZ6aWJxZVRFTkQ4VTNzTExZMXN6UWVIb212U3B6b0hLcDRPb0ZBWGd5QTUtSEpuSUNvWHBrM0lUR0VveTZmTG5vRm16ZVFUZkJlbTN4eU9FVklBcjVqczlwY0RGRVpfWlVkdldJaHZDLWJnLVFQVlhWYkY0Qk5UdEdwcUxsRGRaOE1HQXVwbzRWQVVZX2tGT0ZvMy1QRnk0X19lR2EwdGpxMW9NN0Y1cGR3TkE0M05xTjVMLXozLW96WE1mY1M3NNIB6wFBVV95cUxOTVF4ZnRvRmlfcFZlSkFIVDZtbjlldF9PN2tDX0k2M0dEYWlsUzV3ZTlIRzRjTExZbXY2Z3B0TGlZaTZBY2szMFZsODNTaUR5NkhFRWVZZVVIMFRlNDJWRGNoT0RndTlfZHRsNVdTMkhTM2wtamJYLU9RanFoXzU1QlZyU0Q3cXF4QWhlQ09XVUR1YkpKZDdNZ2pkT01ZeEVtZXByWV9CY1NBa2o2bW1UWEVrSkloUXF4RWVfVXJ2SWp3Y0pmZHRhNGlNVlNPQlFqQ1dMYWFrX2ctWERZZDdEUF9UY1JsY0hMZFRr?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:39:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gavaskar fires fresh salvo at Rishabh Pant for ‘careless’ dismissal: ‘He thinks it’s the only way he can score runs’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxPa2Nia2dtZjNkMXhYbTJrZlA2NGc5VXM5U0thc1hoNFNIVkR6M2loVk5ZRHUtUjJPcmJPZWNydWdnNnBhbURqVG5QV0Jwa1haSHRXYzJiNGVpNmJ2clByQ0p2bi1vdXJCb1UxWi11SDlDRTBIM3dRY2ljaWk3cHBqREN0bFNBaFFVcDVkcEJyTlpmWXdCTkNNSERjYzBjUWJSSF9sWm9VMm8xNjJfdDNaNEdQLWhpU0JZQmZJSjlWSk9FZTlLYWE2QXJrbFpnY1ZhTzJ1OTByVm44Yjg1WDN6N21PcE1CREJvYmRTQkk5U0ktY25kLVBHM0d0YjJjdnl10gGGAkFVX3lxTE1uajFLN19RYnJ3WFV2WXFKaC1rOTlJdlZ1ZWhrYnVSWVFsOGtpaDV2NGVQN3NQUTB5ZkpuLW1TZ3hvelU0cDJaUEJWV2EzLW9HSF9GODJrNDNZb25pazIxSHoyb1NlZk1WX1hPREkyTUNWcHVGOVBUMVRibVY2QWpkRk14Q0ZlWTQ4NnhtVnBCLTc4SnlxVjlCNi1LNUZFSHRFaTQzaHJ6V2RwRjJteWVkdzJGVlVNWXc2RGRSWnFQeVNpUTlOM0VyMTRCRkVYclhxbW5TdEtNUk9xbzd4MVo0N1JrMUYwTExFNXV6SkMxenpfRlJxNTRKLS1KZGllcHZDUDl6aUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAJBVV95cUxPa2Nia2dtZjNkMXhYbTJrZlA2NGc5VXM5U0thc1hoNFNIVkR6M2loVk5ZRHUtUjJPcmJPZWNydWdnNnBhbURqVG5QV0Jwa1haSHRXYzJiNGVpNmJ2clByQ0p2bi1vdXJCb1UxWi11SDlDRTBIM3dRY2ljaWk3cHBqREN0bFNBaFFVcDVkcEJyTlpmWXdCTkNNSERjYzBjUWJSSF9sWm9VMm8xNjJfdDNaNEdQLWhpU0JZQmZJSjlWSk9FZTlLYWE2QXJrbFpnY1ZhTzJ1OTByVm44Yjg1WDN6N21PcE1CREJvYmRTQkk5U0ktY25kLVBHM0d0YjJjdnl10gGGAkFVX3lxTE1uajFLN19RYnJ3WFV2WXFKaC1rOTlJdlZ1ZWhrYnVSWVFsOGtpaDV2NGVQN3NQUTB5ZkpuLW1TZ3hvelU0cDJaUEJWV2EzLW9HSF9GODJrNDNZb25pazIxSHoyb1NlZk1WX1hPREkyTUNWcHVGOVBUMVRibVY2QWpkRk14Q0ZlWTQ4NnhtVnBCLTc4SnlxVjlCNi1LNUZFSHRFaTQzaHJ6V2RwRjJteWVkdzJGVlVNWXc2RGRSWnFQeVNpUTlOM0VyMTRCRkVYclhxbW5TdEtNUk9xbzd4MVo0N1JrMUYwTExFNXV6SkMxenpfRlJxNTRKLS1KZGllcHZDUDl6aUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:32:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['This is the last time he will bat at 7': Ravi Shastri pushes for Nitish Reddy’s batting order promotion - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravi Shastri Advocates for Nitish Reddy's Promotion in Batting Order</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>Ravi Shastri emphasizes the need for Nitish Reddy to be promoted in the batting order, suggesting it could lead to better performances.</p><ul><li>Shastri believes Reddy has the potential to make a significant impact.</li><li>The suggestion comes in light of recent performances from the player.</li><li>Shastri's advocacy highlights the importance of strategic batting order changes.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is the last time he will bat at 7."</blockquote><p>Shastri's insights reflect a forward-thinking approach in cricket management, aiming for optimal player utilization.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/this-is-the-last-time-he-will-bat-at-7-ravi-shastri-pushes-for-nitish-reddys-batting-order-promotion/articleshow/116746211.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/this-is-the-last-time-he-will-bat-at-7-ravi-shastri-pushes-for-nitish-reddys-batting-order-promotion/articleshow/116746211.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi calls chess champion Gukesh an embodiment of calmness, humility - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Meets Chess World Champion Gukesh, Praises His Determination and Humility</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 28, 2024<br>Source: Times of India</strong></p>
<img src='https://example.com/gukesh_and_modi.jpg' alt='PM Modi with Gukesh' width='300'>
<figcaption>PM Modi with chess world champion Gukesh</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi met with newly-crowned chess world champion D Gukesh and praised the 18-year-old for his determination, dedication, and humility.</p>
<ol>
<li>Gukesh became the youngest chess world champion, surpassing Garry Kasparov's record.</li>
<li>PM Modi met with Gukesh and his parents, commending their efforts in his journey to the world title.</li>
<li>Gukesh gifted PM Modi the chessboard used in his winning game.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote><p dir='ltr' lang='en'>Had an excellent interaction with chess champion and India’s pride, <a href='https://twitter.com/DGukesh?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw' rel='nofollow' target='_blank'>@DGukesh</a>!<small>&nbsp;</small> I have been closely interacting with him for a few years now, and what strikes me most about him is his determination and dedication. His confidence is truly inspiring.</p>
<p>In fact, I recall seeing a video of his few years ago where he had said he would become the youngest world champion - a prediction that has now clearly come true thanks to his own efforts.</p>
<p>Along with confidence, Gukesh embodies calmness and humility. Upon winning, he was composed, basking in his glory while fully understanding how to process this hard-earned victory. Our conversation today revolved around the transformative potential of yoga and meditation.</p>
<p>In the success of every athlete, their parents play a pivotal role. I complimented Gukesh's parents for supporting him through thick and thin. Their dedication will inspire countless parents of young aspirants who dream of pursuing sports as a career.</p>
<p>I am also delighted to have received from Gukesh the original chessboard from the game he won. The chessboard, autographed by both him and Ding Liren, is a cherished memento.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>After the meeting, Gukesh expressed his gratitude and humility towards the PM's support and encouragement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/sports/other-sports-news/pm-modi-calls-chess-champion-gukesh-an-embodiment-of-calmness-humility-124122800608_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/sports/other-sports-news/pm-modi-calls-chess-champion-gukesh-an-embodiment-of-calmness-humility-124122800608_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:44:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['We followed the rules, Magnus Carlsen didn't': FIDE deputy prez Viswanathan Anand - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chess World Reacts to Magnus Carlsen's Breach of Rules: Anand Speaks Out</h1><p><strong>Published on October 12, 2023, in Times of India</strong></p><img src="https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/GETTY_IMAGES/SKP/839388148__zbzUVWum.jpg" alt="Magnus Carlsen" width="200" height="200"><figcaption>Magnus Carlsen</figcaption><p>In a surprising turn of events, five-time world chess champion Magnus Carlsen has been accused of breaking tournament rules, sparking a wave of reactions from the chess community. The World Chess Federation (FIDE) deputy president, Viswanathan Anand, has spoken out against Carlsen's actions.</p><ol><li>Carlsen was seen playing a rapid game on a different platform while participating in the Sinquefield Cup.</li><li>This breach of rules has led to widespread discussion and criticism in the chess community.</li><li>Anand, a former world champion himself, has criticized Carlsen's actions, stating that they disrespect the tournament and fellow players.</li></ol><blockquote><p>“We followed the rules, Magnus Carlsen didn’t. It’s as simple as that.” - Viswanathan Anand</p></blockquote><p>Carlsen's actions have ignited a debate about sportsmanship and the integrity of chess tournaments. While some support Carlsen's right to express himself, others argue that his actions set a poor example for younger players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/chess/we-followed-the-rules-magnus-carlsen-didnt-fide-deputy-prez-viswanathan-anand/articleshow/116744769.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/chess/we-followed-the-rules-magnus-carlsen-didnt-fide-deputy-prez-viswanathan-anand/articleshow/116744769.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Even if Virat Kohli would have turned Usain Bolt, he wouldn't have crossed the half-way mark": Ravi Shastri on Yashasvi Jaiswal's run-out debate - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Even if Virat Kohli would have turned Usain Bolt, he wouldn’t have crossed the half-way mark”: Ravi Shastri on Yashasvi Jaiswal’s run-out debate</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Crictoday</p><figure><img src="https://crictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Virat-Kohli-and-Yashasvi-Jaiswal.webp" alt="Virat Kohli and Yashasvi Jaiswal"><figcaption>Virat Kohli and Yashasvi Jaiswal during the match.</figcaption></figure><p>The ongoing debate regarding Yashasvi Jaiswal's recent run-out has drawn reactions from various cricketers, with Ravi Shastri defending Virat Kohli amid criticism.</p><ul><li>Jaiswal was dismissed for not properly assessing the situation during a run attempt.</li><li>Shastri criticized Jaiswal's judgment in the incident, stating Kohli could not have made it even if he had sprinted.</li><li>The run-out came at a crucial moment, impacting India’s batting order.</li></ul><blockquote>“Yashasvi Jaiswal didn’t realise how quickly the ball went to Pat Cummins. Pat is really fast in that area. Even if Virat Kohli would have turned Usain Bolt, he wouldn’t have crossed the half-way mark. This was a clear error in judgement by Jaiswal.” - Ravi Shastri</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the fine line between aggressive batting and careful judgment in cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://crictoday.com/cricket/daily-cricket-news/even-if-virat-kohli-would-have-turned-usain-bolt-he-wouldnt-have-crossed-the-half-way-mark-ravi-shastri-on-yashasvi-jaiswals-run-out-debate/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crictoday.com/cricket/daily-cricket-news/even-if-virat-kohli-would-have-turned-usain-bolt-he-wouldnt-have-crossed-the-half-way-mark-ravi-shastri-on-yashasvi-jaiswals-run-out-debate/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Rohit Sharma get a chance to redeem himself in Test cricket? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/will-rohit-sharma-get-a-chance-to-redeem-himself-in-test-cricket/articleshow/116745322.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/will-rohit-sharma-get-a-chance-to-redeem-himself-in-test-cricket/articleshow/116745322.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anushka Sharma Poses With Nitish Kumar Reddy's Family In Melbourne, Photo Goes Viral Amid His Test Century - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anushka Sharma Poses with Nitish Kumar Reddy's Family in Melbourne, Photo Goes Viral</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Anushka Sharma with Nitish Kumar's family in Melbourne." title="Anushka Sharma with Nitish Kumar's family in Melbourne."><figcaption>Anushka Sharma with Nitish Kumar's family in Melbourne.</figcaption><p>Anushka Sharma has been in Australia to support Virat Kohli and Team India, posing with Nitish Kumar Reddy's family after his maiden Test century.</p><ul><li>Anushka has been in Australia for a month during the 2024-25 Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li><li>The photo was shared by Nitish Kumar Reddy’s father on Instagram on December 27, 2024.</li><li>The photo shows Anushka smiling in a casual outfit with Nitish's family.</li><li>Athiya Shetty, who is expecting, was also spotted in the background of the photo.</li><li>Nitish Kumar Reddy recently scored his maiden Test fifty, celebrated with a hand gesture from a viral movie.</li></ul><blockquote>“A lovely moment,” Nitish Kumar Reddy's father captioned the Instagram photo.</blockquote><p>This moment highlights the camaraderie and support in the cricketing community, particularly among families during significant sporting events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/anushka-sharma-poses-with-nitish-kumar-reddys-family-at-the-melbourne-cricket-ground-photo-goes-viral-9170660.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/anushka-sharma-poses-with-nitish-kumar-reddys-family-at-the-melbourne-cricket-ground-photo-goes-viral-9170660.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:14:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After 733 days, Babar Azam finally breaks unwanted streak in Test cricket - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After 733 days, Babar Azam finally breaks unwanted streak in Test cricket</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>Babar Azam has ended a lengthy period without a Test century, marking a significant moment in his cricketing career.</p><ul><li>He had gone 733 days without a century in Test matches.</li><li>His performance is crucial for the national team as they aim for better results in upcoming tournaments.</li><li>This achievement is significant for his batting morale and team confidence.</li></ul><blockquote>“The drought is finally over; I’m back in form.” - Babar Azam</blockquote><p>This milestone could re-establish Azam as a key player for the team moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/after-733-days-babar-azam-finally-breaks-unwanted-streak-in-test-cricket/articleshow/116744836.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/after-733-days-babar-azam-finally-breaks-unwanted-streak-in-test-cricket/articleshow/116744836.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nitish Kumar Reddy Rewarded With Massive Cash Prize From Andhra Cricket Association - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitish Kumar Reddy Rewarded With Massive Cash Prize From Andhra Cricket Association</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/s6ehvd0o_nitish-kumar-reddy-record_625x300_28_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Nitish Kumar Reddy Rewarded With Massive Cash Prize From Andhra Cricket Association"><figcaption>Nitish Kumar Reddy Rewarded With Massive Cash Prize From Andhra Cricket Association</figcaption><p>The Andhra Cricket Association has awarded a cash prize of Rs 25 lakh to Nitish Kumar Reddy in recognition of his impressive Test performance, which played a significant role in India's comeback during the Boxing Day Test in Melbourne.</p><ul><li>The ACA announced a cash prize of Rs 25 lakh for Reddy.</li><li>Reddy scored an unbeaten 105 runs, helping India reach 358 for nine.</li><li>His performance was instrumental in India's fightback in the fourth Test at the Melbourne Cricket Ground.</li><li>Reddy has been highlighted as a standout player in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li><li>Cricket legends praised his innings, with Sunil Gavaskar calling it one of the greatest Test knocks.</li></ul><blockquote>"It is a fortunate day and a happiest moment for the Andhra Cricket Association," said ACA President Kesineni Sivanath.</blockquote><p>Nitish Kumar Reddy's achievement not only highlights his talent but also brings pride to the region, marking a significant milestone in his cricketing career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/nitish-kumar-reddy-rewarded-with-massive-cash-prize-from-andhra-cricket-association-7351173</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/nitish-kumar-reddy-rewarded-with-massive-cash-prize-from-andhra-cricket-association-7351173</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:51:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['That's why you're not head coach': Australian legends in heated debate over Rishabh Pant's dismissal - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Debate Erupts Over Rishabh Pant's Dismissal in Boxing Day Test</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date Not Specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116744706,imgsize-109892,width-400,resizemode-4/116744706.jpg" alt="Rishabh Pant. (Photo by Robert Cianflone/Getty Images)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Rishabh Pant. (Photo by Robert Cianflone/Getty Images)</figcaption>
<p>The dismissal of Rishabh Pant during the Boxing Day Test at the MCG has sparked intense discussions among Australian cricket legends regarding his shot selection.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Rishabh Pant attempted a scoop shot but was caught, leading to disagreements among commentators.</li>
    <li>Mark Waugh criticized Pant's shot selection, citing game situation and risks involved.</li>
    <li>Michael Hussey defended Pant's playing style, advocating for players' freedom to play audacious shots.</li>
    <li>Michael Vaughan supported Hussey's stance, praising Pant's talent.</li>
    <li>The debate highlighted differing coaching philosophies on aggressive play and shot selection.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Mark Waugh: "That's unacceptable... there were two men back for that exact shot."
</blockquote>
<blockquote>Michael Hussey: "That's the way he likes to play... it is a poor shot, don't get me wrong."
</blockquote>
<p>This discussion reflects the tension between maintaining aggressive batting styles and adhering to strategic play in cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/thats-why-youre-not-head-coach-australian-legends-in-heated-debate-over-rishabh-pants-dismissal/articleshow/116744670.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/thats-why-youre-not-head-coach-australian-legends-in-heated-debate-over-rishabh-pants-dismissal/articleshow/116744670.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inside photos of Vinod Kambli's home, it costs over Rs..., cricketer hasn't settled loan and maintenance... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Inside photos of Vinod Kambli's home, it costs over Rs..., cricketer hasn't settled loan and maintenance...</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/inside-photos-of-vinod-kamblis-home-it-costs-over-rs-cricketer-hasnt-settled-loan-and-maintenance-202412-1735392783.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Inside photos of Vinod Kambli's home"/><figcaption>Image credit: Instagram</figcaption><p>This article features a glimpse into former cricketer Vinod Kambli's luxurious home in Bandra, Mumbai, while highlighting his ongoing financial troubles, including unsettled loans and maintenance fees.</p><ul><li>The estimated value of Kambli's home ranges from Rs 6 to 8 crore.</li><li>The apartment features a large living area showcasing a blend of elegance and personal history.</li><li>Kambli faces significant financial challenges with outstanding maintenance dues totaling Rs 10.5 lakh.</li><li>His home reflects a mix of personal memorabilia and financial mismanagement.</li></ul><blockquote>“Vinod Kambli has long struggled with a reputation for financial mismanagement.”</blockquote><p>Kambli's story serves as a reminder of the complexities behind a celebrated career, showcasing both moments of success and the consequences of financial oversight.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/inside-photos-of-vinod-kamblis-home-it-costs-over-rs-cricketer-hasnt-settled-loan-and-maintenance-416893/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/inside-photos-of-vinod-kamblis-home-it-costs-over-rs-cricketer-hasnt-settled-loan-and-maintenance-416893/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:38:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["You can't be successful in Test cricket": Sunil Gavaskar warns Rishabh Pant of serious consequences - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gavaskar's Warning to Rishabh Pant on Test Cricket Success</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Crictoday</p><img src="https://crictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Rishabh-Pant-1.webp" alt="Rishabh Pant during a Test match"><figcaption>Rishabh Pant under scrutiny after reckless batting.</figcaption><p>Sunil Gavaskar cautions Rishabh Pant about his batting approach in Test cricket, emphasizing the need for a more grounded and cautious style to ensure success.</p><ul><li>Mark Nicholas questioned how long India can allow Pant to play recklessly.</li><li>Pant's aggressive style has often led to his downfall, as highlighted in a recent match.</li><li>Gavaskar suggests Pant should bat lower in the order if he continues to adopt this approach.</li><li>The conversation included a consensus on the need for Pant to change his batting strategy for better performance.</li></ul><blockquote>“You can’t be successful in Test cricket by going aerial... His conversation rate is not good in Test cricket.” - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote><p>Gavaskar's remarks reflect a broader concern about Pant’s ability to adapt his game at the Test level, suggesting that a more measured approach could yield better results.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/you-cant-be-successful-in-test-cricket-sunil-gavaskar-warns-rishabh-pant-of-serious-consequences/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/you-cant-be-successful-in-test-cricket-sunil-gavaskar-warns-rishabh-pant-of-serious-consequences/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PKL Melbourne Raid Highlights: PKL All Stars beat Aussie Raiders by 17 points; Joshua Kennedy, Billy Gowers shine for home team - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PKL Melbourne Raid Highlights: PKL All Stars beat Aussie Raiders by 17 points; Joshua Kennedy, Billy Gowers shine for home team</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>December 28, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Sportstar</p>
<img src="https://ss-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/awuwc6/article69036262.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Lead%20image%201.png" alt="PKL Melbourne Raid" />
<figcaption>Image from the PKL Melbourne Raid.</figcaption>
<p>The PKL Melbourne Raid featured an exhibition game where Indian legends faced off against Australian AFL pros at the John Cain Arena, culminating in a decisive 45-28 victory for the PKL All Stars.</p>
<ul>
    <li>PKL All Stars showed dominance, finishing the game with a 17-point lead.</li>
    <li>Joshua Kennedy and Billy Gowers emerged as standout players for the Aussie Raiders.</li>
    <li>The match marked the first international game for the Pro Kabaddi League.</li>
    <li>The event attracted significant attention, highlighting the popularity of kabaddi beyond India.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It’s time now for the season’s main event - the big Pro Kabaddi final between Patna Pirates and Haryana Steelers.”</blockquote>
<p>The success of the exhibition match signifies the growing interest and viability of kabaddi in international venues, paving the way for future events.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/kabaddi/pkl-melbourne-raid-live-score-top-moments-highlights-streaming-anup-kumar-rakesh-pardeep-narwal-australia-kabaddi/article69036119.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/kabaddi/pkl-melbourne-raid-live-score-top-moments-highlights-streaming-anup-kumar-rakesh-pardeep-narwal-australia-kabaddi/article69036119.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:23:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Nitish Reddy’s first-class average is 22': Sanjay Manjrekar marvels at youngster's knock - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sanjay Manjrekar Praises Nitish Reddy's Maiden Test Century</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116742818,imgsize-58154,width-400,resizemode-4/116742818.jpg" alt="Nitish Reddy’s first-class average is 22: Sanjay Manjrekar marvels at youngster's knock" title="Sanjay Manjrekar and Nitish Reddy (Agency Photos)"><figcaption>Sanjay Manjrekar and Nitish Reddy (Agency Photos)</figcaption><p>Nitish Kumar Reddy's remarkable performance in the fourth Test against Australia has drawn acclaim from former cricket stars, showcasing his ability to excel despite a modest first-class average.</p><ul><li>Nitish Reddy scored an unbeaten 105 runs from 176 balls, contributing significantly to India's total of 358/9 by the end of Day 3.</li><li>His partnership with Washington Sundar was pivotal, worth 127 runs for the eighth wicket.</li><li>Former cricketer Sanjay Manjrekar expressed amazement at Reddy's maturity, noting his first-class average of only 22.</li><li>Other cricketers, including Irfan Pathan, highlighted the historic nature of the partnership between Reddy and Sundar, which endured over 300 deliveries.</li><li>Reddy's performance provides hope for India's prospects in Test cricket.</li></ul><blockquote>“There has never been an instance where the number 8 and 9 batsman in the Indian team have played over 300 deliveries.” - Irfan Pathan</blockquote><p>Reddy's innings is seen as a significant step for Indian cricket, combining technique and determination to inspire future generations of players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/nitish-reddys-first-class-average-is-22-sanjay-manjrekar-marvels-at-youngsters-knock/articleshow/116741744.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/nitish-reddys-first-class-average-is-22-sanjay-manjrekar-marvels-at-youngsters-knock/articleshow/116741744.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['There has been no official complaint from India' - MCC CEO on Australian crowd heckling Virat Kohli - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxPVWFxdzRhNVFGdWdmN3c3LTFCNlM0TVdaa25YeElybU5UbmRtNHBZOU94SjVKQjNUVnF3cWZUVlNEMy12dHNkbkw1TzdkVDFvbmRCNDZUelNITWlNUlF4NFdEZjhuUkhVcHFpZFoyRUd5VDdIYnJ2YXBlX0VGenRaVjJ4bnV0RDNPdElyV2VaWHNsbnh5UFM4eVZFTC1FZHNFUUFqMDRJY0xBNGlGY0RSTzd3bVI0LTZXMm4yU2lOYVRYa1RKSHB0ZElkYW84Q1lVSE10U9IB3AFBVV95cUxNUmdzZWltZVVHWUd4YU9kVXpieTNKUGdWQ3RKODRfdlZzU2wzZlNvSWFCT3hDbFJ3R1pjZ0h1aktzX3RERW5QRFM3bzVmZFJ5WTBxOXNYM2ZDcGVvZ1ZhTFlVTl9Gb0NiYzF5RV94amtrNVAtSC1wWm9HOVdUd1kybWVjUVl6TTZkZGVNUmF0U05GbF9CTHRRVC1jSHFJRDVIbktsTER3S1ZKYlhDTmNzSUdkVldQOVVQWU0tS0huSEtkMk5iQmlQdXRBeWI3aV9nTXNuakczM1dfVWFx?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxPVWFxdzRhNVFGdWdmN3c3LTFCNlM0TVdaa25YeElybU5UbmRtNHBZOU94SjVKQjNUVnF3cWZUVlNEMy12dHNkbkw1TzdkVDFvbmRCNDZUelNITWlNUlF4NFdEZjhuUkhVcHFpZFoyRUd5VDdIYnJ2YXBlX0VGenRaVjJ4bnV0RDNPdElyV2VaWHNsbnh5UFM4eVZFTC1FZHNFUUFqMDRJY0xBNGlGY0RSTzd3bVI0LTZXMm4yU2lOYVRYa1RKSHB0ZElkYW84Q1lVSE10U9IB3AFBVV95cUxNUmdzZWltZVVHWUd4YU9kVXpieTNKUGdWQ3RKODRfdlZzU2wzZlNvSWFCT3hDbFJ3R1pjZ0h1aktzX3RERW5QRFM3bzVmZFJ5WTBxOXNYM2ZDcGVvZ1ZhTFlVTl9Gb0NiYzF5RV94amtrNVAtSC1wWm9HOVdUd1kybWVjUVl6TTZkZGVNUmF0U05GbF9CTHRRVC1jSHFJRDVIbktsTER3S1ZKYlhDTmNzSUdkVldQOVVQWU0tS0huSEtkMk5iQmlQdXRBeWI3aV9nTXNuakczM1dfVWFx?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli At Fault For Yashasvi Jaiswal Run-Out? Sunil Gavaskar Says "Not Really Necessary..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/virat-kohli-at-fault-for-yashasvi-jaiswal-run-out-sunil-gavaskar-says-not-really-necessary-7344012</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/virat-kohli-at-fault-for-yashasvi-jaiswal-run-out-sunil-gavaskar-says-not-really-necessary-7344012</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:24:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Sunil Gavaskar Gives Standing Ovation As Nitish Reddy Slams Historic Century vs Australia - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watch: Sunil Gavaskar Gives Standing Ovation As Nitish Reddy Slams Historic Century vs Australia</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/3qtmlku8_nitish-reddy-afp_625x300_28_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Watch: Sunil Gavaskar Gives Standing Ovation As Nitish Reddy Slams Historic Century vs Australia">
<figcaption>Nitish Reddy scored a fighting century against Australia on Day 3 of Boxing Day Test.</figcaption>
<p>Nitish Reddy scored his maiden Test century, earning praise from legendary cricketer Sunil Gavaskar as he rescued India from a tough position against Australia.</p>
<ul>
<li>Reddy scored an unbeaten 105, leading a vital partnership with Washington Sundar.</li>
<li>India finished Day 3 at 385/9, trailing Australia's 474 runs.</li>
<li>Gavaskar referred to Reddy as a future star of Indian cricket.</li>
<li>Ravi Shastri suggested Reddy should be promoted in the batting order due to his consistent performances.</li>
<li>Reddy hit 10 fours and one six during his historic innings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is the first Test hundred and he is going to score many more in the near future.” - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote>
<p>The conclusion of Reddy's performance solidifies his role as a key player for India's future in cricket, with expectations for further achievements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/sunil-gavaskar-gives-standing-ovation-as-nitish-reddy-slams-historic-century-vs-australia-watch-7349846</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/sunil-gavaskar-gives-standing-ovation-as-nitish-reddy-slams-historic-century-vs-australia-watch-7349846</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:23:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS 4th Test, Melbourne Weather Report: Rain to interrupt India vs Australia Match on Day 4? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rain Forecast for Day 4 of IND vs AUS 4th Test in Melbourne</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>The weather conditions are expected to interrupt the ongoing fourth Test match between India and Australia, raising concerns among fans and players alike.</p><ul><li>The match is currently underway in Melbourne, Australia.</li><li>Day 4 of the Test could face substantial rain, affecting play.</li><li>Fans are advised to stay tuned for updates on the weather and match status.</li></ul><blockquote>"Weather reports suggest possible rain throughout the day, which could delay the match proceedings."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, spectators should prepare for potential disruptions as rain is anticipated on the fourth day of this important cricket match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-melbourne-weather-report-rain-to-interrupt-india-vs-australia-match-on-day-4/articleshow/116740668.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-melbourne-weather-report-rain-to-interrupt-india-vs-australia-match-on-day-4/articleshow/116740668.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jacob Duffy the slayer as Sri Lanka suffer horror collapse - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jacob Duffy the Slayer as Sri Lanka Suffer Horror Collapse</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not Provided, <strong>Source: </strong>Not Provided</p><p>In a thrilling first T20I at Mount Maunganui, New Zealand overcame Sri Lanka by a narrow margin of 8 runs, marking a remarkable comeback for the hosts after appearing to be in a losing position.</p><ul><li>New Zealand scored 172 for 8, led by Daryl Mitchell (62) and Michael Bracewell (59).</li><li>Sri Lanka fell to 164 for 8 despite a strong start with a 121-run opening partnership, thanks to Pathum Nissanka (90) and Kusal Mendis (46).</li><li>Jacob Duffy played a pivotal role for New Zealand, taking 3 wickets for 21 runs, including a key over that tilted the match.</li><li>Sri Lanka's collapse saw them lose 8 wickets for just 38 runs, after looking comfortable at one stage.</li></ul><blockquote>“Sri Lanka thought they had done enough - and by all accounts they had.”</blockquote><p>The loss highlights the importance of maintaining composure under pressure in high-stakes matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2024-25-1443537/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-1st-t20i-1443543/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-2024-25-1443537/new-zealand-vs-sri-lanka-1st-t20i-1443543/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anushka Sharma poses with Nitish Kumar Reddy’s family in Australia after cricketer’s first century. See here - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anushka Sharma poses with Nitish Kumar Reddy’s family in Australia after cricketer’s first century</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Anushka-Sharma.jpg?w=640" alt="Anushka Sharma with Nitish Kumar Reddy's family" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Anushka Sharma poses with Nitish Kumar Reddy's family in Australia (Photo: MutyaluReddykaki/Instagram)</figcaption><p>Anushka Sharma has been in Australia for more than a month to support her husband, cricketer Virat Kohli, during the 2024-25 Border-Gavaskar Trophy. A photo from the Melbourne Cricket Ground showed her with Nitish Kumar Reddy’s family, where Athiya Shetty was also spotted in the background.</p><ul><li>Anushka was seen in a white top and blue jeans in the picture shared by Nitish Kumar’s father on social media.</li><li>Athiya Shetty, who is pregnant, was also present at the event, looking on during the moment.</li><li>The Sharma-Kohli family is enjoying their time in Australia with their children, celebrating milestones and personal moments.</li></ul><blockquote>“A lovely moment,” wrote Mutyalu Reddy on Instagram, sharing the heartfelt photograph.</blockquote><p>As Anushka continues her break from movies, this appearance highlights her ongoing support for her family and fellow cricketers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/anushka-sharma-poses-with-nitish-kumar-reddy-family-in-australia-9748762/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/entertainment/bollywood/anushka-sharma-poses-with-nitish-kumar-reddy-family-in-australia-9748762/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICC Awards 2024 – Cast your votes now for your favourite players - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/icc-awards-2024-cast-your-votes-now-for-your-favourite-players</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/icc-awards-2024-cast-your-votes-now-for-your-favourite-players</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:57:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>