<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:22:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker to receive Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna after week-long confusion over nomination, Gukesh among four recipients - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manu Bhaker awarded Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna amid nomination confusion</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/Paris-Games-double-medallist-Manu-Bhaker---EPA-EFE_1735809572589_1735809578932.jpg" alt="Paris Games double medallist Manu Bhaker" title="Paris Games double medallist Manu Bhaker"><figcaption>Paris Games double medallist Manu Bhaker. (EPA-EFE)(HT_PRINT)</figcaption><p>Manu Bhaker and D Gukesh are among the four recipients of the prestigious Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna Award, confirmed by the sports ministry following a week of confusion regarding Bhaker's nomination.</p><ul><li>Manu Bhaker made history as the first athlete from independent India to win two medals in a single Olympic Games.</li><li>Along with Bhaker, Harmanpreet Singh and para-athlete Praveen Kumar also received the award.</li><li>Gukesh became the youngest-ever World Champion in chess.</li><li>The award ceremony will take place at Rashtrapati Bhavan on January 17, 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“I believe there has been a lapse, possibly on my part, while filing for the nomination, which is being corrected. Irrespective of the award, I shall remain motivated to win more medals for my country.” - Manu Bhaker</blockquote><p>This year's Khel Ratna award not only honors excellence in sports but also highlights the dedication of these athletes to inspire future generations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/manu-bhaker-to-receive-dhyan-chand-khel-ratna-after-week-long-confusion-over-nomination-gukesh-among-four-recipients-101735809074039.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/manu-bhaker-to-receive-dhyan-chand-khel-ratna-after-week-long-confusion-over-nomination-gukesh-among-four-recipients-101735809074039.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:20:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir Under Scanner: Report Says "Players Insecure". After Champions Trophy, Coach May Be... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Under Scanner: Report Says 'Players Insecure'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/gu34d4qg_gambhir-and-rohit-afp_625x300_01_January_25.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Gautam Gambhir Under Scanner: Report Says 'Players Insecure'. After Champions Trophy, Coach May Be..."><figcaption>Gautam Gambhir with Rohit Sharma</figcaption></p>
<p>Gautam Gambhir, the Indian cricket team coach, is under scrutiny following a series of poor performances by the team. After his appointment, India has struggled significantly, raising concerns about player communication and team stability.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gambhir took over as head coach expecting to lead a transition in the team.</li>
  <li>The team suffered losses against Sri Lanka and New Zealand, and is trailing in the ongoing Test series against Australia.</li>
  <li>Reports indicate that players feel insecure due to constant lineup experimentation by Gambhir.</li>
  <li>There are concerns about communication issues between Gambhir and the players, especially compared to previous coaches like Ravi Shastri.</li>
  <li>With the upcoming Champions Trophy, Gambhir's position may be in jeopardy if performances do not improve.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"If the performance doesn't improve, even Gautam Gambhir's position wouldn't be safe," a senior BCCI official stated.</blockquote>
<p>This situation raises questions about the future of the Indian cricket team under Gambhir as tension mounts ahead of critical tournaments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-under-scanner-report-says-players-insecure-after-champions-trophy-coach-may-be-7383030</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-under-scanner-report-says-players-insecure-after-champions-trophy-coach-may-be-7383030</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:30:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man Utd transfer news: Marcus Rashford takes action as Ruben Amorim decides priority signing - The Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Man Utd transfer news: Marcus Rashford sets the record straight as Ruben Amorim eyes key signing</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 03:00, 2 Jan 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Mirror Football</p><div><img src="https://i2-prod.mirror.co.uk/incoming/article34396296.ece/ALTERNATES/n615/0_GettyImages-2191216187.jpg" alt="Marcus Rashford applauds the fans"><figcaption>Marcus Rashford could be on the move in the January transfer window</figcaption></div><p>The transfer window has opened, and Manchester United is preparing for changes as rumors swirl around players like Marcus Rashford and potential signings by head coach Ruben Amorim.</p><ul><li>United currently sits in 14th place in the Premier League following consecutive losses.</li><li>Rashford denies any talks with a new agency regarding his potential transfer, asserting his loyalty to his current representation.</li><li>Amorim is reportedly seeking a new goalkeeper amid concerns over Andre Onana's performances.</li><li>Casemiro may be considering a move to a club in the Saudi Pro League, with multiple clubs interested.</li></ul><blockquote>“Been a lot of false stories written over the past few weeks, but guys this is getting ridiculous - never met with any agency and don't have any plans to do so...” - Marcus Rashford</blockquote><p>As Manchester United navigates the transfer market, key decisions will shape the future of the club and its players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mirror.co.uk/sport/football/transfer-news/man-utd-transfers-rashford-amorim-34402558</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mirror.co.uk/sport/football/transfer-news/man-utd-transfers-rashford-amorim-34402558</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli Set For 'Leadership Role' In Tests, Report Says Rohit Sharma Unlikely To... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxOZXBqUXlTcTh4QWlEYzBjNklRRUZNWnNIdUdiOFRJdV9VbHBrVHBodE1DMnBEYWt0b0lVdE9PZHZEOGZGdi14c0k4UHdTdVM3NWpwaEE1cWY1eE5jaEdURGJSRW5sX3JpX3ZhaXJ3T2lManlYNlc3bzNhbUFCZEhRaC1QTGF3T0I2YWlnck1razREbVBmS25sVXo5T3o0d2NGRDV1UDl2ay10TVI3b0JUTDY0U3JJYmtFRUpPRUlxTGh0V2tFaDgzdjFOLXBtZ0ExZmU4QkdWTUFheE0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxOZXBqUXlTcTh4QWlEYzBjNklRRUZNWnNIdUdiOFRJdV9VbHBrVHBodE1DMnBEYWt0b0lVdE9PZHZEOGZGdi14c0k4UHdTdVM3NWpwaEE1cWY1eE5jaEdURGJSRW5sX3JpX3ZhaXJ3T2lManlYNlc3bzNhbUFCZEhRaC1QTGF3T0I2YWlnck1razREbVBmS25sVXo5T3o0d2NGRDV1UDl2ay10TVI3b0JUTDY0U3JJYmtFRUpPRUlxTGh0V2tFaDgzdjFOLXBtZ0ExZmU4QkdWTUFheE0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:48:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli Set For India Test Captaincy Return, Report Says Rohit Sharma Unlikely To... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli Set For India Test Captaincy Return, Report Says Rohit Sharma Unlikely To Continue</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> September 25, 2024 &nbsp; | &nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jisv815g_virat-kohli-and-rohit-sharma-bcci_625x300_25_September_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Virat Kohli Set For India Test Captaincy Return, Report Says Rohit Sharma Unlikely To..."/><figcaption>Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma during a press event.</figcaption><p>India captain Rohit Sharma is likely to step away from Test cricket following the series against Australia, leading to speculation about Virat Kohli's potential return to the captaincy role.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma faces heavy criticism for his recent performances and leadership following losses to New Zealand.</li><li>Reports suggest Rohit may not be part of India’s Test plans after the current Australia series.</li><li>Virat Kohli could be re-considered for captaincy due to a lack of confidence in younger players.</li><li>Kohli has a successful history as captain, including a Test series win in Australia.</li><li>Rohit's future as a player looks uncertain, with speculation about missing the decisive Test in Sydney.</li><li>Head coach Gautam Gambhir indicated that final decisions on team selection would be made closer to match day.</li></ul><blockquote>“Everything is fine with Rohit and I don't think it's anything traditional. We are going to have a look at the wicket and finalize (the team) tomorrow.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>The potential changes in leadership come at a crucial time for the Indian cricket team as they navigate critical Test matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/virat-kohli-set-for-india-test-captaincy-return-report-says-rohit-sharma-unlikely-to-7382290</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/virat-kohli-set-for-india-test-captaincy-return-report-says-rohit-sharma-unlikely-to-7382290</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:48:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Not Virat Kohli, Jasprit Bumrah: Video Sparks Rumour Of 25-Year-Old Replacing Rohit Sharma As India Captain In Sydney - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Not Virat Kohli, Jasprit Bumrah: Video Sparks Rumour Of 25-Year-Old Replacing Rohit Sharma As India Captain In Sydney</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-03/lbueuah_kohli-bumrah-twitter_650x400_01_March_22.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Not Virat Kohli, Jasprit Bumrah: Video Sparks Rumour Of 25-Year-Old Replacing Rohit Sharma As India Captain In Sydney"><figcaption>Not Virat Kohli, Jasprit Bumrah: Video Sparks Rumour Of 25-Year-Old Replacing Rohit Sharma As India Captain In Sydney</figcaption><p>The upcoming India vs Australia Test match in Sydney raises questions about Rohit Sharma's captaincy as he struggles with form. Discussion of a possible leadership change has emerged, with speculation about Shubman Gill stepping up.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma's future as captain is uncertain as India trails 1-2 in the series.</li><li>Coach Gautam Gambhir did not confirm Rohit's inclusion in the playing XI.</li><li>Shreevats Goswami suggests Shubman Gill may captain the team in Sydney.</li><li>Rohit struggled with runs, averaging just 6.20 in recent matches.</li><li>Akash Deep ruled out due to a back injury, but no replacement named.</li></ul><blockquote>“I just said that we're going to have a look at the wicket and announce a playing XI tomorrow. The answer remains the same.” — Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>The outcome of the Sydney Test is crucial for India's hopes of reaching the World Test Championship final, requiring a win and some favorable results from Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/not-virat-kohli-jasprit-bumrah-video-sparks-rumour-of-25-year-old-replacing-rohit-sharma-as-india-captain-in-sydney-7382755</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/not-virat-kohli-jasprit-bumrah-video-sparks-rumour-of-25-year-old-replacing-rohit-sharma-as-india-captain-in-sydney-7382755</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:46:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can Indian spinners do an Anil Kumble in spin-friendly Sydney? - SCG trivia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Can Indian spinners do an Anil Kumble in spin-friendly Sydney? - SCG trivia</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116878034,imgsize-45076,width-400,resizemode-4/116878034.jpg" alt="Washington Sundar, left, and Ravindra Jadeja" title="Washington Sundar, left, and Ravindra Jadeja are the only two spinners left in India's Test squad on Australia tour after the mid-series retirement of Ravichandran Ashwin (PTI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Washington Sundar, left, and Ravindra Jadeja are the only two spinners left in India's Test squad on Australia tour after the mid-series retirement of Ravichandran Ashwin (PTI Photo)</figcaption>
<p>India aims to end a 46-year wait for a Test match victory in Sydney as they prepare for the final match of the Border Gavaskar Trophy at the SCG, which historically favors spin bowlers.</p>
<ul>
<li>India's last win at the SCG was in January 1978.</li>
<li>They currently trail the series 2-1 after winning one match and losing two.</li>
<li>The upcoming match's result will impact the retention of the Border Gavaskar Trophy.</li>
<li>Ravichandran Ashwin's absence puts pressure on spinners Ravindra Jadeja and Washington Sundar.</li>
<li>Statistics highlight Kumble’s prowess at the SCG with match figures of 12 for 279 runs.</li>
<li>Sachin Tendulkar boasts an impressive record, averaging 157.00 at SCG.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Will one of them do a Kumble for India? Time will tell.”</blockquote>
<p>The significance of this match lies not only in historical statistics against Australia but also in the opportunity for India’s spin attack to shine and potentially reshape the series outcome.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/can-indian-spinners-do-an-anil-kumble-in-spin-friendly-sydney-scg-trivia/articleshow/116877939.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/can-indian-spinners-do-an-anil-kumble-in-spin-friendly-sydney-scg-trivia/articleshow/116877939.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's dressing room confidentiality breach an unexpected storm, 'leak' reeks of Chappell-Ganguly, Kohli-Kumble feuds - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Dressing Room Confidentiality Breach: A Storm of Controversy</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-26_1735802469820_1735802490107.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah, Rohit Sharma, and Gautam Gambhir in controversy" title="Jasprit Bumrah, Rohit Sharma, and Gautam Gambhir in controversy">
<figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah (L), Rohit Sharma (C) and Gautam Gambhir (R) find themselves in the middle of a controversy at a time when India have a Test match to win(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>In an unexpected turn of events, leaks from within the Indian cricket team following a disappointing defeat against Australia have raised concerns about the sanctity of the dressing room. This breach of confidentiality has drawn parallels to past controversies involving high-profile figures in Indian cricket.</p>
<ul>
<li>The dressing room is traditionally a private space for players to express themselves freely.</li>
<li>Recent alleged leaks come just before a crucial Test match, highlighting the timing's unfortunate nature.</li>
<li>Historical precedents show detrimental effects of such leaks on team dynamics and morale.</li>
<li>The head coach has publicly addressed the situation, emphasizing the need for honesty and integrity among players.</li>
<li>Drawing from past resilience, the team aims to overcome adversity and focus on performance.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Those are just reports. That's not the truth... Honesty is extremely important if you want to go on and achieve some great things.” - Head Coach Gautam Gambhir</blockquote>
<p>This situation underscores the challenges faced by the team but also serves as a reminder of their capacity to rally together and perform against the odds.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/indias-dressing-room-confidentiality-breech-an-unexpected-storm-leak-reeks-of-chappell-ganguly-kohli-kumble-feuds-101735802356404.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/indias-dressing-room-confidentiality-breech-an-unexpected-storm-leak-reeks-of-chappell-ganguly-kohli-kumble-feuds-101735802356404.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:28:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shubman Gill among 4 Gujarat Titans players likely to be summoned by CID in ₹450 crore scam: Report - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shubman Gill and Gujarat Titans Players Potentially Involved in ₹450 Crore Ponzi Scam</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>India international Shubman Gill is among four cricketers from Gujarat Titans who may be summoned by the CID in connection with a ₹450 crore ponzi scam.</p><ul><li>Other cricketers involved include Sai Sudharshan, Rahul Tewatia, and Mohit Sharma.</li><li>The kingpin of the ponzi scheme, Bhupendrasinh Zala, confessed during interrogation that he had not returned the money invested by the players.</li><li>Gill reportedly invested ₹1.95 crore, while the others invested smaller amounts.</li><li>Zala was arrested after being on the run for nearly a month and is currently in custody until January 4.</li></ul><blockquote>“So far, we have learnt that nearly 11,000 individuals had invested in schemes floated by Zala's firm.” - Parikshita Rathod, Deputy Inspector General of Police (CID-Crime)</blockquote><p>The case highlights the risks of ponzi schemes and the importance of rigorous financial scrutiny in investment opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/shubman-gill-among-4-gujarat-titans-players-to-be-summoned-by-cid-in-rs-450-crore-scam-report-11735800792952.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/shubman-gill-among-4-gujarat-titans-players-to-be-summoned-by-cid-in-rs-450-crore-scam-report-11735800792952.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:19:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BPL 2024-2025: Match 5, DC vs DBR Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BPL match between DC vs DBR? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BPL 2024-2025: Match 5 Prediction - Dhaka Capital vs Durbar Rajshahi</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><figure><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1735747813288_DHAKA-CAPITAL-VS-DURBAR-RAJSHAHI.jpeg" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The excitement of T20 cricket continues with Match 5 of the Bangladesh Premier League between Dhaka Capital (DC) and Durbar Rajshahi (DBR), both teams looking to secure their first win in this tournament.</p><ul><li>DC lost their opening match by 40 runs.</li><li>DBR's first game was closely contested but they couldn't defend their target.</li><li>Match details: January 2, 2025, at Shere Bangla National Stadium, Mirpur.</li><li>Pitches are better for batters initially, but expected to favor spinners as the tournament progresses.</li></ul><blockquote>Prediction: Durbar Rajshahi is expected to win today's match.</blockquote><p>The performance of key players like Yasir Ali and Taskin Ahmed could be decisive in determining the match outcome.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bpl-2024-2025-match-5-dc-vs-dbr-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bpl-match-between-dc-vs-dbr-9142/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bpl-2024-2025-match-5-dc-vs-dbr-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bpl-match-between-dc-vs-dbr-9142/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah breaks Waqar Younis's record to go top of this list - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah breaks Waqar Younis's record to go top of this list</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116876081,imgsize-49678,width-400,resizemode-4/116876081.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah breaks Waqar Younis's record to go top of this list" title="Jasprit Bumrah (Photo Source: X)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah (Photo Source: X)</figcaption><p>Jasprit Bumrah has achieved remarkable success in 2024, surpassing Waqar Younis's record to become the best red-ball bowler in international cricket. He has claimed a total of 86 wickets across formats, establishing new benchmarks for average and strike rate.</p><ul><li>Bumrah achieved 86 wickets in 21 matches in 2024.</li><li>He averaged 13.76 with an impressive strike rate of 26.9.</li><li>His performance eclipsed Waqar Younis's previous records set in 1990.</li><li>Bumrah is currently leading wicket-taker in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bumrah is the leading Test wicket-taker of 2024, with 71 wickets at 14.92 runs apiece in 13 matches.”</blockquote><p>Bumrah’s record-breaking performance has positioned him as one of the modern greats in cricket, solidifying his status as a top bowler for the Indian team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-breaks-waqar-youniss-record-to-go-top-of-this-list/articleshow/116876041.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/jasprit-bumrah-breaks-waqar-youniss-record-to-go-top-of-this-list/articleshow/116876041.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gambhir non-committal on Rohit Sharma's selection for SCG Test - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPUVFSeWEtSndJOG5LWXFQTUVjNTVPV1ZESWpybVd5TWpUSl9SODdIaFlkMDNMcXFoLW9GaVJoSmhaZTc1QXV6RFM3RkcxWUc1V0RsWFI0REtzcWNjclUxZ1VIN2YydnBubW8wVXVYUVdQTnRNdnE4S0hSdlBiYklCcm12NGFXcm0yZkdKSksxRVRZbXgzSFlJZDZ2Y0FwUTU0U19VU3FVQVpyUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPUVFSeWEtSndJOG5LWXFQTUVjNTVPV1ZESWpybVd5TWpUSl9SODdIaFlkMDNMcXFoLW9GaVJoSmhaZTc1QXV6RFM3RkcxWUc1V0RsWFI0REtzcWNjclUxZ1VIN2YydnBubW8wVXVYUVdQTnRNdnE4S0hSdlBiYklCcm12NGFXcm0yZkdKSksxRVRZbXgzSFlJZDZ2Y0FwUTU0U19VU3FVQVpyUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:52:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's Predicted XI For 5th Test vs Australia: No Rohit Sharma, Rishabh Pant? Drastic Changes Expected - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Predicted XI For 5th Test vs Australia: No Rohit Sharma, Rishabh Pant?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/92j45s0g_rohit-sharma-rishabh-pant_625x300_02_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="India's Predicted XI For 5th Test vs Australia: No Rohit Sharma, Rishabh Pant? Drastic Changes Expected"><figcaption>File image of Rohit Sharma and Rishabh Pant. © PTI</figcaption><p>Team India faces crucial decisions ahead of the fifth Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy against Australia. The match is essential for India to retain the trophy and maintain their chances for qualification for the World Test Championship (WTC) 2025 final.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma's place in the team is uncertain due to poor performance, with only 31 runs in five innings.</li><li>Shubman Gill may replace Rohit, with KL Rahul returning to the opening position.</li><li>Rishabh Pant could be replaced by Dhruv Jurel due to inconsistent performances.</li><li>Akash Deep is ruled out due to injury, possibly leading to Harshit Rana's inclusion.</li><li>Virat Kohli and Washington Sundar are likely to retain their spots despite recent form issues.</li></ul><blockquote>“If Rohit is dropped, Shubman Gill could come back into the XI.”</blockquote><p>India's Predicted XI includes Yashasvi Jaiswal, KL Rahul, Shubman Gill, Virat Kohli, Dhruv Jurel (wk), Ravindra Jadeja, Nitish Reddy, Washington Sundar, Harshit Rana, Jasprit Bumrah, and Mohammed Siraj.</p><p>Left out: Rohit Sharma, Rishabh Pant, Akash Deep (injury).</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/indias-predicted-xi-for-5th-test-vs-australia-no-rohit-sharma-no-rishabh-pant-drastic-changes-expected-7382236</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/indias-predicted-xi-for-5th-test-vs-australia-no-rohit-sharma-no-rishabh-pant-drastic-changes-expected-7382236</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:21:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BBL 2024-2025: Match 20, REN vs STR Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between REN vs STR? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BBL 2024-2025: Match 20, REN vs STR Match Prediction</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 2, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1735728162248_image_2025_01_01T10_39_13_064Z.png" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption><p>The Melbourne Renegades face the Adelaide Strikers in a crucial match in the Big Bash League. Both teams are looking for a much-needed win as the Renegades sit fifth and the Strikers at seventh in the points table.</p><ul><li>The match takes place at Docklands Stadium in Melbourne.</li><li>Melbourne Renegades have won 2 out of 4 matches, while Adelaide Strikers have won only 1 out of 5.</li><li>The predicted line-ups for both teams have been provided.</li><li>Pitch conditions are expected to favor batters.</li></ul><blockquote>"The prediction is based on the author's understanding, analysis, and instinct."</blockquote><p>The Melbourne Renegades are predicted to win if they bat first, while the Strikers may come out on top if they opt to bat first.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-20-ren-vs-str-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-ren-vs-str/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-20-ren-vs-str-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-ren-vs-str/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AUS vs IND 2024/25, AUS vs IND 5th Test Match Preview - Akash Deep and Marsh out of Sydney showdown - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Akash Deep and Marsh out of Sydney showdown</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Not Provided]</p>
<p>The upcoming Test at the SCG is pivotal for both Australia and India as they vie for the Border-Gavaskar Trophy, with notable player changes due to injuries and performance issues.</p>
<img src="https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg" alt="Story Image">
<figcaption>Image related to the upcoming Test match.</figcaption>
<p>India's captain, Rohit Sharma faces uncertainty in his role, while Akash Deep is ruled out with a stiff back. Beau Webster steps in for Mitchell Marsh.</p>
<ul>
<li>Australia has a chance to claim the Border-Gavaskar Trophy after 10 years.</li>
<li>India struggles with first-innings runs, averaging 22.40 this series.</li>
<li>Player changes: Beau Webster to debut, Akash Deep out due to injury.</li>
<li>Rohit Sharma's performance comes under scrutiny as his future in Test cricket is in question.</li>
<li>Pitch conditions at the SCG are favorable for bowlers, promising a competitive match.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>If someone had said 40-45 days ago that we would be in this situation, that we can come to Sydney and draw this series, it's a good position to be in.<br><i>India coach <b>Gautam Gambhir</b></i></blockquote>
<p>The outcome of this match could be crucial for both teams, with significant implications for team reputations and player futures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/australia-vs-india-2024-25-1426547/australia-vs-india-5th-test-1426559/match-preview</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/australia-vs-india-2024-25-1426547/australia-vs-india-5th-test-1426559/match-preview</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SCG axe leaves Mitchell Marsh's Test career at crossroads - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mitchell Marsh's Test Career at a Crossroads Following Selection Ax</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Mitchell Marsh, named the Allan Border Medalist less than a year ago, finds his Test career uncertain after being dropped for the final Test against India, with Beau Webster set to debut in his place.</p><ul><li>Marsh had limited impact in the series, scoring only 73 runs.</li><li>His reaction to the news was supportive of Webster's debut.</li><li>Marsh has struggled in previous Sydney Tests as well, having been dropped during the 2018-19 series.</li><li>He showed potential during his recent inclusion but has faltered in the current series.</li><li>Webster has proved himself in domestic cricket, prompting his selection at age 31.</li></ul><blockquote>“He was in the side this summer for being a top six batter so that's generally a guiding principle when you are picking a top order.” - Pat Cummins</blockquote><p>Mitchell Marsh's future in Test cricket now hinges on his ability to perform in future opportunities as changes are anticipated in Australia’s squad dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/bgt-aus-vs-ind-scg-axe-leaves-mitchell-marsh-test-career-at-crossroads-1467420</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/bgt-aus-vs-ind-scg-axe-leaves-mitchell-marsh-test-career-at-crossroads-1467420</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:45:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India To Axe Rishabh Pant For Sydney Test? This Star Set To Replace Him: Report - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India To Axe Rishabh Pant For Sydney Test? This Star Set To Replace Him: Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/b65radq_rishabh-pant-afp_625x300_28_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="India To Axe Rishabh Pant For Sydney Test? This Star Set To Replace Him: Report"><figcaption>File image of Rishabh Pant. © AFP</figcaption><p>India's head coach Gautam Gambhir addressed the press before the final Test, denying rumors of team discord and discussing player performance issues. He suggested that Rishabh Pant may be replaced by reserve wicket-keeper Dhruv Jurel due to Pant's recent struggles on the field.</p><ul><li>Gautam Gambhir held a press conference regarding the team dynamics ahead of the Test.</li><li>Reports indicate Rishabh Pant's position in the team is under threat due to poor performance.</li><li>Pant has been criticized for his batting decisions and has not managed to score a half-century in the series.</li><li>Dhruv Jurel could potentially replace Pant after showcasing strong performance in India A's matches.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pant came under huge criticism for recklessly throwing away his wicket.”</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the competitive nature of the Indian cricket team and raises questions about Pant's future following a historically strong performance in previous series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rishabh-pant-to-be-axed-from-sydney-test-vs-australia-report-pinpoints-criticism-factor-7381652</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rishabh-pant-to-be-axed-from-sydney-test-vs-australia-report-pinpoints-criticism-factor-7381652</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:35:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli poised for captaincy return as Rohit Sharma unlikely to continue in Tests after Australia series: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli poised for captaincy return as Rohit Sharma unlikely to continue in Tests after Australia series: Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/AP12-08-2024-000061B-0_1735795460136_1735795481071.jpg' alt='India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and teammate Virat Kohli (AP)' title='India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and teammate Virat Kohli (AP)'><figcaption>India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and teammate Virat Kohli (AP)</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team is facing turmoil ahead of the final Test against Australia, with reports suggesting that Rohit Sharma may not continue as captain beyond this series due to poor performances and unrest in the dressing room.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma's future as Test captain is uncertain following a disappointing series performance.</li><li>Reports of unrest in the Indian dressing room have surfaced amidst poor performances in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li><li>Virat Kohli is seen as a potential returnee to a leadership role, given his involvement in team dynamics.</li><li>Concerns have also arisen regarding the handling of Ravichandran Ashwin’s retirement.</li><li>The BCCI plans to review the performance of coach Gautam Gambhir and his support staff after the Australia tour.</li></ul><blockquote>“Rohit can hold off on such a decision to avoid exacerbating the already tense atmosphere in the team.”</blockquote><p>The upcoming weeks are crucial for the Indian team and the future of its coaching staff as decisions regarding leadership and team direction are set to be made.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-poised-for-captaincy-return-as-rohit-sharma-unlikely-to-continue-in-tests-after-australia-series-report-101735789872324.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-poised-for-captaincy-return-as-rohit-sharma-unlikely-to-continue-in-tests-after-australia-series-report-101735789872324.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:25:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Joshua Zirkzee makes final transfer decision as two clubs offer Man Utd escape route - The Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Man Utd star Joshua Zirkzee makes final transfer decision as two clubs offer escape route</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Mirror</p>
<div>
<img src="https://i2-prod.mirror.co.uk/incoming/article34396509.ece/ALTERNATES/s615b/0_GettyImages-2191878913.jpg" alt="Joshua Zirkzee of Manchester United heads towards the changing room after been substituted"/>
<figcaption>Scrutiny of Joshua Zirkzee's future has increased after he was substituted in the first half of defeat to Newcastle (Image: Carl Recine/Getty Images)</figcaption>
</div>
<p>Joshua Zirkzee, a £36 million signing for Manchester United, has decided to stay and fight for his position in the team, despite being substituted early in a recent match and receiving offers from Juventus and Napoli for a loan deal.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Zirkzee was substituted after just 33 minutes in a match against Newcastle, leading to speculation about his future.</li>
  <li>He was emotional after the game but insists he wants to contribute to United's resurgence in the Premier League.</li>
  <li>Both Juventus and Napoli are interested in signing him, with the possibility of a loan deal, but United may require an obligation to buy.</li>
  <li>Despite interest, Zirkzee is focused on proving himself at Manchester United.</li>
  <li>Manager Ruben Amorim has expressed faith in Zirkzee’s potential and his training efforts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I talked with Josh about that… it's important to express the message, but I'm always thinking about the team.” - Ruben Amorim</blockquote>
<p>Zirkzee hopes to turn his current situation around and help Manchester United improve their standing in the Premier League, where they currently sit at 14th place.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mirror.co.uk/sport/football/transfer-news/joshua-zirkzee-transfer-man-utd-34403918</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mirror.co.uk/sport/football/transfer-news/joshua-zirkzee-transfer-man-utd-34403918</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magnus Carlsen defends Blitz title, shares it with Nepomniachtchi; Wenjun Champion in Women’s section - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Magnus Carlsen defends Blitz title, beats Nepomniachtchi in final; Wenjun Champion in Women’s section</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://ss-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ord7b0/article69048918.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/54237875187_f3f47e7a84_o.jpg" alt="Magnus Carlsen and Ian Nepomniachtchi during the final of the World Blitz Championship 2024 in New York." title="Magnus Carlsen and Ian Nepomniachtchi during the final of the World Blitz Championship 2024 in New York."><figcaption><p>Magnus Carlsen and Ian Nepomniachtchi during the final of the World Blitz Championship 2024 in New York. | Photo Credit: FIDE/Michał Walusza</p></figcaption><p>In a historic and unprecedented result, reigning World Blitz Champion Magnus Carlsen of Norway shared the 2024 World Blitz Championship title with Russia’s Ian Nepomniachtchi on Wall Street, New York, on Wednesday.</p><ul><li>Carlsen started the final with back-to-back wins but both players ended up in sudden-death games.</li><li>After three consecutive draws in sudden death, Carlsen offered to share the title.</li><li>This is Carlsen's eighth Blitz title and 18th major championship triumph overall.</li><li>In the Women’s section, China’s Ju Wenjun triumphed over Lei Tingjie to become the Women’s World Blitz champion.</li></ul><blockquote>— International Chess Federation (@FIDE_chess) January 1, 2025</blockquote><p>The final features rematches from previous championships and highlights the competitive spirit of both champions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/chess/magnus-carlsen-ian-nepomniachtchi-share-world-blitz-championship-title-ju-wenjun-wins-womens-section-result-news/article69048298.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/chess/magnus-carlsen-ian-nepomniachtchi-share-world-blitz-championship-title-ju-wenjun-wins-womens-section-result-news/article69048298.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS: Shubman Gill's SCG Test preparation draws 'special viewers' - WATCH - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS: Shubman Gill's SCG Test preparation draws 'special viewers' - WATCH</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> NEW DELHI</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116872474,imgsize-89164,width-400,resizemode-4/116872474.jpg" alt="Shubman Gill's SCG Test preparation" title="Getty Images" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Shubman Gill prepares for the SCG Test as his parents watch on.</figcaption><p>Shubman Gill's parents were seen observing his batting drills at the Sydney Cricket Ground, where he is preparing for the deciding match of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy against Australia.</p><ul><li>India is trailing 1-2 in the series, making this match crucial.</li><li>Shubman Gill's parents, Lakhwinder Singh and Keart Gill, provided support by attending the practice.</li><li>Rishabh Pant interacted with Gill's parents during practice, highlighting team camaraderie.</li><li>Speculation arose regarding Gill's return to the playing XI after he engaged with head coach Gautam Gambhir and bowler Jasprit Bumrah.</li><li>The final decision on the lineup will depend on pitch conditions, with Akash Deep confirmed out due to a back issue.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will look at the wicket and announce the playing XI tomorrow.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>This upcoming match is pivotal for India as they aim to level the series, and Shubman's performance will be closely watched.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-shubman-gills-scg-test-preparation-draws-special-viewers-watch/articleshow/116872459.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-shubman-gills-scg-test-preparation-draws-special-viewers-watch/articleshow/116872459.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Step inside Vinod Kambli's luxurious home worth Rs..., defaulted on home loan, it can be taken away due to non-payment of Rs... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli's Luxurious Home and Financial Struggles</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> TBD<br><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/step-inside-vinod-kamblis-luxurious-home-worth-rs-defaulted-on-home-loan-it-can-be-taken-away-due-to-non-payment-of-rs-202501-1735792925.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Step inside Vinod Kambli's luxurious home">
<figcaption>Image credit: X (Formerly Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>Former India cricketer Vinod Kambli's luxurious home in Mumbai is reportedly worth over Rs 8 crore, but has recently come under financial distress due to loan defaults.</p>
<ul>
<li>The property, located in Jewel Tower, Mumbai, is home to several former cricketers.</li>
<li>Kambli purchased the house for around Rs 2 crore, which has since appreciated significantly.</li>
<li>His wife, Andrea Hewitt, revealed that their home can be taken away due to defaulting on loans.</li>
<li>They defaulted on home and car loans in 2014, leading to negative publicity.</li>
<li>The couple owes over Rs 18 lakh in maintenance which has put their housing situation in jeopardy.</li>
<li>Kambli recently received financial assistance from the Shiv Sena party amounting to Rs 5 lakh to help with his debts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We haven't paid maintenance for the flat of over Rs 18 lakh.” - Andrea Hewitt, wife of Vinod Kambli</blockquote>
<p>The financial challenges faced by Kambli highlight the often unseen struggles of public figures despite their past achievements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/step-inside-vinod-kambli-luxurious-home-worth-rs-defaulted-on-home-loan-it-can-be-taken-away-due-to-non-payment-of-rs-417633/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/step-inside-vinod-kambli-luxurious-home-worth-rs-defaulted-on-home-loan-it-can-be-taken-away-due-to-non-payment-of-rs-417633/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:54:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Trying To Almost Pick A Fight Because...": Ex-Australia Star's Strange Assessment Of Virat Kohli - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ex-Australia Star's Take on Virat Kohli's Performance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jju9ipd8_virat-kohli-sam-konstas-usman-khawaja_625x300_26_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="&quot;Trying To Almost Pick A Fight Because...&quot;: Ex-Australia Star's Strange Assessment Of Virat Kohli"><figcaption>Virat Kohli and Sam Konstas clashed during the Boxing Day Test.</figcaption><p>Former Australian cricketer Aaron Finch commented on Virat Kohli's recent performances, suggesting that Kohli thrives under pressure by provoking conflict on the field.</p><ul><li>Virat Kohli scored only 167 runs in four Tests of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy, averaging 27.83.</li><li>His altercation with Aussie batter Sam Konstas led to a 20% deduction from his match fee.</li><li>Finch stated Kohli seems to need external pressure to perform at his best.</li><li>Kohli's overall performance in 2023 has been below par, with an average of 24.52.</li><li>In the 2020s, Kohli has scored 2,005 runs at an average of 31.32 across 38 Tests.</li><li>The last chance for redeeming his performance in this series will be in the final Test starting January 3.</li></ul><blockquote>“Virat is someone who has always thrived on pressure and he has thrived when his back is against the wall.” - Aaron Finch</blockquote><p>Overall, Kohli faces considerable pressure in the upcoming Test to reclaim his form and silence critics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/trying-to-almost-pick-a-fight-because-ex-australia-stars-strange-assessment-of-virat-kohli-7379359</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/trying-to-almost-pick-a-fight-because-ex-australia-stars-strange-assessment-of-virat-kohli-7379359</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:46:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shubman Gill to return to India playing XI? India coach tightlipped over team as Rohit Sharma remains low - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shubman Gill to return to India playing XI?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116871541,imgsize-258730,width-400,resizemode-4/116871541.jpg" alt="Shubman Gill to return to India playing XI? India coach tightlipped over team as Rohit Sharma remains lowkey at SCG" title="Shubman Gill in the nets ahead of the fifth and final Test against Australia in Sydney. (Image: TimesofIndia.com)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Shubman Gill in the nets ahead of the fifth and final Test against Australia in Sydney. (Image: TimesofIndia.com)</figcaption><p>Shubman Gill had conversations with coach Gautam Gambhir and teammates, signaling a potential return to the playing XI for the upcoming Test against Australia after missing the previous match.</p><ul><li>Gautam Gambhir discussed team selection but did not confirm Gill's return.</li><li>Akash Deep is confirmed out with a back issue.</li><li>Team decision on playing XI pending until pitch conditions are assessed.</li><li>Rohit Sharma's fitness appears stable according to Gambhir.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will look at the wicket and announce the playing XI tomorrow.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>The uncertainty surrounding the playing XI reflects the team's strategy, with a focus on pitch assessment to finalize selections for this crucial Test match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/shubman-gill-to-return-to-india-playing-xi-india-coach-tightlipped-over-team-as-rohit-sharma-remains-lowkey-at-scg/articleshow/116871476.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/shubman-gill-to-return-to-india-playing-xi-india-coach-tightlipped-over-team-as-rohit-sharma-remains-lowkey-at-scg/articleshow/116871476.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Catch Of The Year": Glenn Maxwell Kicks Off 2025 New Year's Highlight Reel With One-Handed Stunner - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Catch Of The Year: Glenn Maxwell Kicks Off 2025 New Year's Highlight Reel With One-Handed Stunner</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2025<br /><strong>Source:</strong> KFC Big Bash League</p><p><img src='https://via.placeholder.com/600x400' alt='Glenn Maxwell's stunning catch' /><figcaption>Glenn Maxwell makes a spectacular catch during the BBL match.</figcaption></p><p>Australia all-rounder Glenn Maxwell showcased his brilliance with an incredible one-handed catch during the Big Bash League match for Melbourne Stars against Brisbane Heat, marking a spectacular start to 2025.</p><ul><li>Maxwell stopped a potential six with a daring dive.</li><li>He completed the catch while maintaining his balance outside the ropes.</li><li>This catch left Brisbane Heat struggling at 106/6, ultimately scoring 149 runs.</li><li>Melbourne Stars successfully chased down the target.</li></ul><blockquote>“Maxwell, like LeBron James, flies through the air and takes a catch only Glenn Maxwell could do.” — Mark Howard, Commentator</blockquote><p>Despite his brilliance in the field, Maxwell was dismissed for a golden duck with the bat. He is expected to return to the Australian Test squad for the ICC Champions Trophy 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/catch-of-the-year-glenn-maxwell-kicks-off-2025-new-years-highlight-reel-with-one-handed-stunner-7377436</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/catch-of-the-year-glenn-maxwell-kicks-off-2025-new-years-highlight-reel-with-one-handed-stunner-7377436</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 04:23:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir has serious lengthy chats with Jasprit Bumrah, Ajit Agarkar ahead of SCG Test - WATCH - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Discusses Strategy with Jasprit Bumrah Ahead of SCG Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116870769,imgsize-20252,width-400,resizemode-4/116870769.jpg" alt="Gautam Gambhir and Jasprit Bumrah" title="Gautam Gambhir and Jasprit Bumrah (BCCI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Gautam Gambhir and Jasprit Bumrah (BCCI Photo)</figcaption><p>Ahead of the crucial fifth Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy, India head coach Gautam Gambhir was seen in deep discussions with star bowler Jasprit Bumrah.</p><ul><li>The Indian cricket team is trailing 1-2 in the series.</li><li>Gambhir and Bumrah were observed discussing strategies while the rest of the team engaged in warm-up activities.</li><li>After his chat with Bumrah, Gambhir also spoke with chief selector Ajit Agarkar.</li><li>Concerns about unrest in the team were dismissed by Gambhir, emphasizing the importance of open communication.</li><li>Gambhir confirmed that discussions with senior players have been focus-driven and strategy-oriented.</li><li>Pacer Akash Deep has been ruled out of the final Test due to a back injury.</li></ul><blockquote>“Every individual understands their areas of improvement. Our sole focus has been on strategizing to win games.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>The upcoming Test is crucial for India, and Gambhir's conversations highlight the focus on teamwork and performance amidst speculation about team dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/gautam-gambhir-has-serious-lengthy-chats-with-jasprit-bumrah-ajit-agarkar-ahead-of-scg-test/articleshow/116870631.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/gautam-gambhir-has-serious-lengthy-chats-with-jasprit-bumrah-ajit-agarkar-ahead-of-scg-test/articleshow/116870631.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 03:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's unfortunate that India aren't travelling to Pakistan for Champions Trophy: Shane Watson - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/its-unfortunate-that-india-arent-travelling-to-pakistan-for-champions-trophy-shane-watson/articleshow/116870471.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/icc-champions-trophy-2025/its-unfortunate-that-india-arent-travelling-to-pakistan-for-champions-trophy-shane-watson/articleshow/116870471.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 03:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir Refuses To Confirm Rohit Sharma's Place In XI For Sydney Test, Says This - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Refuses To Confirm Rohit Sharma's Place In XI For Sydney Test, Says This</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/c8mp8qg8_rohit-sharma_625x300_31_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Rohit Sharma" /><figcaption>India captain Rohit Sharma's performance raises concerns ahead of the Sydney Test.</figcaption><p>The future of India captain Rohit Sharma in the playing XI for the Sydney Test is uncertain due to his poor form in the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Rohit has only scored 31 runs in five innings, averaging a disappointing 6.20.</li><li>Calls for his replacement have surfaced from fans and experts amid his struggles.</li><li>Gautam Gambhir, the India coach, has indicated that a final decision on the XI has not yet been made.</li><li>Gambhir expressed confidence in India’s ability to win the match and retain the Border Gavaskar Trophy.</li><li>Akash Deep will miss the Sydney Test due to a back injury.</li></ul><blockquote>“We had just one conversation in our dressing room - how we will win the next test, as it is important for us.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>The upcoming match is crucial for India to keep their hopes alive for qualifying for the WTC final.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-refuses-to-confirm-rohit-sharmas-place-in-xi-for-sydney-test-says-this-7381345</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/gautam-gambhir-refuses-to-confirm-rohit-sharmas-place-in-xi-for-sydney-test-says-this-7381345</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 03:37:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Question mark over Rohit’s place in side: Gambhir says decision to be made “after a look at pitch” - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Questions Surround Rohit Sharma's Place in Indian Cricket Team Ahead of Final Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not mentioned<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/rohit-and-bumrah.jpg?w=640" alt="Rohit Sharma and Jasprit Bumrah in practice at the Sydney Cricket Ground." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma and Jasprit Bumrah in practice at the Sydney Cricket Ground. (Express photo by Sriram Veera)</figcaption><p>Speculations surrounding the future of Indian captain Rohit Sharma have increased as the team prepares for the final Border-Gavaskar Trophy Test at Sydney. Coach Gautam Gambhir indicated that a decision on Rohit's inclusion will depend on the pitch conditions.</p><ul><li>Rohit's current average in the series stands at 6.20.</li><li>Gambhir states that the decision will be made after assessing the pitch.</li><li>Concerns over Rohit's poor form and multiple dismissals have led to questions about his place in the team.</li><li>Rohit's scoring sequence since September has been less than impressive, with low scores in recent matches.</li><li>India has a chance to draw the series 2-2, making Rohit's form even more critical.</li></ul><blockquote>“We shall look at the pitch and take a call tomorrow.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>The situation presents a pivotal moment for Rohit Sharma, with the team's chances in the series resting on the decision of the management regarding his selection.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/question-mark-over-rohits-place-in-side-gambhir-says-decision-to-be-made-after-a-look-at-pitch-9755665/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/question-mark-over-rohits-place-in-side-gambhir-says-decision-to-be-made-after-a-look-at-pitch-9755665/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 03:28:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir refuses to confirm Rohit Sharma in India XI for Sydney Test: ‘Head coach is here, that should be enough’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir said that India will announce their playing eleven after assessing the conditions and refused to state whether captain Rohit Sharma will be in it</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025<strong> Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-41_1735787965190_1735787977784.jpg" alt="Gambhir appeared in the pre-match press conference as opposed to Rohit, despite captains normally appearing for the interaction on the eve of matches(AFP)"><figcaption>Gambhir appeared in the pre-match press conference as opposed to Rohit, despite captains normally appearing for the interaction on the eve of matches(AFP)</figcaption><p>India's head coach Gautam Gambhir has not confirmed the inclusion of captain Rohit Sharma in the playing eleven for the upcoming Test match against Australia in Sydney. As Australia leads the series 2-1, there are speculations surrounding the team's performance and Rohit's form.</p><ul><li>Australia leads the Test series 2-1 against India.</li><li>The last Test was under the captaincy of Jasprit Bumrah, where India achieved a win.</li><li>Rohit Sharma has struggled with form, averaging just 10.93 in 15 innings this season.</li><li>Gambhir assures that everything is fine with Rohit and that the decision relies heavily on assessing the conditions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Everything is fine with Rohit and I don't think it's anything traditional. The head coach is here and that should be good enough.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>Gambhir emphasized the need for final evaluations on the wicket before finalizing the team, indicating that the decision regarding Rohit's placement remains open for now.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/gautam-gambhir-refuses-to-confirm-rohit-sharma-in-india-xi-for-sydney-test-head-coach-is-here-that-should-be-enough-101735787578419.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/gautam-gambhir-refuses-to-confirm-rohit-sharma-in-india-xi-for-sydney-test-head-coach-is-here-that-should-be-enough-101735787578419.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 03:24:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>