<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:36:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:36:57 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Rain Continues In Brisbane As Second Session Comes To An End - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Rain Continues To Halt Play, Tomorrow's Forecast Is...</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>Continuing rain has disrupted play in the ongoing 3rd Test match between India and Australia, with uncertainty surrounding tomorrow's weather forecast.</p><ul><li>The match on day 3 has seen multiple interruptions due to rain.</li><li>Officials are optimistic about resuming play depending on the weather.</li><li>Fans are hopeful for a clearer forecast to allow the match to proceed.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are monitoring the situation closely and hope for a timely return to play.”</blockquote><p>The anticipation for tomorrow hinges on weather conditions, which will ultimately decide if play can resume.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:10:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Big Blow To India, Pat Cummins Bags His First Wicket - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Rain Continues In Brisbane</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not provided<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p>
<p>Rain continues to disrupt play during the second session of the third Test match between India and Australia in Brisbane.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Heavy rain has affected the match schedule.</li>
    <li>Players have been waiting for clearance to resume.</li>
    <li>No play has been possible in the second session due to persistent rain.</li>
</ul>
<p>No notable quotes or statistics provided.</p>
<p>This ongoing weather issue has significant implications for the match outcome and player performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:44:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How India Can Qualify For World Test Championship Final If Gabba Test vs Australia Is Washed Out - E.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How India Can Qualify For World Test Championship Final If Gabba Test vs Australia Is Washed Out - Explained</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/65c1cp98_virat-kohli-rishabh-pant-afp_625x300_14_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="How India Can Qualify For World Test Championship Final If Gabba Test vs Australia Is Washed Out - Explained"><figcaption>Image credit: © AFP</figcaption></p><p>The race for places in the World Test Championship final is heating up. Currently, four teams are in contention: South Africa, India, Australia, and Sri Lanka. The outcome of the ongoing series between India and Australia, particularly the possible washout at the Gabba, could impact India's chances of qualification.</p><ul><li>If India wins the series 3-1, they will qualify for the WTC final without depending on others.</li><li>The game at the Gabba was abandoned due to weather conditions, and a possibility of a draw could affect the series outcome.</li><li>India's chances of qualifying depend on the results of their remaining matches and the performance of Sri Lanka against Australia.</li></ul><blockquote>If India draw the series 1-1, Sri Lanka must draw or beat Australia to keep India in the competition.</blockquote><p>The result of the series will ultimately determine India's fate in the World Test Championship.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/how-india-can-qualify-for-world-test-championship-final-if-brisbane-test-vs-australia-is-washed-out-explained-7247503</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/how-india-can-qualify-for-world-test-championship-final-if-brisbane-test-vs-australia-is-washed-out-explained-7247503</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:27:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Olmo 5, Lewandowski 3 | Barcelona 0-1 Leganes: Player ratings - Barca Universal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxPMGNXR05uNzRteFRZd0pmMU82TkxKeGZJcGhaOFNNV1pCWW1OYlFQcjRLcFRUQ0xJR0tmSEhFZDdPSHBuY29Oa0tRLUpvLW0wM2tRMlg4QXZkSDVYUGkzVUFSZWs1a2phS200SVBCVWRPLTN0UzNUUUVCbnE3RjVTUjdITnlQdzVLaW9EbGZR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxPMGNXR05uNzRteFRZd0pmMU82TkxKeGZJcGhaOFNNV1pCWW1OYlFQcjRLcFRUQ0xJR0tmSEhFZDdPSHBuY29Oa0tRLUpvLW0wM2tRMlg4QXZkSDVYUGkzVUFSZWs1a2phS200SVBCVWRPLTN0UzNUUUVCbnE3RjVTUjdITnlQdzVLaW9EbGZR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 04:16:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Mitchell Starc got rid of Yashasvi Jaiswal and Shubman Gill at Gabba - WATCH - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How Mitchell Starc got rid of Yashasvi Jaiswal and Shubman Gill at Gabba - WATCH</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> NEW DELHI <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116352047,imgsize-43418,width-400,resizemode-4/116352047.jpg" alt="Yashasvi Jaiswal and Shubman Gill" title="Yashasvi Jaiswal and Shubman Gill"><figcaption>Yashasvi Jaiswal and Shubman Gill</figcaption><p>Mitchell Starc and Josh Hazlewood dismantled India's top order, leaving the team struggling on Day 3 of the third Test at the Gabba. Starc dismissed both Yashasvi Jaiswal and Shubman Gill, contributing to India's woes.</p><ul><li>Australia scored 445 runs in their first innings.</li><li>Mitchell Starc dismissed Yashasvi Jaiswal and Shubman Gill on the same day.</li><li>Jaiswal's average against left-arm pacers is notably poor at 17.33.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah took 6 wickets for 76 runs for India.</li><li>The series is currently tied at 1-1.</li></ul><blockquote>"Jaiswal's struggles against left-arm pacers continue to haunt him, with six dismissals in nine Test innings."</blockquote><p>The match remains tense, with the series finely balanced as each team aims for a crucial victory.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/how-mitchell-starc-got-rid-of-yashasvi-jaiswal-and-shubman-gill-at-gabba-watch/articleshow/116351817.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/how-mitchell-starc-got-rid-of-yashasvi-jaiswal-and-shubman-gill-at-gabba-watch/articleshow/116351817.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 03:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Edged And Gone": Virat Kohli Repeats Same Mistakes, Triggers Epic Meme Fest - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"Edged And Gone": Virat Kohli Repeats Same Mistakes, Triggers Epic Meme Fest</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ffsnb2fo_virat-kohil-outside-off-x_625x300_16_December_24.jpeg" alt="Edged And Gone: Virat Kohli Repeats Same Mistakes, Triggers Epic Meme Fest">
<figcaption>Virat Kohli was dismissed cheaply yet again.</figcaption>
<p>Virat Kohli faced yet another disappointing dismissal during India’s tour of Australia, falling for just three runs as he chased an outside-off delivery from Josh Hazlewood.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kohli continues to struggle with his form in Australia, often getting out to deliveries outside off stump.</li>
  <li>This dismissal marks a continuation of his issues throughout the series.</li>
  <li>Despite his poor run, fans have taken to social media to humorously critique his performances.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Edged, caught behind the stumps, and gone" - cricket.com.au</blockquote>
<p>In the innings, India faced a challenging situation at 22 for three, following a strong Australian first innings score of 445.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/edged-and-gone-virat-kohli-repeats-same-mistakes-triggers-epic-meme-fest-7257914</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/edged-and-gone-virat-kohli-repeats-same-mistakes-triggers-epic-meme-fest-7257914</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 03:26:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Rain Stops Play Again As Pant, Rahul Look To Rescue India - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Score Updates</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/t5gb4i8_kl-rahul-afp_625x300_06_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates"><figcaption>India vs Australia 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates</figcaption><p>India's match against Australia has been significantly affected by rain. After losing key wickets, Rishabh Pant and KL Rahul have come together to stabilize the innings.</p><ul><li>Australia set a strong total of 445 in their first innings.</li><li>Virat Kohli disappointed again, out for just 3 runs.</li><li>KL Rahul and Rishabh Pant are currently at the crease as India faces mounting pressure.</li><li>The match has been interrupted multiple times due to rain.</li></ul><blockquote>"This Test is turning out to be a disaster for both Team India and fans."</blockquote><p>The ongoing match is crucial for both teams as they strive for dominance in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 03:10:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS: 'Virat Kohli should learn from MS Dhoni and retire' - Indian run machine flops again - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS: 'Virat Kohli should learn from MS Dhoni and retire' - Indian run machine flops again</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not Provided <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116351201,imgsize-44270,width-400,resizemode-4/116351201.jpg" alt="Virat Kohli (AP Photo)" title="Virat Kohli (AP Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Virat Kohli (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>India's star batter Virat Kohli is under fire for his poor performance following another low score during the third Test against Australia at the Gabba, Brisbane.</p><ul><li>Kohli was dismissed for only 3 runs after edging the ball to wicketkeeper Alex Carey.</li><li>This marks the latest in a series of disappointing performances, with scores of 5, 100*, 7, and 11 in the current series.</li><li>Fans are vocally criticizing his recent form, with some calling for his retirement.</li><li>Despite a century in the second Test, Kohli has struggled overall in the series.</li></ul><blockquote>Fans took to social media to express their frustration, urging the player to consider retirement.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Virat Kohli's recent performances have led to significant disappointment among fans, stirring debate about his future in international cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/virat-kohli-should-learn-from-ms-dhoni-and-retire-ind-vs-aus-gabba-test-brisbane-test/articleshow/116351170.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/virat-kohli-should-learn-from-ms-dhoni-and-retire-ind-vs-aus-gabba-test-brisbane-test/articleshow/116351170.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 03:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli blasted over 'poor, impatient' act as Sunil Gavaskar shows no mercy for reckless dismissal in Gabba Test - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli Criticized for Reckless Dismissal in Gabba Test</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-94_1734316992337_1734317006714.jpg" alt="India's Virat Kohli walks back to the pavilion. (Photo by Michael ERREY / AFP)(AFP)"><figcaption>India's Virat Kohli walks back to the pavilion. (Photo by Michael ERREY / AFP)(AFP)</figcaption><p>Virat Kohli faced harsh criticism from former captain Sunil Gavaskar for his dismissal in the Gabba Test against Australia, highlighting his ongoing struggle with wide deliveries.</p><ul><li>Virat Kohli got out cheaply chasing a wide delivery from Josh Hazlewood.</li><li>Sunil Gavaskar emphasized the need for Kohli to exhibit more patience after India's early wickets.</li><li>Kohli's recent performances have raised concerns about his batting consistency, with calls for him to learn from past greats like Sachin Tendulkar.</li><li>Current statistics show Kohli has fallen behind contemporaries in Test centuries since early 2021.</li></ul><blockquote>“If it was on the fourth stump I could understand...this was wide, on the seventh, eighth stump, you could say. There's no need to play that.” - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote><p>The scrutiny surrounding Kohli's dismissals continues, with increasing pressure on him to adapt and perform consistently in high-stakes matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-blasted-over-poor-impatient-act-as-sunil-gavaskar-shows-no-mercy-for-reckless-dismissal-in-gabba-test-101734316777660.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-blasted-over-poor-impatient-act-as-sunil-gavaskar-shows-no-mercy-for-reckless-dismissal-in-gabba-test-101734316777660.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 02:54:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Isa Guha Apologises Over 'Racist Remark' On Jasprit Bumrah, Ravi Shastri Reacts - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Isa Guha Apologises Over 'Racist Remark' On Jasprit Bumrah, Ravi Shastri Reacts</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ai3pj3v8_isa-guha-and-bumrah-insta-and-afp_625x300_16_December_24.jpeg" title="Isa Guha Apologises Over 'Racist Remark' On Jasprit Bumrah, Ravi Shastri Reacts"><figcaption>Isa Guha issued an apology to Jasprit Bumrah © Instagram | AFP</figcaption><p>The incident occurred during commentary of the third Test between India and Australia, where Isa Guha mentioned Jasprit Bumrah in a controversial manner. This led to a public backlash, prompting Guha to issue an apology on live television.</p><ul><li>Isa Guha referred to Jasprit Bumrah as a 'primate' while praising his bowling skills.</li><li>She later clarified that her remark was meant to be a compliment, stating she admires Bumrah greatly.</li><li>Guha apologised for any offense caused, emphasizing her commitment to empathy and inclusivity.</li><li>Ravi Shastri praised Guha's decision to apologise publicly, calling it a brave move.</li></ul><blockquote>A very genuine apology from Isa Guha. — Dan News (@dannews)</blockquote><p>Guha expressed hope that her comment did not overshadow the ongoing Test match and reiterated her lack of malice in the statement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/isa-guha-apologises-over-racist-remark-on-jasprit-bumrah-ravi-shastri-reacts-7257741</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/isa-guha-apologises-over-racist-remark-on-jasprit-bumrah-ravi-shastri-reacts-7257741</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 02:46:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Isha Guha apologises for calling Jasprit Bumrah 'primate', says 'I was trying to...' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/isha-guha-apologises-for-calling-jasprit-bumrah-primate-says-i-was-trying-to-/articleshow/116350682.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/isha-guha-apologises-for-calling-jasprit-bumrah-primate-says-i-was-trying-to-/articleshow/116350682.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 02:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia 3rd Test Day 3 Live Score: Rain returns as IND batters drive into AUS trap; Kohli, Gill, Jaiswal fall - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia 3rd Test Day 3 Live Score: Rain forces players off 4th time shortly after start of second session</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 16, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-94_1733656227223_1734314896681.jpg" alt="India vs Australia 3rd Test Day 3 Live Score: Virat Kohli fell to Josh Hazlewood" loading="lazy" decoding="async">
<figcaption>India vs Australia 3rd Test Day 3 Live Score: Virat Kohli fell to Josh Hazlewood</figcaption>
<p>Rain has interrupted the third day of the Test match between India and Australia multiple times, impacting the flow of play as both teams battle for supremacy in the series.</p>
<ul>
  <li>India was reduced to 22/3 at lunch, trailing by 423 runs.</li>
  <li>Virat Kohli and Shubman Gill both fell early, with poor shot selection being a critical factor.</li>
  <li>Australia scored a total of 445 runs, with Travis Head and Steve Smith dominating on Day 2.</li>
  <li>Alex Carey was key to Australia's innings, securing a half-century efficiently.</li>
  <li>Multiple rain delays have disrupted both innings, with players forced off the field repeatedly.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“One would say it is poor shot selection. You can say that they have bowled well and they have pitched it up but if you look at the three dismissals, none of them were great deliveries.” – Cheteshwar Pujara</blockquote>
<p>As the match progresses, the focus falls on India's performance in batting to recover from a fragile position.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-live-score-today-3rd-test-day-3-border-gavaskar-trophy-gabba-ind-vs-aus-latest-scorecard-updates-101734286386962.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/india-vs-australia-live-score-today-3rd-test-day-3-border-gavaskar-trophy-gabba-ind-vs-aus-latest-scorecard-updates-101734286386962.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 02:17:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sara Tendulkar spotted with this cricketer in Brisbane - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sara Tendulkar Spotted with David Warner in Brisbane</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/brisbane-test-begins-202412-1734312345.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Brisbane Test Begins">
<figcaption><h2>Brisbane Test Begins</h2><p>The third match of the Test series between India and Australia has begun at the Gabba in Brisbane.</p></figcaption>
<p>Sara Tendulkar was spotted in Brisbane with former Australian cricketer David Warner during the third Test match between India and Australia, attracting significant attention on social media.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sara was photographed at the Gabba stadium with David Warner.</li>
  <li>Even though play was postponed on the first day, Sara made headlines due to her presence.</li>
  <li>She arrived unexpectedly to watch the Test match.</li>
  <li>Sara shared her experiences on social media, including photos and videos.</li>
  <li>She was also seen with Bollywood actors.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"One particular photo with an Australian cricketer caught everyone's attention."</blockquote>
<p>This memorable sighting highlights the intersection of sports and celebrity culture, drawing eyes from fans of both cricket and Bollywood.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/sara-tendulkar-spotted-with-this-cricketer-in-brisbane-414438/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/sara-tendulkar-spotted-with-this-cricketer-in-brisbane-414438/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:46:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma's captaincy exposed again; Shastri, Vaughan baffled after Kohli placement: 'That can cost you big time' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma's captaincy exposed again; Shastri, Vaughan baffled after Kohli placement: 'That can cost you big time'</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 16, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-70_1734311384568_1734311457099.jpg" alt="India's Virat Kohli (L) and Rohit Sharma during the Test match" title="India's Virat Kohli (L) and Rohit Sharma during the Test match">
<figcaption>India's Virat Kohli (L) and Rohit Sharma look on during the first day of the third cricket Test match between Australia and India The Gabba in Brisbane(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>The second day of the third Test against Australia has once again put Rohit Sharma's captaincy under scrutiny as experts question his field placements against Travis Head.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Travis Head scores a second consecutive century against India.</li>
  <li>Former cricketers Ravi Shastri and Michael Vaughan express their confusion over Sharma's field placements.</li>
  <li>Shastri criticizes the strategy of prioritizing containment over aggression.</li>
  <li>Vaughan suggests a lack of consistent tactics throughout the match.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“When you see the field set, that can cost you big time.” - Ravi Shastri</blockquote>
<p>This match raises important questions about strategy and decision-making in high-stakes cricket as India struggles under Sharma's leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-captaincy-exposed-ravi-shastri-michael-vaughan-baffled-virat-kohli-placement-can-cost-you-big-time-ind-aus-101734311309054.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-captaincy-exposed-ravi-shastri-michael-vaughan-baffled-virat-kohli-placement-can-cost-you-big-time-ind-aus-101734311309054.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:32:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma's Captaincy In Brisbane Test Blasted By Ravi Shastri: "Worst Set Ups..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharmas-captaincy-in-brisbane-test-blasted-by-ravi-shastri-worst-set-ups-7253578</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharmas-captaincy-in-brisbane-test-blasted-by-ravi-shastri-worst-set-ups-7253578</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:08:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I'm Deeply Sorry': Isa Guha Issues Apology For Remarks On Bumrah, Shastri Calls Her 'Brave Woman' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/im-deeply-sorry-isa-guha-issues-apology-for-her-remarks-on-bumrah-shastri-calls-her-brave-woman-ws-b-9157314.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/im-deeply-sorry-isa-guha-issues-apology-for-her-remarks-on-bumrah-shastri-calls-her-brave-woman-ws-b-9157314.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Jasprit Bumrah Has Done Most Things Right But...": Ravi Shastri Gives Brutal Verdict - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxNclE0UUFudFJsbHk1SGVuTV9NZGM3a0FkeDFDeGlPQ0FzLTM4NnQ3ajAyR1phcEtxU193U251UXpsbzR6ZTlscUxwZ2J0a1J0WnJGMjBnSmU5WGhJMlJKZHZfeTBhYkJtTXE3UXo3ZnU1WlNmZ25tSDA4cmNiT21JdDlWS1E4cW5ldXAxSFVmeFdhRGhOY1JpWVRxMDdsY1draTFBYjlIVTdxenNscU90NE1VTFlORmFuOF9teDF3ZnpEaW83RHRlaHNvdEdRcHc5emlCNdIB3AFBVV95cUxOb0RiY1FsVnh5QlI1aEttMWRYalNYOXh4czg4ZVIwTDBnNE00akk3SWw2b183a3pqU3NFOWdsSVFFWFFGQlExa29RSVMzSHRvbGhFZlFVaTZQNUdBMmw3MDJad2tIY1FXMl90T0Z3c2FfMC1NTkR3SjA0Z3BPcVA4U3BvczJZNXBlV3FaMWFYUEk2X2w3VkFzVWVfRVo5bl9CQXVNQ3cyU0F0eGp4OGZfSFpZcVVKQmQ3TUl3bS1RRm1jZnhpWDhuVWdkOXhfU2RmZVpRcFBwOUczZFJf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxNclE0UUFudFJsbHk1SGVuTV9NZGM3a0FkeDFDeGlPQ0FzLTM4NnQ3ajAyR1phcEtxU193U251UXpsbzR6ZTlscUxwZ2J0a1J0WnJGMjBnSmU5WGhJMlJKZHZfeTBhYkJtTXE3UXo3ZnU1WlNmZ25tSDA4cmNiT21JdDlWS1E4cW5ldXAxSFVmeFdhRGhOY1JpWVRxMDdsY1draTFBYjlIVTdxenNscU90NE1VTFlORmFuOF9teDF3ZnpEaW83RHRlaHNvdEdRcHc5emlCNdIB3AFBVV95cUxOb0RiY1FsVnh5QlI1aEttMWRYalNYOXh4czg4ZVIwTDBnNE00akk3SWw2b183a3pqU3NFOWdsSVFFWFFGQlExa29RSVMzSHRvbGhFZlFVaTZQNUdBMmw3MDJad2tIY1FXMl90T0Z3c2FfMC1NTkR3SjA0Z3BPcVA4U3BvczJZNXBlV3FaMWFYUEk2X2w3VkFzVWVfRVo5bl9CQXVNQ3cyU0F0eGp4OGZfSFpZcVVKQmQ3TUl3bS1RRm1jZnhpWDhuVWdkOXhfU2RmZVpRcFBwOUczZFJf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:00:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘I’m not good enough': Pep Guardiola takes the blame as Manchester City lose to Manchester United - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pep Guardiola Takes Responsibility for Manchester City's Defeat to Manchester United</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/278498292_1734309950860_1734309951088.jpg" alt="Pep Guardiola’s side are fifth (Martin Rickett/PA)" title="Pep Guardiola’s side are fifth (Martin Rickett/PA)">
<figcaption>Pep Guardiola’s side are fifth (Martin Rickett/PA)</figcaption>
<p>Pep Guardiola expressed his disappointment and took the blame for Manchester City's recent 2-1 defeat against Manchester United, marking a difficult period for the team.</p>
<ul>
<li>Manchester City led the match with a goal from Josko Gvardiol.</li>
<li>Late goals from Bruno Fernandes and Amad Diallo sealed the win for Manchester United.</li>
<li>This loss signifies City's eighth defeat in 11 games, raising concerns about team performance.</li>
<li>Guardiola admitted he is struggling to find solutions and feels personally responsible for the team's struggles.</li>
<li>His recent two-year contract extension adds pressure to turn the team's fortunes around.</li>
<li>Ruben Amorim praised his team's performance and confidence in the win over City.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I’m the manager and I’m not good enough, simple as that.” - Pep Guardiola</blockquote>
<p>The defeat adds to the pressure on Guardiola as he attempts to restore Manchester City's form amidst growing concerns from fans and analysts alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/football/im-not-good-enough-pep-guardiola-takes-the-blame-as-manchester-city-lose-to-manchester-united-101734309813548.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/football/im-not-good-enough-pep-guardiola-takes-the-blame-as-manchester-city-lose-to-manchester-united-101734309813548.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:46:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Updates: Rain Stops Play At Gabba As Rohit Faces Criticism - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS, 3rd Test Day 3 Live Score Updates: Virat Kohli Forced To Bat Early As Mitchell Starc Breathes Fire</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Not specified] <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>On the third day of the third Test match between India and Australia, Virat Kohli found himself batting earlier than expected due to the fiery bowling of Mitchell Starc, raising the stakes of an already tense game.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Virat Kohli forced to bat early due to aggressive Australian bowling.</li>
  <li>Mitchell Starc showcased exceptional skills, challenging the Indian batting lineup.</li>
  <li>The live updates cover the ongoing developments as the match continues.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Starc's fiery bowling has put pressure on the Indian batsmen early on."</blockquote>
<p>The match continues to build excitement as both teams vie for dominance, impacting the series significantly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/india-vs-australia-live-score-3rd-test-match-day-3-ind-vs-aus-live-scorecard-updates-7254899</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:30:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[D Gukesh opens up on future after becoming chess world champion: 'Main goal I have had is being the best in the world' - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>D Gukesh opens up on future after becoming chess world champion: 'Main goal I have had is being the best in the world'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent, <strong>Source:</strong> Firstpost</p><div><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/12/D-Gukesh-FIDE-Singapore-1200-2024-12-d30848123a4ea8ea963c82ffa93eeaa9.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="D Gukesh opens up on future after becoming chess world champion: 'Main goal I have had is being the best in the world'" title="D Gukesh opens up on future after becoming chess world champion: 'Main goal I have had is being the best in the world'"><figcaption>D Gukesh celebrates his victory as the 18th FIDE World Champion in Singapore.</figcaption></div><p>D Gukesh has made history by becoming the youngest world champion in chess after defeating Ding Liren 7.5-6.5 in the recent FIDE World Championship. His focus now shifts toward future endeavors while he enjoys the moment with family and friends.</p><ul><li>D Gukesh won the championship with a scoreline of 7.5-6.5, clinching victory in Game 14.</li><li>At 18, he became the youngest world champion ever, breaking a 39-year-old record previously held by Garry Kasparov.</li><li>He expressed that while becoming a world champion is significant, his ultimate goal is to be recognized as the best player in the world.</li><li>Motivated by top players like Magnus Carlsen and Fabiano Caruana, Gukesh aims for continuous improvement and excellence in the sport.</li></ul><blockquote>“The main goal I have had is being the best in the world and achieving my full potential.” - D Gukesh</blockquote><p>In summary, Gukesh's triumph marks not just a personal achievement but also positions him as a significant figure in the chess community with aspirations for even greater accomplishments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/sports/d-gukesh-future-goals-chess-world-champion-13844723.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/sports/d-gukesh-future-goals-chess-world-champion-13844723.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 23:32:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Barcelona are all over the place! La Liga leaders suffer shocking home defeat to Leganes as Robert Lewandowski forgets shooting boots & Lamine Yamal endures rare off-night - GOAL English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Barcelona are all over the place! La Liga leaders suffer shocking home defeat to Leganes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>Goal.com</p><p>Barcelona faced an unexpected defeat at home against Leganes, raising concerns over their current form as they continue to struggle in La Liga.</p><ul><li>Barcelona, the La Liga leaders, unexpectedly lost to Leganes.</li><li>Robert Lewandowski failed to convert scoring opportunities.</li><li>Lamine Yamal had an unusually off night.</li><li>The defeat puts pressure on Barcelona to regain their previous form.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have to evaluate what went wrong and correct it as soon as possible,” a club representative stated.</blockquote><p>This defeat emphasizes the vulnerability of Barcelona despite their position on the league table, suggesting a need to reassess their tactics moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.goal.com/en-in/lists/barcelona-la-liga-leaders-suffer-shocking-home-defeat-leganes-robert-lewandowski-forgets-shooting-boots-lamine-yamal-off-night/bltb3df6ffdd95a9b69</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.goal.com/en-in/lists/barcelona-la-liga-leaders-suffer-shocking-home-defeat-leganes-robert-lewandowski-forgets-shooting-boots-lamine-yamal-off-night/bltb3df6ffdd95a9b69</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:37:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anushka Sharma Shares Heartfelt Reaction To Gukesh Dommaraju’s Father’s Inspiring Video; See Here - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anushka Sharma's Heartfelt Response to Gukesh Dommaraju's Father's Inspiring Video</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Anushka Sharma reacts to Gukesh Dommaraju’s father’s viral video, praising his dedication to supporting his son’s journey as the youngest world chess champion." title="Anushka Sharma reacts to Gukesh Dommaraju’s father’s viral video, praising his dedication to supporting his son’s journey as the youngest world chess champion."><figcaption>Anushka Sharma reacts to Gukesh Dommaraju’s father’s viral video, praising his dedication to supporting his son’s journey as the youngest world chess champion.</figcaption><p>Anushka Sharma shared her heartfelt reaction to a touching video of Gukesh Dommaraju’s father, Dr. Rajnikanth, who spoke about the sacrifices made to help his son achieve success as the youngest world champion in chess.</p><ul><li>Anushka praised Dr. Rajnikanth's perspective on parenting, viewing it as a responsibility rather than a sacrifice.</li><li>Dr. Rajnikanth quit his job as an ENT surgeon to support Gukesh Dommaraju's chess career after recognizing his son's potential.</li><li>Gukesh Dommaraju defeated defending champion Ding Liren to secure his title at age 18.</li><li>Anushka's recent posts indicate she balances her family life with social media, sharing moments with her children and husband, Virat Kohli.</li></ul><blockquote>“Beautiful words by a champion parent,” – Anushka Sharma.</blockquote><p>This heartfelt reaction highlights the importance of support in pursuing dreams, reflecting Anushka's values in family and dedication.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/movies/anushka-sharma-shares-heartfelt-reaction-to-gukesh-dommarajus-fathers-inspiring-video-see-here-9156985.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/movies/anushka-sharma-shares-heartfelt-reaction-to-gukesh-dommarajus-fathers-inspiring-video-see-here-9156985.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:33:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Barcelona vs Leganés, La Liga: TV & Streaming, Live Thread - Barca Blaugranes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxOblh0alJLTzY0bk9lVnRoeXdabEhkcl9TNHZJY1pRMVp0SlJBVXc2QzlmbUlKYVVKOGdycXFWcHdBQ1lwN3VrbVg0dzc0TW1ZdVI4SnpUTGRtdHludkVQMndnU1JnTHNTZXFWUHFCQVZDRjhHY2U4ZTFRYVFhRVRqMUtkcmRSTHpzMzhxeDNrb1hyaWpBTWhpdU9sM2wxdEdaaUR5SEVEU0xoOEg0ampSd1NoT3F3MXR1ZDY5S3NjZk4yOXlYV0xRZ09aTEVxa1lyTk5FeUVnVV8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxOblh0alJLTzY0bk9lVnRoeXdabEhkcl9TNHZJY1pRMVp0SlJBVXc2QzlmbUlKYVVKOGdycXFWcHdBQ1lwN3VrbVg0dzc0TW1ZdVI4SnpUTGRtdHludkVQMndnU1JnTHNTZXFWUHFCQVZDRjhHY2U4ZTFRYVFhRVRqMUtkcmRSTHpzMzhxeDNrb1hyaWpBTWhpdU9sM2wxdEdaaUR5SEVEU0xoOEg0ampSd1NoT3F3MXR1ZDY5S3NjZk4yOXlYV0xRZ09aTEVxa1lyTk5FeUVnVV8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 22:01:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man United 2-1 Man City (15 Dec, 2024) Game Analysis - ESPN India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manchester United Stuns Manchester City with Late Goals in Derby Win</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 15 Dec, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN (IN)</p>
<p>Manchester United delivered a shocking late comeback against Manchester City, winning 2-1 in a thrilling Premier League derby.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bruno Fernandes and Amad Diallo scored late goals to secure the victory for United.</li>
  <li>City initially took the lead with a header from Josko Gvardiol.</li>
  <li>Fernandes converted a penalty in the 88th minute after Diallo was fouled.</li>
  <li>Diallo then scored a spectacular goal moments later to seal the win.</li>
  <li>This marks a significant low for City, now having lost eight of their last eleven matches.</li>
  <li>United hopes this victory will boost their season as they navigate through the festive period.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>"The second half, we pressed good, we wanted to win... we showed today we can win every game and we are very happy to win today," - Amad Diallo</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In light of this match, City’s struggles continue, leading to serious questions about their form and strategy moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espn.in/football/report/_/gameId/704434</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espn.in/football/report/_/gameId/704434</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 21:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chelsea 2-1 Brentford, Premier League: Post-match reaction, ratings - We Ain't Got No History]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chelsea 2-1 Brentford: Match Reaction</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>In a challenging matchup, Chelsea secured a 2-1 victory against Brentford, showcasing their growth in confidence and consistency. Key players like Marc Cucurella and Nicolas Jackson played pivotal roles in the game.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Brentford has been a difficult opponent for Chelsea in recent seasons.</li>
  <li>Moisés Caicedo contributed significantly with his long passes despite his defensive role.</li>
  <li>Chelsea dominated possession and created several scoring opportunities, particularly in the first half.</li>
  <li>Marc Cucurella opened the scoring with a brilliant header.</li>
  <li>Nicolas Jackson, after a frustrating night, scored Chelsea’s second goal.</li>
  <li>Brentford managed a late goal from Mbeumo, adding tension to the match.</li>
  <li>Next, Chelsea will face Shamrock Rovers in the UEFA Conference League.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Carefree!”</blockquote>
<p>This match highlights Chelsea's progress under pressure, although they remain capable of improvement as they prepare for upcoming challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/2024/12/15/24321859/chelsea-2-1-brentford-premier-league-post-match-reaction-ratings</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/2024/12/15/24321859/chelsea-2-1-brentford-premier-league-post-match-reaction-ratings</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 20:57:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah Goes Past Zaheer & Ishant's Tally To Take No. 2 Position In Elite List Led By Kapil Dev - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Surges to No. 2 in India's Elite Five-Wicket Haul List</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Jasprit Bumrah takes No. 2 position in elite list led by Kapil Dev. (Picture Credit: AFP, AP)" title="Jasprit Bumrah takes No. 2 position in elite list led by Kapil Dev. (Picture Credit: AFP, AP)" loading="eager"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah takes No. 2 position in elite list led by Kapil Dev. (Picture Credit: AFP, AP)</figcaption></figure><p>Star Indian pacer Jasprit Bumrah shone during the second day of the third Test against Australia, taking five wickets for 72 runs, surpassing Zaheer Khan and Ishant Sharma to secure the No. 2 spot for most five-wicket hauls among Indian pacers in Test history.</p><ul><li>Bumrah achieved his 12th five-wicket haul in Tests, moving past Zaheer and Ishant's 11.</li><li>He dismissed notable players including Steve Smith (101) and Travis Head (152) in a single over.</li><li>Bumrah is now the leading bowler with eight five-wicket hauls in SENA countries, surpassing Kapil Dev's seven.</li><li>He has equaled Anil Kumble's tally of 49 wickets in Australia, aiming to break Kapil Dev’s record of 51 in the ongoing series.</li><li>This fifer is Bumrah's 9th in the World Test Championship, tying with Pat Cummins for the most by a fast bowler.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bumrah has displayed extraordinary bowling skills, becoming a crucial asset for the Indian cricket team.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Jasprit Bumrah's recent performance not only cements his status among India's elite bowlers but also makes him a pivotal figure in the future landscape of Test cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-goes-past-zaheer-ishants-tally-to-take-no-2-position-in-elite-list-led-by-kapil-dev-9156862.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-goes-past-zaheer-ishants-tally-to-take-no-2-position-in-elite-list-led-by-kapil-dev-9156862.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 19:31:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manchester City vs Manchester United Highlights, Premier League: Man City Stunned As Man Utd Come From Behind To Win Derby - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxPbTgwWGZXVFBhVVVrTkJtS1dfMTNWOEtKOEtfcXBYSXczN1ByRk9weEZUYjRmMm9FZUZiOE5WMDBMTWZTNlFtNG5OdTRTSzduVllERGFTX3k2V1NqZ3A5Q0NVZXV4UG9najNtLVhrVFM4RjgxcHhKSWszc0p0WG9iZjRxNlJXWlJfUS1WRGlIRGI2TUZsaW95Mmk1elZsaGpCbWdsQzFRUk05WWNJVEZzSDd5N1diWTc2V010c25lTzAzNjdBaTJ3emt6bGVZem5vU2R5UmxwempISkFUWHJNeEU4Zmd2aFZoS0RCTVVpZ3phMUxHamfSAf4BQVVfeXFMTW5Jbk83V2ZHQ2h3U3RUOFFGLXVsanJKNjhsa0YtdUZPc0lpQ0xMS2hpU0tOM1dwM1VER2FiTERTZFc4TXI0OElnZVVLM0pQU2dsRjhWQWpCN2pOZF9jUnEwS0dhSDUwUW1tUWp0Z0ZnNkdvaG5qclZVeU1CZDlqSDFLWVUxb0Q0MFNoQVhQQUo0cHZmMW0wdGFESkdlNG9PdHk5QnVRS0c0ZVQ1WlZyUEp5UjVBV09PTU1HZl92akRJb3dFUVFDMHdqTHVCRk13RXAxcVdXTl9NdjMxUmhQUjVRTFRGenRaUUgyc0NqYldOWEtCdmJQM3UzbmVPOEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9gFBVV95cUxPbTgwWGZXVFBhVVVrTkJtS1dfMTNWOEtKOEtfcXBYSXczN1ByRk9weEZUYjRmMm9FZUZiOE5WMDBMTWZTNlFtNG5OdTRTSzduVllERGFTX3k2V1NqZ3A5Q0NVZXV4UG9najNtLVhrVFM4RjgxcHhKSWszc0p0WG9iZjRxNlJXWlJfUS1WRGlIRGI2TUZsaW95Mmk1elZsaGpCbWdsQzFRUk05WWNJVEZzSDd5N1diWTc2V010c25lTzAzNjdBaTJ3emt6bGVZem5vU2R5UmxwempISkFUWHJNeEU4Zmd2aFZoS0RCTVVpZ3phMUxHamfSAf4BQVVfeXFMTW5Jbk83V2ZHQ2h3U3RUOFFGLXVsanJKNjhsa0YtdUZPc0lpQ0xMS2hpU0tOM1dwM1VER2FiTERTZFc4TXI0OElnZVVLM0pQU2dsRjhWQWpCN2pOZF9jUnEwS0dhSDUwUW1tUWp0Z0ZnNkdvaG5qclZVeU1CZDlqSDFLWVUxb0Q0MFNoQVhQQUo0cHZmMW0wdGFESkdlNG9PdHk5QnVRS0c0ZVQ1WlZyUEp5UjVBV09PTU1HZl92akRJb3dFUVFDMHdqTHVCRk13RXAxcVdXTl9NdjMxUmhQUjVRTFRGenRaUUgyc0NqYldOWEtCdmJQM3UzbmVPOEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 18:34:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maia Bouchier: from dad's couch to Test crease - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Maia Bouchier: from dad's couch to Test crease</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Sun, Dec 15, 2024, 05:54 PM | <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c587441/bouchier-became-the-fourth-pla.jpg" alt="Bouchier became the fourth player to score a century on debut for England" title="Bouchier became the fourth player to score a century on debut for England">
<figcaption>Bouchier became the fourth player to score a century on debut for England © Getty</figcaption>
<p>Maia Bouchier made a memorable Test debut for England against South Africa, scoring a century and becoming only the fourth player to do so on debut.</p>
<ul>
<li>Bouchier scored 126 runs, making her the fourth English player to score a century on debut.</li>
<li>Her score was briefly the fastest hundred for England, achieved off 124 balls, until it was surpassed shortly after.</li>
<li>She partnered with Nat Sciver-Brunt to form a significant partnership of 174 runs.</li>
<li>Her father, Anthony Bouchier, was present in the stands to witness her historic moment.</li>
<li>She expressed her pride and joy about the day and her father's emotions during a press conference.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I'm super proud of myself and I know he's proud of me, so that's all I can hope for.”</blockquote>
<p>Bouchier’s achievement marks a significant milestone in her career and adds to the growing narratives of women's cricket advancements globally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132781/maia-bouchier-from-dads-couch-to-test-crease</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132781/maia-bouchier-from-dads-couch-to-test-crease</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:55:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI in need of new treasurer as Ashish Shelar set to step down - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNSk9Cd3R4QUdtY3RBbFZSR2tWOXlNUjdfaXBMVFpoZnlVcVhVVV9GYkhQQjFWcTJQbHRRdjlXZHZvUHRwMmtQODFDWEd0aEVvekpSM0U2YUpmdTU3Y3B4MmFGVjB3OUw2RVRERXdiMkY0V3VUdmYwdThuZXAzWHJqRzRsVTBDb0hsZXJ2U3h5RFpmUTU3Sjh4clFYSHViRUN6cjJrYnBvT1djNDlH?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNSk9Cd3R4QUdtY3RBbFZSR2tWOXlNUjdfaXBMVFpoZnlVcVhVVV9GYkhQQjFWcTJQbHRRdjlXZHZvUHRwMmtQODFDWEd0aEVvekpSM0U2YUpmdTU3Y3B4MmFGVjB3OUw2RVRERXdiMkY0V3VUdmYwdThuZXAzWHJqRzRsVTBDb0hsZXJ2U3h5RFpmUTU3Sjh4clFYSHViRUN6cjJrYnBvT1djNDlH?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI in need of new treasurer with Ashish Shelar set to step down - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI in Need of New Treasurer as Ashish Shelar Set to Step Down</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Sun, Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c587438/shelar-has-been-the-treasurer.jpg" alt="Shelar has been the treasurer of the BCCI since September 2022." title="Shelar has been the treasurer of the BCCI since September 2022." />
<figcaption>Shelar has been the treasurer of the BCCI since September 2022. © Getty</figcaption>
<p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) is set to find a new treasurer as Ashish Shelar, currently in the position, will step down after taking a ministerial role in the Maharashtra Cabinet, which is against BCCI’s constitutional rules.</p>
<ul>
<li>Shelar has served as treasurer since September 2022.</li>
<li>His resignation is the second departure of a BCCI office-bearer in two weeks.</li>
<li>The BCCI constitution disqualifies individuals from office if they hold a ministerial position.</li>
<li>Shelar previously confirmed he would not be taking on a more demanding role within BCCI due to his political commitments.</li>
<li>Questions remain on whether BCCI will elect a new treasurer or if responsibilities will be delegated.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A person shall be disqualified from being an office-bearer... if he or she is: a Minister or a Government Servant.”</blockquote>
<p>This transition within the BCCI comes at a pivotal time, influencing its governance as it navigates future leadership and responsibilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132779/bcci-in-need-of-new-treasurer-with-ashish-shelar-set-to-step-down</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132779/bcci-in-need-of-new-treasurer-with-ashish-shelar-set-to-step-down</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:38:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>