<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:17:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:17:14 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slot: Nottingham Forest ARE in title race - Premier League]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nottingham Forest Emerging as Title Contenders in Premier League</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent <strong>Source:</strong> Premier League News</p><p>Liverpool head coach Arne Slot emphasizes Nottingham Forest's status as serious title contenders as they prepare for an important match against Liverpool at the City Ground.</p><ul><li>Slot claims Forest are in competition with major teams like Arsenal and Manchester City.</li><li>Forest seeks a seventh consecutive Premier League win.</li><li>The match comes four months after Forest's previous victory against Liverpool.</li><li>Nuno Espirito Santo, Forest's manager, stays focused on the present rather than future titles.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’ve always said you can judge the table best halfway through the season.” - Arne Slot</blockquote><p>The match between Forest and Liverpool is highly anticipated, with both teams showcasing strong performances this season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.premierleague.com/news/4221172</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.premierleague.com/news/4221172</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 18:09:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hobart Hurricanes v Melbourne Renegades Big Bash Tips: Renegades in for a thumping - Betting.betfair]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxOb1FaajlxTEFJNjNpczF2ZmJEbFVzNUl5NmdpXy1xRlNmVVpweEZMM0ZSQjMwS1NFb1JOQVVmQ29qcXFndnpWY29IRHJiVWM5MTJNVHZWRDNwbFdxcmdBSDlBejh6d2ttai11SHpwVDRKZTdCeUVDeTNkcThkWkw4UDNmUjh2ckhfYUpkcjRlOU1keHdWOXl2dklUUlpWWjJzSUljc0JKMWlXYlNPbUdjcWZLeUFBN2hsTVItRHZDdlVZM0dVcHplSElvVlRNZUZfaEdJMU5zMEdlUdIB4gFBVV95cUxPclJ4cXE5UzhVcVNGa1VjUkhIUXkxYWM3SklLMGdzNi1qQVNXVnhDaDBsVTItTzdZUTB6R0lkVDhkY1RIWGVQS0VUVHg4QS14emdwelFJMjRoMGdIUndqdUYyblJUNWQ4UzF1QjNaSnR5U3JxZlVPckJsTUV1Y0ZCRktvSkFUNXhuT1lBSk1YbGlNTjRPS0NUWURRQ0k0emQ5UEh5LWo0VGtoSXBQUlR4XzFNWHlRRjRaUW9PYWZRZC1adVhDVFJ2VFNnLWo5MHpYanUyWHNTcHRicU16NkF2aHFB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxOb1FaajlxTEFJNjNpczF2ZmJEbFVzNUl5NmdpXy1xRlNmVVpweEZMM0ZSQjMwS1NFb1JOQVVmQ29qcXFndnpWY29IRHJiVWM5MTJNVHZWRDNwbFdxcmdBSDlBejh6d2ttai11SHpwVDRKZTdCeUVDeTNkcThkWkw4UDNmUjh2ckhfYUpkcjRlOU1keHdWOXl2dklUUlpWWjJzSUljc0JKMWlXYlNPbUdjcWZLeUFBN2hsTVItRHZDdlVZM0dVcHplSElvVlRNZUZfaEdJMU5zMEdlUdIB4gFBVV95cUxPclJ4cXE5UzhVcVNGa1VjUkhIUXkxYWM3SklLMGdzNi1qQVNXVnhDaDBsVTItTzdZUTB6R0lkVDhkY1RIWGVQS0VUVHg4QS14emdwelFJMjRoMGdIUndqdUYyblJUNWQ4UzF1QjNaSnR5U3JxZlVPckJsTUV1Y0ZCRktvSkFUNXhuT1lBSk1YbGlNTjRPS0NUWURRQ0k0emQ5UEh5LWo0VGtoSXBQUlR4XzFNWHlRRjRaUW9PYWZRZC1adVhDVFJ2VFNnLWo5MHpYanUyWHNTcHRicU16NkF2aHFB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:45:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma set to practice with Mumbai Ranji team - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxQeUk2TlhGd01CbjNJeTZMZ0NzWmZMdDladEpxRm9nVk5MWG9nbHlqNUllMkV0TkhlWUwzbzVDVGR0WmFEUmRZRW1XS1FyLVZYLTFnVU5JQkcwYTZNckxTUk1YWmFXYVZkYWMtNkNPczRfSFA5ZWx5TmpzLU9TMmlQeURlWDhfY2V6M3ByZG9KXzF4VnlmQTRHYUFrVlZmd2M5SVRROEtqeXV6dkVIak9iV1dTdzlGRlNqSkU4LUdpSXlZdXBlcUQ1bG9BQUMyUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizgFBVV95cUxQeUk2TlhGd01CbjNJeTZMZ0NzWmZMdDladEpxRm9nVk5MWG9nbHlqNUllMkV0TkhlWUwzbzVDVGR0WmFEUmRZRW1XS1FyLVZYLTFnVU5JQkcwYTZNckxTUk1YWmFXYVZkYWMtNkNPczRfSFA5ZWx5TmpzLU9TMmlQeURlWDhfY2V6M3ByZG9KXzF4VnlmQTRHYUFrVlZmd2M5SVRROEtqeXV6dkVIak9iV1dTdzlGRlNqSkU4LUdpSXlZdXBlcUQ1bG9BQUMyUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 17:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma to turn up for Mumbai Ranji Trophy practice on Tuesday - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma to Participate in Mumbai Ranji Trophy Practice</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Rohit-Sharma-MCG.jpg?w=640" alt="Rohit Sharma, MCG," width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Rohit Sharma watches the ball during play on the last day of the fourth cricket test between Australia and India at the Melbourne Cricket Ground.</figcaption>
<p>Indian captain Rohit Sharma has announced his intention to join the Mumbai Ranji Trophy practice session at Wankhede Stadium.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sharma resumed training to prepare for the upcoming Champions Trophy.</li>
  <li>He has not yet confirmed his availability for the next Ranji Trophy match against Jammu & Kashmir.</li>
  <li>His last match for the Mumbai team was in 2015, before struggling during the recent Test series in Australia.</li>
  <li>Indian team coach Gautam Gambhir emphasized the importance of playing domestic cricket.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If you don’t give importance to domestic cricket, you will never get the desired players that you want in Test cricket.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming Ranji Trophy round begins on January 23, raising questions about other star players' participation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-mumbai-ranji-trophy-practice-on-tuesday-9777113/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/rohit-sharma-mumbai-ranji-trophy-practice-on-tuesday-9777113/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:28:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Squad For Champions Trophy: Out Of Favour Star, Axed From BCCI Contracts, Makes Surprise Entry.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Squad For Champions Trophy: Out Of Favour Star, Axed From BCCI Contracts, Makes Surprise Entry In Spot Race</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not mentioned &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c8e35v08_ishan-kishan_625x300_03_November_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="India Squad For Champions Trophy: Out Of Favour Star, Axed From BCCI Contracts, Makes Surprise Entry In Spot Race">
<figcaption>File photo of the India A squad in the Australia Tour © AFP</figcaption>
<p>The Indian cricket team is preparing for the Champions Trophy, with significant discussions expected on player selections, particularly for the wicketkeeper and wrist spinner positions.</p>
<ul>
<li>KL Rahul is not likely to continue as the primary keeper moving forward.</li>
<li>Rishabh Pant remains the first choice for the wicketkeeping position.</li>
<li>Dhruv Jurel, Ishan Kishan, and Sanju Samson are in contention for the second keeper spot, with Jurel currently leading.</li>
<li>Kishan has faced challenges after missing domestic cricket and losing his BCCI contract.</li>
<li>Kuldeep Yadav's fitness is a concern for the team, and Varun Chakravarthy and Ravi Bishnoi are contenders to fill his role.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>Ishan Kishan has played 27 ODIs with 933 runs, but his recent form raises concerns about his future in the squad.</p></blockquote>
<p>The outcomes of the selection committee's meeting will shape the team dynamics ahead of the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/india-squad-for-champions-trophy-out-of-favour-ishan-kishan-who-lost-bcci-contract-makes-surprise-entry-for-spot-report-7466087</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/india-squad-for-champions-trophy-out-of-favour-ishan-kishan-who-lost-bcci-contract-makes-surprise-entry-for-spot-report-7466087</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 16:04:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kapil Dev Reacts to Yograj Singh's Claim Of Gun Threat: 'Kaun Hai? Kiski Baat Kar Rahe Ho?' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/kapil-dev-reacts-to-yograj-singhs-claim-of-gun-threat-kaun-hai-kiski-baat-kar-rahe-ho-9187649.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/kapil-dev-reacts-to-yograj-singhs-claim-of-gun-threat-kaun-hai-kiski-baat-kar-rahe-ho-9187649.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:42:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah "Would Have F****** Ripped On Don Bradman's...": India Star Receives Ultimate Praise .. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah "Would Have F****** Ripped On Don Bradman's...": India Star Receives Ultimate Praise From Greats</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/kjv5sb58_don-bradman-jasprit-bumrah_625x300_13_January_25.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Jasprit Bumrah and Don Bradman"><figcaption>File photo of Jasprit Bumrah and Don Bradman © AFP</figcaption><p>Jasprit Bumrah has been praised by cricket greats for his remarkable bowling performance during the India vs Australia series, leading to discussions about his potential impact on the game.</p><ul><li>Bumrah took 32 wickets in five Tests against Australia with an average of 13.06.</li><li>His strike-rate of 28.3 is noted as impressive.</li><li>Former players Adam Gilchrist and Michael Vaughan commended Bumrah's skills on a podcast.</li><li>Gilchrist referred to Bumrah's performance as 'infinity and beyond'.</li><li>Bumrah's injury concerns may affect his availability for the upcoming Champions Trophy.</li></ul><blockquote>"Sport cannot have a reward that's high enough for him," said Adam Gilchrist.</blockquote><p>This recognition reinforces Bumrah’s status as one of the leading pacers in cricket, though his injury presents challenges ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-would-have-ripped-on-don-bradmans-india-star-receives-ultimate-praise-from-greats-7465801</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-would-have-ripped-on-don-bradmans-india-star-receives-ultimate-praise-from-greats-7465801</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:26:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Anderson to play the 2025 season with Lancashire - Lancashire Cricket Club]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNbF9qRmlSV2luNTJCVk5VUVVnRjBkOVluN0lvV0hrZ2toREVMaGwwSkgtb1A1N2FxamkzQTRETWItVGtObXJuYkl5amRaek9xMUtudDYwMGxpUHRqZ2pIbGI4bDBWaEdzdXVDRDhwSUNmVjIyb21OblpWRWRQbFFhNjBwRUxhNlJTWFAyQnhPcmhKVk50VEFDVjN5elo3OFg1QktzaEdVamdRWHlZNExN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNbF9qRmlSV2luNTJCVk5VUVVnRjBkOVluN0lvV0hrZ2toREVMaGwwSkgtb1A1N2FxamkzQTRETWItVGtObXJuYkl5amRaek9xMUtudDYwMGxpUHRqZ2pIbGI4bDBWaEdzdXVDRDhwSUNmVjIyb21OblpWRWRQbFFhNjBwRUxhNlJTWFAyQnhPcmhKVk50VEFDVjN5elo3OFg1QktzaEdVamdRWHlZNExN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:56:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Virat Kohli didn’t like him’: Robin Uthappa reveals Ambati Rayudu’s snub from 2019 ODI World Cup - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Virat Kohli didn’t like him’: Robin Uthappa reveals Ambati Rayudu’s snub from 2019 ODI World Cup</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Ambati-Rayudu.jpg?w=640" alt="Former India cricketer Ambati Rayudu. (Express File)" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Former India cricketer Ambati Rayudu. (Express File)</figcaption><p>Robin Uthappa criticizes Virat Kohli for excluding Ambati Rayudu from the 2019 ODI World Cup squad, highlighting the emotional impact of the decision.</p><ul><li>Uthappa claims Kohli's preference caused Rayudu to be overlooked.</li><li>World Cup clothing and kits were sent to Rayudu’s home before the decision.</li><li>Uthappa contrasts Kohli's leadership with Rohit Sharma's empathetic approach.</li><li>Uthappa emphasizes the psychology of players and the importance of communication in leadership.</li></ul><blockquote>“You are shattering someone’s confidence. Anyone deserves that basic communication.”</blockquote><p>The article reveals the complexities of team selection and the personal toll it can take on players, underscoring the importance of empathetic leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/virat-kohli-didnt-liked-ambati-rayudu-robin-uthappa-2019-odi-world-cup-9776067/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/virat-kohli-didnt-liked-ambati-rayudu-robin-uthappa-2019-odi-world-cup-9776067/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Irwansyah in charge of women shuttlers, BAI to hire separate men’s coach - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Irwansyah Adi Pratama has been appointed coach for India's women's badminton team, including PV Sindhu, as BAI focuses on group training for improvement</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/India-s-PV-Sindhu-will-train-under-Indonesian-coac_1736780325119.jpg" alt="India's PV Sindhu will train under Indonesian coach Irwansyah Adi Pratama. (PTI)"><figcaption>India's PV Sindhu will train under Indonesian coach Irwansyah Adi Pratama. (PTI)</figcaption><p>Irwansyah Adi Pratama has taken over as the coach of Indian women’s badminton team, including star player PV Sindhu, aiming for improvement through group training at the national camp in Bengaluru.</p><ul><li>Irwansyah will only coach the women players.</li><li>BAI plans to hire another foreign coach for the men's singles group.</li><li>Indian coaches, including former players, will also be involved in training.</li><li>Irwansyah has replaced Agus Dwi Santoso following his fallout with PBSI.</li><li>The initiative follows a disappointing performance at the Paris Olympics, where Indian players failed to win any medals.</li></ul><blockquote>“It will be like a conference where they are also improving and so am I competing against each other,” said Sindhu.</blockquote><p>This coaching change aims to revitalize Indian women's badminton and enhance competitiveness through collaborative training methods.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/badminton/irwansyah-in-charge-of-women-shuttlers-bai-to-hire-separate-men-s-coach-101736779547522.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/badminton/irwansyah-in-charge-of-women-shuttlers-bai-to-hire-separate-men-s-coach-101736779547522.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:45:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delhi's Anuj Rawat In Trouble After Skipping Ranji Camp To Attend Gujarat Titans Net Session - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anuj Rawat Faces Backlash for Prioritizing IPL Over Ranji Camp</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Gujarat Titans batters in the nets (GT)"><figcaption>Gujarat Titans batters in the nets (GT)</figcaption><p>The incident involving Anuj Rawat, Delhi's senior wicketkeeper-batter, has raised questions about player priorities in cricket as he attended an IPL training session over a crucial Ranji Trophy camp.</p><ul><li>Anuj Rawat skipped the ongoing Ranji Trophy camp to attend Gujarat Titans' training session.</li><li>The BCCI emphasizes the importance of red-ball cricket during the season.</li><li>There is no record of Rawat seeking permission from the Delhi and District Cricket Association (DDCA) to miss the camp.</li><li>Relevant individuals, including DDCA officials, have expressed their discontent over his decision.</li><li>Previously, players who prioritized IPL over domestic commitments faced repercussions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ideally, he needs to take permission from the state association.” - DDCA Secretary Ashok Sharma</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the ongoing tension between domestic cricket obligations and lucrative IPL commitments, emphasizing the need for clear communication and prioritization among players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/delhis-anuj-rawat-in-trouble-after-skipping-ranji-camp-to-attend-gujarat-titans-net-session-9187615.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/delhis-anuj-rawat-in-trouble-after-skipping-ranji-camp-to-attend-gujarat-titans-net-session-9187615.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:42:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli's Video Made PV Sindhu Emotional, Olympic Medallist Says: "Don't Spend..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu's Emotional Response to Vinod Kambli's Viral Video</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV India</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/j2qblvag_vinod-kambli-pv-sindhu_625x300_13_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Vinod Kambli and PV Sindhu"/><figcaption>Vinod Kambli with PV Sindhu</figcaption><p>Former cricketer Vinod Kambli has made headlines recently due to videos showcasing his deteriorating health, which prompted Olympic medallist PV Sindhu to share essential financial advice for athletes.</p><ul><li>Vinod Kambli appeared frail in videos shared on social media.</li><li>Kambli struggled to stand during a memorial for their mentor Ramakant Achrekar.</li><li>He was later hospitalized due to health issues.</li><li>PV Sindhu emphasized the importance of financial management for athletes.</li><li>Sindhu expressed that having guidance in financial matters is crucial.</li></ul><blockquote>“You have to invest and take care of your money and not spend lavishly,” said Sindhu.</blockquote><p>This moment highlights the importance of financial literacy and support systems for athletes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/badminton/vinod-kamblis-video-made-pv-sindhu-emotional-olympic-medallist-says-dont-spend-7465346</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/badminton/vinod-kamblis-video-made-pv-sindhu-emotional-olympic-medallist-says-dont-spend-7465346</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 14:22:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shreyas Iyer 'Ready To Bat Anywhere', Says 'It Will Be A Proud Moment For Me If...' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shreyas Iyer 'Ready To Bat Anywhere', Says 'It Will Be A Proud Moment For Me If...'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Shreyas Iyer is all set to play for India in ICC Champions Trophy 2025. (Picture Credit: PTI)"><figcaption>Shreyas Iyer is all set to play for India in ICC Champions Trophy 2025. (Picture Credit: PTI)</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) is preparing to announce India’s squad for the ICC Champions Trophy 2025. Shreyas Iyer, a standout player from the ODI World Cup 2023, expressed his readiness to bat anywhere in the order, highlighting the pride he would feel if selected.</p><ul><li>Iyer has played 62 ODIs since his debut in December 2017, scoring 2421 runs.</li><li>He scored 530 runs in the 2023 ODI World Cup, averaging 66.25.</li><li>Iyer's contributions in the World Cup included two centuries and three fifties.</li><li>He is set to play for Punjab Kings in IPL 2025 after being bought for Rs 26.75 crore.</li><li>Iyer aims to play as an anchor batsman for Punjab Kings, batting at No. 3.</li></ul><blockquote>“Absolutely. I’m flexible and ready to bat anywhere in the batting order. [...] It will be a proud moment for me if I were to be picked in the Champions Trophy,” Iyer stated.</blockquote><p>Iyer's flexibility and past performance make him a strong candidate for the Champions Trophy, and his upcoming role in IPL 2025 is anticipated to be pivotal for his franchise.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/shreyas-iyer-ready-to-bat-anywhere-says-it-will-be-a-proud-moment-for-me-if-9186866.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/shreyas-iyer-ready-to-bat-anywhere-says-it-will-be-a-proud-moment-for-me-if-9186866.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:56:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Don't compare me with Jasprit Bumrah': Kapil Dev gives verdict on workload management - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Don't compare me with Jasprit Bumrah: Kapil Dev gives verdict on workload management</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117208265,imgsize-21430,width-400,resizemode-4/117208265.jpg" alt="Jasprit Bumrah (Getty Images)" title="'Don't compare me with Jasprit Bumrah': Kapil Dev gives verdict on workload management" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah (Getty Images)</figcaption><p>Kapil Dev, the former Indian cricket captain, emphasizes the differences in cricket across eras when discussing Jasprit Bumrah's workload management issues.</p><ul><li>Kapil Dev highlights the futility of comparing players from different eras.</li><li>He notes modern players score significantly more runs than in his time.</li><li>Balwinder Sandhu criticizes the concept of workload management, arguing it’s a modern invention.</li><li>Bumrah's recent injury raises questions about his fitness ahead of the Champions Trophy.</li><li>Kapil Dev promotes patience for new cricket captains amid workload discussions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Please do not compare (me with Bumrah); you cannot compare one generation with another.” - Kapil Dev</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the discussion around workload management in cricket remains contentious, with differing views on the demands placed on modern players compared to their predecessors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/dont-compare-me-with-jasprit-bumrah-kapil-dev-gives-verdict-on-workload-management/articleshow/117208283.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/dont-compare-me-with-jasprit-bumrah-kapil-dev-gives-verdict-on-workload-management/articleshow/117208283.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Bumrah would have ripped on Bradman in matter of balls’: Gilchrist, Vaughan bold assessment in ‘10/10’ remark - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Bumrah would have ripped on Bradman in matter of balls’: Gilchrist, Vaughan bold assessment in ‘10/10’ remark</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 07:20 PM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-17_1736775941155_1736775958977.jpg" alt="India's Jasprit Bumrah celebrates a successful caught-behind appeal.(AFP)"><figcaption>India's Jasprit Bumrah celebrates a successful caught-behind appeal.(AFP)</figcaption><p>Cricket legends Adam Gilchrist and Michael Vaughan have given their high praise to Indian pacer Jasprit Bumrah after his outstanding performance in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy against Australia.</p><ul><li>Jasprit Bumrah took 32 wickets in nine innings, leading India as a standby skipper.</li><li>Despite Bumrah's efforts, India lost the series 1-3.</li><li>Gilchrist claimed that Bumrah would have succeeded against legendary batsman Don Bradman.</li><li>Vaughan gave Bumrah a perfect score of 10 out of 10, acknowledging his exceptional skill.</li><li>Bumrah has made history in ODI and T20 formats, achieving multiple records including being ranked number one bowler in ICC rankings across all formats.</li></ul><blockquote>“I would give Donald 35 out of Bumrah. You cannot have a reward that’s high enough for him.” - Adam Gilchrist</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Bumrah's remarkable achievements and recent series performance have not gone unnoticed, further solidifying his status as one of the best bowlers in cricket history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/bumrah-would-have-ripped-on-bradman-in-matter-of-balls-gilchrist-vaughan-bold-assessment-in-10-10-remark-101736775756135.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/bumrah-would-have-ripped-on-bradman-in-matter-of-balls-gilchrist-vaughan-bold-assessment-in-10-10-remark-101736775756135.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:50:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-India Coach Accused Of 'Leaking Information', Found 'Resistance From Seniors', Did Not Respect In.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/ex-india-coach-greg-chappell-accused-of-leaking-information-found-resistance-from-seniors-did-not-respect-indian-culture-7464824</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/ex-india-coach-greg-chappell-accused-of-leaking-information-found-resistance-from-seniors-did-not-respect-indian-culture-7464824</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 13:14:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Punjab Kings' Announcement Makes Shreyas Iyer 1st Indian Captain In IPL History To... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Punjab Kings' Announcement Makes Shreyas Iyer 1st Indian Captain In IPL History To...</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/q2pa66u_shreyas-iyer-x-punjabkingsipl_625x300_13_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Punjab Kings' Announcement Makes Shreyas Iyer 1st Indian Captain In IPL History To..."><figcaption>Shreyas Iyer in Punjab Kings' jersey. © X/@PunjabKingsIPL</figcaption><p>Shreyas Iyer has been named the captain of Punjab Kings (PBKS) for the upcoming IPL season, marking a historic achievement as he becomes the first Indian captain to lead three different franchises in IPL history.</p><ul><li>Iyer was bought for a record-breaking Rs 26.75 crore.</li><li>He previously led Kolkata Knight Riders to an IPL title.</li><li>Iyer will work with coach Ricky Ponting again at PBKS.</li><li>He is now the first Indian to captain PBKS, Delhi Capitals, and Kolkata Knight Riders.</li><li>In 2024, Iyer also led Mumbai to their second Syed Mushtaq Ali trophy.</li></ul><blockquote>"I am honoured that the team has reposed its faith in me. I hope to repay the faith shown by the management to deliver our maiden title." — Shreyas Iyer</blockquote><p>This appointment signifies a new chapter for Iyer and Punjab Kings as they look to make a strong impact in the upcoming season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/ipl-2025/pbks-announcement-makes-shreyas-iyer-1st-india-captain-in-ipl-history-to-7464534</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/ipl-2025/pbks-announcement-makes-shreyas-iyer-1st-india-captain-in-ipl-history-to-7464534</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:34:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karun Nair’s mystery India exile explained by Virat Kohli’s ex-teammate, uses R Ashwin’s WTC Final snubs as example - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karun Nair’s mystery India exile explained by Virat Kohli’s ex-teammate, uses R Ashwin’s WTC Final snubs as example</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/PTI11-15-2024-000224A-0_1736771384158_1736771406548.jpg" alt="Vidarbha's Karun Nair celebrates a century.(PTI)" title="Vidarbha's Karun Nair celebrates a century.(PTI)">
<figcaption>Vidarbha's Karun Nair celebrates a century.(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Karun Nair, a well-known name in Indian cricket, continues to raise questions regarding his absence in the international sphere despite notable domestic performances. He has recently caught the attention of selectors after scoring 664 runs in the Vijay Hazare Trophy.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nair scored 112*, 44*, 163*, 111*, 112*, 122* in the tournament.</li>
  <li>He made his international debut in 2016 and scored a triple century in his third Test match.</li>
  <li>After only six Tests, he was dropped from the squad in 2017.</li>
  <li>Former player Robin Uthappa criticized the selection committee's decisions regarding players like Nair and R Ashwin.</li>
  <li>The article discusses cultural politics affecting team selections in Indian cricket.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If you are not going to let him play, then why are you promising him... Just tell him that you don’t believe that he can succeed in international cricket.” - Robin Uthappa</blockquote>
<p>This article sheds light on the selection politics in Indian cricket and calls attention to the need for change in the approach towards talented players like Karun Nair.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/karun-nair-s-mystery-india-exile-explained-by-virat-kohli-s-ex-teammate-uses-r-ashwin-s-wtc-final-snubs-as-example-101736771158229.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/karun-nair-s-mystery-india-exile-explained-by-virat-kohli-s-ex-teammate-uses-r-ashwin-s-wtc-final-snubs-as-example-101736771158229.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:31:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As it prepares to host 2034 FIFA World Cup, Saudi Arabia can take a cue from Qatar in how to deal with women fans - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saudi Arabia's 2034 FIFA World Cup: Lessons from Qatar on Welcoming Women Fans</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/FIFA-World-Cup-2026.jpg?w=640" alt="FIFA World Cup 2034" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Argentina players celebrate with the trophy after winning the World Cup (Reuters)</figcaption><p>This article discusses the importance of accommodating women fans at sporting events, using the upcoming 2034 FIFA World Cup in Saudi Arabia and the experiences of Qatar as a backdrop.</p><ul><li>The Iranian film Offside highlights the struggles of female fans in the Middle East.</li><li>Women were only permitted to enter football stadiums in Iran in 2023 after years of restrictions.</li><li>Saudi Arabia can learn from Qatar’s approach in allowing greater access for female fans during events.</li></ul><blockquote>“In December 2023, 3,000 women swarmed into the stands of the suitably-title Azadi Stadium.”</blockquote><p>As Saudi Arabia prepares for the World Cup, ensuring the inclusion of women fans will be crucial for creating a welcoming atmosphere.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/football/2034-fifa-world-cup-saudi-arabia-can-take-a-cue-from-qatar-in-how-to-deal-with-women-fans-9775723/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/football/2034-fifa-world-cup-saudi-arabia-can-take-a-cue-from-qatar-in-how-to-deal-with-women-fans-9775723/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 12:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australian Open 2025: Novak Djokovic survives Nishesh Basavareddy scare in first round, set to face Jaime Faria next - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australian Open 2025: Novak Djokovic survives Nishesh Basavareddy scare in first round, set to face Jaime Faria next</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Monday, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>24-time champion Novak Djokovic started his Australian Open 2025 campaign with a comeback victory against USA's Nishesh Basavareddy. After losing the first set, Djokovic prevails with scores of 4-6, 6-3, 6-4, 6-2, and is set to face Jamie Faria in the second round.</p><ul><li>Djokovic encountered a rough start, dropping the first set to Basavareddy.</li><li>The Serbian delivered 22 aces against Basavareddy's four.</li><li>In the next round, Djokovic will play against Portugal's Jaime Faria.</li><li>Other notable matches included Jannik Sinner's victory and Alex Michelsen's upset win over Stefanos Tsitsipas.</li></ul><blockquote>“He delivered 22 aces in response to Basavareddy's four.”</blockquote><p>Djokovic's performance sets the tone for his pursuit of a record 25th Grand Slam title, as he advances to the second round of the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/tennis-news/australian-open-2025-novak-djokovic-survives-nishesh-basavareddy-scare-in-first-round-set-to-face-jaime-faria-next-11736768627476.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/tennis-news/australian-open-2025-novak-djokovic-survives-nishesh-basavareddy-scare-in-first-round-set-to-face-jaime-faria-next-11736768627476.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:54:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Virat Kohli didn’t liked him’: Robin Uthappa reveals Ambati Rayudu’s snub from 2019 ODI World Cup - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Virat Kohli didn’t like him’: Robin Uthappa reveals Ambati Rayudu’s snub from 2019 ODI World Cup</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Ambati-Rayudu.jpg?w=640" alt="Former India cricketer Ambati Rayudu. (Express File)" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Former India cricketer Ambati Rayudu. (Express File)</figcaption><p>In a recent interview, former cricketer Robin Uthappa criticized Virat Kohli for his role in the exclusion of Ambati Rayudu from the 2019 ODI World Cup squad.</p><ul><li>Uthappa claims Kohli ‘shut the door’ on Rayudu before the World Cup squad announcement.</li><li>Rayudu was sent World Cup gear, creating false hope before being left out.</li><li>Uthappa highlighted the negative impact of such decisions on a player's mental health.</li><li>The interview contrasted Kohli's leadership with that of Rohit Sharma.</li></ul><blockquote>“You have to understand that these are things that impact the mindset, the mentality... a human being for a really long time.”</blockquote><p>This revelation emphasizes the importance of communication and empathetic leadership in sports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/virat-kohli-didnt-liked-ambati-rayudu-robin-uthappa-2019-odi-world-cup-9776067/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/virat-kohli-didnt-liked-ambati-rayudu-robin-uthappa-2019-odi-world-cup-9776067/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PV Sindhu gets 'emotional' seeing Vinod Kambli's video: 'Take care of money, don't spend lavishly' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu Gets Emotional Over Vinod Kambli's Video: A Call for Financial Caution</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 06:59 PM IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/12345678_1736767841010_1736767858541.jpg" alt="PV Sindhu admitted to feeling emotional after seeing Vinod Kambli's viral video.(PTI/ANI)" title="PV Sindhu admitted to feeling emotional after seeing Vinod Kambli's viral video.(PTI/ANI)">
<figcaption>PV Sindhu admitted to feeling emotional after seeing Vinod Kambli's viral video.(PTI/ANI)</figcaption>
<p>PV Sindhu expressed her emotions after witnessing Vinod Kambli's first public appearance in a long time, emphasizing the importance of financial prudence and having supportive people in one's life.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sindhu felt emotional watching Kambli's viral video during his first public appearance since attending a memorial in December 2024.</li>
  <li>She advised people to manage their finances wisely, emphasizing the need to invest thoughtfully and avoid lavish spending.</li>
  <li>Kambli's recent health issues have raised concerns among fans, highlighting the importance of taking care of one's health.</li>
  <li>Fellow cricket legends like Kapil Dev and Sunil Gavaskar have offered their support to Kambli.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>PV Sindhu stated, "There are ups and downs in life. You need to be careful... You have to invest carefully. You need to pay your taxes. It is important." </blockquote>
<p>This emotional moment serves as a reminder of the importance of financial management, especially for athletes, and highlights the community's support during challenging times.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/pv-sindhu-gets-emotional-seeing-vinod-kamblis-video-take-care-of-money-dont-spend-lavishly-101736767058279.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/pv-sindhu-gets-emotional-seeing-vinod-kamblis-video-take-care-of-money-dont-spend-lavishly-101736767058279.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:31:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's Champions Trophy Squad: Ravindra Jadeja, KL Rahul Axed; Sanju Samson Over Rishabh Pant In Si.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Champions Trophy Squad: Ravindra Jadeja, KL Rahul Axed; Sanju Samson Over Rishabh Pant In Side By Harbhajan</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/t1th5hro_kl-rahul-rishabh-pant_625x300_09_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="India's Champions Trophy Squad: Ravindra Jadeja, KL Rahul Axed; Sanju Samson Over Rishabh Pant In Side By Harbhajan"><figcaption>India's Champions Trophy Squad: KL Rahul and Rishabh Pant © AFP</figcaption><p>The excitement builds as the Indian cricket team prepares for the upcoming Champions Trophy while making notable squad modifications. Harbhajan Singh advocates for a refreshed lineup excluding KL Rahul and Ravindra Jadeja, with a preference for Sanju Samson over Rishabh Pant.</p><ul><li>India and Pakistan have yet to announce their squads for the Champions Trophy.</li><li>Harbhajan Singh has proposed his ideal 15-member squad, suggesting key omissions and inclusions.</li><li>A focus on players who excelled in recent games, including Tilak Varma and Yashasvi Jaiswal.</li><li>Sanju Samson is favored to be picked over Rishabh Pant due to recent performances.</li></ul><blockquote>“We should not get emotional after the defeat in Australia. We need to use our wisdom in picking the best side.” - Harbhajan Singh</blockquote><p>With significant changes to the expected lineup, the decision-making for the Champions Trophy squad could pave the way for India's competitive edge in the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-ravindra-jadeja-kl-rahul-axed-sanju-samson-over-rishabh-pant-in-side-by-harbhajan-singh-7463986</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-squad-ravindra-jadeja-kl-rahul-axed-sanju-samson-over-rishabh-pant-in-side-by-harbhajan-singh-7463986</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:30:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ruben Amorim names three unsung heroes behind Man Utd's Arsenal success - The Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxNSG1iY3RwY1EwU3RCLXNyX3RkZWVkVTcwVDBzVmRVZ1Q5VHB6bTJaM2d1OUo1SVM5cXcwLWRfSzNlSGxDNV9SX1U3NmVsQzloV21BMjBCTUctM2RiYmlONWRNb09ta2RMZHY1ZTdBSWY4UXhJN2YzMjFkVXdOeFdNRWtHaS1SVnBtRlBvd2l5NVhHRHRPUTBj0gGcAUFVX3lxTE9UR3lUcW5GRUsySHdET3RCajdZemJyRldSaWE0NERuZ3JSanNWazB3M1ZFQnkyaUk2SW9XVTJkaWVTd2NCX1U1a2dyUXNkTHB4WjYxanJBMGtLSVh6U2RwT1NJNWUzYW5icU9vakVlbWhMUWtHajM2eFZKaTA5STZ4NTdEZTZURmdBelIyU0xxbWJ0cExMa2ZzZy1Faw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxNSG1iY3RwY1EwU3RCLXNyX3RkZWVkVTcwVDBzVmRVZ1Q5VHB6bTJaM2d1OUo1SVM5cXcwLWRfSzNlSGxDNV9SX1U3NmVsQzloV21BMjBCTUctM2RiYmlONWRNb09ta2RMZHY1ZTdBSWY4UXhJN2YzMjFkVXdOeFdNRWtHaS1SVnBtRlBvd2l5NVhHRHRPUTBj0gGcAUFVX3lxTE9UR3lUcW5GRUsySHdET3RCajdZemJyRldSaWE0NERuZ3JSanNWazB3M1ZFQnkyaUk2SW9XVTJkaWVTd2NCX1U1a2dyUXNkTHB4WjYxanJBMGtLSVh6U2RwT1NJNWUzYW5icU9vakVlbWhMUWtHajM2eFZKaTA5STZ4NTdEZTZURmdBelIyU0xxbWJ0cExMa2ZzZy1Faw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Fire Inside is Burning Bright’ - HSBC BWF World Tour]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNWW92SDFwV0IybzNPQmp4bGZLUmtMdWo3SnExQXFaazB6Q3BxeVg1VGhSS2FwTG1ZR0J4Z1dYZmN0VGMzblZKRXhUd01yVVgyVnV6TnFDai1hR1ViWlo4NXdNTGxfTlNmNVVENmFuUVM2WW1mTEE5dmdLOWtUS0M3SjhFd3k5alFBREh6ek1veE5kdWZZNnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNWW92SDFwV0IybzNPQmp4bGZLUmtMdWo3SnExQXFaazB6Q3BxeVg1VGhSS2FwTG1ZR0J4Z1dYZmN0VGMzblZKRXhUd01yVVgyVnV6TnFDai1hR1ViWlo4NXdNTGxfTlNmNVVENmFuUVM2WW1mTEE5dmdLOWtUS0M3SjhFd3k5alFBREh6ek1veE5kdWZZNnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 11:05:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[USA edge New Zealand as U19 World Cup warm-up action begins - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxQUWNucHVEQzZIeWRjT2UwbE9ldHlNaWVmalZyMU9yVW5sZ1A2eUxTbHptQVpWYzNzalh4TEFwUExXUVJnR3FBOTNrTEVlTmpjeFNoOUhBSHJDY2V4eml4UGJSLURadVlZWHZ1MEpqRmI3N2RZdjFhb3dNQS1zMkRfa044LWNzSFZQOGNCaWFJMzNCN1pHYmkzMWM0WWJ2ZFFMS20xQldtck1nTnBla1d2elNJZ3NDVFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxQUWNucHVEQzZIeWRjT2UwbE9ldHlNaWVmalZyMU9yVW5sZ1A2eUxTbHptQVpWYzNzalh4TEFwUExXUVJnR3FBOTNrTEVlTmpjeFNoOUhBSHJDY2V4eml4UGJSLURadVlZWHZ1MEpqRmI3N2RZdjFhb3dNQS1zMkRfa044LWNzSFZQOGNCaWFJMzNCN1pHYmkzMWM0WWJ2ZFFMS20xQldtck1nTnBla1d2elNJZ3NDVFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:52:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix’s cricket documentary The Greatest Rivalry: India vs Pakistan is releasing Feb 7 - Culture - Images - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Netflix’s Cricket Documentary 'The Greatest Rivalry: India vs Pakistan' to Release on February 7</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> February 7</p><p>Netflix just announced the release date of its anticipated cricket documentary, 'The Greatest Rivalry: India vs Pakistan'. Fans are eager to watch this installment, which explores one of the most intense sports rivalries.</p><img src='path/to/image.jpg' alt='Documentary Poster'><figcaption>The poster showcases Indian legends heading towards the pitch.</figcaption><ul><li>Documentary to release on February 7 on Netflix.</li><li>Features iconic players Sachin Tendulkar and Virender Sehwag.</li><li>The poster highlights players’ back view with the Pakistan team celebrating in the background.</li><li>Last year, a teaser was released but provided limited information.</li><li>The Netflix site includes a promo featuring interviews with cricket legends discussing strategy.</li></ul><blockquote>The comment section on social media highlights fans' enthusiasm and expectations for the documentary.</blockquote><p>This documentary promises to delve deep into the cricket rivalry, showcasing the sporting spirit and history between India and Pakistan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://images.dawn.com/news/1193133/netflixs-cricket-documentary-the-greatest-rivalry-india-vs-pakistan-is-releasing-feb-7</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://images.dawn.com/news/1193133/netflixs-cricket-documentary-the-greatest-rivalry-india-vs-pakistan-is-releasing-feb-7</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:47:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Worst Experience With IndiGo": India Cricket Star Rips Into Airline For 'Worst Staff Management, Ru.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxQNy12cDBrZkRhS3BoZnRvY0hMMWZZb0luZVp4V0NqaFhTVWZlS2tfcVlrMmhDalh5ZnVaYjlSclhFb0g4VE5XTnhoSzNiNThCRnZ3ZzNPeDU5Q0hlUlc1bDl1SkNaQ1YwdGZLcFBJNFdsUmU5MjZzM3o4MmI0RzZFTm1TYVNXeEUxb0UzSjJEZVpxaFFxYUc1UkJqbFluS0ZzVlMtbG4xZ1Q3OWdjRnVtR2RGbDFhMEY5RThSWl9zYXJSbnBzUWp2S05YYnNSbW5lMHlKTFRkWU5Pb0RxbXUtX25kZkktQdIB7gFBVV95cUxNcGVsR25WZjlTM3Rpd3dCOEFPZnlkbWZlRERTU1p2RDdBS1RtRkR2dVRfdkZSbEt0aDJxVmZHQ3Q3M19iT0ptYjlkWnlmTk9pdDdkMEtudUstSS10MFBUTG5vcG1vaW9nVWdxYTVFYU5GLUxOTmJHWS1QRTNtdmZkNVRsRF9neFJLWGlQVG56X0xNbFlFSGFWY29laTdDQ1dZTzF1Y1prYU9xRVE5Q2xJd0Q0VlNXRVZoMVotejlVdXRRbTlGWUw5N0p0U2xuVmg3Z0haTDBFNjd2X1BpZkdQODI0ME0zWl9KNXhMR0RR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxQNy12cDBrZkRhS3BoZnRvY0hMMWZZb0luZVp4V0NqaFhTVWZlS2tfcVlrMmhDalh5ZnVaYjlSclhFb0g4VE5XTnhoSzNiNThCRnZ3ZzNPeDU5Q0hlUlc1bDl1SkNaQ1YwdGZLcFBJNFdsUmU5MjZzM3o4MmI0RzZFTm1TYVNXeEUxb0UzSjJEZVpxaFFxYUc1UkJqbFluS0ZzVlMtbG4xZ1Q3OWdjRnVtR2RGbDFhMEY5RThSWl9zYXJSbnBzUWp2S05YYnNSbW5lMHlKTFRkWU5Pb0RxbXUtX25kZkktQdIB7gFBVV95cUxNcGVsR25WZjlTM3Rpd3dCOEFPZnlkbWZlRERTU1p2RDdBS1RtRkR2dVRfdkZSbEt0aDJxVmZHQ3Q3M19iT0ptYjlkWnlmTk9pdDdkMEtudUstSS10MFBUTG5vcG1vaW9nVWdxYTVFYU5GLUxOTmJHWS1QRTNtdmZkNVRsRF9neFJLWGlQVG56X0xNbFlFSGFWY29laTdDQ1dZTzF1Y1prYU9xRVE5Q2xJd0Q0VlNXRVZoMVotejlVdXRRbTlGWUw5N0p0U2xuVmg3Z0haTDBFNjd2X1BpZkdQODI0ME0zWl9KNXhMR0RR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:32:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SA20 2025: Match 6, MICT vs PR Match Prediction – Who will win today’s SA20 match between MICT vs PR? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SA20 2025: Match 6, MICT vs PR Match Prediction – Who will win today’s SA20 match between MICT vs PR?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><figure><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736665345501_MI-CAPE-TOWN-VS-PAARL-ROYALS.jpeg" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The SA20 tournament proceeds with MI Cape Town (MICT) facing off against Paarl Royals (PR) in match 6 at Newlands, Cape Town. MICT leads the standings while PR aims to gain their second win of the season.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>MICT currently leads the SA20 standings with one win and one loss.</li><li>PR is in second place with one win in their only match.</li><li>The match will be held at Newlands, Cape Town at 9:00 pm IST.</li><li>The venue favors bowlers, with a potential for a low-scoring game.</li></ul><h3>Notable Quotes or Statistics:</h3><blockquote>MICT has won 3 out of 4 head-to-head matches against PR.</blockquote><p>Probable Best Batter: Ryan Rickleton from MI Cape Town</p><p>Probable Best Bowler: Lungi Ngidi from Paarl Royals</p><p><strong>Today's Match Prediction:</strong> The team bowling first is likely to win the match.</p><p>Scenario examples reflect the potential outcomes based on first innings scores.</p><p>Disclaimer: Predictions are subjective and based on analysis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-6-mict-vs-pr-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-mict-vs-pr-5052/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-6-mict-vs-pr-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-mict-vs-pr-5052/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alcaraz makes smooth start to bid for career Grand Slam - ATP Tour]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Carlos Alcaraz makes smooth start to bid for career Grand Slam</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> ATP Tour</p><img src="/-/media/images/news/2025/01/13/09/48/alcaraz-australian-open-2025-monday.jpg" alt="Carlos Alcaraz in action against Alexander Shevchenko on Monday in Melbourne."><figcaption>Carlos Alcaraz in action against Alexander Shevchenko on Monday in Melbourne.</figcaption><p>Carlos Alcaraz began his Australian Open campaign with a decisive victory over Alexander Shevchenko, putting him on the path to potentially become the youngest player to complete a career Grand Slam.</p><ul><li>Alcaraz won the match 6-1, 7-5, 6-1, showcasing impressive skills and 37 winners.</li><li>After losing momentum in the second set, he bounced back to dominate the match.</li><li>This win marks his advance to the second round for the fourth consecutive year.</li><li>He is pursuing his fifth major title, having previously won the US Open, Wimbledon, and Roland Garros.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am pleased to be through. I try to be the better version of myself every day. I work hard and that is the secret to my best level,” said Alcaraz.</blockquote><p>Alcaraz is set to face Yoshihito Nishioka in the next round as he continues his quest in the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.atptour.com/en/news/alcaraz-shevchenko-australian-open-2025-monday</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atptour.com/en/news/alcaraz-shevchenko-australian-open-2025-monday</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 10:10:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>