<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:24:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:24:40 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohun Bagan vs East Bengal Highlights, ISL 2024-25: Jamie Maclaren Scores As MBSG Beat EBFC 1-0 - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohun Bagan vs East Bengal Highlights, ISL 2024-25: Jamie Maclaren Scores As MBSG Beat EBFC 1-0</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>In a thrilling encounter in the Indian Super League, Mohun Bagan Super Giant triumphed over East Bengal FC, with Jamie Maclaren scoring the decisive goal to secure a 1-0 victory.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The match featured a strong performance from both teams, but Mohun Bagan showcased superior tactics.</li>
  <li>Jamie Maclaren's goal was pivotal, solidifying MBSG's position in the league.</li>
  <li>Fans celebrated the hard-fought victory, with highlights showcasing key plays and moments from the match.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This win is crucial for our season. We showed resilience and skill on the field today.” - Coach of Mohun Bagan</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the match reflected the competitive spirit of the ISL, reinforcing the rivalry between these two storied clubs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/indian-super-league/mohun-bagan-vs-east-bengal-live-score-indian-super-league-2024-25-football-match-live-scorecard-updates-7450753</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/indian-super-league/mohun-bagan-vs-east-bengal-live-score-indian-super-league-2024-25-football-match-live-scorecard-updates-7450753</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:54:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohammed Shami returns for India's T20I series against England - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammed Shami Returns for India's T20I Series Against England</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p>Fast bowler Mohammed Shami has made a comeback to the India squad for the upcoming T20I series against England starting January 22 in Kolkata, after recovering from injury.</p><ul><li>Shami last played for India in the ODI World Cup final in November 2023 and has undergone ankle surgery.</li><li>The T20I series will be led by Suryakumar Yadav.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah and Rishabh Pant are notable exclusions from the squad due to injuries and rest.</li><li>The series includes five matches in various Indian cities followed by three ODIs in February.</li></ul><blockquote>“Mohammed Shami returns after key surgeries, aiming for a strong performance in the T20I series.”</blockquote><p>The return of Mohammed Shami to the squad adds depth to India's bowling attack as they prepare to face England in the upcoming T20I series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/mohammed-shami-returns-for-indias-t20i-series-against-england-1468583</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/mohammed-shami-returns-for-indias-t20i-series-against-england-1468583</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:58:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India’s squad for T20I series against England announced - BCCI]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India’s squad for T20I series against England announced</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <strong>January 11, 2025</strong></p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> BCCI</p>
<p>The Men’s Selection Committee has picked India’s 15-member squad for the upcoming IDFC First Bank five-match T20I series against England starting from 22<sup>nd</sup> January in Kolkata.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Captain: Suryakumar Yadav</li>
    <li>Wicketkeeper: Sanju Samson</li>
    <li>Key Players: Hardik Pandya, Axar Patel (vc), Mohammad Shami</li>
    <li>Matches will be held across various venues in India including Kolkata, Chennai, Rajkot, Pune, and Mumbai.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Match Schedule:</strong></p>
<table>
    <tr><th>Match</th><th>Date</th><th>Time</th><th>Venue</th></tr>
    <tr><td>1st T20I</td><td>22-Jan-25</td><td>7:00 PM</td><td>Kolkata</td></tr>
    <tr><td>2nd T20I</td><td>25-Jan-25</td><td>7:00 PM</td><td>Chennai</td></tr>
    <tr><td>3rd T20I</td><td>28-Jan-25</td><td>7:00 PM</td><td>Rajkot</td></tr>
    <tr><td>4th T20I</td><td>31-Jan-25</td><td>7:00 PM</td><td>Pune</td></tr>
    <tr><td>5th T20I</td><td>02-Feb-25</td><td>7:00 PM</td><td>Mumbai</td></tr>
</table>
<p><strong>Notable Quotes:</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>“We are confident this squad will perform well against England.” - Devajit Saikia, Honorary Joint Secretary, BCCI.</p></blockquote>
<p>This series is anticipated to be a closely contested affair, as both teams prepare to showcase their skills in the T20 format.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bcci.tv/articles/2025/news/55556173/india-s-squad-for-t20i-series-against-england-announced?platform=international&amp;type=men</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bcci.tv/articles/2025/news/55556173/india-s-squad-for-t20i-series-against-england-announced?platform=international&amp;type=men</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:54:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rio Ngumoha impresses as Federico Chiesa sends Liverpool message - 4 talking points vs Accrington - Liverpool.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.liverpool.com/liverpool-fc-news/features/liverpool-accrington-ngumoha-federico-chiesa-30758636</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.liverpool.com/liverpool-fc-news/features/liverpool-accrington-ngumoha-federico-chiesa-30758636</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:15:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rio Ngumoha impresses as Federico Chiesa sends Liverpool message - 4 talking points vs Accrington - Liverpool.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.liverpool.com/liverpool-fc-news/features/liverpool-accrington-ngumoha-federico-chiesa-30758636</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.liverpool.com/liverpool-fc-news/features/liverpool-accrington-ngumoha-federico-chiesa-30758636</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:15:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team India squad for England series Live Updates: BCCI selectors reportedly pick Mohammed Shami and Dhruv Jurel - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Team India squad for England series Highlights</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Firstpost</p><div><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2025/01/Mohammed-Shami-comeback1-2025-01-b22dafb4f7568b6111278426e544c11a-1200x675.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Mohammed Shami makes a comeback in T20I squad" title="Mohammed Shami makes a comeback in T20I squad"><figcaption>Pacer Mohammed Shami last played for India in the 2023 ODI World Cup. Image: PTI</figcaption></div><p>Mohammed Shami has made a comeback to the Indian cricket team as part of the T20I squad for the series against England, replacing wicket-keeper Rishabh Pant with Dhruv Jurel. This announcement comes as anticipation builds for the 2025 ICC Champions Trophy and the home series following India’s 3-1 defeat in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Mohammed Shami returns to the Indian team after injury, marking his first appearance since the 2023 ODI World Cup.</li><li>Dhruv Jurel has been included in the squad over Rishabh Pant, who was not mentioned in the announcement.</li><li>Axar Patel has been appointed vice-captain for the T20I series.</li><li>Series against England includes five T20Is starting from January 22, 2025.</li><li>The squad has experienced significant changes post the recent Tour of Australia.</li></ul><blockquote>“Shami return is the talking point.” — Boria Majumdar, Twitter</blockquote><p>The selections indicate a strategic approach by the selectors as the team gears up for the Champions Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/firstcricket/sports-news/champions-trophy-2025-india-team-announcement-live-updates-rohit-bumrah-shami-13851666.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/firstcricket/sports-news/champions-trophy-2025-india-team-announcement-live-updates-rohit-bumrah-shami-13851666.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:14:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohammed Shami returns for India T20Is vs England; Rishabh Pant, Shubman Gill rested - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammed Shami Returns for India T20Is vs England; Rishabh Pant, Shubman Gill Rested</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><p>The Indian cricket team has announced its squad for the upcoming T20I series against England, with Mohammed Shami returning while Rishabh Pant and Shubman Gill have been rested.</p><ul><li>Mohammed Shami is back in the T20I format after a hiatus.</li><li>Rishabh Pant and Shubman Gill are being rested to manage their workloads.</li><li>The squad reflects a mix of experience and young talent.</li></ul><blockquote>“The decision to rest key players is strategic as we look to balance performance and player fitness.”</blockquote><p>This T20I series will provide an opportunity for the team to assess its depth ahead of upcoming tournaments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/mohammed-shami-set-to-return-for-india-t20is-vs-england-team-for-odis-champions-trophy-to-be-picked-later/articleshow/117151192.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/mohammed-shami-set-to-return-for-india-t20is-vs-england-team-for-odis-champions-trophy-to-be-picked-later/articleshow/117151192.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Aryan to Anaya Bangar: Sanjay Bangar's son shares his emotional transformation journey - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>From Aryan to Anaya Bangar: Sanjay Bangar's son shares his emotional transformation journey</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided - <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/from-aryan-to-anaya-bangar-sanjay-bangars-son-shares-his-emotional-transformation-journey-202501-1736603212.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="From Aryan to Anaya Bangar Sanjay Bangar s son shares his emotional transformation journey"><figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption><p>This inspiring article chronicles the emotional transformation of Sanjay Bangar's son as he evolves from Aryan to Anaya Bangar.</p><ul><li>Sanjay Bangar's son expressed his childhood struggles with gender identity.</li><li>He described living a double life, trying to conform to societal norms while hiding his true self.</li><li>After deciding to transition, he moved to the UK for support and care.</li><li>His journey includes challenges faced during hormone treatment and the impact on relationships.</li><li>Despite hardships, he found happiness and comfort in his new identity.</li></ul><blockquote>"I took a tough decision of taking a break from cricket and moved to UK to transition, I socially came out and found supportive friends."</blockquote><p>His story serves as an uplifting reminder of the value of authenticity and support during times of personal change.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/from-aryan-to-anaya-bangar-sanjay-bangar-son-shares-his-emotional-transformation-journey-419464/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/from-aryan-to-anaya-bangar-sanjay-bangar-son-shares-his-emotional-transformation-journey-419464/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:49:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nazia Bibi: first player from J&K to represent India at Kho Kho World Cup - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nazia Bibi: First Player from J&K to Represent India at Kho Kho World Cup</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>Nazia Bibi, a 21-year-old athlete from Jammu and Kashmir, has made history by being the first player from the region selected for the Indian Women’s Kho Kho team.</p><img src='image-url.jpg' alt='Nazia Bibi playing Kho Kho'><figcaption>Nazia Bibi representing J&K</figcaption><p>The upcoming tournament will feature over 20 nations and starts on January 13, 2025, at the Indira Gandhi Indoor Stadium in New Delhi.</p><ul><li>Nazia started her sports journey during her school years and has been playing professionally for the past seven years.</li><li>She is currently pursuing a BA at Padma Shri Padma Sachdev Govt College for Women in Jammu.</li><li>Her army-serving cousins inspired her passion for athletics.</li><li>Nazia is the only female athlete from J&K selected after a national camp.</li><li>Her family is immensely proud and supportive of her achievement.</li><li>Officials from the J&K State Kho Kho Association have praised her selection as a milestone for regional sports.</li></ul><blockquote>“Watching my cousins excel in athletics fueled my passion to pursue a career in sports.” - Nazia Bibi</blockquote><p>Nazia Bibi's selection marks a significant moment for sports in Jammu and Kashmir, inspiring future generations of athletes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/jammu/nazia-bibi-first-player-from-jk-to-represent-india-at-kho-kho-world-cup/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/jammu/nazia-bibi-first-player-from-jk-to-represent-india-at-kho-kho-world-cup/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:43:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Chat GPT Product": Nitish Rana, Harshit Rana's Similar Posts Defending Gautam Gambhir After 'Hypocr.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitish and Harshit Rana Defend Gautam Gambhir Amid Criticism</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/lqr0cmqo_gautam-gambhir-x_625x300_05_January_25.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Gautam Gambhir"/>
<figcaption>File photo of Gautam Gambhir. © X (formerly Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>Following India's 1-3 loss to Australia in a Test series, criticism has been directed toward coach Gautam Gambhir. In the wake of this, cricketers Nitish and Harshit Rana issued similar statements in defense of Gambhir, but former player Aakash Chopra commented that their posts resembled outputs from Chat GPT.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gautam Gambhir faced heavy criticism after India's poor performance in the Test series.</li>
  <li>Former cricketer Manoj Tiwary termed Gambhir a 'hypocrite' in his criticism.</li>
  <li>Nitish and Harshit Rana expressed support for Gambhir, but their posts were strikingly similar.</li>
  <li>Aakash Chopra remarked that the two posts seemed like they were generated by Chat GPT.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"If you look at it, it looks like a Chat GPT product. There are many similarities in both statements, or someone wrote them and sent them to post on social media." - Aakash Chopra</blockquote>
<p>Despite a strong start to Gambhir's tenure, India has struggled in the Tests, raising questions about the team's performance and his coaching capabilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/chat-gpt-product-nitish-rana-harshit-ranas-similar-posts-defending-gautam-gambhir-after-hypocrite-attack-blasted-7450573</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/chat-gpt-product-nitish-rana-harshit-ranas-similar-posts-defending-gautam-gambhir-after-hypocrite-attack-blasted-7450573</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:36:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohammed Shami picked for T20 series against England - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammed Shami Returns for T20 Series Against England</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>Fast bowler Mohammed Shami is set to return to the Indian cricket team for the upcoming T20 series against England after recovering from an ankle injury.</p><ul><li>Shami last played for India in the 2023 World Cup final.</li><li>He underwent surgery and has been recovering, playing domestic matches in the interim.</li><li>The selectors have included Dhruv Jurel as the second wicketkeeper, while Rishabh Pant misses out.</li><li>Nitish Reddy, who performed well in Australia, is also included in the T20 squad.</li><li>Riyan Parag has been excluded due to injury.</li></ul><blockquote>“Based on the current medical assessment, the BCCI medical team has determined that his knee requires more time for controlled exposure to bowling loads.” - BCCI Release</blockquote><p><strong>India T20 squad:</strong> Suryakumar Yadav, Sanju Samson, Yashasvi Jaiswal, Tilak Varma, Nitish Reddy, Mohd Shami, Arshdeep Singh, Harshit Rana, Dhruv Jurel, Rinku Singh, Hardik Pandya, Axar Patel, Ravi Bishnoi, Varun Chakravarthy, Washington Sundar.</p><p>The T20 matches against England will begin on January 22 in Kolkata.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/mohammed-shami-picked-for-t2o-series-against-england-9773515/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/mohammed-shami-picked-for-t2o-series-against-england-9773515/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:24:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Well-wishers' urged Rohit Sharma to not retire, decision upset Gautam Gambhir - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Well-wishers' urged Rohit Sharma to not retire, decision upset Gautam Gambhir</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Publication Date]</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117150218,imgsize-54140,width-400,resizemode-4/117150218.jpg" alt="Gautam Gambhir and Rohit Sharma" title="Gautam Gambhir and Rohit Sharma (PTI photo)"><figcaption>Gautam Gambhir and Rohit Sharma (PTI photo)</figcaption><p>India captain Rohit Sharma reportedly changed his mind about retiring after being urged by well-wishers, despite a disappointing run in recent matches. This decision did not sit well with coach Gautam Gambhir.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma was set to retire after the fourth Test against Australia at the MCG.</li><li>He returned to open for the Boxing Day Test, pushing Shubman Gill out of the team.</li><li>Sharma struggled with performance, scoring just 31 runs in five innings.</li><li>There has been tension between Sharma and Gambhir over team decisions.</li><li>Sharma plans to participate in the upcoming ICC Champions Trophy, which could be pivotal for senior players.</li></ul><blockquote>"Had his well-wishers from the outside didn't force him to change his mind, we could have well seen another retirement in Australia."</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the ongoing challenges Sharma faces as captain and the dynamics within the team as they prepare for crucial upcoming matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/well-wishers-urged-rohit-sharma-to-not-retire-decision-upset-gautam-gambhir/articleshow/117150252.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/well-wishers-urged-rohit-sharma-to-not-retire-decision-upset-gautam-gambhir/articleshow/117150252.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[THIS, new sensation of CSK created havoc before IPL 2025, changed the match with one ball in SA20.... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/this-new-sensation-of-csk-created-havoc-before-ipl-2025-changed-the-match-with-one-ball-in-sa20-noor-ahmad-419453/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/this-new-sensation-of-csk-created-havoc-before-ipl-2025-changed-the-match-with-one-ball-in-sa20-noor-ahmad-419453/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:10:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[THIS, new sensation of CSK created havoc before IPL 2025, changed the match with one ball in SA20.... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/this-new-sensation-of-csk-created-havoc-before-ipl-2025-changed-the-match-with-one-ball-in-sa20-noor-ahmad-419453/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/this-new-sensation-of-csk-created-havoc-before-ipl-2025-changed-the-match-with-one-ball-in-sa20-noor-ahmad-419453/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:10:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI Rejects KL Rahul’s Request For A Rest, Asks Him To Play England Series - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/bcci-rejects-kl-rahuls-request-for-a-rest-asks-him-to-play-england-series-9185158.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/bcci-rejects-kl-rahuls-request-for-a-rest-asks-him-to-play-england-series-9185158.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:08:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karnataka in semis after beating Baroda in a thriller - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka Secures Semi-Final Spot by Defeating Baroda in Thrilling Match</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> <em>October 2023</em>, <strong>Source:</strong> <a href='https://www.espncricinfo.com/'>ESPN Cricinfo</a></p>
<p>Karnataka won a nail-biting match against Baroda by just five runs to advance to the semi-finals of the Vijay Hazare Trophy. Devdutt Padikkal was the standout performer, scoring 102 runs.</p>
<ul>
<li>Karnataka scored 281 for 8, with notable contributions from Padikkal (102) and Aneesh (52).</li>
<li>Baroda, chasing 282, was on track at 185 for 2 but lost key wickets swiftly.</li>
<li>Karnataka's wicketkeeping and fielding were crucial in turning the tide of the match.</li>
<li>Baroda's Shashwat Rawat scored a century (104) but couldn’t secure victory.</li>
<li>In a tense finish, Baroda needed 8 runs off the last two balls but fell short when Bhatt was run out.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Karnataka's catching made a massive difference to the result.</blockquote>
<p>This thrilling match showcased both teams' strengths, but Karnataka's ability to defend their score under pressure ensured their place in the next round.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-1445828/karnataka-vs-baroda-4th-quarter-final-1446237/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-1445828/karnataka-vs-baroda-4th-quarter-final-1446237/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 12:47:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yuvraj Singh's Old Interview Goes Viral After Virat Kohli Gets Blamed For Cutting Short His Career - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yuvraj Singh's Old Interview Goes Viral After Virat Kohli Gets Blamed For Cutting Short His Career</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/jahtii2_yuvraj-singh-and-virat-kohli-bcci_625x300_10_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Yuvraj Singh's Old Interview Goes Viral After Virat Kohli Gets Blamed For Cutting Short His Career"><figcaption>File photo of Yuvraj Singh (left) and Virat Kohli. © BCCI</figcaption><p>An old interview of former India player Yuvraj Singh has gone viral after ex-batter Robin Uthappa held Virat Kohli indirectly responsible for cutting short the all-rounder's international career. Uthappa claimed that Yuvraj's request for certain fitness concessions during his return to the team after beating cancer was denied by then-captain Kohli.</p><ul><li>Yuvraj was one of India's finest players, contributing to the team's World Cup success in 2011.</li><li>After recovering from cancer, he made a comeback, scoring a hundred against England.</li><li>Following limited outings, he decided to retire in 2019 after feeling sidelined.</li></ul><blockquote>“Never thought that I would be dropped after being the Man of the Match in 2 games... I was told to prepare for the Sri Lanka series. Then suddenly, the Yo-Yo test came into the picture.” - Yuvraj Singh</blockquote><p>This controversy highlights issues within team management decisions and the treatment of players faced with challenging circumstances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/yuvraj-singhs-old-interview-goes-viral-after-virat-kohli-gets-blamed-for-cutting-short-his-career-7450333</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/yuvraj-singhs-old-interview-goes-viral-after-virat-kohli-gets-blamed-for-cutting-short-his-career-7450333</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 12:41:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICC Champions Trophy 2025 India Squad Announcement: Rohit Sharma reaches BCCI office in Mumbai for review meeting - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICC Champions Trophy 2025 India Squad Announcement: Rohit Sharma reaches BCCI office in Mumbai for review meeting</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>With the ICC deadline approaching, Indian skipper Rohit Sharma arrived in Mumbai for the BCCI review meeting regarding the squad announcement for the Champions Trophy 2025.</p>
<ul>
<li>Rohit Sharma met with BCCI officials to finalize the squad details.</li>
<li>Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma likely to miss the England series.</li>
<li>Focus on pacers and spinners due to injuries to key players like Jasprit Bumrah.</li>
<li>Surprise picks may include Varun Chakravarthy and Nitish Kumar Reddy.</li>
<li>Upcoming three-match ODI series against England is scheduled.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Suryakumar Yadav isn't there, but Shreyas Iyer is. Since the start of the World Cup, he has scored 620 runs in 15 innings.” - Aakash Chopra</blockquote>
<p>This review meeting is crucial as it sets the stage for India's preparations ahead of the significant cricketing event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/icc-champions-trophy-2025-india-squad-announcement-rohit-sharma-reaches-bcci-office-in-mumbai-for-review-meeting-11736598765809.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/icc-champions-trophy-2025-india-squad-announcement-rohit-sharma-reaches-bcci-office-in-mumbai-for-review-meeting-11736598765809.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 12:35:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's Champions Trophy And England Series Squad Live: BCCI To Take Drastic Step Over Jasprit Bumrah, Mohammed Siraj? - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Champions Trophy 2025 And England Series Squad Announcement Live</h1><p><strong>Date: January 10, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: NDTV</strong></p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/0be70nho_rohit-gambhir-agarkar-pti_625x300_03_January_25.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="India's Champions Trophy And England Series Squad Live"><figcaption>India's Champions Trophy And England Series Squad Live: BCCI To Take Drastic Step Over Jasprit Bumrah, Mohammed Siraj?</figcaption><p>The deadline for the squad selection for the Champions Trophy and the England white-ball series is fast approaching. India has requested an extension to submit the provisional squad, which needs to be finalized by February 12.</p><ul><li>The BCCI selection committee, led by Ajit Agarkar, will announce the squads soon.</li><li>Following a disappointing performance against Australia, significant changes are likely.</li><li>Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma are expected to be included in the teams.</li><li>Mohammed Siraj and Jasprit Bumrah may not play in the T20Is but are expected to return for the ODIs.</li><li>KL Rahul's participation remains uncertain as he might be rested.</li></ul><blockquote>“Will the squad be announced today? Fans are eagerly awaiting the decisions from the selection committee.”</blockquote><p>The live updates provide insights into the anticipated squad application and player conditions, with several players' fitness under scrutiny.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-2025-squad-india-vs-england-odi-t20-full-schedule-squads-announcement-live-updates-7440002</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-champions-trophy-2025-squad-india-vs-england-odi-t20-full-schedule-squads-announcement-live-updates-7440002</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:48:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Key spinner returns as Pakistan announce squad for West Indies Tests - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan Announces Squad for West Indies Tests with Key Changes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Sports News</p><p>In a strategic move to manage player workload, Pakistan has announced its squad for the upcoming Test series against West Indies, highlighting several key changes.</p><ul><li>The pace quartet of Aamir Jamal, Mohammad Abbas, Mir Hamza, and Naseem Shah have been rested.</li><li>Uncapped Kashif Ali is included in the squad.</li><li>Khurram Shahzad has been retained for the series.</li><li>Openers Imam-ul-Haq and Mohammad Huraira are recalled as replacements for injured and out-of-form players.</li><li>Rohail Nazir is brought in as backup wicketkeeper following an injury to Haseebullah.</li></ul><p><strong>Squad:</strong> Shan Masood (captain), Saud Shakeel, Abrar Ahmed, Babar Azam, Imam-ul-Haq, Kamran Ghulam, Kashif Ali, Khurram Shahzad, Mohammad Ali, Mohammad Huraira, Mohammad Rizwan, Noman Ali, Rohail Nazir, Sajid Khan, and Salman Ali Agha.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/world-test-championship/news/key-spinner-returns-as-pakistan-announce-squad-for-west-indies-tests</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/world-test-championship/news/key-spinner-returns-as-pakistan-announce-squad-for-west-indies-tests</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:32:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['After Yuvraj, he's one batter who can do that': India star backed with flattering comparison right before CT 2025 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Star Sanju Samson Compared to Yuvraj Singh Ahead of CT 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/CRICKET-T20-ZAF-IND--28_1731692364447_1736595067918.JPG" alt="India's Arshdeep Singh celebrates with teammates after taking the lbw wicket of South Africa's Heinrich Klaasen during a T20I series in 2024(REUTERS)"><figcaption>India's Arshdeep Singh celebrates with teammates after taking the lbw wicket of South Africa's Heinrich Klaasen during a T20I series in 2024(REUTERS)</figcaption><p>Former India batting coach Sanjay Bangar has praised Sanju Samson for his impressive performances in T20 internationals, drawing a flattering comparison to Yuvraj Singh. Samson's recent success in T20 matches positions him well ahead of the upcoming Champions Trophy.</p><ul><li>Sanju Samson achieved a successful comeback in T20Is after previous inconsistency.</li><li>He scored centuries against Bangladesh and South Africa.</li><li>Bangar noted that consistent playing time has helped Samson flourish.</li><li>Samson is expected to play in the upcoming limited-overs series against England.</li></ul><blockquote>"After Yuvraj Singh, if there is one batter who can do it with such ease on a consistent basis, it has to be Sanju Samson." - Sanjay Bangar</blockquote><p>With the Champions Trophy approaching, Sanju Samson aims to make a strong impact if selected for the series against England.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/after-yuvraj-hes-one-batter-who-can-do-that-india-star-backed-with-flattering-comparison-right-before-ct-2025-101736591094857.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/after-yuvraj-hes-one-batter-who-can-do-that-india-star-backed-with-flattering-comparison-right-before-ct-2025-101736591094857.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:32:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Chance For Jasprit Bumrah, Mohammed Siraj: Report Makes Big Claim On India Squad vs England In T2.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>No Chance For Jasprit Bumrah, Mohammed Siraj: Report Makes Big Claim On India Squad vs England In T20Is</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>January 25, 2025</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/vbqdd5g_jasprit-bumrah_625x300_09_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Jasprit Bumrah and Mohammed Siraj"><figcaption>File photo of Jasprit Bumrah © AFP</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team's upcoming five-T20I series against England is set to kick off on January 22, marking their first assignment after the Border Gavaskar Trophy. Reports suggest key players Jasprit Bumrah and Mohammed Siraj may be missing from the squad.</p><ul><li>The T20 squad is expected to be announced soon, with no major surprises anticipated.</li><li>Arshdeep Singh is likely to lead the pace attack in Bumrah and Siraj's absence.</li><li>Mohammed Shami may return for the ODI series and Champions Trophy despite missing the T20Is.</li><li>Nitish Kumar Reddy is expected to be included in the T20I squad against England.</li></ul><blockquote>“The squad for the Champions Trophy may take some time to be announced.”</blockquote><p>This series serves as an important preparation ahead of the ICC Champions Trophy starting February 19, making the squad announcements critical for team strategy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/india-vs-england-2025/no-chance-for-jasprit-bumrah-mohammed-siraj-report-makes-big-claims-on-india-squad-vs-england-in-t20is-7450328</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/india-vs-england-2025/no-chance-for-jasprit-bumrah-mohammed-siraj-report-makes-big-claims-on-india-squad-vs-england-in-t20is-7450328</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:26:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FC Barcelona Rejects $36 Million Offer For First Team Star But Names Asking Price, Reports MARCA - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/tomsanderson/2025/01/11/fc-barcelona-rejects-36-million-offer-for-first-team-star-and-names-asking-price-reports-marca/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/tomsanderson/2025/01/11/fc-barcelona-rejects-36-million-offer-for-first-team-star-and-names-asking-price-reports-marca/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:15:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Shaheen And Naseem Shah As PCB Announces Test Squad For West Indies Series - OneCricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan Announces Test Squad for West Indies Series: Key Players Rested</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> One Cricket News</p>
<img src="https://onecricketnews.akamaized.net/parth-editor/oc-dashboard/news-images-prod/1736592902015_Shaheen_afridi.jpg" alt="Shaheen Afridi has been rested [Source: ICC]" width="474" height="240">
<figcaption>Shaheen Afridi has been rested [Source: ICC]</figcaption>
<p>In the latest development, Pakistan has revealed their Test squad for the West Indies series, scheduled to be played in Multan from January 17-21 and January 25-29. Key players have been rested to manage their workload.</p>
<ul>
<li>Seven changes have been made to the squad that toured South Africa.</li>
<li>Star pacers Naseem Shah and Shaheen Afridi are among those rested.</li>
<li>Experienced spinners Sajid Khan and Abrar Ahmed have been added to support Noman Ali.</li>
<li>Imam-ul-Haq and Mohammad Huraira return to replace injured Saim Ayub and Abdullah Shafique.</li>
<li>Kashif Ali, an uncapped pacer, has been included in the squad.</li>
<li>Haseebullah Khan is out due to a hand injury; Rohail Nazir has been named in his place.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Pakistan Squad For The West Indies Tests:</strong> Shan Masood (captain), Saud Shakeel (vice-captain), Abrar Ahmed, Babar Azam, Imam-ul-Haq, Kamran Ghulam, Kashif Ali, Khurram Shahzad, Mohammad Ali, Mohammad Huraira, Mohammad Rizwan (wicketkeeper/batter), Noman Ali, Rohail Nazir (wicketkeeper/batter), Sajid Khan, and Salman Ali Agha.</p>
<p>This squad adjustment highlights Pakistan's strategic approach to player management ahead of future matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://cricket.one/cricket-news/no-place-for-shaheen-naseem-imam-returns-pakistans-squad-for-wi-tests-announced/67824fde740f2ee0d9bc2da0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cricket.one/cricket-news/no-place-for-shaheen-naseem-imam-returns-pakistans-squad-for-wi-tests-announced/67824fde740f2ee0d9bc2da0</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 11:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan name squad for West Indies Tests - PCB]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan Announces Squad for West Indies Test Series</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>11 January 2025</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Pakistan Cricket Board</p><p>The Pakistan Cricket Board has announced a 15-player squad for the upcoming Tests against the West Indies in Multan.</p><ul><li>The matches are scheduled from January 17-21 and January 25-29.</li><li>Seven changes were made from the previous squad that toured South Africa.</li><li>Shan Masood remains captain, with Saud Shakeel as vice-captain.</li><li>Off-spinner Sajid Khan and mystery spinner Abrar Ahmed return to bolster the spin department.</li><li>Openers Imam-ul-Haq and Mohammad Huraira replace injured and out-of-form players.</li><li>Former U19 captain Rohail Nazir joins the squad as wicketkeeper-batter due to Haseebullah's injury.</li></ul><p><strong>Pakistan squad for the West Indies Tests:</strong> Shan Masood (captain), Saud Shakeel (vice-captain), Abrar Ahmed, Babar Azam, Imam-ul-Haq, Kamran Ghulam, Kashif Ali, Khurram Shahzad, Mohammad Ali, Mohammad Huraira, Mohammad Rizwan (wicketkeeper/batter), Noman Ali, Rohail Nazir (wicketkeeper/batter), Sajid Khan, Salman Ali Agha.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pcb.com.pk/press-release-detail/pakistan-name-squad-for-west-indies-tests.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pcb.com.pk/press-release-detail/pakistan-name-squad-for-west-indies-tests.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 10:51:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ILT20 2025: Match 1, DC vs MIE Match Prediction – Who will win today’s ILT20 match between DC vs MIE? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxNQVFiVlNLNWJHWlB3c0FmOXFwWTU4dFJOdEdnLUZXMUpIT0l6UlB4WjhmZTY2OUtGRDFHQ2tfemN1M2UzcFdWR0txRTdreWZwaUZwazFuem1lcDYyWnVOVGw0UWlaTm5SbG9HTmpOVzE2Q09TbDNuMVFDY2xtaTNIbjZrUDhNc3Z0NGV1ZjVjRmVjbEQ1NFVSRzFyZ2VuXzFIU2fSAaoBQVVfeXFMTUcxRzRHcU1JQTM3VjBNN2EtSEdFMGFacDgtbVI1VXkwUXZtaTM0VmxhM2VvcWR1RzdSLTJEZ0stbjQ5dmxNZWdmSEhpUmd6Wi1OYzduYWdpXzQ2bWpxMFVHNEd5aFJWQWhBSUEtTzRsSlBwcnBSbU1xbWVtOTVCN2Rmb3ljaFF2ckxHeHZyVXk2akNEbnU2Rko4cTZ5MjVsbmNSRVRQYy1lWnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxNQVFiVlNLNWJHWlB3c0FmOXFwWTU4dFJOdEdnLUZXMUpIT0l6UlB4WjhmZTY2OUtGRDFHQ2tfemN1M2UzcFdWR0txRTdreWZwaUZwazFuem1lcDYyWnVOVGw0UWlaTm5SbG9HTmpOVzE2Q09TbDNuMVFDY2xtaTNIbjZrUDhNc3Z0NGV1ZjVjRmVjbEQ1NFVSRzFyZ2VuXzFIU2fSAaoBQVVfeXFMTUcxRzRHcU1JQTM3VjBNN2EtSEdFMGFacDgtbVI1VXkwUXZtaTM0VmxhM2VvcWR1RzdSLTJEZ0stbjQ5dmxNZWdmSEhpUmd6Wi1OYzduYWdpXzQ2bWpxMFVHNEd5aFJWQWhBSUEtTzRsSlBwcnBSbU1xbWVtOTVCN2Rmb3ljaFF2ckxHeHZyVXk2akNEbnU2Rko4cTZ5MjVsbmNSRVRQYy1lWnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 10:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yuzvendra Chahal vs Prithvi Shaw: Who is RICHER? Check their net worth - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxObGRzNUlHM25BSXZvdkpsRVAwTFpLZWRvUWRrSzFQMEcxSjNQQVJJcnBJWGRjUWVDY05UUi1ybVB5XzZ6dXQ5SHJUWXktYjN5UVBHRXg1QmUzRi14dE4wTE1tRWt4dGo4X3o1dURHRENYOGEycDBSbHpDSGFSMlR2Q2UxODRYdWJnNjBUa01UbFFmX21Od1J5UGNGaEhZbGZlbmtRRXlCRW9NRE9RajFTb09n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxObGRzNUlHM25BSXZvdkpsRVAwTFpLZWRvUWRrSzFQMEcxSjNQQVJJcnBJWGRjUWVDY05UUi1ybVB5XzZ6dXQ5SHJUWXktYjN5UVBHRXg1QmUzRi14dE4wTE1tRWt4dGo4X3o1dURHRENYOGEycDBSbHpDSGFSMlR2Q2UxODRYdWJnNjBUa01UbFFmX21Od1J5UGNGaEhZbGZlbmtRRXlCRW9NRE9RajFTb09n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 10:33:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SA20 2025: Match 4, JSK vs MICT Match Prediction – Who will win today’s SA20 match between JSK vs MICT? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SA20 2025: Match 4 Prediction - Joburg Super Kings vs MI Cape Town</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Saturday, January 11, 9 pm IST - CricTracker</p><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736528840062_image_2025_01_10T17_00_34_703Z.png" alt="JSK vs MICT Match Prediction" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption><p>The fourth match of the 2025 SA20 season features a face-off between Joburg Super Kings and MI Cape Town at The Wanderers Stadium. The Super Kings are set to make their debut in the tournament, while Cape Town arrives with a recent dominant victory.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>Venue: The Wanderers Stadium, Johannesburg</li><li>Joburg Super Kings will play their first game of the season.</li><li>MI Cape Town won their previous match by 97 runs.</li><li>The pitch is expected to favor high scores, advantageous for batters.</li><li>Head-to-head record: 4 matches - 2 wins each for both teams.</li><li>Predicted best batter: Reeza Hendricks</li><li>Predicted best bowler: Trent Boult</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Today's Match Prediction: MI Cape Town to win the match.”</p></blockquote><p>It's anticipated that MI Cape Town will continue their winning momentum against the Joburg Super Kings in this exciting matchup.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-4-jsk-vs-mict-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-jsk-vs-mict/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-4-jsk-vs-mict-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-jsk-vs-mict/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SA20 2025: Match 3, PR vs SEC Match Prediction – Who will win today’s SA20 match between PR vs SEC? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SA20 2025: Match 3, PR vs SEC Match Prediction – Who will win today’s SA20 match between PR vs SEC?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p>
<img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736516741221_image_2025_01_10T13_45_18_405Z.png" width="700" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Image depicting the match scenario for Paarl Royals vs Sunrisers Eastern Cape.</figcaption>
<p>Paarl Royals will face Sunrisers Eastern Cape in Match 3 of SA20 2025 at Boland Park. This match is anticipated as Sunrisers aim to continue their winning streak from 2024.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Paarl Royals qualified for the knockouts in 2024 but were eliminated by Joburg Super Kings.</li>
  <li>Sunrisers Eastern Cape last won the SA20 title in 2024.</li>
  <li>The pitch at Boland Park favors batters, although spinners may find assistance.</li>
  <li>Paarl Royals are hopeful for better performance with the addition of Dinesh Karthik.</li>
  <li>Match prediction favors the team batting first to win.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Today's Match Prediction: Team batting first to win the match.”</blockquote>
<p>This match sets the stage for an exciting clash as both teams look to assert dominance early in the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-3-pr-vs-sec-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-pr-vs-sec/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-3-pr-vs-sec-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-pr-vs-sec/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive | Electrician-turned-cricketer chases Shoaib Akhtar's pace after leaving Pakistan; eyes set on - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/exclusive-electrician-turned-cricketer-chases-shoaib-akhtars-pace-after-leaving-pakistan-eyes-set-on-huge-ilt20-milestone/articleshow/117145957.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/exclusive-electrician-turned-cricketer-chases-shoaib-akhtars-pace-after-leaving-pakistan-eyes-set-on-huge-ilt20-milestone/articleshow/117145957.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 10:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>