<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:17:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:17:01 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI Unveils 10-Point Diktat After Australia Debacle, Threatens "Disciplinary Action Against..." - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Implements Strict 10-Point Policy Following Australia's Tour Failures</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/v48ovkfg_gambhir-rohit-bumrah-afp_625x300_06_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="BCCI Unveils 10-Point Diktat After Australia Debacle, Threatens &quot;Disciplinary Action Against...&quot;"><figcaption>File photo of Indian cricket team and staff. © AFP</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has announced a new 10-point policy aimed at promoting discipline and unity within the Indian cricket team after their recent poor performances abroad.</p><ul><li>The policy enforces mandatory participation in domestic cricket.</li><li>Restrictions are placed on the presence of families and personal staff during tours.</li><li>Individual commercial endorsements are banned during ongoing series.</li><li>Players must seek approval from the head coach and chairman for any relaxation of policies.</li><li>There will be a maximum two-week allowance for families to join players on long overseas tours.</li><li>Players are required to adhere to specified baggage limits while traveling.</li><li>All players must stay for the entirety of scheduled practice sessions.</li><li>Players are discouraged from traveling separately with their families.</li><li>Disciplinary actions may be enforced for non-compliance, including fines and exclusion from IPL matches.</li><li>The policy aims to strengthen commitment and operational efficiency within the team.</li></ul><blockquote>“Any exceptions or deviations must be pre-approved by the Chairman of the Selection Committee and Head Coach. Non-compliance may lead to disciplinary action as deemed appropriate by the BCCI.”</blockquote><p>This initiative reflects BCCI's commitment to maintaining professional standards within the sport. It seeks to reintegrate star players into the domestic cricket ecosystem, promoting long-term growth and success for Indian cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/bcci-unveils-10-point-diktat-after-australia-debacle-threaten-disciplinary-action-against-7490367</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/bcci-unveils-10-point-diktat-after-australia-debacle-threaten-disciplinary-action-against-7490367</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:07:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pant available for Delhi's next Ranji Trophy game, but DDCA 'haven't heard from Kohli' - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rishabh Pant Available for Upcoming Ranji Trophy Match, Virat Kohli's Status Unclear</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 23, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p>Rishabh Pant is set to join Delhi for their next Ranji Trophy match against Saurashtra, while the participation of Virat Kohli remains uncertain.</p><ul><li>Rishabh Pant last played in the Ranji Trophy in the 2017-2018 season.</li><li>Ravindra Jadeja also makes his first-class return after playing last in January 2023.</li><li>Virat Kohli last played in the Ranji Trophy for Delhi in 2012.</li><li>Both Pant and Kohli are named in Delhi's list of probables for the season.</li></ul><blockquote>“Yes, Pant has confirmed his availability for next Ranji game...About Virat Kohli, we want him to play but we haven't heard from him.” - Ashok Sharma, DDCA Secretary</blockquote><p>The ongoing speculation about Kohli's return to domestic cricket continues, with former players urging him to regain form through red-ball matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/rishabh-pant-available-for-delhis-next-ranji-trophy-game-but-ddca-havent-heard-from-virat-kohli-1469103</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/rishabh-pant-available-for-delhis-next-ranji-trophy-game-but-ddca-havent-heard-from-virat-kohli-1469103</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:43:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Karun Nair stars again for Vidarbha to set up finale date with Karnataka - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karun Nair Leads Vidarbha to Vijay Hazare Trophy Final</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>Karun Nair's outstanding performance, scoring an unbeaten 88 runs, propelled Vidarbha to a 69-run victory over Maharashtra in the semi-finals of the 2024-25 Vijay Hazare Trophy, setting up a final clash against his former team, Karnataka.</p><ul><li>Vidarbha scored 380 for 3, with significant contributions from Dhruv Shorey (116) and Yash Rathod (114).</li><li>Maharashtra managed 311 for 7 in their chase, falling short despite Kulkarni's 90 runs.</li><li>Nair's explosive innings included nine fours and five sixes, showcasing exceptional batting skill in the final overs.</li><li>Vidarbha's win marks their first entry into the Vijay Hazare Trophy final.</li></ul><blockquote>“Nair's innings was a defining moment in the match, particularly his late-overs fireworks.”</blockquote><p>With this victory, Vidarbha aims for a maiden title in the Vijay Hazare Trophy, promising an exciting final against Karnataka.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-1445828/vidarbha-vs-maharashtra-2nd-semi-final-1446241/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-1445828/vidarbha-vs-maharashtra-2nd-semi-final-1446241/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:41:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI bars India players from taking personal hairstylists, chefs, security guards on tours | New guidelines come after India's loss in BGT | Inshorts - Inshorts]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI bars India players from taking personal hairstylists, chefs, security guards on tours</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 02:31 pm on Thursday 16 January, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Inshorts</p>
<p>The BCCI has introduced new guidelines prohibiting Indian players from bringing personal staff such as hairstylists, chefs, and security guards during international tours. These measures aim to foster a professional and unified team environment following India's recent performance in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Players must use team transportation for all travel during matches and practice sessions.</li>
  <li>The new regulations are a response to recent team dynamics and are intended to enhance professionalism.</li>
  <li>These guidelines come after India's loss in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Quote:</strong> “The BCCI's stringent measures are aimed at ensuring a more professional and unified team culture,” reported ANI.</p>
<p>In conclusion, these new rules reflect the BCCI's commitment to improving team cohesion and performance as they move forward in international competitions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://inshorts.com/en/news/bcci-bars-india-players-from-taking-personal-hairstylists--chefs--security-guards-on-tours-1737037867532</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inshorts.com/en/news/bcci-bars-india-players-from-taking-personal-hairstylists--chefs--security-guards-on-tours-1737037867532</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:36:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India squads for Champions Trophy, England ODIs Highlights: Calls grow to pick Karun Nair and Devdutt Padikkal - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxNbmZEd0Zvdnk5RGNhZlZpbTl4Z0VucU04dWJTYTRWR2ZsZnpQeVdJcXdtS2RLX3E0TWNmaWtfT0d3T25PX0RReXNYdVBUVzU2c3NnZUs3ZmRUNTRrbTAyZlQtTDVPYm9oaVRwbWNtRDBxYmNjejhLb1k1aGF6U3hXdW9tS012WmhSUDVuaXJJQTV5MFZERHlZNjRaUDJvRmtGMUlzR3ZsY3hnQ2JOdmdIdjRaNGNDLVpuWUtvSURabnF5cF9ySWdtVmhzLUdIRVprbXk3WXhxT2o4US1LUUNXbFpxY3nSAeoBQVVfeXFMTkM1eU9FYlJEWkk1SEp5VUp4Q3JBQVVQNkZFU2FLbF9GbWd5NlpRb1dLamRybVZoN0JuTnV2dGsxczl3UEhWaXpJS2JhUVFJcTBfQTdlMVd2Y3U1a1FFVU0zTGpPd2tiR2dnSzY3RGllVHBzRWVrS1Y3MFItVkU1by05OURBc2NXQTlVV3V3ellpLVZPTkl4UGREVU8yMzRLeml2cGZodGotcjlNT3VKS3pxcUpZUEJ5a0xNOVlhX0tYWGFVSUEzQUVLTEV2bjdETUpyNWlRQ0R0NHgzU3l1Z20wUFhoYXFfbU9n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxNbmZEd0Zvdnk5RGNhZlZpbTl4Z0VucU04dWJTYTRWR2ZsZnpQeVdJcXdtS2RLX3E0TWNmaWtfT0d3T25PX0RReXNYdVBUVzU2c3NnZUs3ZmRUNTRrbTAyZlQtTDVPYm9oaVRwbWNtRDBxYmNjejhLb1k1aGF6U3hXdW9tS012WmhSUDVuaXJJQTV5MFZERHlZNjRaUDJvRmtGMUlzR3ZsY3hnQ2JOdmdIdjRaNGNDLVpuWUtvSURabnF5cF9ySWdtVmhzLUdIRVprbXk3WXhxT2o4US1LUUNXbFpxY3nSAeoBQVVfeXFMTkM1eU9FYlJEWkk1SEp5VUp4Q3JBQVVQNkZFU2FLbF9GbWd5NlpRb1dLamRybVZoN0JuTnV2dGsxczl3UEhWaXpJS2JhUVFJcTBfQTdlMVd2Y3U1a1FFVU0zTGpPd2tiR2dnSzY3RGllVHBzRWVrS1Y3MFItVkU1by05OURBc2NXQTlVV3V3ellpLVZPTkl4UGREVU8yMzRLeml2cGZodGotcjlNT3VKS3pxcUpZUEJ5a0xNOVlhX0tYWGFVSUEzQUVLTEV2bjdETUpyNWlRQ0R0NHgzU3l1Z20wUFhoYXFfbU9n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 16:12:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overlooked India Star's Average Hits 752 In Elite BCCI Event, Sends Strong Signal For Champions Trop.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Overlooked India Star's Average Hits 752 In Elite BCCI Event, Sends Strong Signal For Champions Trophy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/v118ruv8_karun-nair-x_625x300_12_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Overlooked India Star's Average Hits 752 In Elite BCCI Event, Sends Strong Signal For Champions Trophy"></p><figcaption>File photo of Karun Nair © X/Twitter</figcaption><p>Karun Nair has made headlines in the Vijay Hazare Trophy, achieving an impressive average of 752 after his latest performance. His exceptional scores and consistency hint at a strong showing in the upcoming Champions Trophy.</p><ul><li>Nair scored 88* runs in the second semi-final against Maharashtra, contributing to a total of 380 runs posted by his team.</li><li>He holds the distinction of being the first captain in Vijay Hazare Trophy to surpass 700 runs.</li><li>Nair's scoring performance includes two centuries, four half-centuries, and multiple unbeaten innings in the tournament.</li><li>After a challenging period of not being selected for the Karnataka team, he has revived his career playing for Vidarbha.</li></ul><blockquote>“Funnily enough I said I think I need to score a hundred in every single innings to kind of get noticed.” - Karun Nair</blockquote><p>Nair's latest run of form points towards a potential comeback at the national level, making his upcoming matches in the Champions Trophy highly anticipated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/overlooked-india-star-karun-nairs-average-hits-752-in-vijay-hazare-trophy-sends-strong-signal-for-champions-trophy-7489811</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/overlooked-india-star-karun-nairs-average-hits-752-in-vijay-hazare-trophy-sends-strong-signal-for-champions-trophy-7489811</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:49:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet Devisha Shetty, star India cricketer's wife who is a dance coach: Look at her luxurious lifestyle and educational qualification - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meet Devisha Shetty, Wife of India Cricketer Suryakumar Yadav: A Dance Coach and Her Luxurious Lifestyle</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/meet-devisha-shetty-star-india-cricketers-wife-who-is-a-dance-coach-look-at-her-luxurious-lifestyle-and-educational-qualification-202501-1737042016.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Devisha Shetty" />
<figcaption>Image credit: Instagram</figcaption>
<p>Devisha Shetty, the spouse of Indian cricketer Suryakumar Yadav, is an accomplished dance instructor and businesswoman. She is highly passionate about Bharatanatyam and has a deep affection for animals. Alongside Suryakumar, she leads a life filled with luxury.</p>
<ul>
<li>Devisha is known for her expertise in Bharatanatyam.</li>
<li>She hails from a respected South Indian family in Mumbai.</li>
<li>Her educational journey includes prestigious institutions like R.A. Podar College and H.R. College.</li>
<li>She has carved her path in the dance industry while supporting Suryakumar's cricket career.</li>
<li>They share a luxurious lifestyle, including high-end vehicles and stylish homes.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Devisha and Suryakumar share a motivating partnership, thriving in their respective fields.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Devisha Shetty's journey from a talented dancer to a successful coach and her luxurious partnership with Suryakumar Yadav highlight her dedication and passion for both her profession and personal life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/meet-devisha-shetty-star-india-cricketer-suryakumar-yadav-wife-who-is-a-dance-coach-look-at-her-luxurious-lifestyle-and-educational-qualification-420378/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/meet-devisha-shetty-star-india-cricketer-suryakumar-yadav-wife-who-is-a-dance-coach-look-at-her-luxurious-lifestyle-and-educational-qualification-420378/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WPL 2025 Schedule out! Holders RCB take on Gujarat Giants in season opener on February 14 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WPL 2025 Schedule out! Holders RCB take on Gujarat Giants in season opener on February 14</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>WPL Official</p>
<p>An exciting announcement has been made regarding the WPL 2025 season, as the defending champions, RCB, will open the tournament against the Gujarat Giants.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The first match is scheduled for February 14, 2025.</li>
  <li>RCB will aim to capitalize on their previous success in the league.</li>
  <li>The Gujarat Giants are looking to establish themselves as strong contenders this season.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The opening match promises to set the tone for an electrifying season ahead." - WPL Official</blockquote>
<p>This year's WPL is expected to draw significant attention as teams prepare for fierce competition and potential surprises in gameplay.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/wpl/wpl-2025-schedule-out-holders-rcb-take-on-gujarat-giants-in-season-opener-on-february-14/articleshow/117306396.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/wpl/wpl-2025-schedule-out-holders-rcb-take-on-gujarat-giants-in-season-opener-on-february-14/articleshow/117306396.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man Utd 'inform Napoli' how much they will sell Alejandro Garnacho for as exit door opens - Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Man Utd Set £60 Million Price for Garnacho's Transfer to Napoli</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Express.co.uk</p><p>Manchester United have demanded a staggering £60 million for Alejandro Garnacho's potential transfer to Napoli in the upcoming January transfer window.</p><ul><li>United rejected Napoli's initial £40 million bid for Garnacho.</li><li>Sir Jim Ratcliffe’s management is under pressure from the Premier League's Profit and Sustainability Rules.</li><li>Garnacho has been identified by Napoli as a top target to replace the outgoing Khvicha Kvaratskhelia.</li><li>The player, open to moving, has seen his starting position become uncertain.</li><li>Garnacho's recent performance included an assist in the FA Cup victory over Arsenal.</li></ul><blockquote>United's top brass insist Napoli must meet their £60 million valuation for any deal.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Manchester United is firm on their £60 million asking price for Garnacho amid growing interest from Napoli as they look to bolster their squad.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.express.co.uk/sport/football/2001393/Man-Utd-transfer-news-Napoli-Alejandro-Garnacho</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.express.co.uk/sport/football/2001393/Man-Utd-transfer-news-Napoli-Alejandro-Garnacho</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hurricanes seal home final with last-ball win; Heat and Australia sweat on Kuhnemann injury - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hurricanes Seal Home Final with Last-Ball Victory over Brisbane Heat</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Date Not Provided <strong>Source:</strong> Not Provided</p><p>In a thrilling encounter, the Hobart Hurricanes chased down the Brisbane Heat's total of 201 runs, winning by five wickets in a breathtaking finish.</p><img src='URL_to_image' alt='Hobart Hurricanes Celebration'><figcaption>Hobart Hurricanes celebrate their victory.</figcaption><p>The match showcased spectacular performances from both sides and had significant implications for the BBL finals.</p><ul><li>Hobart Hurricanes chased down 207 runs, achieving the target with a six from Matthew Wade on the last ball.</li><li>Caleb Jewell and Mitchell Owen provided a strong start for the Hurricanes with explosive batting.</li><li>Marnus Labuschagne starred for the Brisbane Heat with a commendable 77 runs.</li><li>A critical injury to spinner Matthew Kuhnemann raised concerns for Australia’s Test squad.</li><li>The result was vital for the finals chances of other teams including Adelaide Strikers and Perth Scorchers.</li></ul><blockquote>“Wade finished as the hero with a six off Xavier Bartlett that sailed over deep square leg.”</blockquote><p>This match kept the Hurricanes' finals hopes alive and has ramifications beyond just the win, highlighting the competitive nature of the BBL.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/big-bash-league-2024-25-1443056/brisbane-heat-vs-hobart-hurricanes-36th-match-1443092/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/big-bash-league-2024-25-1443056/brisbane-heat-vs-hobart-hurricanes-36th-match-1443092/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:48:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Retired Supreme Court Justice Arun Mishra appointed BCCI Ombudsman - Bar & Bench - Indian Legal News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Retired Supreme Court Justice Arun Mishra appointed BCCI Ombudsman</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-16T14:44:43.563Z" title="2025-01-16 14:44">16 Jan 2025, 2:44 pm</time></p><img src="https://www.bcci.tv/bcci-documentation-details/126485" alt="Justice Arun Mishra with BCCI Logo"><figcaption>Justice Arun Mishra with BCCI Logo</figcaption><p>Former Supreme Court judge Justice <strong>Arun Mishra</strong> has been appointed as the Ombudsman for the Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI), also serving as the BCCI Ethics Officer.</p><ul><li>Justice Mishra was the chairperson of the National Human Rights Commission (NHRC) before his current appointment.</li><li>He has a long career in law, having enrolled as a lawyer in 1978 and served as a judge in various high courts.</li><li>His tenure in the Supreme Court was marked by notable controversies.</li></ul><blockquote>“His tenure at the Supreme Court was marked by various controversies, prominent being the Judge Loya case and the Prashant Bhushan contempt of court case.”</blockquote><p>This appointment comes as a significant role within the BCCI, impacting the governance of cricket in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.barandbench.com/news/justice-arun-mishra-appointed-bcci-ombudsman</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.barandbench.com/news/justice-arun-mishra-appointed-bcci-ombudsman</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:44:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["If Sarfaraz Khan Leaked Dressing Room News In Australia, You...": Harbhajan Singh's Direct Message .. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Harbhajan Singh Urges Gautam Gambhir to Handle Dressing Room Rumors Wisely</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/5o5gfm6_harbhajan-singh-gautam-gambhir_625x300_16_January_25.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Harbhajan Singh and Gautam Gambhir"><figcaption>File photo of Harbhajan Singh and Gautam Gambhir © AFP</figcaption><p>Following controversies surrounding the India vs Australia Border Gavaskar Trophy, Indian cricket faces scrutiny over rumored leaks from the dressing room. Harbhajan Singh has a message for Gautam Gambhir regarding allegations against Sarfaraz Khan.</p><ul><li>Harbhajan emphasized the importance of privacy in the dressing room, criticizing any public disclosure of internal discussions.</li><li>He expressed concern over the impact of rumors on the team dynamic and stressed the need for better communication between players and coaching staff.</li><li>Singh highlighted the responsibility of senior players to guide younger team members and maintain harmony.</li><li>Sarfaraz Khan reportedly did not play in the recent Border Gavaskar series, which raised questions about his involvement in these controversies.</li></ul><blockquote>“You should not talk bad about your own family members in the open, that way your family's name gets tarnished.” - Harbhajan Singh</blockquote><p>Harbhajan Singh calls for unity and discretion within the cricket community, urging the need for internal resolution over public commentary.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/if-sarfaraz-khan-leaked-dressing-room-news-in-australia-you-harbhajan-singhs-direct-message-to-gautam-gambhir-7489239</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/if-sarfaraz-khan-leaked-dressing-room-news-in-australia-you-harbhajan-singhs-direct-message-to-gautam-gambhir-7489239</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:31:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India squads for Champions Trophy, England ODIs LIVE: Should India pick Karun Nair and Devdutt Padikkal? - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India squads for Champions Trophy, England ODIs LIVE: Should India pick Karun Nair and Devdutt Padikkal?</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 16, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Firstpost</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/12/India-Pakistan_Reuters-2024-12-ee8254d245f2529d5826d6c162d49460-1200x675.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="India squads for Champions Trophy, England ODIs LIVE: Should India pick Karun Nair and Devdutt Padikkal?" title="India squads for Champions Trophy, England ODIs LIVE: Should India pick Karun Nair and Devdutt Padikkal?">
<figcaption>India and Pakistan are the only remaining teams yet to announce their squad for the upcoming ICC Champions Trophy. Reuters</figcaption>
<p>The Indian cricket team is under scrutiny after a poor performance in Australia. With a chance to adjust the squad, players like Karun Nair and Devdutt Padikkal are being considered due to their exceptional form in domestic cricket.</p>
<ul>
  <li>BCCI seeks extension for Champions Trophy squad announcement.</li>
  <li>Shreyas Iyer expresses his desire to be included in the squad.</li>
  <li>Harsha Bhogle calls for an end to cricketers using PR agencies.</li>
  <li>Karun Nair shines with recent performances in the Vijay Hazare Trophy.</li>
  <li>Devdutt Padikkal emerges as a potential pick for the ODI squad.</li>
  <li>BCCI to announce squads for Englands ODIs and ICC Champions Trophy soon.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I never understood how he was dropped after a triple century. It pains me that no one talks about players like him.” - Harbhajan Singh</blockquote>
<p>The selection for the upcoming tournaments is crucial, and performances in the domestic leagues will play a significant role in determining the final squad.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/firstcricket/sports-news/india-icc-champions-trophy-2025-ind-vs-eng-odi-squad-announcement-live-updates-16-jan-13853242.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/firstcricket/sports-news/india-icc-champions-trophy-2025-ind-vs-eng-odi-squad-announcement-live-updates-16-jan-13853242.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:04:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Arsenal pushing to sign Benjamin Sesko in January transfer window - Pain In The Arsenal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arsenal Pursues Benjamin Sesko in January Transfer Window</h1><p><strong>Date: January 16, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Twitter</strong></p><p>Arsenal have identified RB Leipzig's Benjamin Sesko as their top transfer target and are pushing to sign the striker this month, according to reports.</p><ol><li>Arsenal seeks to sign Sesko, having reopened talks with RB Leipzig.</li><li>The Gunners are interested in an initial loan with a buy option, but Leipzig prefers an upfront payment.</li><li>Manager Mikel Arteta has communicated with Sesko multiple times about the move.</li><li>Sesko is highly regarded as one of Europe's top young strikers, with significant potential for growth.</li><li>Despite indications that a January move may be unlikely, the right offer could change Sesko's mind.</li></ol><blockquote>“🚨 EXCLUSIVE: Arsenal are in talks with RB Leipzig for Benjamin Sesko.” — Sam C (@SamC_reports)</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://paininthearsenal.com/arsenal-pushing-sign-benjamin-sesko-january-transfer-window</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://paininthearsenal.com/arsenal-pushing-sign-benjamin-sesko-january-transfer-window</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:46:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's Squad For Champions Trophy: Big Boost For Team India, Injured Star 'Locked In' For Comeback - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-squad-for-champions-trophy-injured-star-locked-in-comeback-on-the-cards-7485299</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/indias-squad-for-champions-trophy-injured-star-locked-in-comeback-on-the-cards-7485299</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:44:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Announce Playing XI For 1st Test vs West Indies; No Place For Imam-ul-Haq - OneCricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan Confirms Playing XI for 1st Test Against West Indies</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 17, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> One Cricket News</p><img width="474" height="240" src="https://onecricketnews.akamaized.net/parth-editor/oc-dashboard/news-images-prod/1737034742107_Babar_Azam.jpg?im=Resize=(650,450)?type=mq" alt="Pakistan will face West Indies in the first Test match (Source:@ziishankhan1,x.com)"><figcaption>Pakistan will face West Indies in the first Test match (Source:@ziishankhan1,x.com)</figcaption><p>In a significant development, Pakistan has revealed its playing XI for the opening Test against the West Indies, facing a side they aim to reclaim their form against after a recent series loss to South Africa.</p><ul><li>Mohammad Huraira will make his Test debut, replacing Saim Ayub due to injury.</li><li>Babar Azam will bat at three, following captain Shan Masood.</li><li>The bowling lineup is spin-heavy, featuring Noman Ali and Sajid Khan.</li><li>Khurram Shahzad is the only pace bowler in the squad.</li></ul><blockquote>“This solid core of experienced players will look to provide stability and support for Pakistan's batting line-up.”</blockquote><p>The anticipated spin-friendly conditions at the Multan Cricket Ground will be crucial for Pakistan's bowling strategy as they aim for a successful start against the West Indies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://cricket.one/cricket-news/babar-azam-at-3-masood-to-lead-as-pakistan-confirm-playing-xi-for-1st-test-vs-wi/6789094ea8a76e509f124373</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cricket.one/cricket-news/babar-azam-at-3-masood-to-lead-as-pakistan-confirm-playing-xi-for-1st-test-vs-wi/6789094ea8a76e509f124373</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:27:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BBL 2025: Match 37, SIX vs THU Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between SIX vs THU? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BBL 2025: Match 37, SIX vs THU Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between SIX vs THU?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1737023060081_image_2025_01_16T10_22_51_547Z.png" alt="SIX vs THU Match Prediction, Match 37 - Who will win today's BBL match between Sixers vs Thunder?" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption><p>The Big Bash League (BBL) 2025 features a crucial match between Sydney Sixers (SIX) and Sydney Thunder (THU) at the Sydney Cricket Ground.</p><ul><li>Sydney Sixers have qualified for the playoffs, leading the points table with six wins out of nine matches.</li><li>Sydney Thunder also made the playoffs, securing third place with five wins.</li><li>The match is scheduled for January 17, at 1:45 PM IST.</li><li>Pitch conditions indicate high-scoring potential, suggesting a target of 180+ when batting first.</li></ul><h2>Probable Top Performers</h2><p><strong>Best Batter:</strong> David Warner (Sydney Thunder) - 324 runs, average 54.</p><p><strong>Best Bowler:</strong> Ben Dwarshuis (Sydney Sixers) - 12 wickets, average 23.42.</p><p><strong>Today's Match Prediction:</strong> Sydney Sixers are favored to win the match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-37-six-vs-thu-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-six-vs-thu/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-37-six-vs-thu-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-six-vs-thu/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finger injury looms over van der Dussen as he consciously expands white-ball game - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxNdV83NWVrTTZ0SDZFa2t1OF9HWlJ2cWoydWpPdHdmN1JiRW9sRGdOSW8wb2hqdUlWS2ctclpGczRJc2xRUzFJRzBySzBFNFNaSGM4QVhSX2RpemNMRXRsZWJmMkREc2FQNmdZTjdoSmpkdzVvbkk0MkExdHFpLXRlektZRnB4NDhhSC1BODBVQWwwNDhqaVFJX3RUc1lnN1oybGw5N0RzU3p0dGJVVVZ6Skd2OHg2UGdBZUd5eUFNUEQ4ZDJsSmhYZ0lhdDlCUDZlellvUjloMW3SAeoBQVVfeXFMTXotMXdxbjcxOGExMHpIazFwSDljRy10NWlleUZ1NUlpNmJFaVBaQzM0OWdxQnpaMlJ1S3VxaGFxejNZRFdiaWx4dFdHZGJHeFZGS0I0ODg1UWVicmRxb1pPZEtVSXlGdU8zSWsxakFZUE53eExYQUd2bGplVk5pUGtWZm9nMFJabFFqVHZvZHJ3aUVuS21CT3c2MnVhTXZ4MGpoRHdBN0s2UGIyOGM4U2VJdnQya1dVSFdscll4ZFVqWW5UQWg0UmJmQW5mSlhEeTNFU3ZqLUhtVHVMZWpaczFkcTNOMXk0QU5B?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxNdV83NWVrTTZ0SDZFa2t1OF9HWlJ2cWoydWpPdHdmN1JiRW9sRGdOSW8wb2hqdUlWS2ctclpGczRJc2xRUzFJRzBySzBFNFNaSGM4QVhSX2RpemNMRXRsZWJmMkREc2FQNmdZTjdoSmpkdzVvbkk0MkExdHFpLXRlektZRnB4NDhhSC1BODBVQWwwNDhqaVFJX3RUc1lnN1oybGw5N0RzU3p0dGJVVVZ6Skd2OHg2UGdBZUd5eUFNUEQ4ZDJsSmhYZ0lhdDlCUDZlellvUjloMW3SAeoBQVVfeXFMTXotMXdxbjcxOGExMHpIazFwSDljRy10NWlleUZ1NUlpNmJFaVBaQzM0OWdxQnpaMlJ1S3VxaGFxejNZRFdiaWx4dFdHZGJHeFZGS0I0ODg1UWVicmRxb1pPZEtVSXlGdU8zSWsxakFZUE53eExYQUd2bGplVk5pUGtWZm9nMFJabFFqVHZvZHJ3aUVuS21CT3c2MnVhTXZ4MGpoRHdBN0s2UGIyOGM4U2VJdnQya1dVSFdscll4ZFVqWW5UQWg0UmJmQW5mSlhEeTNFU3ZqLUhtVHVMZWpaczFkcTNOMXk0QU5B?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:14:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pant axed, Samson promoted; Jaiswal is Rohit's new partner in India's Champions Trophy squad picked by Harbhajan, Sehwag - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pant axed, Samson promoted; Jaiswal is Rohit's new partner in India's Champions Trophy squad picked by Harbhajan, Sehwag</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 16, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/samson_jaiswal_1737032793041_1737032796918.jpg" alt="Virender Sehwag wants to see Yashasvi Jaiswal (L) play ODIs for India and Harbhajan vouches for Sanju Samson over Rishabh Pant.(AP-PTI)" title="Virender Sehwag wants to see Yashasvi Jaiswal (L) play ODIs for India and Harbhajan vouches for Sanju Samson over Rishabh Pant.(AP-PTI)">
<figcaption>Virender Sehwag wants to see Yashasvi Jaiswal (L) play ODIs for India and Harbhajan vouches for Sanju Samson over Rishabh Pant.(AP-PTI)</figcaption>
<p>As the cricketing world anticipates India's squad for the Champions Trophy 2025, former players Virender Sehwag and Harbhajan Singh share their insights on the final 15 players. Their choices suggest notable changes in the team, particularly regarding wicketkeeper and opener selections.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Harbhajan Singh advocates for Sanju Samson over Rishabh Pant as the preferred wicketkeeper.</li>
  <li>Virender Sehwag recommends young opener Yashasvi Jaiswal to partner with Rohit Sharma.</li>
  <li>India's selection process is closely tied to performances in the ongoing Vijay Hazare Trophy.</li>
  <li>The final squad is expected to be announced by January 19.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Sanju Samson is my choice. Sanju Samson would be the first-choice," said Harbhajan Singh about the wicketkeeper selection.</blockquote>
<p>With these recommendations, both Sehwag and Harbhajan are contributing to shaping India's lineup ahead of a crucial international tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/pant-axed-samson-promoted-jaiswal-is-rohits-new-partner-in-indias-champions-trophy-squad-picked-by-harbhajan-sehwag-101737032331401.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/pant-axed-samson-promoted-jaiswal-is-rohits-new-partner-in-indias-champions-trophy-squad-picked-by-harbhajan-sehwag-101737032331401.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:07:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SA20 2025: Match 10, JSK vs PC Match Prediction – Who will win today’s SA20 match between JSK vs PC? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SA20 2025: Match 10 Prediction – Joburg Super Kings vs Pretoria Capitals</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Thursday, January 16 | <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736933637031_image_2025_01_15T09_27_10_435Z.png" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption><p>The SA20 tournament continues with Joburg Super Kings (JSK) facing off against the Pretoria Capitals (PC) at the Wanderers Stadium in Johannesburg. JSK remains unbeaten in the tournament, while PC hopes to improve their standings.</p><ul><li><strong>Match:</strong> Joburg Super Kings vs Pretoria Capitals, Match 10, SA20 2025</li><li><strong>Venue:</strong> The Wanderers Stadium, Johannesburg</li><li><strong>Date & Time:</strong> Thursday, January 16, 9:00 pm IST</li><li><strong>Live Broadcast:</strong> Star Sports and Sports18 Network, Disney+ Hotstar</li></ul><h3>Pitch Report</h3><p>The pitch at the Wanderers Stadium is balanced, favoring both batters and bowlers. Winning the toss and opting to bowl may be a smart choice.</p><h3>Head-to-Head Record</h3><ul><li><strong>Matches Played:</strong> 4</li><li><strong>Won by JSK:</strong> 2</li><li><strong>Won by PC:</strong> 1</li><li><strong>No Result:</strong> 1</li></ul><h3>Predicted Playing XI</h3><p><strong>JSK:</strong> Faf du Plessis (c), Jonny Bairstow (wk), Wihan Lubbe, Sibonelo Makhanya, Moeen Ali, Donovan Ferreira, David Wiese, Hardus Viljoen, Gerald Coetzee, Tabraiz Shamsi, Imran Tahir.</p><p><strong>PC:</strong> Rahmanullah Gurbaz, Will Jacks, Steve Stolk, Rilee Rossouw (c), Kyle Verreynne (wk), Liam Livingstone, James Neesham, Senuran Muthusamy, Kyle Simmonds, Eathan Bosch, Daryn Dupavillon.</p><h3>Probable Top Performers</h3><ul><li><strong>Best Batter:</strong> Faf du Plessis – in good form with 247 runs in the last 10 matches.</li><li><strong>Best Bowler:</strong> Donovan Ferreira – two wickets with just 15 runs conceded in his last game.</li></ul><h3>Match Prediction</h3><p><strong>Prediction:</strong> Joburg Super Kings are predicted to win the match based on their current form.</p><p><strong>Scenario 1:</strong> JSK win the toss and opt to bowl first, likely winning with a score range of 155-165 for PC.</p><p><strong>Scenario 2:</strong> PC win the toss and bowl, with JSK still favored to win.</p><p><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> These predictions are based on analysis and should be taken as guidance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-10-jsk-vs-pc-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-jsk-vs-pc-0919/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-10-jsk-vs-pc-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-jsk-vs-pc-0919/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ILT20 2025: Match 7, DV vs MIE Match Prediction – Who will win today’s ILT20 match between DV vs MIE? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxQTk5WU3dLZWg4WkY5ZVZfaHJBQ0Z6ZzN1WVhkR2lSdTlXMFlZb05fMGRBdW1CVFctRjJTSHdpcUdMb3pySHZEdEFibEtwTDdhanhHUEdpaGU4bGxrY1hnZ19fdGxzUDRsb0VfV3VvVGd3TUNmSi1oR1k2ek5ZM0lGQ2xHZTB6a0I1MkJxYlhtczR0SjA2bElXUkZXMlJHSllGeGl1MUw3UjBWZ0RGQVp1Qnp6T2RraFZNMk5id3gwSXBzZ0kzM29JYWNnekJjTUtHbUxocWJEMDIxeEVGWW1pdFJmbi3SAewBQVVfeXFMTnZGS1BIZmZlMW8wOGhsUEk5RWNHd2F2RzFVVHhXSFFTdThKWGw0RkxZXy1OR091cFZUNjFrLWdvV1BWN2FkNFVOSkI5S2p3allSN3pZTTFDaUhWSENUX1ZEamtZekxNTW02V0lMamVHdkpKNkxZSVJGZDdFaXgxa0RxTUVfOXNGQzRyX1BocnVjTHFmODhVZmw2WVF5MVY3ZTZVdnZKQWhxLUg2S3ZRNXhKelFZZW9leERHbEE0S180clRVRHpJRmI1a2VHd0Zia09NLTBMdTNxQlVJUnI0b0lSTGhrVklPaUUyVHU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxQTk5WU3dLZWg4WkY5ZVZfaHJBQ0Z6ZzN1WVhkR2lSdTlXMFlZb05fMGRBdW1CVFctRjJTSHdpcUdMb3pySHZEdEFibEtwTDdhanhHUEdpaGU4bGxrY1hnZ19fdGxzUDRsb0VfV3VvVGd3TUNmSi1oR1k2ek5ZM0lGQ2xHZTB6a0I1MkJxYlhtczR0SjA2bElXUkZXMlJHSllGeGl1MUw3UjBWZ0RGQVp1Qnp6T2RraFZNMk5id3gwSXBzZ0kzM29JYWNnekJjTUtHbUxocWJEMDIxeEVGWW1pdFJmbi3SAewBQVVfeXFMTnZGS1BIZmZlMW8wOGhsUEk5RWNHd2F2RzFVVHhXSFFTdThKWGw0RkxZXy1OR091cFZUNjFrLWdvV1BWN2FkNFVOSkI5S2p3allSN3pZTTFDaUhWSENUX1ZEamtZekxNTW02V0lMamVHdkpKNkxZSVJGZDdFaXgxa0RxTUVfOXNGQzRyX1BocnVjTHFmODhVZmw2WVF5MVY3ZTZVdnZKQWhxLUg2S3ZRNXhKelFZZW9leERHbEE0S180clRVRHpJRmI1a2VHd0Zia09NLTBMdTNxQlVJUnI0b0lSTGhrVklPaUUyVHU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hurricanes seal home final with last-ball win; Heat, Australia sweat on Kuhnemann injury - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hurricanes Secure Home Final with Thrilling Last-Ball Victory Over Heat</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>In a nail-biting finish, the Hobart Hurricanes clinched a five-wicket victory over the Brisbane Heat, ensuring a home final in the Big Bash League (BBL). Matthew Wade's last-ball six marked a significant moment in the match, maintaining the finals hopes for other teams.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Hurricanes scored 207 for 5, thanks to significant contributions from Caleb Jewell (76) and Mitchell Owen (44).</li>
  <li>Brisbane Heat posted 201 for 6, with Marnus Labuschagne leading the charge with 77 runs.</li>
  <li>Matthew Wade hit a six off the final ball, leading to the win.</li>
  <li>Heat's Matthew Kuhnemann suffered an injury that may affect Australia's upcoming Test squad.</li>
  <li>This victory marks the Hurricanes' seventh consecutive win.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Wade finished as the hero with a six off Xavier Bartlett that sailed over deep square leg."</blockquote>
<p>The result not only secures the Hurricanes a home final but also keeps the hopes alive for other teams like Adelaide Strikers, Perth Scorchers, and Melbourne Renegades.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/big-bash-league-2024-25-1443056/brisbane-heat-vs-hobart-hurricanes-36th-match-1443092/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/big-bash-league-2024-25-1443056/brisbane-heat-vs-hobart-hurricanes-36th-match-1443092/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:41:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fact-Check: Did Rohit Sharma's Wife Ritika Sajdeh Slam Harsha Bhogle For 'Ban Team Members' PR Agenc.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fact-Check: Did Rohit Sharma's Wife Ritika Sajdeh Slam Harsha Bhogle For 'Ban Team Members' PR Agencies' Remark?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/tvq9mgs8_rohit-sharma-ritika-sajdeh-instagram-rohitsharma45_625x300_16_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Rohit Sharma with wife Ritika Sajdeh"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma (right) with wife Ritika Sajdeh. © Instagram/@rohitsharma45</figcaption><p>In the aftermath of India's loss to Australia, the BCCI is considering new regulations to address player conduct. Harsha Bhogle suggested banning team members from having PR agencies, which was contested by a parody account claiming to be Ritika Sajdeh.</p><ul><li>BCCI is contemplating new regulations after a 3-1 loss to Australia.</li><li>Players may be limited in their commuting options during matches and practice.</li><li>A fake account seemingly impersonating Ritika Sajdeh responded to Bhogle's tweet, claiming he was disrespecting her husband.</li><li>The real Ritika Sajdeh's account has nearly 250,000 followers.</li><li>Proposals include withholding match fees for skipping domestic tournaments.</li></ul><blockquote>“With due regards Harsha, This is misleading. You are implicitly calling out my husband. You can't disrespect the captain of ICT. Please, reconsider this.” — Ritika Sajdeh (@imkaisar53) January 15, 2025</blockquote><p>The BCCI's measures aim to ensure a professional team culture.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/did-rohit-sharmas-wife-ritika-sajdeh-slam-harsha-bhogle-for-ban-team-members-pr-agencies-remark-7488069</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/did-rohit-sharmas-wife-ritika-sajdeh-slam-harsha-bhogle-for-ban-team-members-pr-agencies-remark-7488069</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:37:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BPL 2024-2025: Match 22, CHK vs KHT Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BPL match between CHK vs KHT? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BPL 2024-25: Match 22, CHK vs KHT Match Prediction</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Thursday, January 16, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736935191170_image_2025_01_15T09_49_25_317Z.png" width="700" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Chittagong Kings vs Khulna Tigers Match Preview</figcaption><p>The BPL 2024-25 continues with Chittagong Kings facing Khulna Tigers at Zahur Ahmed Chowdhury Stadium. The Kings are currently second in the standings with three wins out of four games, while the Tigers are fourth with two wins and three losses.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>Match Date & Time: January 16, 2025, at 6:00 pm IST</li><li>Venue: Zahur Ahmed Chowdhury Stadium, Chattogram</li><li>Current Standings: CHK - 6 points, KHT - 4 points</li><li>Head-to-Head Record: CHK has won 7 out of 16 matches against KHT.</li></ul><blockquote>Prediction: Chittagong Kings to win the match.</blockquote><p>Scenarios indicate both teams may score decisively, with CHK being the more favorable side based on current form.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bpl-2024-2025-match-22-chk-vs-kht-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bpl-match-between-chk-vs-kht/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bpl-2024-2025-match-22-chk-vs-kht-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bpl-match-between-chk-vs-kht/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reports: No hairstylists, cooks and personal security guards to be allowed on tours after revised BCCI rules - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Implements New Rules to Restrict Personal Staff During Tours</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has introduced revised rules to enhance player discipline and professionalism following disappointing performances in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Players will no longer be permitted to travel with hairstylists, personal cooks, or private security guards during international tours.</li><li>Players must use team transportation for matches and practice, eliminating independent travel options.</li><li>Family members can only accompany players on overseas tours for limited durations: 14 days for tours longer than 45 days and one week for shorter tours.</li><li>Players skipping domestic cricket risks losing match fees unless valid reasons are provided.</li></ul><blockquote>“These measures are designed to minimise distractions and ensure players maintain their focus on cricket.”</blockquote><p>In response to the BCCI's new measures, players like Rohit Sharma and Shubman Gill have begun training with their state Ranji teams, indicating a push for greater involvement in domestic cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-news/bccis-revised-rules-says-no-to-hairstylists-cooks-and-personal-security-guards-on-tours/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-news/bccis-revised-rules-says-no-to-hairstylists-cooks-and-personal-security-guards-on-tours/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan star Shahid Afridi was afraid to bat against this bowler, the name will surprise you, his name is... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shahid Afridi Reveals His Fear of Facing Glenn McGrath</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/shahid-afridis-statement-on-glenn-mcgrath-202501-1737027644.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Shahid Afridi's statement on Glenn McGrath"><figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption><p>Former Pakistan cricketer Shahid Afridi opened up about his fear of batting against legendary Australian bowler Glenn McGrath during a recent podcast. This revelation highlights the respect and apprehension Afridi felt towards one of the greatest bowlers in cricket history.</p><ul><li>Afridi described batting against McGrath as the most challenging part of his career.</li><li>He noted McGrath's exceptional skill in line and length bowling, as well as his swing and bounce.</li><li>The statement has gained traction on social media ahead of the Champions Trophy 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“Batting against Glenn McGrath was the most difficult for any batsman. He not only bowled on the right line and length, but dealing with his swing and bounce was a big challenge for me.” - Shahid Afridi</blockquote><p>The upcoming ICC Champions Trophy 2025, where Pakistan is the host and defending champion, adds to the relevance of Afridi's comments as cricket fans anticipate the event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/pakistan-star-shahid-afridi-was-afraid-to-bat-against-this-bowler-the-name-will-surprise-you-his-name-is-glenn-mcgrath-420358/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/pakistan-star-shahid-afridi-was-afraid-to-bat-against-this-bowler-the-name-will-surprise-you-his-name-is-glenn-mcgrath-420358/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:45:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trent Alexander-Arnold major update as Liverpool star 'verbally agrees' Real Madrid deal - The Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQUkt5aFppR2h3NWtXODgtN1hnRGwydnpzQTZZanJ5eVdvazBuanBHM3RVRG5MREtTN29vRVNFWGh0clNoMXdjTmhOaTVmTnMtNFRYRHN5a2ZLaFVOMlVocWtQNHVQdVhSdElLRHFpOFBlZ2JDdElCRTk1bWM0T2thRHU4RDdmRlI0eGpJSjBHcVR5UldEM3U4Tks4cEpmRlU4cExld21sQ1JFZ9IBrwFBVV95cUxOT3BxUTNORXJDRE91MUJCZldDb1NVMndoa0NlUzgycUtPelhpTFN1eGwwNWV4eGdSenZRSEdFaTVXSS1XZGg0NHZmcEJsQ1d1aHpoSTFzOFFaSVRpOURFdDhMU1N1MGx3cWVfal9xcWdKQVpiYjladm1XaENQem1RUEdkSGZscVlPQUVPdWllbzB0bDJtbUdwMzB0OEVRZ2tZXzU5S3Rrc2V5MGFqanFF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQUkt5aFppR2h3NWtXODgtN1hnRGwydnpzQTZZanJ5eVdvazBuanBHM3RVRG5MREtTN29vRVNFWGh0clNoMXdjTmhOaTVmTnMtNFRYRHN5a2ZLaFVOMlVocWtQNHVQdVhSdElLRHFpOFBlZ2JDdElCRTk1bWM0T2thRHU4RDdmRlI0eGpJSjBHcVR5UldEM3U4Tks4cEpmRlU4cExld21sQ1JFZ9IBrwFBVV95cUxOT3BxUTNORXJDRE91MUJCZldDb1NVMndoa0NlUzgycUtPelhpTFN1eGwwNWV4eGdSenZRSEdFaTVXSS1XZGg0NHZmcEJsQ1d1aHpoSTFzOFFaSVRpOURFdDhMU1N1MGx3cWVfal9xcWdKQVpiYjladm1XaENQem1RUEdkSGZscVlPQUVPdWllbzB0bDJtbUdwMzB0OEVRZ2tZXzU5S3Rrc2V5MGFqanFF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI agrees to Gautam Gambhir's demand, appoints Sitanshu Kotak as batting coach - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxQbURNblpEalFZSjgzOTJFXzJRR1ZHS1AzNHZhbFFGN0t3TGVwMG5lQzFSemR5Nmk2Mk1jNWlCWlVEc2xLa2pEVXBwNDFCYXlqdTRoNW04NXEzVVRUQWVsbTUxcUNXT1NQVTRCcWxmdExfdXRjcWNjSDF3R0lzWnRyc3N4N2FvdW1waWw1WmoyeUxrWlhITUFLZ0ktS01JVmJPOHZDRXVWQWt3Q1dfVi1rQVFJRVJXUnM4RkV4TGJBRDhzd04wTTJ6NlJkMVVCcGsxN09QSEpBVXo4QmZ5cnRVSkpvcE9ENE9HMlFlZUxQNkZ6dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxQbURNblpEalFZSjgzOTJFXzJRR1ZHS1AzNHZhbFFGN0t3TGVwMG5lQzFSemR5Nmk2Mk1jNWlCWlVEc2xLa2pEVXBwNDFCYXlqdTRoNW04NXEzVVRUQWVsbTUxcUNXT1NQVTRCcWxmdExfdXRjcWNjSDF3R0lzWnRyc3N4N2FvdW1waWw1WmoyeUxrWlhITUFLZ0ktS01JVmJPOHZDRXVWQWt3Q1dfVi1rQVFJRVJXUnM4RkV4TGJBRDhzd04wTTJ6NlJkMVVCcGsxN09QSEpBVXo4QmZ5cnRVSkpvcE9ENE9HMlFlZUxQNkZ6dw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Get New Batting Coach, "Abhishek Nayar's Expertise Isn't Helping": Senior BCCI Official On Gau.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxQNkR6THRwQk5oOVdLWmtRU2U1SVVUSmVmZHAxOERoOTF3UUg1MmZveGN2MndVYVJYYnVhVVJyQkY0Yk5UaWhxSmVZV0c0Zm5xQlJlSldmdk1fU3VybTZGVnVVaFdHSmlaWkdVcDNIQ2Z4YUJqanBTVUkxeTR2SDJtYVVpQkhMUk5VeFFQZXZ2NzAxb0l4ZkxQam41b0J0b3h4SHYzRGZNNlZVaGoyMVFNWTNuNmlUZXlsdmRqN0UwYVFrZTVuTFpOejljYmhqM0RTU0FXTFBrR3h3SHp5Uzh5VmxnSHB6Z9IB7gFBVV95cUxNdmEwZVkzZXhQbkNIT25SQk9BOEpmM04yWm9JZlo5eVE2OVRKNlR5MXpRc2xfbjJfamVKa2k4Zzd2enVlZk8zZndtN0trd0ZZaWpaYTdiYjUzcElPZGRGUksxajFZLXVNUHNaeGdlU1NPbXV2M2xoV1FjRklpblZ0TWtwRzZJV2JNWUwtQ2FuNE1sRWpHa2VxVUEtSzZyY2JHbXBuZVo3UmRrMDdCMjh1QlgyLV9XZHpncUpwMThvU01QdmF3WmRReFY3UjdFbjNNRUZZNGs3eldubmVlZ1hUejRYZlJzM2Y0YlJmb29n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5gFBVV95cUxQNkR6THRwQk5oOVdLWmtRU2U1SVVUSmVmZHAxOERoOTF3UUg1MmZveGN2MndVYVJYYnVhVVJyQkY0Yk5UaWhxSmVZV0c0Zm5xQlJlSldmdk1fU3VybTZGVnVVaFdHSmlaWkdVcDNIQ2Z4YUJqanBTVUkxeTR2SDJtYVVpQkhMUk5VeFFQZXZ2NzAxb0l4ZkxQam41b0J0b3h4SHYzRGZNNlZVaGoyMVFNWTNuNmlUZXlsdmRqN0UwYVFrZTVuTFpOejljYmhqM0RTU0FXTFBrR3h3SHp5Uzh5VmxnSHB6Z9IB7gFBVV95cUxNdmEwZVkzZXhQbkNIT25SQk9BOEpmM04yWm9JZlo5eVE2OVRKNlR5MXpRc2xfbjJfamVKa2k4Zzd2enVlZk8zZndtN0trd0ZZaWpaYTdiYjUzcElPZGRGUksxajFZLXVNUHNaeGdlU1NPbXV2M2xoV1FjRklpblZ0TWtwRzZJV2JNWUwtQ2FuNE1sRWpHa2VxVUEtSzZyY2JHbXBuZVo3UmRrMDdCMjh1QlgyLV9XZHpncUpwMThvU01QdmF3WmRReFY3UjdFbjNNRUZZNGs3eldubmVlZ1hUejRYZlJzM2Y0YlJmb29n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:30:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI ditches big names, picks Sitanshu Kotak as India batting coach; to start rescue mission from England series: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI ditches big names, picks Sitanshu Kotak as India batting coach; to start rescue mission from England series: Report</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-0_1737024031591_1737024041533.jpg" alt="India's captain Jasprit Bumrah (C) talks with coach Gautam Gambhir (3rd L) and teammates before the start of day three of the fifth cricket Test match between Australia and India(AFP)" />
<figcaption>India's captain Jasprit Bumrah (C) talks with coach Gautam Gambhir (3rd L) and teammates before the start of day three of the fifth cricket Test match between Australia and India(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>India’s cricket board has appointed Sitanshu Kotak as the new batting coach, starting with the upcoming home series against England, following the team’s recent poor performances.</p>
<ul>
<li>Kevin Pietersen expressed interest in the batting coach position, but BCCI chose Kotak.</li>
<li>India will play five T20Is and three ODIs against England starting January 22.</li>
<li>Kotak previously served as the India A batting coach and has extensive coaching experience.</li>
<li>The current coaching staff includes Gautam Gambhir, Morne Morkel, T Dilip, and assistant coaches Abhishek Nayar and Ryan ten Doeschate.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Kotak will be joining the Indian team as a batting coach. The Indian team will be having a three day-camp in Kolkata and players will be reporting on January 18.”</blockquote>
<p>Sitanshu Kotak's extensive experience and domestic cricket record make him a promising choice to bolster India's batting lineup.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/bcci-ditches-big-names-identifies-india-new-batting-coach-sitanshu-kotak-starts-rescue-mission-from-england-home-series-101737023598008.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/bcci-ditches-big-names-identifies-india-new-batting-coach-sitanshu-kotak-starts-rescue-mission-from-england-home-series-101737023598008.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 11:23:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>