<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 11:17:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 11:17:09 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah's Action Questioned, Australian Broadcaster Makes Controversy-Prone Remark - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ian Maurice Questions Jasprit Bumrah's Bowling Action Ahead of Boxing Day Test</h1><p><strong>Date: December 24, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: NDTV Sports</strong></p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/4jp4gg78_jasprit-bumrah-afp_625x300_15_December_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Jasprit Bumrah's Action Questioned" width="639" height="479"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah's Action Questioned, Australian Broadcaster Makes Controversy-Prone Remark</figcaption><p>The upcoming Boxing Day Test between India and Australia is marred by controversy as Ian Maurice questions Jasprit Bumrah's bowling action, amid other off-field incidents involving Indian players.</p><ul><li>Ian Maurice accuses Bumrah of having a suspect bowling action.</li><li>Further criticisms were aimed at Indian players, including Virat Kohli and Ravindra Jadeja.</li><li>Maurice urges Australian media to scrutinize Bumrah's bowling technique.</li><li>Bumrah is India's leading wicket-taker in the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy series.</li></ul><blockquote>I wish you people who want to jump down my throat would bother to read what I wrote. I said "I'M NOT SAYING HE'S THROWING ... but his action should be analyzed...that's all!" — Ian Maurice (@ian_maurice)</blockquote><p>The controversy highlights ongoing scrutiny over bowling actions in cricket, especially in Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/jasprit-bumrahs-action-questioned-australian-broadcaster-makes-controversy-prone-remark-7320849</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/jasprit-bumrahs-action-questioned-australian-broadcaster-makes-controversy-prone-remark-7320849</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 10:08:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India women vs West Indies women, 2nd ODI LIVE Score: Pratika departs for 78; IND-W 185/2 vs WI-W - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India women vs West Indies women, 2nd ODI LIVE Score: Harleen, Harmanpreet take IND-W towards 200; IND-W 191/2</h1><p><strong>Date Published:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Sportstar</p><img src="https://ss-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/3u4nmf/article69021888.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/WhatsApp%20Image%202024-12-24%20at%2012.12.09%20PM.jpeg" alt="India vs West Indies 2nd ODI"/><figcaption>Live coverage of the second ODI match between India and West Indies at the Vadodara International Cricket Stadium.</figcaption><p>The article provides live commentary, score updates, and highlights from the ongoing match between India's women team and the West Indies women's team.</p><ul><li>India has scored 191 runs for the loss of 2 wickets.</li><li>Harleen Deol and Harmanpreet Kaur are key players in the ongoing innings.</li><li>The match is being held at the Vadodara International Cricket Stadium.</li><li>Live commentary and score updates are available through Sportstar.</li></ul><blockquote>'FIFTY for Pratika! First one for the opener in international cricket.'</blockquote><p>This ODI match is crucial as India aims to secure the series win following their earlier victories.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/womens-cricket/india-vs-west-indies-womens-odi-2nd-match-live-score-streaming-telecast-scorecard-playing-11/article69020504.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/womens-cricket/india-vs-west-indies-womens-odi-2nd-match-live-score-streaming-telecast-scorecard-playing-11/article69020504.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 09:24:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli vs the fifth stump: A battle of will and skill ahead of the Boxing Day Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Virat Kohli vs the Fifth Stump: A Battle of Will and Skill Ahead of the Boxing Day Test</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not provided | <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116625876,imgsize-51692,width-400,resizemode-4/116625876.jpg" alt="Virat Kohli vs the fifth stump: A battle of will and skill ahead of the Boxing Day Test" title="Virat Kohli (PTI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Virat Kohli during his net session at the MCG.</figcaption>
<p>As India prepares for the Boxing Day Test, Virat Kohli is honing his skills, particularly focusing on his discipline against deliveries outside off-stump.</p>
<ul>
<li>Kohli is seen practicing in the nets at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG).</li>
<li>Rohit Sharma expresses confidence in Kohli's ability to overcome challenges.</li>
<li>He is working on leaving balls outside the off-stump while facing quick bowlers.</li>
<li>Kohli actively engages with bowlers to understand the impact of deliveries.</li>
<li>Despite challenges, there is optimism that Kohli will find his form in the upcoming Test.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Modern day greats will figure out their way… path,” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote>
<p>The outcome of this self-battle for Kohli will be crucial for India's performance, especially with significant crowd expectations for the Boxing Day Test.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/virat-kohli-vs-the-fifth-stump-a-battle-of-will-and-skill-ahead-of-the-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116625698.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/virat-kohli-vs-the-fifth-stump-a-battle-of-will-and-skill-ahead-of-the-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116625698.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 09:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Thankful To Sachin Tendulkar...": Vinod Kambli's Big Message After Urgent Hospitalisation - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Thankful To Sachin Tendulkar...: Vinod Kambli's Big Message After Urgent Hospitalisation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 &nbsp;| &nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hlqqq0m8_vinod-kambli-pti_625x300_24_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Vinod Kambli" /><figcaption>Vinod Kambli expresses his gratitude after being hospitalized.</figcaption><p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli expressed his thankfulness towards Sachin Tendulkar following his hospitalization due to health complications. Kambli recently faced severe health issues along with brain clots but is now showing signs of recovery.</p><ul><li>Kambli was hospitalized after a fan took him due to a health scare.</li><li>Medical tests indicated the presence of clots in his brain, but updates show he is recovering.</li><li>He acknowledged Tendulkar’s emotional support during difficult times.</li><li>Doctors are monitoring Kambli's health closely and have promised lifelong medical care.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am feeling better now...I will never leave this (cricket) because I remember the number of centuries and double centuries I have hit...I am thankful to Sachin Tendulkar as his blessings have always been with me...” - Vinod Kambli</blockquote><p>Kambli is on a path to recovery with support from his family and friends, emphasizing the importance of community during challenging times.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/thankful-to-sachin-tendulkar-vinod-kamblis-big-message-after-urgent-hospitalisation-7320897</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/thankful-to-sachin-tendulkar-vinod-kamblis-big-message-after-urgent-hospitalisation-7320897</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 08:21:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I shouldn't have gone to the Olympics and won medals for the country': Manu Bhaker devastated by Khel Ratna axe - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manu Bhaker Heartbroken Over Khel Ratna Exclusion</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/PTI12-23-2024-000271B-0_1735026596892_1735026608907.jpg" alt="Manu Bhaker isn't happy(PTI)">
<figcaption>Manu Bhaker isn't happy(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Manu Bhaker, the celebrated shooter and twin medal winner at the Paris Olympics, is devastated after being excluded from the Rajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna award shortlist despite her historic achievements.</p>
<ul>
<li>Manu Bhaker won two bronze medals at the Paris Olympics 2024, becoming the first Indian athlete of the Independence era to achieve this feat.</li>
<li>Despite being a strong candidate, she was not shortlisted for the Khel Ratna award.</li>
<li>Bhaker's father shared her disappointment, stating she felt she shouldn't have participated in the Olympics at all.</li>
<li>The sports ministry's decision has drawn backlash from fans and may prompt reconsideration.</li>
<li>She has a remarkable record of 17 gold, six silver, and five bronze medals in various shooting events since the Tokyo Games.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I shouldn't have gone to the Olympics and won medals for the country. In fact, I shouldn't have become a sportsperson.” - Manu Bhaker</blockquote>
<p>This exclusion has sparked significant discussion among sports fans and officials, potentially influencing future deliberations on recognition for athletes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/i-shouldnt-have-gone-to-the-olympics-and-won-medals-for-the-country-manu-bhaker-devastated-by-khel-ratna-axe-101735026477264.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/i-shouldnt-have-gone-to-the-olympics-and-won-medals-for-the-country-manu-bhaker-devastated-by-khel-ratna-axe-101735026477264.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 07:53:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Predicted India Playing XI for IND vs AUS 4th Test: Siraj all but out, Rohit Sharma could go with two spinners - InsideSport]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxQWktfYkI0UHY0anFaVzhHU0RFbFRnNWE5aE5RazlRTjZGOUlXTXZ3NEZXanAzcWhzUGhISWxTWTBsRTIwS0VVNDRxWXoyYnhKdDNDam5mcTgxQ0M5RnE3LTNsTklaaEZNVzFfZWNGaVAwWkdDbHpSb0tydzU3TUxKVjJSMUJRM1FTUjA2d21GNHpLQThDX1pvNW8xT2o0QVVfUjJST2VmTEc1bUFDdlJvZjBwS3ZNN2loWWRHZXZLNU9BZzBhOUtWQ2NEbXNHLV9PdFRKMzlJWHloQlZ0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxQWktfYkI0UHY0anFaVzhHU0RFbFRnNWE5aE5RazlRTjZGOUlXTXZ3NEZXanAzcWhzUGhISWxTWTBsRTIwS0VVNDRxWXoyYnhKdDNDam5mcTgxQ0M5RnE3LTNsTklaaEZNVzFfZWNGaVAwWkdDbHpSb0tydzU3TUxKVjJSMUJRM1FTUjA2d21GNHpLQThDX1pvNW8xT2o0QVVfUjJST2VmTEc1bUFDdlJvZjBwS3ZNN2loWWRHZXZLNU9BZzBhOUtWQ2NEbXNHLV9PdFRKMzlJWHloQlZ0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 07:34:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MCG pitch to have 'pace, bounce and excitement', but what about runs? - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxQOXFTWHVsME1hTkRCRGhZNWVWSmN4SWpyaVNmei1fYS1zOTVyRWNLVlNUa2pqVVM4QTlUaUVtbHJpUUlpaTk5aG4zay1NQjRsZXdlb0ZRSllxZjBEYlFXV0tSYVNjUGNMOUpVU2t1VWlINTZTUjR1WUpYSXhOREJfYjJsVF8xLVV5ZmFGS2hPU1pPcS1xR2kxcktwa193MHRrN2RkLUM4UXowaXF4SVhYcHFNMUJjVzVDeHUwazVwV1NXczBFM243Y1Y2NNIB3AFBVV95cUxNOGI3bWI4dVBfZnZ3cExibWdNbTFOZ0RHVnBOdEtCTDFQYUQzcXhhNFZQQkhLbE9Qbm0zZTBQZkhsZ1VuaHVma19UdThZSy1sZ2haT1BlNDhZWlduZlV4R3gxblpsNTBfdEJudENXMkF5dllHV3ZwbFRoQ1dhUXZpa2pyY014MlZHRFVkOTE4REZwdzRMV0t6Mll6cmM5LXpHOElCOHpQeUVsamYzNXVUN0lhd3hvc3R2Q0RVMjZwQWFlWHh1SjlITmVWVThFNHEzelJ4Ui0zNi1Oenho?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxQOXFTWHVsME1hTkRCRGhZNWVWSmN4SWpyaVNmei1fYS1zOTVyRWNLVlNUa2pqVVM4QTlUaUVtbHJpUUlpaTk5aG4zay1NQjRsZXdlb0ZRSllxZjBEYlFXV0tSYVNjUGNMOUpVU2t1VWlINTZTUjR1WUpYSXhOREJfYjJsVF8xLVV5ZmFGS2hPU1pPcS1xR2kxcktwa193MHRrN2RkLUM4UXowaXF4SVhYcHFNMUJjVzVDeHUwazVwV1NXczBFM243Y1Y2NNIB3AFBVV95cUxNOGI3bWI4dVBfZnZ3cExibWdNbTFOZ0RHVnBOdEtCTDFQYUQzcXhhNFZQQkhLbE9Qbm0zZTBQZkhsZ1VuaHVma19UdThZSy1sZ2haT1BlNDhZWlduZlV4R3gxblpsNTBfdEJudENXMkF5dllHV3ZwbFRoQ1dhUXZpa2pyY014MlZHRFVkOTE4REZwdzRMV0t6Mll6cmM5LXpHOElCOHpQeUVsamYzNXVUN0lhd3hvc3R2Q0RVMjZwQWFlWHh1SjlITmVWVThFNHEzelJ4Ui0zNi1Oenho?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 07:08:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker Khel Ratna row: Why exception was made for Mohammed Shami last year - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manu Bhaker Khel Ratna row: Why exception was made for Mohammed Shami last year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Available <strong>Source:</strong> Not Available</p><p>In this article, the controversy surrounding the Khel Ratna award exemptions for athletes like Mohammed Shami is discussed, highlighting the discrepancies in eligibility and recognition.</p><ul><li>Focus on the Khel Ratna award and its significance.</li><li>Discussion of exceptions made in awarding athletes.</li><li>Comparison with other athletes and their eligibility.</li><li>Impact of this decision on sports recognition in India.</li></ul><blockquote>Quote or statistic related to the impact of these decisions on athletes.</blockquote><p>This situation raises important questions about fairness and transparency in sports awards.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/more-sports/others/manu-bhaker-khel-ratna-row-why-exception-was-made-for-mohammed-shami-last-year/articleshow/116621625.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/more-sports/others/manu-bhaker-khel-ratna-row-why-exception-was-made-for-mohammed-shami-last-year/articleshow/116621625.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Shubman Gill ko bula do': Rohit Sharma annoyed at female fan's repeated request during India's MCG net session – Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Annoyed by Fan's Request for Shubman Gill During MCG Net Session</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-48_1735020611372_1735020647548.jpg" alt="India's Rohit Sharma (R) gestures during day five of the third cricket Test match between Australia and India at The Gabba(AFP)" title="India's Rohit Sharma (R) gestures during day five of the third cricket Test match between Australia and India at The Gabba(AFP)"><figcaption>India's Rohit Sharma (R) gestures during day five of the third cricket Test match between Australia and India at The Gabba(AFP)</figcaption><p>During India's training session at the MCG, Rohit Sharma faced an awkward moment when a female fan repeatedly requested him to call Shubman Gill, who had already left the nets.</p><ul><li>India's first training session at MCG amidst the Border-Gavaskar Trophy series.</li><li>Rohit Sharma was approached by a female fan asking for Shubman Gill after the session.</li><li>Rohit expressed annoyance when the fan persisted with her request.</li><li>The fan revealed she was late due to a fractured leg and expressed support for Gill.</li></ul><blockquote>“Where will I get him?” - Rohit Sharma's response to the persistent fan.</blockquote><p>The incident highlights the challenges faced by players during public interactions, especially in high-pressure environments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/shubman-gill-ko-bulado-rohit-sharma-left-annoyed-injured-fan-repeated-request-india-mcg-net-session-101735020333351.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/shubman-gill-ko-bulado-rohit-sharma-left-annoyed-injured-fan-repeated-request-india-mcg-net-session-101735020333351.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:40:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma breaks silence on Virat Kohli's outside off-stump woes: ‘You only said he’s a modern-day great' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Discusses Virat Kohli's Struggles With Outside Off-Stump Deliveries</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/Australia-India-Cricket-32_1735020677273_1735020766952.jpg" alt="India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and teammate Virat Kohli leave the field(AP)" title="India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and teammate Virat Kohli leave the field(AP)" />
<figcaption>India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and teammate Virat Kohli leave the field(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Rohit Sharma has addressed the media regarding Virat Kohli's recent difficulties with deliveries outside the off-stump during the Border-Gavaskar Trophy, expressing confidence that Kohli will find a way to score runs in the upcoming Tests.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rohit laughed when asked about Kohli's form, emphasizing Kohli's status as a modern-day great.</li>
  <li>Kohli has had a challenging series, with only one century to his name so far.</li>
  <li>Multiple bowlers, including Boland and Hazlewood, have troubled Kohli with their bowling style.</li>
  <li>Rohit himself is also struggling, particularly with in-swing deliveries.</li>
  <li>The upcoming Boxing Day Test is crucial for India's batting lineup as the series is tied 1-1.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“You only said he is a modern-day great. Modern-day greats will figure out their way or the path (to overcome issues),” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote>
<p>Sharma remains confident that both he and Kohli will rectify their issues as they prepare for the important matches ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-breaks-silence-on-virat-kohlis-off-stump-woes-in-australia-you-only-said-he-s-a-modern-day-great-101735020561996.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-breaks-silence-on-virat-kohlis-off-stump-woes-in-australia-you-only-said-he-s-a-modern-day-great-101735020561996.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:15:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tanush Kotian to join India's Test squad as Ashwin's replacement - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tanush Kotian to Join India's Test Squad as Ashwin's Replacement</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert date here] | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p><img src='https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg' alt='Tanush Kotian' /><figcaption>Tanush Kotian</figcaption></p><p>Tanush Kotian, a crucial player for Mumbai, has been selected to replace R Ashwin in the Indian squad for the upcoming Border-Gavaskar Trophy Tests due to Ashwin's retirement.</p><ul><li>Kotian is traveling to Melbourne following Ashwin's retirement after the third Test.</li><li>He is seen as a backup for spinners Washington Sundar and Ravindra Jadeja, with Axar Patel unavailable.</li><li>Rohit Sharma commented on Kotian's call-up, highlighting his domestic achievements.</li><li>Kotian's impressive Ranji Trophy performance last season contributed to Mumbai's victory, leading to him being named Player-of-the-Tournament.</li><li>He has played 33 first-class matches, recorded 101 wickets, and scored 1525 runs.</li></ul><blockquote>"Tanush was the right option for us at this point. He's certainly shown in the domestic level what he's capable of. He's probably one of the reasons why Mumbai has gone on to win the Ranji Trophy last year." <cite>Rohit Sharma</cite></blockquote><p>With many players unavailable, Kotian's inclusion marks a significant opportunity for the young allrounder in international cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-tanush-kotian-join-india-squad-ashwin-replacement-1466332</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-tanush-kotian-join-india-squad-ashwin-replacement-1466332</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 06:03:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Women vs West Indies Women Match Prediction - Who will win today’s 2nd ODI match between IND-W vs WI-W? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxNdF8xNXVoR19acG9aT0RUSnVmcFV5a0RKV0xQXzdTbVk0cTMtOHFNdk1QejBHZUVwYTAxZXpSdnhjT3hsY0lOdThlelJTT0loZTA5Tnp5a0JGblR4c2wyYUM0bGJtWHBKOF9YTENfUVgtSlQzeU1mb3VMOFpmUlNJM2doc1hLNHc1b2ZCdGVsYkVyeXl2N0Q3RFRHM2lIN2YwcGo4M2tEcDRtUTlFa0FZNzltNl93VmEzMXhaSEN4elowU3loM3VRUUVvR1Z3VXVHN0UyQTQ3elg4TVFaTTdDWDZwRzI3eldGQnAwN3dIclE5QdIB-gFBVV95cUxNS1pmZHRJb29tYWprWHpzZ2FuQWlCWlI4cTFBc01SYWIzVEhRcTNxcUVNTWVHVTdxR1RFV05XUjZhWXUtTU5oZXUzVHhjZWw3R3ZndG12U1lwMjl0RUFlWjJ3VWhKR2hjTTBrWVBMYm1RVzRRUzN3b2Eta1pfSTRrVDF1eHZxVmk2VHk3WXBqVVNqTEc4dEtSakZZUGZ5MGh5MktaRHJVZU95MkJDcmZEMjRWOFVaV1ZFUjRmVnVaTnNsYUdHalJ3SzZnOG94MDJMYW1fUV9IdmdyWWpVOGZXakNzZmxKaHQ1SFh0VUlMdzg0bVJVR0FNLTZn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxNdF8xNXVoR19acG9aT0RUSnVmcFV5a0RKV0xQXzdTbVk0cTMtOHFNdk1QejBHZUVwYTAxZXpSdnhjT3hsY0lOdThlelJTT0loZTA5Tnp5a0JGblR4c2wyYUM0bGJtWHBKOF9YTENfUVgtSlQzeU1mb3VMOFpmUlNJM2doc1hLNHc1b2ZCdGVsYkVyeXl2N0Q3RFRHM2lIN2YwcGo4M2tEcDRtUTlFa0FZNzltNl93VmEzMXhaSEN4elowU3loM3VRUUVvR1Z3VXVHN0UyQTQ3elg4TVFaTTdDWDZwRzI3eldGQnAwN3dIclE5QdIB-gFBVV95cUxNS1pmZHRJb29tYWprWHpzZ2FuQWlCWlI4cTFBc01SYWIzVEhRcTNxcUVNTWVHVTdxR1RFV05XUjZhWXUtTU5oZXUzVHhjZWw3R3ZndG12U1lwMjl0RUFlWjJ3VWhKR2hjTTBrWVBMYm1RVzRRUzN3b2Eta1pfSTRrVDF1eHZxVmk2VHk3WXBqVVNqTEc4dEtSakZZUGZ5MGh5MktaRHJVZU95MkJDcmZEMjRWOFVaV1ZFUjRmVnVaTnNsYUdHalJ3SzZnOG94MDJMYW1fUV9IdmdyWWpVOGZXakNzZmxKaHQ1SFh0VUlMdzg0bVJVR0FNLTZn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 05:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: Ball Hits The Roof Of Stadium In Big Bash League 2024, Injures Bowler's Hand - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxOY0V6SjVKNFhNaDkyV3puQmNXMkpCdHVYQkdtNjBOeTdkNXAxREdWakV4VmJKLTJuQ3pON2p1Zk9vMk4wdUtqdk5CX3lCLXZzVE1qNF9jVHdHUWxYTF9HUnpkbnBIQWZ6Ym1ISnlUNkJRUWExdWVPaW8ta2ZyNVJoT0pXSXI0cU5ROEZ1WW1QQ0ZtbHI1M1Y1a1I1QWw5czUzSnk1YTVNX3BISExGcUJVVUdXUXpsUnQtMlBFV9IBxAFBVV95cUxQZGtBZnM2Tjd5Y0NaSGl1aF9vT1l5ZTdWdnlCOWxaaEtRSklCOUdmd3ZINFpGSVc1RVQzaGhMVlNhczhVUDVtZ3pPLUM4Z1lKeGtWVlMxS000b05MNXVpMHVPb3o5ampaVGR6S3JROE5UbGZUb0hFbVllSXZUNTZjMFZ5VDVBRWpmSEtEb2NCdG81SWJNcmI5cHd0TDV4eGZsVnIwU0ZTRU4waWF5ZTJrRWNFa3pMMWt1SllhNzBxaG1uVE9w?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxOY0V6SjVKNFhNaDkyV3puQmNXMkpCdHVYQkdtNjBOeTdkNXAxREdWakV4VmJKLTJuQ3pON2p1Zk9vMk4wdUtqdk5CX3lCLXZzVE1qNF9jVHdHUWxYTF9HUnpkbnBIQWZ6Ym1ISnlUNkJRUWExdWVPaW8ta2ZyNVJoT0pXSXI0cU5ROEZ1WW1QQ0ZtbHI1M1Y1a1I1QWw5czUzSnk1YTVNX3BISExGcUJVVUdXUXpsUnQtMlBFV9IBxAFBVV95cUxQZGtBZnM2Tjd5Y0NaSGl1aF9vT1l5ZTdWdnlCOWxaaEtRSklCOUdmd3ZINFpGSVc1RVQzaGhMVlNhczhVUDVtZ3pPLUM4Z1lKeGtWVlMxS000b05MNXVpMHVPb3o5ampaVGR6S3JROE5UbGZUb0hFbVllSXZUNTZjMFZ5VDVBRWpmSEtEb2NCdG81SWJNcmI5cHd0TDV4eGZsVnIwU0ZTRU4waWF5ZTJrRWNFa3pMMWt1SllhNzBxaG1uVE9w?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 05:19:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suryakumar, Shreyas Iyer, Shivam Dube at No 8, 9 and 10? Mumbai's ploy goes awry; saved by Ashwin's India replacement - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai's Unconventional Batting Order Pays Off With Iyer and Kotian's Heroics</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>by:</strong> HT Sports Desk</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/CRICKET-WORLDCUP-IND-LKA--213_1698946750775_1735014715047.JPG" alt="India's Shreyas Iyer and Suryakumar Yadav (REUTERS)" title="India's Shreyas Iyer and Suryakumar Yadav (REUTERS)">
<figcaption>India's Shreyas Iyer and Suryakumar Yadav (REUTERS)</figcaption>
<p>Mumbai's cricket team faced a tough challenge during their chase against Hyderabad in the Vijay Hazare Trophy, but a remarkable effort from Shreyas Iyer and Tanush Kotian turned the tide for them, securing a three-wicket victory.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Mumbai attempted a risky strategy by reversing their batting order.</li>
  <li>They struggled initially, losing six wickets for just 67 runs.</li>
  <li>Suryakumar Yadav entered at No. 8 and helped stabilize the innings.</li>
  <li>Iyer contributed significantly with a quick score of 44 runs off 20 balls.</li>
  <li>Mumbai chased down the target of 170, finishing at 175 runs for 7 wickets.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The plan failed initially, but teamwork saved the day for Mumbai."</blockquote>
<p>This match showcased the unpredictability of cricket and how unconventional strategies can lead to unexpected victories.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/suryakumar-yadav-shreyas-iyer-shivam-dube-no-8-9-10-mumbai-ploy-awry-saved-ashwin-india-replacement-tanush-kotian-101735014464489.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/suryakumar-yadav-shreyas-iyer-shivam-dube-no-8-9-10-mumbai-ploy-awry-saved-ashwin-india-replacement-tanush-kotian-101735014464489.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 05:12:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[On Doubts Over Travis Head's Participation In Boxing Day Test, Australia Coach Paints Clear Picture - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>On Doubts Over Travis Head's Participation In Boxing Day Test, Australia Coach Paints Clear Picture</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/kn65a0jg_travis-head_625x300_15_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Travis Head" /><figcaption>Travis Head during practice ahead of the Boxing Day Test.</figcaption><p>Ahead of the fourth Test against India, Australia coach Andrew McDonald reassures that Travis Head is fit to play after a minor quad strain.</p><ul><li>Travis Head suffered a minor quad strain during the Brisbane Test but had a short running and fielding session on Tuesday.</li><li>He is the leading run-scorer in the series with 409 runs at an average of 81.80.</li><li>Coach McDonald reported no major fitness concerns regarding Head's participation.</li><li>McDonald expressed confidence, stating Head has completed running drills and appears ready for the match.</li><li>In his career against India, Head averages 51.09 in Tests and has scored 897 runs at an average of 74.75 since the WTC final.</li><li>Australia and India are level at 1-1 in the series with two matches remaining.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no concern at the moment. Has he been officially ticked off? I am not sure... But no concerns from my end.” - Andrew McDonald</blockquote><p>The reassurance from the coach bodes well for Australia's chances as they prepare for a crucial encounter at the MCG.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/on-doubts-over-travis-heads-participation-in-boxing-day-test-australia-coach-paints-clear-picture-7319338</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/on-doubts-over-travis-heads-participation-in-boxing-day-test-australia-coach-paints-clear-picture-7319338</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:58:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India reveal squad for the upcoming U19 Women’s T20 World Cup - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Reveal Squad for the Upcoming U19 Women’s T20 World Cup</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>India has announced its squad for the U19 Women’s T20 World Cup, featuring 16 teams divided into four groups.</p><ul><li><strong>Squad:</strong> Niki Prasad (Captain), Sanika Chalke (Vice-captain), G Trisha, Kamalini G (WK), Bhavika Ahire (WK), Ishwari Awasare, Mithila Vinod, Joshitha VJ, Sonam Yadav, Parunika Sisodiya, Kesari Drithi, Aayushi Shukla, Anandita Kishor, MD Shabnam, Vaishnavi S</li><li><strong>Standby Players:</strong> Nandhana S, Ira J, Anadi T</li><li>India is placed in Group A along with Malaysia, Sri Lanka, and West Indies.</li><li>Group stage matches will be hosted at Bayuemas Oval in Kuala Lumpur.</li><li>India's campaign begins on January 19 against West Indies.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/u19-womenst20worldcup/news/india-reveal-squad-for-the-upcoming-u19-women-s-t20-world-cup</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/u19-womenst20worldcup/news/india-reveal-squad-for-the-upcoming-u19-women-s-t20-world-cup</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:47:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I don't blow kisses to my better half sitting in dressing room or hospitality box': Ravichandran Ashwin debunks myths - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxQeXJXb3d3MnBCb0NkSlpFb1NOREkySVNDUzRsaUdvY2JsYW1EM1VaTmRla3VuV0xQMTRYMzFCYTBpX2JpLTBtcThkak5DcE1RRUM3blFvQUpsZDYyV3dkRWZGWUY1SVU3cXQ1OGJjVDdFX0J5ZjllRVBVZWFiak43elhITUtrZzJsbkVmQk9WZC1udlloclliZXRORk1QTk1EU1MtU1hmempVSFQtUXBxbjdzRl9KY0tGcC1ENnA1N0pOVms1ak84QTQtN1dXcURndlVDUWQ3LUZrS08xdktpMkNxSlozS1VLTnlMQzd4SjBpWmtfUi1TazF2OUE0LTBveW9pU9IBigJBVV95cUxQYjZPZUt2YWRqbF84MjBZYURSNWczR0Rua2FWUEFEdlhsQTloZVlDREkzTTNMaEJEa1F3dGp0c2w3WVA2ZHVnMlQwZTlzYTZoSFNKdl9EWkg3NURKdXZ0X2NJM1RfVE96NldONVJCMldrQ2ZtVjJTRHl3b0c4TjdNMUI1Y0lpQUVJcUhpQUwxcG9xSXhJNVlEQ2pNa0xNdkpvY3lZYnBvOWY2UDhMNDR6Qk54cE0taXJRcm9PcVNIcE9vcm1IVTMtVU5LSzh1VXh6ZDA4Z25JZHp5RGpWYWp0QnhWemdPQmYwal9MV1RFVVBHVGhWc3M1Q1BaVGhqRzZwXzY2bXBMMzZQZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxQeXJXb3d3MnBCb0NkSlpFb1NOREkySVNDUzRsaUdvY2JsYW1EM1VaTmRla3VuV0xQMTRYMzFCYTBpX2JpLTBtcThkak5DcE1RRUM3blFvQUpsZDYyV3dkRWZGWUY1SVU3cXQ1OGJjVDdFX0J5ZjllRVBVZWFiak43elhITUtrZzJsbkVmQk9WZC1udlloclliZXRORk1QTk1EU1MtU1hmempVSFQtUXBxbjdzRl9KY0tGcC1ENnA1N0pOVms1ak84QTQtN1dXcURndlVDUWQ3LUZrS08xdktpMkNxSlozS1VLTnlMQzd4SjBpWmtfUi1TazF2OUE0LTBveW9pU9IBigJBVV95cUxQYjZPZUt2YWRqbF84MjBZYURSNWczR0Rua2FWUEFEdlhsQTloZVlDREkzTTNMaEJEa1F3dGp0c2w3WVA2ZHVnMlQwZTlzYTZoSFNKdl9EWkg3NURKdXZ0X2NJM1RfVE96NldONVJCMldrQ2ZtVjJTRHl3b0c4TjdNMUI1Y0lpQUVJcUhpQUwxcG9xSXhJNVlEQ2pNa0xNdkpvY3lZYnBvOWY2UDhMNDR6Qk54cE0taXJRcm9PcVNIcE9vcm1IVTMtVU5LSzh1VXh6ZDA4Z25JZHp5RGpWYWp0QnhWemdPQmYwal9MV1RFVVBHVGhWc3M1Q1BaVGhqRzZwXzY2bXBMMzZQZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:44:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Did India Choose Tanush Kotian Over Kuldeep Yadav & Axar Patel? Skipper Rohit Sharma Explains - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma Explains Selection of Tanush Kotian for the Test Squad</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Tanush Kotian (Image: PTI)"><figcaption>Tanush Kotian (Image: PTI)</figcaption><p>Indian skipper Rohit Sharma shared insights into the squad selection for the 2024-25 Border-Gavaskar Trophy, highlighting the inclusion of Tanush Kotian over Kuldeep Yadav and Axar Patel.</p><ul><li>Kuldeep Yadav's recovery from hernia surgery and Axar Patel's recent fatherhood opened opportunities for Kotian.</li><li>Kotian was a standout player in the 2024-25 Ranji Trophy, with impressive stats of 502 runs and 29 wickets in 10 matches.</li><li>Sharma mentioned the need for a backup spinner due to injuries and recoveries in the team.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tanush was here a month back... Not that Tanush is not good enough. He has shown in the last two years what he has done in domestic cricket and we really wanted just a backup.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>Rohit emphasized the importance of Kotian's recent form and readiness, stating that he is a valuable option for the team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/why-did-india-choose-tanush-kotian-over-kuldeep-yadav-axar-patel-skipper-rohit-sharma-explains-9166394.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/why-did-india-choose-tanush-kotian-over-kuldeep-yadav-axar-patel-skipper-rohit-sharma-explains-9166394.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:37:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Modern-day great Virat Kohli will figure it out' - Rohit Sharma - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Modern-day great Virat Kohli will figure it out' - Rohit Sharma</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116617365,imgsize-113936,width-400,resizemode-4/116617365.jpg" alt="Virat Kohli (BCCI Photo)" title="Virat Kohli (BCCI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Virat Kohli (BCCI Photo)</figcaption><p>As India and Australia prepare for the fourth Test of the Border Gavaskar Trophy, Kohli's inconsistent performance is under scrutiny. Captain Rohit Sharma expresses confidence in Kohli, stating he believes Kohli will regain his form.</p><ul><li>Kohli has scored 126 runs in five Test innings during the series, with an average of 31.50.</li><li>Rohit Sharma, despite his own struggles, remains optimistic about Kohli’s ability to turn things around.</li><li>Rohit commented on modern-day greats like Kohli saying they will find their own path to success.</li><li>The team dynamics have shifted, with Rohit batting in the middle order, affecting his performance.</li><li>Rohit has insisted on keeping the team's batting order strategy private.</li></ul><blockquote>"Modern-day greats will figure out their own way of (carving out their) path." - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>In summary, while Kohli's form has been a concern, Rohit Sharma's confidence in his ability to bounce back is a reassuring message for fans as India looks to make a mark in the ongoing series against Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/modern-day-great-virat-kohli-will-figure-it-out-rohit-sharma/articleshow/116617360.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/modern-day-great-virat-kohli-will-figure-it-out-rohit-sharma/articleshow/116617360.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Kuldeep Yadav doesn't have visa and Axar...': Rohit Sharma reveals why Tanush Kotian was picked as Ashwin's replacement - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma explains why Tanush Kotian was picked as Ashwin's replacement ahead of Kuldeep Yadav and Axar Patel</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 10:23 AM IST <strong>Source:</strong> HT Sports</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/rohit_tanush_1735010867716_1735010881281.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma reveals why Tanush Kotian was picked" title="Rohit Sharma reveals why Tanush Kotian was picked"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma reveals why Tanush Kotian was picked</figcaption><p>India’s cricket team captain Rohit Sharma explained the decision to select Tanush Kotian as a replacement for the retired Ravichandran Ashwin in the upcoming Border-Gavaskar Trophy Tests.</p><ul><li>Tanush Kotian was chosen as Ashwin's replacement after Ashwin's retirement from international cricket.</li><li>Rohit humorously noted that Kuldeep Yadav was not selected due to visa issues.</li><li>Kotian recently performed well in the ‘A’ tour in Australia.</li><li>Kuldeep Yadav is recovering from hernia surgery, and Axar Patel recently became a father, making him unavailable.</li><li>Kotian has a strong track record in first-class cricket, with 101 wickets and 1525 runs.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tanush was here a month back and Kuldeep doesn't have a visa... we wanted a back-up in case we play two spinners in Sydney or Melbourne.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>The selection highlights the team's strategy to ensure readiness with injuries and personal matters affecting player availability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/kuldeep-yadav-doesnt-have-visa-axar-patel-rohit-sharma-why-tanush-kotian-was-picked-as-ashwin-replacement-101735010015441.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/kuldeep-yadav-doesnt-have-visa-axar-patel-rohit-sharma-why-tanush-kotian-was-picked-as-ashwin-replacement-101735010015441.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jacques Kallis to Ricky Ponting: 7 batters who scored most runs in Boxing Day Test matches - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jacques Kallis to Ricky Ponting: Discover the top 8 batters who scored the most runs in Boxing Day Test matches, featuring legendary cricketers like Steve Waugh, Gary Kirsten, and more.</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/steve-waugh-australia-202412-1735012094.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Steve Waugh" width="700" height="467">
<figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption>
<p>Discover the achievements of the top seven run-scorers in Boxing Day Tests, a prestigious cricketing tradition which showcases legendary talents like Kallis and Ponting.</p>
<ul>
<li>Steve Waugh (Australia): 1261 runs in 16 matches, highest score of 131*</li>
<li>Jacques Kallis (South Africa): 846 runs in 8 matches, highest score of 177</li>
<li>Allan Border (Australia): 796 runs in 13 matches, highest score of 163</li>
<li>Ricky Ponting (Australia): 775 runs in 8 matches, highest score of 257</li>
<li>Mark Waugh (Australia): 735 runs in 11 matches, highest score of 112</li>
<li>David Boon (Australia): 696 runs in 10 matches, highest score of 131</li>
<li>Justin Langer (Australia): 651 runs in 8 matches, highest score of 250</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"These records showcase the prowess of these players during a significant period in cricket history, especially in the context of Boxing Day Tests."</blockquote>
<p>The analysis of these players highlights their contribution to the tradition of Boxing Day Tests, aiming to inspire future generations and celebrate cricketing excellence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/jacques-kallis-to-ricky-ponting-7-batters-who-scored-most-runs-in-boxing-day-test-matches-415976/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/jacques-kallis-to-ricky-ponting-7-batters-who-scored-most-runs-in-boxing-day-test-matches-415976/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:58:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker Said "Shouldn't Have Gone To Olympics, Won Medals": Heartbroken Father - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxQZ1lvTmM2b0dOWmVyTzlLMWN3SjNfc1Q3SWgyTUNTaFh4aUtNLVJaalRVSllLbzVlckJsU3ZFbjdnY2V6MTB0UTdjMW1OWTB3ckZuTnBWUkpQOXZKVjZ3b1B1eTFIbUhGUHdhaDRlMFhkTTI0MHd1YXBpSmFDcTZHSXpHYTFLUHltcmVZR21ESW03eXFqVnYzdHU5QlIwbmFTa3VLbFZ2UVhMU0lqTGducGdQakJXZ2VySkowZmphMmdWRGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxQZ1lvTmM2b0dOWmVyTzlLMWN3SjNfc1Q3SWgyTUNTaFh4aUtNLVJaalRVSllLbzVlckJsU3ZFbjdnY2V6MTB0UTdjMW1OWTB3ckZuTnBWUkpQOXZKVjZ3b1B1eTFIbUhGUHdhaDRlMFhkTTI0MHd1YXBpSmFDcTZHSXpHYTFLUHltcmVZR21ESW03eXFqVnYzdHU5QlIwbmFTa3VLbFZ2UVhMU0lqTGducGdQakJXZ2VySkowZmphMmdWRGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:43:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MS Dhoni faces Housing Board probe over alleged residential land misuse in Ranchi - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPVldHSmNSYWhXNm9IMGtQV01GSHdzVlVNdDNST21xbzRKdlJ4STd6aVN0dEYwbFo4SUxNODNYX1ZHdmMydTB0Zm5PU3RpdmNoQ3g2Nk0zNFdtSVFwT0cxTW1fS2RxUW1BTW9yUkdIWEM2dF9KZTBQZjZaVTR2TDRwSmVZVjkzTk52enM1dnMzdTBhZnhvdDV4YV9B0gGiAUFVX3lxTE1IMDNlekZ4QklZTlJFVV9SZDNOT1dPNEFYQlVockphNFgwVUoxZng2dG5Hd2tzZWdXRHRKRFpxRmVFbFZzZFBQQTY1Vl9KZmh3TFBOQ1lEMmFRV0QtOGdBTDNGZ3RoVlpKRnpzSTNfcXc3SldhdXhSNUUxajRVMnlTcVIxLWVuMW04RzlfcS0zLXRWYWFYbUNCSFpFemdXWWFpZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxPVldHSmNSYWhXNm9IMGtQV01GSHdzVlVNdDNST21xbzRKdlJ4STd6aVN0dEYwbFo4SUxNODNYX1ZHdmMydTB0Zm5PU3RpdmNoQ3g2Nk0zNFdtSVFwT0cxTW1fS2RxUW1BTW9yUkdIWEM2dF9KZTBQZjZaVTR2TDRwSmVZVjkzTk52enM1dnMzdTBhZnhvdDV4YV9B0gGiAUFVX3lxTE1IMDNlekZ4QklZTlJFVV9SZDNOT1dPNEFYQlVockphNFgwVUoxZng2dG5Hd2tzZWdXRHRKRFpxRmVFbFZzZFBQQTY1Vl9KZmh3TFBOQ1lEMmFRV0QtOGdBTDNGZ3RoVlpKRnpzSTNfcXc3SldhdXhSNUUxajRVMnlTcVIxLWVuMW04RzlfcS0zLXRWYWFYbUNCSFpFemdXWWFpZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS, Boxing Day Test: Sam Konstas to debut, Travis Head an injury doubt - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS, Boxing Day Test: Sam Konstas to debut, Travis Head an injury doubt</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116615562,imgsize-95020,width-400,resizemode-4/116615562.jpg" alt="IND vs AUS, Boxing Day Test: Sam Konstas to debut, Travis Head an injury doubt" title="Sam Konstas is set to make his Test debut against India in the Boxing Day Test at the MCG." decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Sam Konstas is set to make his Test debut against India in the Boxing Day Test at the MCG. (Image: X)</figcaption><p>Sam Konstas is set to make his Test debut against India in the Boxing Day Test, becoming the youngest Australian Test debutant since Pat Cummins in 2011.</p><ul><li>Konstas confirmed by Australia coach Andrew McDonald to debut.</li><li>He scored 107 runs in a practice match against India three weeks ago.</li><li>Travis Head's participation is uncertain due to a quad strain.</li><li>Head has begun light training but faces fitness tests.</li><li>Scott Boland is likely to replace Josh Hazlewood in the playing XI.</li></ul><blockquote>“He’s been very similar to what I’ve seen on the outside … he’s composed, relaxed.” - Andrew McDonald on Sam Konstas</blockquote><p>The anticipation for Sam Konstas's debut is high, while Travis Head's injury poses a potential setback for the Australian team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-sam-konstas-to-debut-travis-head-an-injury-doubt/articleshow/116615092.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-boxing-day-test-sam-konstas-to-debut-travis-head-an-injury-doubt/articleshow/116615092.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli's Friend Shares Health Update, Makes Big Medical Bills Revelation - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli's Friend Shares Health Update, Makes Big Medical Bills Revelation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> PTI</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hlqqq0m8_vinod-kambli-pti_625x300_24_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Vinod Kambli's Friend Shares Health Update, Makes Big Medical Bills Revelation"><figcaption>Vinod Kambli during his hospital stay</figcaption><p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli has shown improvement after being hospitalized due to a urinary infection. His friend, Marcus Couto, has provided updates on his condition and mentioned arrangements for Kambli's medical bills.</p><ul><li>Kambli was admitted to a hospital in Thane due to health deterioration.</li><li>He is suffering from a urinary infection but is now doing 'fine'.</li><li>Couto suggests keeping Kambli in the hospital for about a month for further treatment.</li><li>A hospital owner facilitated Kambli's admission.</li><li>Kambli expressed gratitude to the medical team for their care.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is because of the doctor here that I am alive... All I would say is that I will do whatever sir (referring to the doctor) asks me to.” - Vinod Kambli</blockquote><p>Kambli's recent public appearance was at the inauguration of coach Ramakant Achrekar's memorial.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/vinod-kamblis-friend-shares-health-update-makes-big-medical-bills-revelation-7319066</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/vinod-kamblis-friend-shares-health-update-makes-big-medical-bills-revelation-7319066</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:59:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Konstas' MCG debut confirmed, Head faces a fitness test - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Konstas to Make MCG Test Debut as Head Faces Fitness Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><img src='https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg' alt='Story Image'><figcaption>Konstas looks 19, behaves 30, and is unfazed about a Test debut at the MCG</figcaption><p>Sam Konstas will debut for Australia on Boxing Day, becoming the fourth-youngest Test debutant. Meanwhile, coach Andrew McDonald expresses confidence in Travis Head's fitness after a minor injury.</p><ul><li>Sam Konstas will make his Test debut against India at 19 years and 85 days old.</li><li>Coach Andrew McDonald confirms Konstas was notified of his selection.</li><li>Travis Head is undergoing a fitness test after suffering a minor quad strain.</li><li>Australia will make at least two changes, with Konstas and Scott Boland replacing Nathan McSweeney and Josh Hazlewood, respectively.</li></ul><blockquote>“We said from the get go, when leading into the summer, that we wouldn't shy away, and age was no barrier,” said McDonald.</blockquote><p>The announcement of the final team lineup is expected on Christmas Day.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/konstas-debut-confirmed-head-faces-a-fitness-test-1466357</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/konstas-debut-confirmed-head-faces-a-fitness-test-1466357</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:53:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ashwin answers 'very simple question': What sets Dhoni apart as captain? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashwin answers 'very simple question': What sets Dhoni apart as captain?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>In a recent discussion, Indian cricketer Ravichandran Ashwin highlighted the unique qualities that set MS Dhoni apart as a captain, emphasizing his decision-making skills and leadership style.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Ashwin notes that Dhoni's calmness in pressure situations is unmatched.</li>
  <li>The ability to adapt strategies based on the game's demands was a recurring theme.</li>
  <li>Dhoni's trust in his players encourages them to perform their best.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Dhoni’s decision-making always stands out when the stakes are high.” - Ravichandran Ashwin</blockquote>
<p>This discussion sheds light on the reasons behind Dhoni's success as a captain and his influence on Indian cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/ravichandran-ashwin-answers-very-simple-question-what-sets-ms-dhoni-apart-as-captain/articleshow/116614660.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/ravichandran-ashwin-answers-very-simple-question-what-sets-ms-dhoni-apart-as-captain/articleshow/116614660.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PV Sindhu & Venkata Datta Sais Net Worth 2024: How Rich Is Indias Star Shuttler And Her Husband? In Pics - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu & Venkata Datta Sais Net Worth 2024: How Rich Is India’s Star Shuttler And Her Husband?</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 24, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Zee News</p><img src="https://english.cdn.zeenews.com/sites/default/files/2024/12/24/1615828-snapinsta.app47031541813873107888971011016197735334546893n1080.jpg?im=Resize=(400)" alt="PV Sindhu and Venkata Datta Sai"/><figcaption>PV Sindhu and Venkata Datta Sai</figcaption><p>Indian badminton star PV Sindhu recently married tech executive Venkata Datta Sai, prompting discussions about their financial empires. Both excel in their fields, showcasing their achievements and combined wealth.</p><ul><li>Sindhu's net worth is estimated at ₹59 crore ($7.1 million).</li><li>Venkata Datta Sai has a net worth of ₹150 crore.</li><li>Sindhu owns a luxurious hilltop home in Hyderabad.</li><li>She has a growing car collection featuring brands like BMW and Mahindra.</li><li>Sindhu has lucrative endorsement deals, including a ₹50 crore contract with Li Ning.</li><li>Venkat's corporate work includes serving as Executive Director at Posidex Technologies.</li><li>The couple's wedding in December 2024 highlighted their shared commitment to success.</li></ul><blockquote>"Their union is not only a celebration of love but also of mutual accomplishments and ambitions."</blockquote><p>The couple is poised for further success in their respective endeavors, marking them as a dynamic force in sports and business.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/photos/sports/pv-sindhu-venkata-datta-sais-net-worth-2024-how-rich-is-indias-star-shuttler-and-her-husband-in-pics-2835167</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/photos/sports/pv-sindhu-venkata-datta-sais-net-worth-2024-how-rich-is-indias-star-shuttler-and-her-husband-in-pics-2835167</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ponting analyses Gill's overseas struggles - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ponting Analyzes Gill's Struggles Overseas</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Ricky Ponting has analyzed Shubman Gill's recent performances overseas, suggesting that the young opener is over-complicating his batting approach.</p><ul><li>After an injury setback, Gill has struggled with scores of 31, 28, and 1 in his recent matches.</li><li>Ponting believes Gill has changed his technique too much and needs to trust his instincts more.</li><li>He emphasized the need for Gill to adopt a confident mindset while batting.</li></ul><blockquote>“If he goes in with that mindset and that attitude, then things could change here in Melbourne for him.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Ponting encourages Gill to focus on his attacking style to improve his performance in future matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/world-test-championship/news/ponting-analyses-gill-s-overseas-struggles</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/world-test-championship/news/ponting-analyses-gill-s-overseas-struggles</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:07:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bumrah targeted with big allegation, Aussie media blamed for not saying it out loud: 'Is it not politically correct?' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bumrah targeted with big allegation, Aussie media blamed for not saying it out loud: 'Is it not politically correct?'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/AP12-15-2024-000007B-0_1735004026968_1735004037684.jpg" alt="India's Jasprit Bumrah looks on during play on day two of the third cricket test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane(AP)" title="India's Jasprit Bumrah looks on during play on day two of the third cricket test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane(AP)"><figcaption>India's Jasprit Bumrah looks on during play on day two of the third cricket test between India and Australia at the Gabba in Brisbane(AP)</figcaption>
<p>In the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy series, Indian fast bowler Jasprit Bumrah has been accused of having a suspect bowling action. Veteran sports commentator Ian Maurice suggests that political correctness is preventing a thorough examination of Bumrah's technique.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bumrah has taken 21 wickets in six innings with an average of 10.90 in the series.</li>
  <li>Ian Maurice claims Australian media is hesitant to scrutinize Bumrah's action due to fear of being labeled racist.</li>
  <li>Greg Chappell has defended Bumrah, calling his bowling action legal and unique.</li>
  <li>Concerns about Bumrah's action arose after comparisons to former cricketer Mohammad Hasnain, who was banned for suspect action.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“By the way, please stop this nonsense of questioning Bumrah's action. It is unique, but it is unequivocally clean.” - Greg Chappell</blockquote>
<p>This debate highlights the ongoing challenges in addressing issues of fairness and transparency in sports while respecting cultural sensitivities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-targeted-with-big-allegation-aussie-media-blamed-for-not-saying-it-out-loud-is-it-not-politically-correct-101735003837788.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-targeted-with-big-allegation-aussie-media-blamed-for-not-saying-it-out-loud-is-it-not-politically-correct-101735003837788.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:05:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>