<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:27:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:27:39 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BBL 2024-2025: Match 36, HEA vs HUR Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between HEA vs HUR? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BBL 2025: Match 36, HEA vs HUR Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736932785486_image_2025_01_15T09_12_44_433Z.png" alt="" width="700" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Hobart Hurricanes are favorites to win according to the match prediction.</figcaption><p>The Big Bash League (BBL) 2025 features a match between Brisbane Heat and Hobart Hurricanes at the Brisbane Cricket Ground. The Heat aim to improve their standings while the Hurricanes seek to maintain their top position.</p><ul><li>The Heat's record: 4 losses out of 8 matches.</li><li>The Hurricanes' record: 6 wins out of 8 matches.</li><li>Pitch report suggests a high-scoring game, favoring batters.</li><li>Key players to watch: Max Bryant (HEA) and Riley Meredith (HUR).</li><li>Prediction favors Hobart Hurricanes to win the match.</li></ul><blockquote>“Prediction is based on the author's understanding and analysis, considering each team's current form.”</blockquote><p>As the BBL season progresses, both teams will be looking to make their mark. The Heat need to adapt quickly, while the Hurricanes look to extend their winning streak.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-36-hea-vs-hur-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-hea-vs-hur/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-36-hea-vs-hur-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-hea-vs-hur/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 05:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Father Had Heart Attack Two Days Before I Got Dropped, Didn't Tell Him": India Star Shafali Verma - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"Father Had Heart Attack Two Days Before I Got Dropped, Didn't Tell Him": India Star Shafali Verma</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 9, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/njdt6juc_shafali-verma_625x300_09_October_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Shafali Verma"/><figcaption>File photo of Shafali Verma</figcaption><p>Shafali Verma, a promising player in the Indian women's cricket team, shares her emotional journey after being dropped from the squad amid personal family challenges. Despite her current absence from the team, she continues to work hard to enhance her skills with her father's support.</p><ul><li>Shafali Verma was dropped from the Indian women's cricket squad due to a recent poor performance.</li><li>She kept her team omission a secret from her father, who suffered a heart attack shortly before the announcement.</li><li>Since her drop, she has been actively competing in domestic tournaments, amassing impressive scores.</li><li>Shafali emphasizes the importance of mental toughness and working on her weaknesses for future games.</li></ul><blockquote>"It's not easy to get over it. I didn't want to reveal it because my father had a heart attack about two days before I got dropped from the team." - Shafali Verma</blockquote><p>Shafali's story reflects resilience in the face of adversity, as she aims to improve and earn back her spot on the national team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/father-had-heart-attack-two-days-before-i-got-dropped-didnt-tell-him-shafali-verma-7484922</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/father-had-heart-attack-two-days-before-i-got-dropped-didnt-tell-him-shafali-verma-7484922</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 05:10:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yamal 9.5, Raphinha 9 | Barcelona 5-1 Real Betis: Player ratings - Barca Universal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxOa0NzM3VRMlVyV2RhTFZmel9TTHhjeng5LUhrc0pCM2JjZzNGOGVHSUxjUVBscVU4MDBDVnlfR3o3dWVpQmcyU3VpQlR4S01WbXdUUndzX0tzLXh6TmF2b1lTd2FVRUI1MjRwZXJyZHZ3RzFJMHU3MnVUcWk1MEg4Y1dNRVU5b0lDQWxsOXpiTk95QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxOa0NzM3VRMlVyV2RhTFZmel9TTHhjeng5LUhrc0pCM2JjZzNGOGVHSUxjUVBscVU4MDBDVnlfR3o3dWVpQmcyU3VpQlR4S01WbXdUUndzX0tzLXh6TmF2b1lTd2FVRUI1MjRwZXJyZHZ3RzFJMHU3MnVUcWk1MEg4Y1dNRVU5b0lDQWxsOXpiTk95QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 03:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["He Needs To Learn To...": Ruben Amorim's Clear Message To Alejandro Garnacho Amid Exit Rumours - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"He Needs To Learn To...": Ruben Amorim's Clear Message To Alejandro Garnacho Amid Exit Rumours</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/btmdm5ig_alejandro-garnacho-afp_625x300_14_March_23.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Ruben Amorim's Message to Garnacho"><figcaption>File image of Alejandro Garnacho. © AFP</figcaption><p>Ruben Amorim expresses confidence in Alejandro Garnacho's potential at Manchester United amid rumors of a transfer.</p><ul><li>Garnacho has not played since December 7 but made the starting XI in the recent FA Cup match.</li><li>United has distanced itself from rumors of Garnacho leaving for Napoli during the January window.</li><li>Amorim believes Garnacho has the talent to succeed and emphasizes the need for him to adapt to different playing positions.</li><li>He praises Harry Maguire for his dedication during the match against Arsenal despite health issues.</li><li>Amorim aims to create a tougher team environment at United.</li></ul><blockquote>“He has talent. He needs to learn to play in a different position.” - Ruben Amorim</blockquote><p>This article highlights the challenges and potential growth paths for young players like Garnacho at major clubs like Manchester United.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/football/he-needs-to-learn-to-ruben-amorims-clear-message-to-alejandro-garnacho-amid-exit-rumours-7484309</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/football/he-needs-to-learn-to-ruben-amorims-clear-message-to-alejandro-garnacho-amid-exit-rumours-7484309</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 03:15:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who is the tallest fast bowler to take seven wickets in a Test innings? - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQekxVNEVqN29NOUJWQWJvNHJkUjM3RVlzSEVVei16a2R3Mzc4TWVtTDg2ZXRpX3pRRkc0QmlLUldQOWxSM1RCMWE0c0hjMGhETzlPWDU1ZnhNR2YyRXBlLUpGaW5ZMnBpNDhKeVJqbzRUWEs4bGNaNjltSEV2MF9XVUhtaWFVajdBWVhhZDExbzF2SnktbENVNVhpbTFpOVk1VFFrdmpR0gG3AUFVX3lxTE16bk1DVFEtUkh3VHFJRHZxaS11UTlrYUFYa25RUkYzSDRqd0ktRUU4OXVnOGs3Nld6bWtvRmp2WWdnc2ZCTXdNU2U4Wm5sdkhRakkwcXVQeC1hWXYxTnlsbHU2NmlnMm0yZGZ2WHBKMGktRHRWRndtTUpONkVNaktUbWFKZ1F3c2Y2clBkYmFWaWpuekxQcDJwdkhXeUl3d09IQjlCTGdiVXBUemNkOHVQY0E4LU1ROA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxQekxVNEVqN29NOUJWQWJvNHJkUjM3RVlzSEVVei16a2R3Mzc4TWVtTDg2ZXRpX3pRRkc0QmlLUldQOWxSM1RCMWE0c0hjMGhETzlPWDU1ZnhNR2YyRXBlLUpGaW5ZMnBpNDhKeVJqbzRUWEs4bGNaNjltSEV2MF9XVUhtaWFVajdBWVhhZDExbzF2SnktbENVNVhpbTFpOVk1VFFrdmpR0gG3AUFVX3lxTE16bk1DVFEtUkh3VHFJRHZxaS11UTlrYUFYa25RUkYzSDRqd0ktRUU4OXVnOGs3Nld6bWtvRmp2WWdnc2ZCTXdNU2U4Wm5sdkhRakkwcXVQeC1hWXYxTnlsbHU2NmlnMm0yZGZ2WHBKMGktRHRWRndtTUpONkVNaktUbWFKZ1F3c2Y2clBkYmFWaWpuekxQcDJwdkhXeUl3d09IQjlCTGdiVXBUemNkOHVQY0E4LU1ROA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 03:01:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is ‘tap, hold and load in 4k’? All about the viral trend that has taken over X - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What is ‘tap, hold and load in 4k’? All about the viral trend that has taken over X</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/Tap_Hold_And_Load_in_4k_Viral_Trend_X_1736992649218_1736992661432.jpg" alt="FIFA took part in the ‘tap, hold and load in 4k’ viral trend. (X/@FIFAWorldCup)" title="FIFA took part in the ‘tap, hold and load in 4k’ viral trend. (X/@FIFAWorldCup)">
<figcaption>FIFA took part in the ‘tap, hold and load in 4k’ viral trend. (X/@FIFAWorldCup)</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses the viral trend ‘tap, hold and load in 4K’ that has gained momentum on social media, particularly among sports fans on X, after FIFA's participation in it. The trend revolves around a feature that allows users to save images in high resolution.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The trend originated in January 2025 and has quickly become popular.</li>
  <li>It features a method for downloading images in 4K quality on X, previously introduced in 2021.</li>
  <li>The term '4K' refers to images with a horizontal resolution of about 4,000 pixels, enhancing photo quality.</li>
  <li>Tips on how to upload photos in 4K are provided, emphasizing settings adjustments on X.</li>
  <li>Notable engagement from FIFA highlights the trend's significance among sports enthusiasts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“As a regular social media user, you may have seen these six words plastered all over.”</blockquote>
<p>This trend illustrates how platforms like X can rejuvenate older features through creative user engagement and viral challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/what-is-tap-hold-and-load-in-4k-all-about-the-viral-trend-that-has-taken-over-x-101736992610629.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/what-is-tap-hold-and-load-in-4k-all-about-the-viral-trend-that-has-taken-over-x-101736992610629.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 02:12:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Won 5 Of 6 T20I Series He Captained": Hardik Pandya's Leadership Snub Baffles Ex India Star - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"Won 5 Of 6 T20I Series He Captained": Hardik Pandya's Leadership Snub Baffles Ex India Star</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/rp19ndo_hardik-pandya_625x300_14_November_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Hardik Pandya"><figcaption>File photo of Hardik Pandya</figcaption><p>Recent changes in India's T20I team structure have raised eyebrows regarding Hardik Pandya's leadership role, as he has been demoted amid talks of grooming new captaincy candidates.</p><ul><li>Hardik Pandya has been removed as vice-captain of India's T20I team.</li><li>Suryakumar Yadav is now the T20I skipper with Axar Patel as his deputy.</li><li>Former cricketer Aakash Chopra has expressed confusion over Pandya's exclusion from leadership discussions despite his successful captaincy record.</li><li>Chopra noted that Pandya leads the Mumbai Indians and had a standout performance in the T20 World Cup.</li><li>The rumored shift in leadership aims to promote younger talents for future team leadership.</li></ul><blockquote>“What has happened with Hardik Pandya? Nobody is thinking or talking about him.” - Aakash Chopra</blockquote><p>In summary, the movement away from Hardik Pandya in leadership roles sparks discussion on the direction of India's cricket team and its future leadership structure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/won-5-of-6-t20i-series-he-captained-hardik-pandyas-leadership-snub-baffles-ex-india-star-7476581</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/won-5-of-6-t20i-series-he-captained-hardik-pandyas-leadership-snub-baffles-ex-india-star-7476581</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:53:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat Kohli, Rohit Sharma's struggles raise alarm as BCCI likely to bolster Team India's coaching staff: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Considering New Coaching Staff Amid Player Struggles</h1><p><strong>Jan 16, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/AP12-06-2024-000299A-0_1736136086995_1736992056109.jpg" alt="India's captain Rohit Sharma, left, looks on as teammate Virat Kohli rubs to shine the ball before passing it to the bowler(AP)" title="India's captain Rohit Sharma, left, looks on as teammate Virat Kohli rubs to shine the ball before passing it to the bowler(AP)"><figcaption>India's captain Rohit Sharma, left, looks on as teammate Virat Kohli rubs to shine the ball before passing it to the bowler(AP)</figcaption><p>The BCCI is reportedly contemplating the addition of a dedicated batting coach to Team India following a disappointing series defeat to Australia.</p><ul><li>The discussion arises after India lost 1-3 in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li><li>Concerns have been raised about the batting performances of key players Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma.</li><li>Growing tensions between head coach Gautam Gambhir and captain Rohit Sharma have been noted.</li><li>A review meeting was held on January 11 to address these issues and consider potential changes to the coaching staff.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kohli and Sharma’s underwhelming performances have drawn most of the attention.”</blockquote><p>The BCCI's exploration of new coaching options indicates a serious commitment to improving India's batting performance ahead of upcoming series, including five T20Is and three ODIs against England.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-rohit-sharmas-struggles-raise-alarm-as-bcci-likely-to-bolster-team-indias-coaching-staff-report-101736989542902.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/virat-kohli-rohit-sharmas-struggles-raise-alarm-as-bcci-likely-to-bolster-team-indias-coaching-staff-report-101736989542902.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:48:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah Breaks Silence On "Bed Rest" Report Amid Champions Trophy Concerns - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Breaks Silence On "Bed Rest" Report Amid Champions Trophy Concerns</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/15spv2v_jasprit-bumrah-afp_625x300_14_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Jasprit Bumrah Breaks Silence On Bed Rest Report" />
<figcaption>File photo of Jasprit Bumrah. © AFP</figcaption>
<p>Team India pacer Jasprit Bumrah has denied reports suggesting he was advised to take bed rest before the Champions Trophy, asserting the claims are false.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bumrah labels the bed rest reports as fake news.</li>
  <li>He recently suffered an injury scare during a Test match against Australia.</li>
  <li>Bumrah ended the series as the highest wicket-taker with 32 wickets.</li>
  <li>He was named Player of the Series for his outstanding performance.</li>
  <li>Bumrah has received nominations for ICC Awards 2024.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I know fake news is easy to spread but this made me laugh. Sources unreliable." — Jasprit Bumrah</blockquote>
<p>Bumrah aims to continue his success as he prepares for the upcoming Champions Trophy. His strong performances have marked a memorable year for the bowler.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-breaks-silence-on-bed-rest-report-amid-champions-trophy-concerns-7482531</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-breaks-silence-on-bed-rest-report-amid-champions-trophy-concerns-7482531</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:47:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rules From Virat Kohli's Captaincy Back? BCCI Planning Big U-Turn Amid Slump In Form: Report - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rules From Virat Kohli's Captaincy Back? BCCI Planning Big U-Turn Amid Slump In Form: Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 15 January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/n9c4suno_virat-kohli-bcci_625x300_15_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Rules From Virat Kohli's Captaincy Back? BCCI Planning Big U-Turn Amid Slump In Form: Report"><figcaption>Virat Kohli in a practice drill © BCCI/Sportzpics</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) is reportedly considering reinstating old fitness rules from Virat Kohli's captaincy amidst the team's recent struggles under head coach Gautam Gambhir. This includes potentially reintroducing the mandatory yo-yo fitness test, which was previously removed to ease the players' workload.</p><ul><li>BCCI is dissatisfied with Team India's performance since the arrival of Gautam Gambhir as head coach.</li><li>There are discussions within the BCCI to reintroduce old fitness criteria for player selection.</li><li>The mandatory yo-yo fitness test was previously lifted to prevent injuries but could make a comeback.</li><li>Concerns have been raised about players' complacency due to the absence of strict fitness standards.</li><li>Changes may also include limiting the stay of players' families during overseas tours to avoid distractions.</li><li>A new rule will mandate all players to travel with the team to strengthen cohesion.</li></ul><blockquote>“The board had gone lenient on the players since they are mostly on the road... A certain fitness level criteria needs to be reintroduced so that complacency doesn't creep in,” said a source.</blockquote><p>This potential shift in BCCI's approach highlights their commitment to enhancing team performance and discipline as they aim to improve results on the international stage.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/rules-from-virat-kohlis-captaincy-back-bcci-planning-big-u-turn-amid-slump-in-form-report-7478504</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/rules-from-virat-kohlis-captaincy-back-bcci-planning-big-u-turn-amid-slump-in-form-report-7478504</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:42:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starstruck! Shreyas Iyer's heartwarming gesture for a fan girl goes viral - WATCH - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shreyas Iyer's Heartwarming Gesture for a Fan Goes Viral</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 23, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>An uplifting moment captured the hearts of fans as Indian cricketer Shreyas Iyer goes out of his way to meet a young supporter, showcasing his kindness and humility.</p><ul><li>Shreyas Iyer was spotted engaging with fans after a cricket match.</li><li>A young girl approached him for an autograph and a photo.</li><li>The heartfelt interaction quickly gained popularity on social media.</li><li>Fans praised Iyer for his down-to-earth nature and positive demeanor.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was a dream come true to meet him!” - A fan's reaction to the encounter.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the personal connections athletes can establish with their supporters, fostering a sense of community and inspiration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/shreyas-iyer-signs-autograph-clicks-selfie-with-fan-girl-watch/articleshow/117281328.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/shreyas-iyer-signs-autograph-clicks-selfie-with-fan-girl-watch/articleshow/117281328.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shreyas Iyer signs autograph, clicks selfie with fan girl - WATCH - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Starstruck! Shreyas Iyer's Heartwarming Gesture for a Fan Goes Viral - WATCH</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not specified] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source not specified]</p>
<p>In a touching moment that has captured the hearts of many, Indian cricketer Shreyas Iyer showcased his kindness by interacting with a young fans, which has since gone viral.</p>
<ul>
<li>Shreyas Iyer met a fan girl and shared a moment of joy.</li>
<li>The heartwarming interaction was filmed and shared widely on social media.</li>
<li>Fans have expressed their admiration for Iyer's humility and approachability.</li>
<li>Various social media platforms are abuzz with reactions and shares of the video.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It's inspiring to see such kind gestures from our sports heroes,” a fan commented.</blockquote>
<p>This event highlights the important connection between athletes and their fans, promoting positivity and goodwill.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/shreyas-iyer-signs-autograph-clicks-selfie-with-fan-girl-watch/articleshow/117281328.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/shreyas-iyer-signs-autograph-clicks-selfie-with-fan-girl-watch/articleshow/117281328.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Martin Zubimedni transfer twist emerges amid Arsenal '£51m plan' and Man City & Liverpool 'interest' - ManchesterWorld]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Martin Zubimendi Transfer Twist Emerges Amid Arsenal '£51m Plan' and Man City & Liverpool 'Interest'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Latest update<br><strong>Source:</strong> Daily Mail</p>
<img src="https://videos.skysports.com/image/v1/static/6057984924001/a5021a2f-3913-4480-893b-5161e33471bb/ec68be81-922f-4fb7-9ade-74f62a9788b8/160x90/match/image.jpg" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Transfer Talk: Mendes to Man Utd would be a highlight.</figcaption>
<p>Manchester City target Martin Zubimendi is reportedly close to joining Premier League rivals Arsenal, amid strong interest from Liverpool.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Daily Mail reports that Zubimendi has turned down a move to Liverpool in the summer.</li>
<li>Arsenal is allegedly planning to meet the midfielder’s £51 million release clause.</li>
<li>Real Sociedad is against Zubimendi's move to Arsenal but negotiations are at an advanced stage.</li>
<li>Zubimendi expressed his focus on the current season and dismisses transfer rumors.</li>
<li>Manchester City sees Zubimendi as a potential replacement for the injured Rodri.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I tried to be, although it may seem untrue, as selfish as possible, thinking about myself first and foremost, the best thing was to stay.” - Martin Zubimendi</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while Arsenal appears committed to signing Zubimendi, the player remains focused on his current club, creating uncertainty around the transfer.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.manchesterworld.uk/sport/football/manchester-city/martin-zubimedni-transfer-twist-emerges-amid-arsenal-ps51m-plan-and-man-city-liverpool-interest-4945731</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.manchesterworld.uk/sport/football/manchester-city/martin-zubimedni-transfer-twist-emerges-amid-arsenal-ps51m-plan-and-man-city-liverpool-interest-4945731</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai selectors to approach Rohit Sharma over Ranji Trophy availability amid continued uncertainty - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai Selectors to Approach Rohit Sharma for Ranji Trophy Participation</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Rohit-Sharma-bats-during-a-practice-session-of-Mum_1736963678886_1736963689739.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma bats during a practice session of Mumbai's Ranji Trophy team at Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai.(PTI)" title="Rohit Sharma bats during a practice session of Mumbai's Ranji Trophy team at Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai.(PTI)">
<figcaption>Rohit Sharma bats during a practice session of Mumbai's Ranji Trophy team at Wankhede Stadium in Mumbai.(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Team India captain Rohit Sharma has not confirmed his availability for the upcoming Ranji Trophy match against Jammu and Kashmir. Amidst his recent poor performance, the Mumbai Cricket Association plans to engage with him for his selection.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rohit Sharma's performance has drawn scrutiny due to low scores in previous Test series.</li>
  <li>The MCA confirms it will approach Sharma for selection before announcing the squad.</li>
  <li>A scheduled squad announcement is expected on January 20.</li>
  <li>Young talents Yashasvi Jaiswal, Shubman Gill, and Rishabh Pant are confirmed to play in upcoming Ranji matches.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If you don’t give importance to domestic cricket, you will never get the desired players that you want,” said head coach Gautam Gambhir.</blockquote>
<p>The selectors' decision will be crucial for both Rohit Sharma and the Mumbai team as the Ranji Trophy season continues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/mumbai-selectors-to-approach-rohit-sharma-over-ranji-trophy-availability-amid-continued-uncertainty-101736961990505.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/mumbai-selectors-to-approach-rohit-sharma-over-ranji-trophy-availability-amid-continued-uncertainty-101736961990505.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:36:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India Open Super 750: Lakshya Sen, Priyanshu Rajawat, HS Prannoy bow out in round one as giddy days of men’s singles feel distant - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Open Super 750: Lakshya Sen, Priyanshu Rajawat, HS Prannoy bow out in round one</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/India-badminton.jpg?w=640" alt="Lakshya Sen HS Prannoy Priyanshu India Open" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Lakshya Sen, Priyanshu Rajawat and HS Prannoy in action on Day 2 at Yonex Sunrise India Open 2025. (BAI)</figcaption><p>The Indian men's singles badminton players faced disappointing early exits at the India Open Super 750, with Priyanshu Rajawat and HS Prannoy losing in three games, and Lakshya Sen failing to make a mark in a straight-games defeat.</p><ul><li>All three players, once celebrated for their achievements like the Thomas Cup victory, struggled to progress beyond the first round.</li><li>Priyanshu lost to Kodai Naraoka in an intense battle, while Prannoy fell to Su Li Yang.</li><li>Lakshya Sen faced a challenging match against Lin Chun Yi, struggling with pace and momentum.</li><li>Both Priyanshu and Prannoy expressed their frustrations, while Lakshya described his performance as a 'bad day.'</li><li>Prannoy, dealing with health setbacks, is focused on remaining competitive despite uncertainties.</li></ul><blockquote>“I couldn’t really play my game.” - Lakshya Sen</blockquote><blockquote>“It’s tough... I have to find my own answers.” - HS Prannoy</blockquote><p>The performances raise concerns about the current state of Indian men's singles badminton, highlighting the need for improvement if they are to reclaim their previous success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/badminton/india-open-lakshya-sen-priyanshu-prannoy-bow-out-mens-singles-9780960/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/badminton/india-open-lakshya-sen-priyanshu-prannoy-bow-out-mens-singles-9780960/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 23:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir accuses Sarfaraz Khan of leaking dressing room information during Border-Gavaskar Trophy: Report - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AFBVV95cUxPMEs3UUJaTjFNd2ZzYlFaTWVEMEowa29MM09zOGRlTWlsN2NxWE9NdWhwT284U0JYbkd0VkJlb2hvSld3WGUyQ2pWcDk0X0x5cXp2aEpGRm1wNTE5VkpRcDNNcC1kTVVrOGRnZWdwTmRtR3dJZEo0cWlpM3JoVi1MLWdXTkZqSW9neTY5cjU5Szg5SXgtSXlWWTQ1bkFYM1N1NG1pVVBDWGhLM1l6bjdKOGlwc3NKWEctT3o4UjVnUzFSOEJLMWltcWNjbEhTZW5iRUNBaGpuVGhVRF85dVNGc9IB5gFBVV95cUxQTjM2WXgzaVdDS09WOTRlSVNlc2k1UXVMaExDdzJjd1hQWFkzMm5rdm1mZU9NUHpnN1BqbkU5Y194a0JycnM5SFNVa3RIQllMY0tDZWIxbUJHMEtmVWVsbnFpYjRORHhpcUxMU2VOOWgtZVN2NTRCQ1RET2gta0g4eUxpTmZDS1dLdjdMRTNISHBzcTNvUkFYQURRZ0ZaYUEyMzJFWFhacGhqNUkzX1lNdENJMFNnTGxrVElwbk5HWmtTVmtxZFU2TFVISW1JUGFKR0R2RHI0eXpCeHpIaENaRXVwX2tidw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AFBVV95cUxPMEs3UUJaTjFNd2ZzYlFaTWVEMEowa29MM09zOGRlTWlsN2NxWE9NdWhwT284U0JYbkd0VkJlb2hvSld3WGUyQ2pWcDk0X0x5cXp2aEpGRm1wNTE5VkpRcDNNcC1kTVVrOGRnZWdwTmRtR3dJZEo0cWlpM3JoVi1MLWdXTkZqSW9neTY5cjU5Szg5SXgtSXlWWTQ1bkFYM1N1NG1pVVBDWGhLM1l6bjdKOGlwc3NKWEctT3o4UjVnUzFSOEJLMWltcWNjbEhTZW5iRUNBaGpuVGhVRF85dVNGc9IB5gFBVV95cUxQTjM2WXgzaVdDS09WOTRlSVNlc2k1UXVMaExDdzJjd1hQWFkzMm5rdm1mZU9NUHpnN1BqbkU5Y194a0JycnM5SFNVa3RIQllMY0tDZWIxbUJHMEtmVWVsbnFpYjRORHhpcUxMU2VOOWgtZVN2NTRCQ1RET2gta0g4eUxpTmZDS1dLdjdMRTNISHBzcTNvUkFYQURRZ0ZaYUEyMzJFWFhacGhqNUkzX1lNdENJMFNnTGxrVElwbk5HWmtTVmtxZFU2TFVISW1JUGFKR0R2RHI0eXpCeHpIaENaRXVwX2tidw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 23:30:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah follows Mohammed Shami to clear the air on reports of being advised bed rest to recover from a back injury - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Addresses Bed Rest Rumors Amid Injury Recovery</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Cric Today</p><img width="1200" height="675" src="https://crictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Jasprit-Bumrah-2.webp" alt="Jasprit Bumrah" /><figcaption>Bumrah decided to clear the air on the reports and accused one of the X users of planting wrong stories on him.</figcaption><p>Jasprit Bumrah recently spoke out regarding rumors about needing bed rest to recover from a back injury. He has mocked claims circulating on social media and has addressed the uncertainty surrounding his fitness for the upcoming ICC Champions Trophy 2025.</p><ul><li>Bumrah was injured in the final Test against Australia due to back spasms.</li><li>Medical staff recommend rest to recover from back swelling before rehabilitation can continue.</li><li>He criticized a social media user for spreading false information regarding his injury status.</li><li>Bumrah was instrumental in his recent series against Australia, taking 32 wickets.</li></ul><blockquote>“I know fake news is easy to spread but this made me laugh. Sources unreliable,” wrote Bumrah on his social media account.</blockquote><p>The article highlights the broader implications of misinformation in sports and the pressure athletes face in maintaining their public image.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/jasprit-bumrah-follows-mohammed-shami-to-clear-the-air-on-reports-of-being-advised-bed-rest-to-recover-from-a-back-injury/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/jasprit-bumrah-follows-mohammed-shami-to-clear-the-air-on-reports-of-being-advised-bed-rest-to-recover-from-a-back-injury/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 23:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Probably should have scored 10' - Declan Rice insists Arsenal could have routed Tottenham in north London derby victory as he hints at incoming transfers amid injury woes - GOAL English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPLTYycWxqMU1ndkRqUDBCbDcyd09nUGd6VFU2ZURJQmxIVmZ0NFhHZm5HY3cyNnpGdmg2OG9kVkMyUGRMTTY5Vkl4QmVGWEhnR2JPZjM5d1l0al9VQ3VvUENDV2RuZGlkamtHNVEybnpYdlJocFJHNnFMVUZJNzB1eHdxc3VSSjQ4a2tULThTTnFRYW5SdVlycERoYjNUNTRmckhJeGlLUW1RVWtrdVUxWGJkUC11V0lLTmVRS1VvWjBMcDktNHpuYWFOYlUybHJfS1VxVU5vb3hhUHI4WGpWaGxuZlk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxPLTYycWxqMU1ndkRqUDBCbDcyd09nUGd6VFU2ZURJQmxIVmZ0NFhHZm5HY3cyNnpGdmg2OG9kVkMyUGRMTTY5Vkl4QmVGWEhnR2JPZjM5d1l0al9VQ3VvUENDV2RuZGlkamtHNVEybnpYdlJocFJHNnFMVUZJNzB1eHdxc3VSSjQ4a2tULThTTnFRYW5SdVlycERoYjNUNTRmckhJeGlLUW1RVWtrdVUxWGJkUC11V0lLTmVRS1VvWjBMcDktNHpuYWFOYlUybHJfS1VxVU5vb3hhUHI4WGpWaGxuZlk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 23:00:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Probably should have scored 10' - Declan Rice insists Arsenal could have routed Tottenham in north London derby victory as he hints at incoming transfers amid injury woes - Goal.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Probably should have scored 10' - Declan Rice Reflects on Arsenal's Performance Against Tottenham and Talks Possible Transfers</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 - <strong>Source:</strong> Goal.com</p><p>Declan Rice believes Arsenal had the chance to achieve a more dominant victory against Tottenham and hints at potential transfer activity amid injury challenges.</p><ul><li>Declan Rice suggests Arsenal could have scored more goals in their latest match.</li><li>He emphasizes the team's need for strategic additions to cope with injury concerns.</li><li>The performance highlights Arsenal's attacking prowess and areas needing improvement.</li></ul><blockquote>"We should have been more clinical, honestly. The opportunities were there."</blockquote><p>As Arsenal looks to build on their recent successes, the talk of transfers and squad depth becomes increasingly relevant.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.goal.com/en-in/lists/declan-rice-arsenal-routed-tottenham-north-london-derby-victory-hints-incoming-transfers-injury-woes/bltf9fb35f5d12329fd</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.goal.com/en-in/lists/declan-rice-arsenal-routed-tottenham-north-london-derby-victory-hints-incoming-transfers-injury-woes/bltf9fb35f5d12329fd</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 23:00:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Africa sweat on Rassie van der Dussen's finger injury - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Africa Sweats on Rassie van der Dussen's Finger Injury Ahead of Champions Trophy</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p>
<img src="https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg" alt="Rassie van der Dussen" />
<figcaption>Rassie van der Dussen in action during the match.</figcaption>
<p>Rassie van der Dussen performed admirably in a recent match, scoring 91 runs, but faces uncertainty regarding his participation in the upcoming Champions Trophy due to a finger injury sustained while fielding. This follows South Africa's previous injury setbacks with Anrich Nortje also ruled out.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Van der Dussen scored an unbeaten 91, showcasing his batting skills.</li>
  <li>He suffered a finger injury while fielding close in when trying to catch a ball.</li>
  <li>The injury was swollen but did not appear serious immediately after the match.</li>
  <li>South Africa is concerned as they are already missing other key players.</li>
  <li>There are discussions around the talent emerging in South African cricket.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“As a senior player, it pushes you to never be complacent but also it shows you the talent we have in our system coming through.” - Rassie van der Dussen</blockquote>
<p>Despite the injury worries, van der Dussen’s impressive performance indicates his importance to the team's strategy moving forward in international cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa20-2025-south-africa-sweat-on-van-der-dussen-injury-1469208</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa20-2025-south-africa-sweat-on-van-der-dussen-injury-1469208</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 22:33:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four Observations from Bayern Munich’s 5-0 smashing of Hoffenheim - Bavarian Football Works]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bayern Munich Dominates Hoffenheim with 5-0 Victory</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Bavarian Football Works</p>
<p>This article recaps Bayern Munich's impressive 5-0 win over Hoffenheim, highlighting key performances, particularly from Leroy Sané, and the struggles faced by Hoffenheim.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bayern Munich showcased dominant performance, scoring five goals against Hoffenheim.</li>
  <li>Leroy Sané scored two goals and returned to form after a period of struggle.</li>
  <li>The match highlights Bayern's aggressive intent, continuously pressing Hoffenheim.</li>
  <li>Hoffenheim failed to create significant chances, hampering their gameplay.</li>
  <li>Pressure mounts on Hoffenheim as they face relegation threats.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It’s a big [expletive],” lamented Andrej Kramarić after the match.</blockquote>
<p>Bayern's performance indicates a returning vigor post-Winterpause, while Hoffenheim must urgently rethink their strategies to avoid relegation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bavarianfootballworks.com/2025/1/15/24344607/bayern-munich-tsg-hoffenheim-observations-match-analysis-leroy-sane-bundesliga-kramaric-pavlovic-tel</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bavarianfootballworks.com/2025/1/15/24344607/bayern-munich-tsg-hoffenheim-observations-match-analysis-leroy-sane-bundesliga-kramaric-pavlovic-tel</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 22:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why did PUMA rebrand itself as PVMA ? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PUMA Rebrands as PVMA in Honor of PV Sindhu</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117244110,imgsize-78568,width-400,resizemode-4/117244110.jpg" alt="Why did PUMA rebrand itself as PVMA ?" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>PUMA rebrands to PVMA in honor of PV Sindhu.</figcaption>
<p>PUMA India has undertaken a significant rebranding initiative, temporarily changing its signage to “PVMA” in celebration of its new collaboration with badminton champion PV Sindhu.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The rebranding symbolizes PUMA's official entry into badminton.</li>
  <li>The campaign generated excitement online and involved changing signage in select stores across India.</li>
  <li>A new badminton range will launch featuring high-performance products.</li>
  <li>PV Sindhu joins an elite roster of PUMA athletes, including various sports stars and influencers.</li>
  <li>57 million fans of badminton are currently in India, with a growing interest among Gen Z.</li>
  <li>Official debut of the collaboration is set for the India Open 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I hope to inspire others, especially women, to take risks, believe in themselves, and strive for greatness both on and off the court.” - PV Sindhu</blockquote>
<p>This partnership not only enhances badminton’s profile in India but also aims to inspire a new generation of players through innovative sport initiatives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/fashion/luxury/fashion/why-did-puma-rebrand-itself-as-pvma-/articleshow/117244110.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/fashion/luxury/fashion/why-did-puma-rebrand-itself-as-pvma-/articleshow/117244110.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohammedan SC vs Chennaiyin FC, ISL 2024-25: Match Preview, Live Streaming, Predicted XI and Full Squads - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammedan SC vs Chennaiyin FC, ISL 2024-25 Match Preview</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 16, 2025, 01:01 IST</p><figure><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='Mohammedan SC vs Chennaiyin FC match preview' title='Mohammedan SC vs Chennaiyin FC match preview'><figcaption>Mohammedan SC vs Chennaiyin FC match preview, live streaming details, Dream11 predictions, predicted starting XI, and full squads for ISL 2024-25.</figcaption></figure><p>Mohammedan SC will face Chennaiyin FC in their next Indian Super League 2024-25 match on January 15 at the Kishore Bharati Krirangan in Kolkata, starting at 7:30 pm IST. Both teams are struggling for form, with Mohammedan having won just one of their last five matches and Chennaiyin sitting in 10th place.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Mohammedan SC's recent form: Won 1 of last 5 matches.</li><li>Chennaiyin FC's current position: 10th place with 16 points.</li><li>Previous match outcomes: Mohammedan SC won against Bengaluru FC; Chennaiyin FC drew with Odisha FC.</li><li>Broadcasting: Match to be aired on Sports18 in India.</li><li>Streaming: Available on the JioCinema app and website.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics</h2><blockquote>Chennaiyin FC have faced Mohammedan SC just once in ISL, losing 0-1.</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>This match could be pivotal for both teams as they look to improve their standings in the league.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/football/mohammedan-sc-vs-chennaiyin-fc-isl-2024-25-live-streaming-match-preview-squads-lineups-probable-xi-9189160.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/football/mohammedan-sc-vs-chennaiyin-fc-isl-2024-25-live-streaming-match-preview-squads-lineups-probable-xi-9189160.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:41:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Man Utd striker wants to join Barcelona - English Premier League Index - Opta Stats]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Report: Rashford Prioritises Barcelona Amid January Transfer Speculation</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Sport</p>
<figure><img src="https://eplindex.com/wp-content/uploads/imago1045574031-scaled.jpg" alt="Rashford" width="2560" height="1784"><figcaption>Photo: IMAGO</figcaption></figure>
<p>Marcus Rashford has become a key target for Barcelona as they look to enhance their attacking options during the January transfer window. Rashford has expressed a desire to join Barcelona but has set a deadline of January 15 for the club's response regarding a potential loan.</p>
<ul>
<li>Barcelona considering Rashford primarily as a loan option.</li>
<li>Hansi Flick supports the move, citing Rashford's versatility.</li>
<li>Concerns exist within Barcelona about Rashford's consistency and off-field issues.</li>
<li>Rashford's representatives are exploring other offers from AC Milan and Borussia Dortmund.</li>
<li>A meeting with Dortmund officials indicates interest but Rashford prefers a move to Barcelona.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Rashford brings a dynamic edge to the game, and his skill set aligns with the demands of modern football.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while Rashford’s potential transfer to Barcelona is steeped in hope for personal revival, it raises questions about Manchester United’s management of his talents and future implications for the club.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://eplindex.com/125660/report-man-utd-striker-wants-to-join-barcelona.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://eplindex.com/125660/report-man-utd-striker-wants-to-join-barcelona.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:30:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rift Between Gautam Gambhir And Morne Morkel After India Head Coach Scolded South African For Arriving Late - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/rift-between-gautam-gambhir-and-morne-morkel-after-india-head-coach-scolded-south-african-for-arriving-late-to-a-training-session-report-9189374.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/rift-between-gautam-gambhir-and-morne-morkel-after-india-head-coach-scolded-south-african-for-arriving-late-to-a-training-session-report-9189374.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:23:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fabrizio Romano: 'Incredible' Man Utd Star is 'Dream' Signing for Euro Giants - GIVEMESPORT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garnacho: A Dream Signing for Napoli?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> GiveMeSport</p><figure><img src="https://static0.givemesportimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/untitled-design-2025-01-15t151727-553.png" alt="Alejandro Garnacho"><figcaption>Alejandro Garnacho</figcaption></figure><p>The article discusses Alejandro Garnacho's fluctuating status at Manchester United and the interest from Napoli for a potential transfer.</p><ul><li>Garnacho's inconsistent playtime under coach Ruben Amorim raises questions about his future.</li><li>He has performed well when given the chance, contributing to a recent FA Cup victory.</li><li>Rumors suggest Napoli views him as a replacement for Khvicha Kvaratskhelia, who may leave for PSG.</li><li>Fabrizio Romano highlights the high price tag United would set for Garnacho.</li></ul><blockquote>“He's kind of a dream signing for Napoli. He's a player they really appreciate internally.” - Fabrizio Romano</blockquote><p>The interest from Napoli indicates that Garnacho's talent is recognized, but any transfer would have to align with the club's budget considerations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.givemesport.com/manchester-united-transfer-news-garnacho-dream-napoli-signing-conte/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.givemesport.com/manchester-united-transfer-news-garnacho-dream-napoli-signing-conte/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ruben Amorim names pacey Man Utd wonderkid who is 'training really well' - Metro.co.uk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://metro.co.uk/2025/01/15/ruben-amorim-names-pacey-man-utd-wonderkid-training-really-well-22368099/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://metro.co.uk/2025/01/15/ruben-amorim-names-pacey-man-utd-wonderkid-training-really-well-22368099/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Durbar Rajshahi's local players skip training to protest non-payment of fees - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Local Players of Durbar Rajshahi Protest Non-Payment by Skipping Training</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p>
<p>Durbar Rajshahi's Bangladeshi players opted to skip a training session in Chattogram to protest their unpaid fees by the BPL franchise, which has led to significant unrest among the local players.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The training session was canceled after players voiced their concerns over delayed payments.</li>
  <li>Overseas players received 25% of their fees only after the fourth match of the season.</li>
  <li>The board president discussed the issue with Rajshahi's management in an attempt to resolve the matter.</li>
  <li>Players faced bounced cheques, leading to threats of not participating in an upcoming match.</li>
  <li>The franchise has not followed the BPL payment schedule as required.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We haven’t been paid our wages. None of us have.” — Anamul Haque, Captain of Durbar Rajshahi</blockquote>
<p>The situation remains tense, with players threatening to withdraw from future games unless payments are made promptly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/bpl-2025-durbar-rajshahi-local-players-skip-training-to-protest-non-payment-of-fees-1469204</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/bpl-2025-durbar-rajshahi-local-players-skip-training-to-protest-non-payment-of-fees-1469204</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:30:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Titled Tuesday - January 14, 2025 - Chess.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Titled Tuesday Sets Participation Record, Hikaru Joins 2025 Win Column</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Chess.com</p>
<img src="https://www.chess.com/bundles/web/images/image-default.445cb543.svg" alt="Titled Tuesday">
<figcaption>Titled Tuesday Tournament</figcaption>
<p>Titled Tuesday achieved a participation milestone with 905 players competing, marking the first time the event surpassed 900 participants since June 2020. GM Arjun Erigaisi won the early tournament, while GM Hikaru Nakamura claimed victory in the late tournament.</p>
<ul>
<li>905 participants set a new record for Titled Tuesday.</li>
<li>GM Arjun Erigaisi scored 10 points in the early tournament.</li>
<li>GM Hikaru Nakamura won the late tournament with a score of 9.5 points.</li>
<li>The tournaments contributed to the ongoing Titled Tuesday Grand Prix standings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Over 25k watched on Twitch / X. @chesscom truly has the strongest tournament in the world TWICE every Tuesday!!” — Hikaru Nakamura</blockquote>
<p>This week's tournaments demonstrated the growing popularity of online chess, as over 25,000 viewers tuned in to watch.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.chess.com/news/view/arjun-nakamura-win-titled-tuesday-january-14-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.chess.com/news/view/arjun-nakamura-win-titled-tuesday-january-14-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Titled Tuesday Sets Participation Record, Hikaru Joins 2025 Win Column - Chess.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Titled Tuesday Sets Participation Record, Hikaru Joins 2025 Win Column</h1><p><strong>Date: January 14, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Chess.com</strong></p><img src="https://www.chess.com/bundles/web/images/image-default.445cb543.svg" alt="Titled Tuesday"><figcaption>Titled Tuesday event image</figcaption><p>The latest Titled Tuesday event attracted a record 905 participants, marking the highest turnout since June 2020. GM Arjun Erigaisi won the early tournament, while GM Hikaru Nakamura secured his first victory of 2025 in the late tournament.</p><ul><li>The event saw GM Arjun Erigaisi score 10 points but needed tiebreaks to win against GM Hikaru Nakamura.</li><li>Nakamura finished with 9.5 points and won the late event, his first of the year.</li><li>Over 25,000 viewers watched the event live on Twitch/X.</li></ul><blockquote>“Over 25k watched on Twitch / X. @chesscom truly has the strongest tournament in the world TWICE every Tuesday!!” — Hikaru Nakamura</blockquote><p>The Titled Tuesday series continues to draw significant participation and viewer engagement, highlighting its popularity within the chess community.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.chess.com/news/view/arjun-nakamura-win-titled-tuesday-january-14-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.chess.com/news/view/arjun-nakamura-win-titled-tuesday-january-14-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>