<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:24:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 03:24:55 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R Ashwin Hits Bullseye, Explains Difference Between MS Dhoni And Other Captains - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>R Ashwin Hits Bullseye, Explains Difference Between MS Dhoni And Other Captains</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width='639' height='479' src='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/qrmafk8g_ms-dhoni-and-r-ashwin-bcci_625x300_24_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605' alt='R Ashwin and MS Dhoni' /><figcaption>File photo of MS Dhoni and R Ashwin © BCCI/Sportzpics</figcaption><p>Ravichandran Ashwin highlights the attributes that make MS Dhoni a standout captain compared to others, emphasizing his focus on the basics and decision-making during critical moments.</p><ul><li>Ashwin praises Dhoni's ability to stick to fundamental principles of cricket.</li><li>Dhoni's calm leadership led India to several significant victories, including T20 and ODI World Cups.</li><li>Examples of Dhoni allowing bowlers to express themselves while enforcing standards.</li><li>Dhoni's captaincy in IPL helped Tushar Deshpande become a top wicket-taker.</li><li>Statistical overview of Dhoni's success as a captain in all formats.</li></ul><blockquote>"In my head, I think he does most of the basic things right... over the years, I realised people have forgotten the basics." - R Ashwin</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Ashwin's observations shed light on Dhoni's unique style of captaincy, which balances simplicity with effectiveness, making him one of cricket's most revered leaders.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/r-ashwin-hits-bullseye-explains-difference-between-ms-dhoni-and-other-captains-7317802</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/r-ashwin-hits-bullseye-explains-difference-between-ms-dhoni-and-other-captains-7317802</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:57:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma Troubled By Part-Timer Devdutt Padikkal In Nets, Video Viral - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-troubled-by-part-timer-devdutt-padikkal-in-nets-video-viral-7312682</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-troubled-by-part-timer-devdutt-padikkal-in-nets-video-viral-7312682</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:43:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ben Stokes ruled out of all cricket for three months - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ben Stokes Ruled Out of Cricket for Three Months Due to Injury</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Tue, Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c590565/ben-stokes-will-be-out-of-acti.jpg" alt="Ben Stokes will be out of action for at least three months" title="Ben Stokes will be out of action for at least three months">
<figcaption>Ben Stokes will be out of action for at least three months © Getty</figcaption>
<p>Ben Stokes has been ruled out of all cricket for at least three months with a torn left hamstring, sustained during the third Test against New Zealand, which England won.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Stokes missed the England squad for the Champions Trophy due to his injury.</li>
  <li>He had previous injury issues, including knee surgery in October 2023.</li>
  <li>In August, he suffered a similar hamstring injury that limited his playing time.</li>
  <li>Stokes had been managing his workload and opted out of IPL 2024.</li>
  <li>He expressed confidence in his physical fitness before the injury occurred.</li>
  <li>He will also miss next year's Hundred competition starting on January 9.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I have to work so much harder on the physical side of the job to allow me to go out and do my job...” - Ben Stokes</blockquote>
<p>This latest injury adds to Stokes' challenges on the field, potentially impacting England's future performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132884/ben-stokes-ruled-out-of-all-cricket-for-three-months</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132884/ben-stokes-ruled-out-of-all-cricket-for-three-months</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:43:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I Deserve It. Let India Decide...": What Manu Bhaker Told Father On Khel Ratna Snub - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Some Orders Being Followed: Manu Bhaker's Father Hints At Khel Ratna Snub 'Conspiracy'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> July 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/d9uaet08_manu-bhaker-x_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Some Orders Being Followed: Manu Bhaker's Father Hints At Khel Ratna Snub 'Conspiracy'"><figcaption>File image of Manu Bhaker. © X (Twitter)</figcaption><p>Manu Bhaker, despite her remarkable achievements including two bronze medals at the Paris Olympic Games, has been snubbed for the Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna award by the Sports Ministry. Her father, Ram Kishan, implies a questionable decision-making process within the committee, voicing their belief that she is deserving of the award and criticizing the lack of respect for Olympic medalists.</p><ul><li>Manu Bhaker won two bronze medals at the Paris Olympics, making history for female shooters in India.</li><li>Her father claims there may be a conspiracy behind the lack of recommendation for the prestigious Khel Ratna award.</li><li>There is a contrast between the Sports Ministry's claim that Manu did not apply for the award and her father's assertions of multiple applications.</li><li>Her absence from the nominees list has disappointed many supporters, further fueled by previous controversies surrounding her social media posts.</li></ul><blockquote>"Despite such a fantastic performance if Manu is not recommended for Major Dhyan Chand Khel Ratna, then I am forced to believe that all is not well in the committee, or some orders were being followed." - Ram Kishan</blockquote><p>This controversy raises questions about the integrity of the awards process and highlights the challenges faced by athletes in India. Manu Bhaker's story reminds us of the need for recognition and support for those who achieve excellence in sports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/shooting/i-deserve-it-let-india-decide-what-manu-bhaker-told-father-on-khel-ratna-snub-7316545</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/shooting/i-deserve-it-let-india-decide-what-manu-bhaker-told-father-on-khel-ratna-snub-7316545</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:40:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘…MS Dhoni would be livid, he would take me off the bowling’: Ashwin dissects basics that set legendary captain apart - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ashwin Discusses What Sets MS Dhoni Apart as a Captain</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/Ashwin_CSK_BCCI_1639749410486_1734972696240.jpeg" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin reveals what makes MS Dhoni truly great as a leader. (BCCI)"><figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin reveals what makes MS Dhoni truly great as a leader. (BCCI)</figcaption><p>Ravichandran Ashwin highlights MS Dhoni's excellence as a captain, emphasizing that he excels in the basics of cricket, which many captains overlook.</p><ul><li>Dhoni recognized Ashwin's potential during the 2010 IPL season.</li><li>Ashwin recalls specific moments where Dhoni's expectations pushed players to perform better.</li><li>Ashwin emphasizes the importance of basic cricketing skills, which are often forgotten.</li><li>The conversation reveals insights into Dhoni's strategy and leadership approach.</li></ul><blockquote>“He does most basic things right, and most other captains miss the basic elementary things.” - Ravichandran Ashwin</blockquote><p>This conversation sheds light on the essential qualities that make MS Dhoni a legendary captain and highlights Ashwin's admiration for his leadership style.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ms-dhoni-would-be-livid-he-would-take-me-off-the-bowling-ashwin-dissects-basics-that-set-legendary-captain-apart-101734972698340.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ms-dhoni-would-be-livid-he-would-take-me-off-the-bowling-ashwin-dissects-basics-that-set-legendary-captain-apart-101734972698340.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:49:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Australian cricketers Pat Cummins, Steve Smith, Travis Head and others described BCCI and ICC: Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australian Cricketers Comment on ICC and BCCI Ahead of Test Match</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/smith_head_icc_bcci_1734933452438_1734933463540.jpg" alt="Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket" title="Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket"><figcaption>Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket</figcaption><p>Amid rising tensions between India and Australia, Australian cricketers, including Pat Cummins and Travis Head, made their comments on the ICC and BCCI during a game organized by ABC Sport.</p><ul><li>Pat Cummins described ICC, BCCI, and Indian cricket as 'Big'.</li><li>Travis Head referred to the BCCI as 'rulers' and the ICC as 'second'.</li><li>Glenn Maxwell, Alex Carey, and Steve Smith called the BCCI 'powerful' while describing the ICC as 'boss' and 'not as powerful'.</li><li>Steve Smith later backtracked on his remark, claiming it was a joke and restated the ICC as 'leaders'.</li><li>Usman Khawaja chose to 'pass' on describing the ICC, referencing past controversies with the organization.</li></ul><blockquote>“No, no I can't say that. It was a joke.” - Steve Smith</blockquote><p>The light-hearted game shed light on the players' perceptions of cricket's governing bodies as they prepare for the crucial Border-Gavaskar Trophy match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/steve-smith-calls-icc-not-as-powerful-as-bcci-then-immediately-backtracks-travis-head-says-indian-board-rulers-101734930106913.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/steve-smith-calls-icc-not-as-powerful-as-bcci-then-immediately-backtracks-travis-head-says-indian-board-rulers-101734930106913.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I am alive because…': Vinod Kambli clutches doctor's hand, gives first statement from hospital bed - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli's Emotional Hospital Statement: Grateful to Doctors</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Dec 24, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/20241223-MTH-PGD-MN-Vinod-kambali-001004-0_1734999473491_1734999481025.JPG" alt="Vinod Kambli continues to undergo treatment in Thane's Akruti Hospital(PTI)" title="Vinod Kambli continues to undergo treatment in Thane's Akruti Hospital(PTI)">
<figcaption>Vinod Kambli continues to undergo treatment in Thane's Akruti Hospital(PTI)</figcaption>
<p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli, recovering from clots in his brain, expressed profound gratitude to his doctors for saving his life during an emotional hospital statement while receiving treatment in Thane.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Kambli was hospitalized due to clots in his brain, reportedly in critical condition.</li>
    <li>He recounted a touching moment of holding his doctor’s hand and thanked them for their care.</li>
    <li>His condition deteriorated recently after suffering from a urinary infection.</li>
    <li>Despite past financial struggles, Kambli expressed commitment to rehabilitation if offered help by the cricket community.</li>
    <li>Acknowledged support from fans and the medical team during his recovery.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I am alive because of the doctors here. All I would say is that I will do whatever sir (referring to the doctor) asks me to. People will see the inspiration that I'll give them," said Kambli.</blockquote>
<p>Kambli's ongoing recovery brings hope, as he remains grateful for the support from both healthcare professionals and fans, highlighting a poignant chapter in his life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/i-am-alive-because-vinod-kambli-clutches-doctors-hand-gives-first-statement-from-hospital-bed-101734999376454.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/i-am-alive-because-vinod-kambli-clutches-doctors-hand-gives-first-statement-from-hospital-bed-101734999376454.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:34:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli is fine, says his friend Marcus Couto after ex-cricketer is hospitalized - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli is fine, says his friend Marcus Couto after ex-cricketer is hospitalized</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified. <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified.</p><p>Vinod Kambli, the former Indian cricketer, has been hospitalized recently, but his friend Marcus Couto has confirmed that he is doing fine.</p><ul><li>Kambli was hospitalized, prompting concern among fans and supporters.</li><li>His friend Marcus Couto provided reassurance about Kambli's health status.</li><li>The situation reflects the ongoing interest in Kambli’s well-being among the public.</li></ul><blockquote>“Vinod is fine, don’t worry,” said Marcus Couto.</blockquote><p>This reassurance from a close friend helps alleviate concerns surrounding Vinod Kambli's health following his hospitalization.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-is-fine-says-his-friend-couto-after-ex-cricketer-is-hospitalized/articleshow/116613381.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-is-fine-says-his-friend-couto-after-ex-cricketer-is-hospitalized/articleshow/116613381.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rattled sports ministry scrambles to save face, 'may award' Manu Bhaker Khel Ratna - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rattled sports ministry scrambles to save face, 'may award' Manu Bhaker Khel Ratna</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>The sports ministry is under pressure regarding the potential awarding of the Khel Ratna to shooter Manu Bhaker, as concerns arise over their handling of athlete recognition.</p><ul><li>The sports ministry is considering awarding the Khel Ratna to Manu Bhaker amidst criticisms.</li><li>There is ongoing debate about the criteria and process for awarding sports honors.</li><li>Ministry officials are attempting to appease the public and sports community.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are looking into all deserving candidates for the Khel Ratna this year.”</blockquote><p>This situation underscores the importance of transparency and fairness in the recognition of athletes' achievements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/more-sports/shooting/rattled-sports-ministry-scrambles-to-save-face-may-award-manu-khel-ratna/articleshow/116613326.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/more-sports/shooting/rattled-sports-ministry-scrambles-to-save-face-may-award-manu-khel-ratna/articleshow/116613326.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jio and Star to operate as unified entity from India-England series - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jio and Star to Operate as Unified Entity from India-England Series</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Mon, Dec 23, 2024, 05:16 PM | <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c383312/star-and-jio-formally-came-tog.jpg" alt="Star and Jio formally came together in November 2024 when Reliance Industries Ltd announced the merger" title="Star and Jio formally came together in November 2024 when Reliance Industries Ltd announced the merger" />
<figcaption>Star and Jio formally came together in November 2024 when Reliance Industries Ltd announced the merger © Getty</figcaption>
<p>With the completion of the mega-merger between Jio and Star, the two sports broadcasting giants will start operating as a unified entity during the England tour of India.</p>
<ul>
<li>The merger allows for cross-promotion of properties across platforms.</li>
<li>The England series will be broadcast live on Star Sports and Disney+ Hotstar, along with original platforms like JioCinema.</li>
<li>The transaction of the joint venture was worth INR 70.352 crore (USD 8.5 billion).</li>
<li>Reliance Industries invested Rs 11,500 crore (1.4 billion) into the venture.</li>
<li>Star Sports remains a leading sports channel in India but has faced competition from rivals like Sports18 and JioCinema.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The merger of the media and JioCinema businesses of Viacom18 into Star India Private Limited (SIPL) has become effective.” - Reliance Industries Limited</blockquote>
<p>This integration marks a new era in sports broadcasting in India, potentially reshaping how cricket and other sports are presented to the audience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132883/jio-and-star-to-operate-as-unified-entity-from-india-england-series</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132883/jio-and-star-to-operate-as-unified-entity-from-india-england-series</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:17:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Khel Ratna list not finalised, says ministry on Manu Bhaker ‘snub’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Khel Ratna Award Controversy: Ministry Responds to Manu Bhaker's Exclusion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Monday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/Manu-Bhaker-had-won-two-bronze-medals-at-the-Paris_1734973961937.jpg" alt="Manu Bhaker had won two bronze medals at the Paris Olympics -- the women’s 10m air pistol and the mixed 10m air pistol event. (PTI)" title="Manu Bhaker had won two bronze medals at the Paris Olympics -- the women’s 10m air pistol and the mixed 10m air pistol event. (PTI)"><figcaption>Manu Bhaker had won two bronze medals at the Paris Olympics -- the women’s 10m air pistol and the mixed 10m air pistol event. (PTI)</figcaption></figure><p>The sports ministry announced that Manu Bhaker was not considered for the Khel Ratna Award due to her not applying for it, despite her notable achievements.</p><ul><li>The sports ministry clarified that the final list for the Khel Ratna is not yet finalised.</li><li>Controversy arose as the awards committee's recommendations overlooked Bhaker, who has achieved historic success.</li><li>Critics, including Bhaker's family, question the need for an application for an athlete of her caliber.</li><li>The awards committee follows protocols requiring athletes to self-apply through an online portal.</li></ul><blockquote>“If she had applied, there is no reason for us not to consider her.”</blockquote><p>The Khel Ratna, India’s highest sports award, offers a medal and a cash prize of ₹25 lakh. The issue raises questions about the selection process and the treatment of exceptional athletes like Bhaker.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/khel-ratna-list-not-finalised-says-ministry-on-manu-bhaker-snub-101734973965522.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/khel-ratna-list-not-finalised-says-ministry-on-manu-bhaker-snub-101734973965522.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:12:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chelsea loanee Raheem Sterling ruled out ‘for a while’ at Arsenal with knee injury - We Ain't Got No History]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/2024/12/23/24328136/chelsea-loanee-raheem-sterling-ruled-out-for-a-while-at-arsenal-with-knee-injury</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/2024/12/23/24328136/chelsea-loanee-raheem-sterling-ruled-out-for-a-while-at-arsenal-with-knee-injury</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:56:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tanush Kotian to join India's Test squad as Ashwin's replacement - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tanush Kotian to Join India's Test Squad as Ashwin's Replacement</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><img src='https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg' alt='Tanush Kotian' /><figcaption>Tanush Kotian</figcaption><p>Tanush Kotian, a talented offspin-bowling allrounder from Mumbai, has been chosen to replace R Ashwin in India's Test squad for the upcoming Border-Gavaskar Trophy Tests.</p><ul><li>Kotian will fly to Melbourne following Ashwin's retirement after the third Test.</li><li>He is in Ahmedabad for the Vijay Hazare Trophy as part of the Mumbai squad.</li><li>The fourth Test starts on Thursday, with the series being tied 1-1.</li><li>Kotian has a first-class record of 101 wickets and 1525 runs in 33 matches.</li><li>He was instrumental in Mumbai's Ranji Trophy success, earning the Player-of-the-Tournament award.</li><li>Kotian is alongside Manav Suthar in being viewed as a future prospect for the India Test setup.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kotian was the only player to complete the season double of 500 runs and 25 wickets.”</blockquote><p>This inclusion highlights Kotian's rising profile and adds depth to India's spinning options as they navigate the crucial Test matches ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-tanush-kotian-join-india-squad-ashwin-replacement-1466332</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/border-gavaskar-trophy-2024-25-tanush-kotian-join-india-squad-ashwin-replacement-1466332</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:41:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Melbourne Pitch To Help Jasprit Bumrah And Co. In Boxing Day Test vs Australia? Curator Says: "As Mu.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxOU0hCSERSMlBFOUcxT0s3am9TNkR5UlFja0ZqRXItbTBlUlRYTHVJTDhsczFXLUJPVUJYTUZQcmRfcXU1d0lLRHhidnFqRmw4NmM0RFVYc2c2ckNXdkRYM2tVYnlmWUd6V0UxdFNGZVpWSENiUlNmTlFLSlZrSDBkRThhaUhnUjctMkNuQThyTmx5b1FScEsxLVc2TzVZN0lza2ttYjZhWkdVWUxJeU90bjY0V3JOSUwzRzE0RHAyWFZQVmMwU1Z1STdjQnMyLU8zWGRLRjlTZVo1TlNwU080alBteUhBV2dscDJkd01FN0V4X1A40gH8AUFVX3lxTFA1Q01fVVBwSGExa0N3RjFwekJVbTBOTFh0N1VnMktTMGF0ZmxMeUtaYmg2TDFfdWlSVWlZUjdjRFZiTTFBMUdwYl9aOWoyVlJ1ZnZjUWZlNWhtYWNnQnhTT3JleW4xZlZMa01hX1RvU0hfOXhiblZ6ZFQyb3FjbEpaVjZyRnVnMkVTaThJRlo2Yi1UbUpYSFB6cVYwM3Z4ZmlFVlpydUp5U0d4b0l3WE1zNnlJSHMwX0o5cXdzZFVPU3JLYUFOTkFuQlFMcFdLRkRKeS1pd0RJb1lmMUpKWFZzQXRremU4c0JQdHZvSVRJSVNTelFvV0tZY0hCYQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxOU0hCSERSMlBFOUcxT0s3am9TNkR5UlFja0ZqRXItbTBlUlRYTHVJTDhsczFXLUJPVUJYTUZQcmRfcXU1d0lLRHhidnFqRmw4NmM0RFVYc2c2ckNXdkRYM2tVYnlmWUd6V0UxdFNGZVpWSENiUlNmTlFLSlZrSDBkRThhaUhnUjctMkNuQThyTmx5b1FScEsxLVc2TzVZN0lza2ttYjZhWkdVWUxJeU90bjY0V3JOSUwzRzE0RHAyWFZQVmMwU1Z1STdjQnMyLU8zWGRLRjlTZVo1TlNwU080alBteUhBV2dscDJkd01FN0V4X1A40gH8AUFVX3lxTFA1Q01fVVBwSGExa0N3RjFwekJVbTBOTFh0N1VnMktTMGF0ZmxMeUtaYmg2TDFfdWlSVWlZUjdjRFZiTTFBMUdwYl9aOWoyVlJ1ZnZjUWZlNWhtYWNnQnhTT3JleW4xZlZMa01hX1RvU0hfOXhiblZ6ZFQyb3FjbEpaVjZyRnVnMkVTaThJRlo2Yi1UbUpYSFB6cVYwM3Z4ZmlFVlpydUp5U0d4b0l3WE1zNnlJSHMwX0o5cXdzZFVPU3JLYUFOTkFuQlFMcFdLRkRKeS1pd0RJb1lmMUpKWFZzQXRremU4c0JQdHZvSVRJSVNTelFvV0tZY0hCYQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:36:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tanush Kotian added to India's squad for the last two Tests against Australia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tanush Kotian added to India's squad for the last two Tests against Australia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116606686,imgsize-19566,width-400,resizemode-4/116606686.jpg" alt="Tanush Kotian added to India's squad for the last two Tests against Australia" title="Tanush Kotian (Photo by Darrian Traynor/Getty Images)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Tanush Kotian (Photo by Darrian Traynor/Getty Images)</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has announced the addition of all-rounder Tanush Kotian to the Indian cricket squad for the fourth and fifth Tests of the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy against Australia.</p><ul><li>Kotian, an off-spinner from Mumbai, has been rewarded for his impressive performances in domestic cricket.</li><li>He has taken 101 wickets in 33 first-class matches at an average of 25.70, including three five-wicket hauls.</li><li>Kotian has scored two centuries and 13 half-centuries.</li><li>The 24-year-old's standout performances in the 2023-24 Ranji Trophy season helped Mumbai achieve victory.</li><li>He was named Player of the Tournament, scoring 502 runs at an average of 41.83 and taking 29 wickets at an average of 16.96.</li><li>Kotian replaces R Ashwin, who announced his retirement after the third Test.</li></ul><blockquote>Kotian's addition provides the Indian team with an additional spin-bowling option and batting depth as they aim to clinch the series against the formidable Australian side.</blockquote><p>The series is currently tied at 1-1 after three Tests, making these upcoming matches crucial for both teams.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/tanush-kotian-added-to-indias-squad-for-the-last-two-tests-against-australia/articleshow/116606378.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/tanush-kotian-added-to-indias-squad-for-the-last-two-tests-against-australia/articleshow/116606378.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Wanted To Leave Things Behind As...": Ravichandran Ashwin Ends Silence On Abruptly Retiring Mid-Ser.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wanted To Leave Things Behind As...: Ravichandran Ashwin Ends Silence On Abruptly Retiring Mid-Series In Australia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> September 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ep9v9u98_ashwin-rohit-bcci_625x300_22_September_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin"/><figcaption>File photo of Ravichandran Ashwin and India captain Rohit Sharma © AFP</figcaption><p>Indian cricket star Ravichandran Ashwin surprised fans by announcing his retirement from international cricket after the third Test against Australia in the Border Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Ashwin, the highest wicket-taker among active bowlers, retired with two Tests remaining in the series.</li><li>His decision to retire was questioned by former players like Sunil Gavaskar.</li><li>In an interview, Ashwin expressed his need to not hold onto things and emphasized his belief in leaving without celebration or attention.</li><li>He reflected on his love for the game and his journey, highlighting that he has no regrets regarding his career.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’ve got no regrets because I’ve had to do it the hard way, but it has left me with the idea that the game has been my calling.” - Ravichandran Ashwin</blockquote><p>Ashwin's retirement marks the end of a significant chapter in Indian cricket, affecting fans and the team as they adapt to his absence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/wanted-to-leave-things-behind-as-ravichandran-ashwin-ends-silence-on-abruptly-retiring-mid-series-in-australia-7316719</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/wanted-to-leave-things-behind-as-ravichandran-ashwin-ends-silence-on-abruptly-retiring-mid-series-in-australia-7316719</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:11:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Celebrate 2024 And Vote For This Year's Chess.com Awards - Chess.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Celebrate 2024 And Vote For This Year's Chess.com Awards</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Misc</p>
<img src="https://images.chesscomfiles.com/uploads/v1/user/33.862d5ff1.35x35o.a0641016de67.png" alt="CHESScom">
<figcaption>Image by CHESScom</figcaption>
<p>2024 has been an eventful year for chess, marked by new talents and thrilling performances. It's time for you to vote for the 2024 Chess.com Awards and recognize the highlights of this year in chess.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Player of the Year:</strong> Best performance throughout the year</li>
  <li><strong>Woman Player of the Year:</strong> Best performance by a woman player</li>
  <li><strong>Creator of the Year:</strong> Creator with the biggest impact</li>
  <li><strong>Game of the Year:</strong> Most fantastic game played</li>
  <li><strong>Move of the Year:</strong> Most impressive move played</li>
  <li><strong>Rising Star of the Year:</strong> Best player who's 18 or younger</li>
  <li><strong>ChessKid of the Year:</strong> Best player who's 13 or younger</li>
  <li><strong>Commentator of the Year:</strong> Best explanation during an event</li>
  <li><strong>Photo of the Year:</strong> Most iconic photo</li>
  <li><strong>Book of the Year:</strong> Best book published this year</li>
</ul>
<p>Vote for your favorites by December 31 for a chance to win a diamond membership!</p>
<p>Learn more about the awards in the <a href="https://www.chess.com/article/view/chesscom-awards">Chess.com Awards guide</a>.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-chesscom-awards-vote</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-chesscom-awards-vote</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[R Ashwin Drops Bombshell After Shock Retirement, Reveals Why He Retired Without Any Fanfare - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>R Ashwin Drops Bombshell After Shock Retirement, Reveals Why He Retired Without Any Fanfare</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116606394,thumbsize-1995214,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116606394.jpg" alt="R Ashwin" title="R Ashwin"><figcaption>R Ashwin retired from international cricket in Australia. Photo: BCCI</figcaption><p>Indian cricket legend R Ashwin has announced his retirement from international cricket after the third Test match of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy against Australia. Despite his contributions as a match-winner, he has opted for a low-key exit, expressing his disdain for celebration and attention.</p><ul><li>Ashwin was dropped from the playing XI for the Perth Test and chose to retire after that game.</li><li>He contemplated retirement multiple times, stating the need for a creative future.</li><li>Throughout his career, Ashwin has achieved significant milestones including 3503 runs and 537 wickets in Tests.</li><li>He played pivotal roles in India's major tournament victories, including the 2011 World Cup.</li><li>Ashwin confirmed his return to cricket with Chennai Super Kings in IPL 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“I always wanted to leave things behind as nonchalantly as I could because I do not believe in people celebrating me.” - R Ashwin</blockquote><p>R Ashwin's retirement marks the end of an illustrious international career, characterized by remarkable achievements and a unique personal philosophy towards fame and celebration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/r-ashwin-drops-bombshell-after-shock-retirement-reveals-why-he-retired-without-any-fanfare-article-116606342</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/sports/cricket/r-ashwin-drops-bombshell-after-shock-retirement-reveals-why-he-retired-without-any-fanfare-article-116606342</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:58:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man Utd star ‘agitated’ team-mate vs Bournemouth as Amorim’s ‘telling’ reaction is revealed - Football365]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.football365.com/news/man-utd-agitated-zirkzee-dalot-bournemouth-amorim-telling-reaction</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.football365.com/news/man-utd-agitated-zirkzee-dalot-bournemouth-amorim-telling-reaction</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:45:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli diagnosed with 'clots in brain' in worrying health update; hospital provides life-long free treatment - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli Diagnosed with Brain Clots; Hospital Offers Free Treatment</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/Vinod_Kambli_1734967479613_1734967479963.jpg" alt="Vinod Kambli was admitted to the hospital on Monday.(ANI)"><figcaption>Vinod Kambli was admitted to the hospital on Monday.(ANI)</figcaption><p>Vinod Kambli, former Indian cricketer, has been diagnosed with clots in his brain after being admitted to the hospital following a health decline over the weekend. The hospital has committed to providing him with lifelong free treatment.</p><ul><li>Kambli was admitted to Akruti Hospital due to urinary infection and cramps.</li><li>Doctors found clots in his brain after conducting examinations.</li><li>The hospital's medical in-charge announced lifelong free treatment for Kambli.</li><li>Kambli suffered a previous collapse due to health issues about a month ago.</li><li>Concerns from cricket legends like Kapil Dev and Sunil Gavaskar regarding his health were noted.</li></ul><blockquote>"I was suffering from a urine problem... My head started spinning; I collapsed and fell down." - Vinod Kambli</blockquote><p>Kambli's health situation is being closely monitored, and he is receiving additional medical examinations as needed.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/vinod-kambli-diagnosed-with-clots-in-brain-in-worrying-health-update-hospital-provides-life-long-free-treatment-101734965708405.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/vinod-kambli-diagnosed-with-clots-in-brain-in-worrying-health-update-hospital-provides-life-long-free-treatment-101734965708405.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:28:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravichandran Ashwin ends silence on his decision to retire from international cricket: 'I have never been a person who…' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ravichandran-ashwin-ends-silence-on-his-decision-to-retire-from-international-cricket-i-have-never-been-a-person-who-101734966572331.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ravichandran-ashwin-ends-silence-on-his-decision-to-retire-from-international-cricket-i-have-never-been-a-person-who-101734966572331.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:27:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Very, Very Ordinary": Dinesh Karthik Doesn't Mince Words, Gives Blunt Analysis On Shubman Gill - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQRTRKNzllc19xUTI5Vjd4N2ZVZDFYRXBPUkZwWUVCWElUcmw0SnJoYzhwbmFtTjg5c3c5eTNKeWcxVHZpbFJmNHZXVF9rWUFhcENIU3lqRnBIaWZyV19FTUlla3VsUkp6SkxMQjA3RnppTlZOQ19PcmlRWjRmUUR5T0ZGTmZuUnowdkp0cHdNeG5DcXJYam1KM2M1T2RKVDM2S0VjYUNIS1JZZVQycTVTRHVvS0xkOTJkQVJQbmdmQnc2LWZWUTEyTXUzTUlXckxMUWF0QmFzNW1TVGNUbHZBTGN30gHqAUFVX3lxTE1HTUM2eDc0anRnbDVaWl9QT0xoY3BSZHNLc3QxWVBXZTA2UzJ1UFA1TUl5cTVlaGxFYmh5OE5ncnhJQ3EycWYzd0hFX25oWm9oSk5xOURCRnM1dHBVTWZfTXNtQ3dEWmdBbExzQXZWdUtTMGVRMTZnQ0JzNWFFVGZCYmRLYnVrRjllMkIyOFIzNlViVDZvNDhNSElmUDlrd1pKamUyUmlwNGNuZWdEQkUxZF9KOUJQMTJ3SW45cTNiQldyMWJnUll4SFdqNjBfLWhqYU0tQ2tuMWJXYTh2S3BZY3VfWkJtTW9hdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQRTRKNzllc19xUTI5Vjd4N2ZVZDFYRXBPUkZwWUVCWElUcmw0SnJoYzhwbmFtTjg5c3c5eTNKeWcxVHZpbFJmNHZXVF9rWUFhcENIU3lqRnBIaWZyV19FTUlla3VsUkp6SkxMQjA3RnppTlZOQ19PcmlRWjRmUUR5T0ZGTmZuUnowdkp0cHdNeG5DcXJYam1KM2M1T2RKVDM2S0VjYUNIS1JZZVQycTVTRHVvS0xkOTJkQVJQbmdmQnc2LWZWUTEyTXUzTUlXckxMUWF0QmFzNW1TVGNUbHZBTGN30gHqAUFVX3lxTE1HTUM2eDc0anRnbDVaWl9QT0xoY3BSZHNLc3QxWVBXZTA2UzJ1UFA1TUl5cTVlaGxFYmh5OE5ncnhJQ3EycWYzd0hFX25oWm9oSk5xOURCRnM1dHBVTWZfTXNtQ3dEWmdBbExzQXZWdUtTMGVRMTZnQ0JzNWFFVGZCYmRLYnVrRjllMkIyOFIzNlViVDZvNDhNSElmUDlrd1pKamUyUmlwNGNuZWdEQkUxZF9KOUJQMTJ3SW45cTNiQldyMWJnUll4SFdqNjBfLWhqYU0tQ2tuMWJXYTh2S3BZY3VfWkJtTW9hdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:24:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India dealt blow as pacer is ruled out for remainder of Australia series - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India dealt blow as pacer Shami is ruled out for remainder of Australia series</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Indian pacer Mohammed Shami has been ruled out for the rest of the Test series against Australia due to a recurring heel injury.</p><ul><li>Shami has been nursing a right heel injury since the 2023 Men’s Cricket World Cup.</li><li>He returned to competitive cricket in the Ranji Trophy and has participated in T20 games for West Bengal.</li><li>Indian captain Rohit Sharma emphasized the importance of not risking players who are not fully fit.</li><li>Shami has taken 31 wickets in 8 Tests played in Australia.</li><li>Harshit Rana has been included in the Test squad in Shami's absence.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is no way we want to take that chance – unless we are not 100%, 200% sure, we're not going to take any risk.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>India faces challenges in their bowling lineup without Shami, who has been pivotal in past tours to Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/india-dealt-blow-as-pacer-is-ruled-out-for-remainder-of-australia-series</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/india-dealt-blow-as-pacer-is-ruled-out-for-remainder-of-australia-series</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:22:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive | Father played with Joe Root’s dad, son to partner Virat Kohli: Jacob Bethell’s rise to RCB’s Rs 2.6 crore star - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/ipl/top-stories/exclusive-father-played-with-joe-roots-dad-son-to-partner-virat-kohli-jacob-bethells-rise-to-rcbs-rs-2-6-crore-star/articleshow/116604857.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/ipl/top-stories/exclusive-father-played-with-joe-roots-dad-son-to-partner-virat-kohli-jacob-bethells-rise-to-rcbs-rs-2-6-crore-star/articleshow/116604857.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive | Father played with Joe Root’s dad, son to partner Virat Kohli: Jacob Bethell’s rise to RCB’s - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/ipl/top-stories/exclusive-father-played-with-joe-roots-dad-son-to-partner-virat-kohli-jacob-bethells-rise-to-rcbs-rs-2-6-crore-star/articleshow/116604857.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/ipl/top-stories/exclusive-father-played-with-joe-roots-dad-son-to-partner-virat-kohli-jacob-bethells-rise-to-rcbs-rs-2-6-crore-star/articleshow/116604857.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Don't cry because its over': Heartfelt sentiments from R Ashwin with the Indian flag as the backdrop - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Don't cry because its over': Heartfelt sentiments from R Ashwin with the Indian flag as the backdrop</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116605370,imgsize-38078,width-400,resizemode-4/116605370.jpg" alt="R Ashwin (X Photo)"><figcaption>R Ashwin shares a heartfelt moment as he announces his retirement.</figcaption><p>India's premier off-spinner, R Ashwin, announced his retirement from international cricket while reflecting on his journey, expressing gratitude and fond memories.</p><ul><li>Ashwin retired mid-series against Australia, marking the end of a storied international career.</li><li>He is India's second-highest wicket-taker in Test cricket, with 537 wickets.</li><li>The farewell photo featured a smiling Ashwin with the Indian national flag in the background.</li><li>Despite his retirement, he affirmed he still has cricket left in him.</li><li>Ashwin's career spanned various formats, amassing significant wicket totals in ODIs and T20Is as well.</li></ul><blockquote>“Don't cry because it's over, smile because it happened.”</blockquote><p>R Ashwin's retirement emphasizes the end of an era for Indian cricket, celebrated for his skill, intellect, and contributions to the game.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/dont-cry-because-its-over-heartfelt-sentiments-from-r-ashwin-with-the-indian-flag-as-the-backdrop/articleshow/116604394.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/dont-cry-because-its-over-heartfelt-sentiments-from-r-ashwin-with-the-indian-flag-as-the-backdrop/articleshow/116604394.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star batter misses optional Aussie session; Indian quick officially ruled out — Test Daily - Fox Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygJBVV95cUxOdjM3Mm50bVpOVVVZem5BRWh6WHJXX3BUOG9iV0tMZGlBQzhKWWpYS2hnZk9LUVdmNTNrcHIwVmpIUmV4SHZJLUVMajhVNC1UQzk4NTdjS1JiVThzaEtkclI2bHJfbGk3UDlDeWlQcVlreHI2SlhlQVVTWmJUNWwzN1RMaE5qV29HTGFNdkFHeFYzMDhJdzZGcG9EZndFSzB4eExtM1hNdnhOR0VmV3ZIdmJSeVRYb1hlU1R6dGd4SzRaWkF5bUdRdkRLa3YwRmRpSy1yMENmZkNyRjAtcWdTOTJrcVlNRGlSMFBiekgyc01DOTJzaE9aRUJDZGVrUnVSdHRaUmZ6SGg4R2dEYi1MVEFpSFBBNlhFSXdZUF82OHlaN2I5NjdhVEN4SVAxRnM5Q1o2VDM1dGZMWmF3TS0xYzV1blFnNFpxTmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiygJBVV95cUxOdjM3Mm50bVpOVVVZem5BRWh6WHJXX3BUOG9iV0tMZGlBQzhKWWpYS2hnZk9LUVdmNTNrcHIwVmpIUmV4SHZJLUVMajhVNC1UQzk4NTdjS1JiVThzaEtkclI2bHJfbGk3UDlDeWlQcVlreHI2SlhlQVVTWmJUNWwzN1RMaE5qV29HTGFNdkFHeFYzMDhJdzZGcG9EZndFSzB4eExtM1hNdnhOR0VmV3ZIdmJSeVRYb1hlU1R6dGd4SzRaWkF5bUdRdkRLa3YwRmRpSy1yMENmZkNyRjAtcWdTOTJrcVlNRGlSMFBiekgyc01DOTJzaE9aRUJDZGVrUnVSdHRaUmZ6SGg4R2dEYi1MVEFpSFBBNlhFSXdZUF82OHlaN2I5NjdhVEN4SVAxRnM5Q1o2VDM1dGZMWmF3TS0xYzV1blFnNFpxTmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:11:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["No Worth Of Olympic Sports": Manu Bhaker's Father On Shooter's Khel Ratna Snub, Sports Ministry Say.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxPUDJKTmZ1Rzd0aVAyUlFMdWw2QUk3RkRva3N6Nktzc01oZ2NpcHNhbDRWZUI5bnZubjlPX3FYdV83QXhkQkNISkFGeGhUX0ptRDk3SURQSmh1cl9iNURIdHZfYlRUbDc2U0Q1NjVIeTRVbl9mZjlPVHpBNk5lVGZ4bG5ubzZEZ3Q0cl9WMkIxMTUxdFdOT003UjV0b3JPT2swREJHX05xc2p3TmFkcHpkdWI5RFNWQnViSFhxcDlMR29menU3ODg0V3d2OVoyOTZSYVQ1RDdvdUR1dXBvSTFj0gHnAUFVX3lxTE16NDNieVlQTktfTXprX2dMRl9ZYkIzb21fWjRET2ZENm5OaEtBV1VRS2RuTEFrRnAxOGNrQmwzLVRfV2FjZi1kb2kxZ1Z6NGo4MGo0YWt2bUFqRmVTWGw4aFFraUNZUG1laEFNYnlNeTBKLVNFMzItT1BYSWxscUdOVE9qS3NTd0dhTlBiRzRCZkl3Tk5ER1ZlbGd6UEw3UUVMWXBpWllSRFh4X2hRWmdzdVcxaUl5bzBZczV0NnZySlJ0dVhoZ2FPUTdRd0hOU1g4amV4U1d5Z1lyYjZfSk1kUTFIZnU2VQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3wFBVV95cUxPUDJKTmZ1Rzd0aVAyUlFMdWw2QUk3RkRva3N6Nktzc01oZ2NpcHNhbDRWZUI5bnZubjlPX3FYdV83QXhkQkNISkFGeGhUX0ptRDk3SURQSmh1cl9iNURIdHZfYlRUbDc2U0Q1NjVIeTRVbl9mZjlPVHpBNk5lVGZ4bG5ubzZEZ3Q0cl9WMkIxMTUxdFdOT003UjV0b3JPT2swREJHX05xc2p3TmFkcHpkdWI5RFNWQnViSFhxcDlMR29menU3ODg0V3d2OVoyOTZSYVQ1RDdvdUR1dXBvSTFj0gHnAUFVX3lxTE16NDNieVlQTktfTXprX2dMRl9ZYkIzb21fWjRET2ZENm5OaEtBV1VRS2RuTEFrRnAxOGNrQmwzLVRfV2FjZi1kb2kxZ1Z6NGo4MGo0YWt2bUFqRmVTWGw4aFFraUNZUG1laEFNYnlNeTBKLVNFMzItT1BYSWxscUdOVE9qS3NTd0dhTlBiRzRCZkl3Tk5ER1ZlbGd6UEw3UUVMWXBpWllSRFh4X2hRWmdzdVcxaUl5bzBZczV0NnZySlJ0dVhoZ2FPUTdRd0hOU1g4amV4U1d5Z1lyYjZfSk1kUTFIZnU2VQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:04:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chess.com Creator of the Month December 2024 - Chess.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sagar Shah On World Champion Gukesh, Samay Raina, Chess In India, And More</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Chess.com</p>
<figure><img src="https://images.chesscomfiles.com/uploads/v1/images_users/tiny_mce/NathanielGreen/phptLGmOt.jpg" alt="Wedding rings" width="480" height="320">
<figcaption>The very special rings from the wedding, and the article, that started it all. © ChessBase/Sagar Shah.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Sagar Shah, cofounder and CEO of ChessBase India, reflects on the evolution of chess in India, Gukesh's historic world championship victory, and the critical role of entertainment in promoting the game.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Sagar Shah shares insights on the founding of ChessBase India and its growth.</li>
    <li>He highlights the impact of comedians, particularly Samay Raina, in popularizing chess.</li>
    <li>Gukesh's world championship win is seen as a landmark achievement for Indian chess.</li>
    <li>ChessBase India's YouTube channel features over 14,000 videos with immense viewership.</li>
    <li>The approach to content creation focuses on player narratives and educational entertainment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Samay made chess fun and exciting, breaking barriers that it was only for the very intelligent." - Sagar Shah</blockquote>
<p>This piece serves as a testament to the dynamic growth of chess in India, showcasing the blend of serious competition and entertainment that is reshaping the sport's landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.chess.com/article/view/creator-of-the-month-sagar-shah</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.chess.com/article/view/creator-of-the-month-sagar-shah</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WEST INDIES ANNOUNCES TEST SQUAD FOR TWO TEST SERIES AGAINST PAKISTAN - Cricket West Indies]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxNODhtUkFOTkdRNllob0QzVS1rSS1iLXlYZzRva0NrZTFheGY3SnMySHg5VVVvOVdoNVNXLUFia3ExS2p6ZWk2Y09KTWV2czRBYUhPQzk4cXc3UV9tSmgxd0lKbFBYLThQejBVY1dFbUdUazJ1TWs5Q05rZ2NGMHJ4M0NGSWFvdEVzLVlwWndUUDZuMDNYNGdIcHhWVms0d2c3cEg2YU82Zllndw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxNODhtUkFOTkdRNllob0QzVS1rSS1iLXlYZzRva0NrZTFheGY3SnMySHg5VVVvOVdoNVNXLUFia3ExS2p6ZWk2Y09KTWV2czRBYUhPQzk4cXc3UV9tSmgxd0lKbFBYLThQejBVY1dFbUdUazJ1TWs5Q05rZ2NGMHJ4M0NGSWFvdEVzLVlwWndUUDZuMDNYNGdIcHhWVms0d2c3cEg2YU82Zllndw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:58:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>