<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:18:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:18:14 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I Am Your Father": Australia Media Insults Virat Kohli Again, Hits All-New Low - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"I Am Your Father": Australia Media Insults Virat Kohli Again, Hits All-New Low</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/s5krgq28_virat-kohli-mcg-afp_625x300_29_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Virat Kohli"/><figcaption>Virat Kohli has been a target at MCG © AFP</figcaption><p>Virat Kohli's contentious relationship with the Australian media continues as he becomes the subject of ridicule following an altercation during the 4th Test at the Melbourne Cricket Ground.</p><ul><li>Kohli has experienced multiple confrontations with the Australian media over the years.</li><li>He was recently referred to as a 'joker' amidst tensions with journalist Sam Konstas.</li><li>An Australian tabloid published a headline: "Virat, I am your father", mocking Kohli's performance.</li><li>During the match, Kohli confronted Konstas, who reacted confidently and scored impressively.</li><li>Kohli was penalized by the ICC after a physical confrontation, leading to further derogatory press coverage.</li></ul><blockquote>"You can't expect much from them. They always do that... Such hard words should not be used." - Wassan, reacting to the media's comments.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the ongoing tension and criticism Kohli faces, showcasing the intense media scrutiny athletes are under, especially during international tours.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/i-am-your-father-australia-media-insults-virat-kohli-again-hits-all-new-low-7354954</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/i-am-your-father-australia-media-insults-virat-kohli-again-hits-all-new-low-7354954</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:20:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WTC final scenarios: South Africa through, but what about India, Australia and Sri Lanka? - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WTC Final Scenarios: South Africa Qualified, India's, Australia's, and Sri Lanka's Paths</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p><p>South Africa's thrilling two-wicket victory over Pakistan has secured their spot in the World Test Championship (WTC) final, leaving one slot open for India, Australia, and Sri Lanka. The article explores the qualifying scenarios for these three teams.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li><strong>South Africa</strong> has confirmed their place in the WTC final with a win over Pakistan.</li><li><strong>India</strong> must win both remaining Tests against Australia to ensure qualification.</li><li><strong>Australia</strong> can qualify with wins over India, regardless of their performances against Sri Lanka.</li><li><strong>Sri Lanka</strong> needs to sweep Australia and rely on outcomes from the India vs Australia Tests.</li></ul><blockquote>“If India win one Test and draw the other, they'll finish on 57.02.”</blockquote><p>Conclusion: The upcoming matches are crucial for India, Australia, and Sri Lanka as they vie for the last spot in the WTC final, contingent on various match outcomes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/wtc-final-scenarios-south-africa-through-but-what-about-india-australia-sri-lanka-1467122</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/wtc-final-scenarios-south-africa-through-but-what-about-india-australia-sri-lanka-1467122</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:16:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICC Reveals Four-Nominee Shortlist For Men's T20I Cricketer Of The Year Award - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICC Reveals Four-Nominee Shortlist For Men's T20I Cricketer Of The Year Award</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Indian pace bowler Arshdeep Singh (AP)" title="Indian pace bowler Arshdeep Singh (AP)" />
<figcaption>Indian pace bowler Arshdeep Singh (AP)</figcaption>
<p>An Indian who starred in the ICC Men’s T20 World Cup triumph joins a Zimbabwe ace and two quality batters from Pakistan and Australia in the nominees for the ICC Men’s T20I Cricketer of the Year.</p>
<ul>
<li>Arshdeep Singh (India): Matches: 18, Wickets: 36, Average: 13.5</li>
<li>Sikandar Raza (Zimbabwe): Matches: 24, Runs: 573, Wickets: 24</li>
<li>Babar Azam (Pakistan): Matches: 24, Runs: 738, Average: 33.54</li>
<li>Travis Head (Australia): Matches: 15, Runs: 539, Average: 38.5</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“His 539 runs are the second-best ever for an Australian in a calendar year.” - Analysis on Travis Head's performance.</blockquote>
<p>This shortlist highlights outstanding performances within T20I cricket, showcasing players who have made significant impacts for their respective teams throughout the year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/icc-reveals-four-nominee-shortlist-for-mens-t20i-cricketer-of-the-year-award-9171736.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/icc-reveals-four-nominee-shortlist-for-mens-t20i-cricketer-of-the-year-award-9171736.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:16:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohammed Siraj's perfect support act! How Sunil Gavaskar, Rohit Sharma's harsh words brought the best out - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammed Siraj's perfect support act! How Sunil Gavaskar, Rohit Sharma's harsh words brought the best out of India pacer</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Mohammed Siraj in action"/><figcaption>Mohammed Siraj showcasing his skills on the field.</figcaption><p>This article discusses how Sunil Gavaskar and Rohit Sharma's candid feedback motivated Indian pacer Mohammed Siraj to elevate his game during crucial moments.</p><ul><li>Siraj's performance improved significantly after receiving direct feedback from senior players.</li><li>The impact of leadership and mentorship on younger players in cricket.</li><li>Analysis of specific matches and key moments highlighting Siraj's contributions.</li></ul><blockquote>“Sometimes, the right words at the right time can change a player’s mindset completely.”</blockquote><p>Ultimately, this narrative emphasizes the importance of constructive criticism and support within team dynamics, showcasing how it can lead to outstanding performances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/mohammed-sirajs-perfect-support-act-how-sunil-gavaskar-rohit-sharmas-harsh-words-brought-the-best-out-of-india-pacer/articleshow/116769386.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/mohammed-sirajs-perfect-support-act-how-sunil-gavaskar-rohit-sharmas-harsh-words-brought-the-best-out-of-india-pacer/articleshow/116769386.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS Day five teaser: Can Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma plot a magical win and rediscover past glory? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS Day five teaser: Can Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma plot a magical win and rediscover past glory?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 29-12-2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/IND-AUS-KOhli-Rohit.jpg?w=640" alt="Virat kohli Rohit sharma mastermind IND vs AUS 4th test day 5" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Australia's Marnus Labuschagne, second left, looks on as India's captain Rohit Sharma, left, and India's Virat Kohli discuss during play on the day four of the fourth cricket test between Australia and India at the Melbourne Cricket Ground, Melbourne, Australia, Sunday, Dec. 29, 2024. (AP Photo/Asanka Brendon Ratnayake)</figcaption><p>The ongoing Test match at the MCG is poised for a thrilling final day, with all outcome possibilities open. India needs to chase a record 333 runs for a historic win, and hopes are pinned on Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma to reclaim their past form.</p><ul><li>The match sees India needing to chase 333 runs.</li><li>Rohit Sharma and Virat Kohli have struggled in their recent performances.</li><li>The last successful chase of such magnitude at the MCG was nearly a century ago.</li><li>Both players face pressure to perform and lead the team to victory.</li></ul><blockquote>“I don’t think Virat is in his best mental shape at all. He doesn’t seem to have that ruthless mental strength... The Kohli of the old wouldn’t have let that moment go.” - Jim Maxwell</blockquote><p>The result of this match could mark a turning point for both players as they aim to revive their careers against Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/virat-kohli-rohit-sharma-mastermind-win-past-glory-ind-aus-day-5-9750312/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/virat-kohli-rohit-sharma-mastermind-win-past-glory-ind-aus-day-5-9750312/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:48:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Updated World Test Championship Points Table After South Africa Defeat Pakistan - What Does It Mean .. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Updated World Test Championship Points Table After South Africa Defeat Pakistan - What Does It Mean For India?</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p> <img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/mf6b4lh8_acs_625x300_29_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Updated World Test Championship Points Table After South Africa Defeat Pakistan - What Does It Mean For India?"> <figcaption>South Africa's victory against Pakistan solidifies their position in the WTC.</figcaption> <p>South Africa booked their spot in the World Test Championship (WTC) Final after a gritty two-wicket victory over Pakistan. This result keeps South Africa at the top of the points table, while India fights to secure their spot.</p> <ul> <li>South Africa defeated Pakistan by two wickets in the first Test match in Centurion.</li> <li>Kagiso Rabada and Marco Jansen's partnership led to the victory.</li> <li>South Africa maintains a PCT of 66.67 in the WTC standings.</li> <li>Australia is slightly ahead of India in the race for the second WTC spot.</li> <li>If the series against Australia ends 1-1, India still has a chance to qualify for the WTC Final.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“Kagiso Rabada and Marco Jansen shared an unbeaten 51-run ninth wicket partnership.”</blockquote> <p>The implications of this match are significant as India seeks to keep its World Test Championship hopes alive amidst a tight competition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/updated-world-test-championship-points-table-after-south-africa-defeat-pakistan-what-does-it-mean-for-india-7357067</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/updated-world-test-championship-points-table-after-south-africa-defeat-pakistan-what-does-it-mean-for-india-7357067</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:47:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Know the educational qualification and net worth of India star cricketer Nitish Kumar Reddy - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nitish Kumar Reddy: Education and Net Worth of Rising Star Cricketer</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/know-the-educational-qualification-and-net-worth-of-india-star-cricketer-nitish-kumar-reddy-202412-1735471665.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Know the educational qualification and net worth of India star cricketer Nitish Kumar Reddy"><figcaption>Image credit: Instagram</figcaption><p>Nitish Kumar Reddy, a promising cricketer for India, celebrated his first Test century in Melbourne, raising his profile as a future star in Indian cricket.</p><ul><li>Nitish scored his maiden Test century during a recent match in Melbourne.</li><li>He has B.Tech in Electronics and Communication and a master’s in business analytics.</li><li>The cricketer resides in Visakhapatnam with his family.</li><li>His net worth is estimated between Rs 8 to 15 crore.</li><li>Nitish plays for Sunrisers Hyderabad in IPL at a retained price of Rs 6 crore.</li><li>He has expressed admiration for fellow cricketer Virat Kohli.</li><li>Nitish owns high-end bikes, showcasing his passion for motorcycles.</li><li>He made his IPL debut in 2023 and has performed commendably in the tournament.</li></ul><blockquote>Nitish Kumar Reddy's net worth is between Rs 8 to 15 crore.</blockquote><p>This article highlights the ascent of Nitish Kumar Reddy in Indian cricket, emphasizing his educational background and financial success following his impressive performances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/know-the-educational-qualification-and-net-worth-of-india-star-cricketer-nitish-kumar-reddy-417019/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/know-the-educational-qualification-and-net-worth-of-india-star-cricketer-nitish-kumar-reddy-417019/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICC names the nominees for Men’s ODI Cricketer of the Year title - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICC names the nominees for Men’s ODI Cricketer of the Year title</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Available, <strong>Source:</strong> Not Available</p>
<p>An overview of the International Cricket Council's nominations for the prestigious Men's ODI Cricketer of the Year award.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The nominees include players with outstanding performances in One Day Internationals.</li>
  <li>This award recognizes the best cricketer over the past year.</li>
  <li>Fans are encouraged to vote for their favorite candidate.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The award acknowledges excellence in ODI cricket, highlighting key performances that have had a significant impact on matches."</blockquote>
<p>This year's nominees reflect a remarkable year in cricket, showcasing talent and dedication among the players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/icc-announces-shortlist-for-mens-odi-cricketer-of-the-year-award/articleshow/116767655.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/icc-announces-shortlist-for-mens-odi-cricketer-of-the-year-award/articleshow/116767655.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Africa qualify for WTC final; here’s what India and Australia need to do to book their ticket to Lord's - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Africa seal qualification for the WTC final after beating Pakistan in the first Test.</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/South-Africa-Pakistan-Cricket-20_1735474588706_1735474602576.jpg" alt="South Africa qualify for WTC final after beating Pakistan in 1st Test by two wickets (AP Photo/Themba Hadebe)(AP)"/>
<figcaption>South Africa qualify for WTC final after beating Pakistan in 1st Test by two wickets (AP Photo/Themba Hadebe)(AP)</figcaption>
<p>South Africa has officially qualified for the World Test Championship (WTC) final, to be held at Lord's in June 2025, after a dramatic victory over Pakistan.</p>
<ul>
  <li>South Africa defeated Pakistan by two wickets in the first Test.</li>
  <li>Kagiso Rabada and Marco Jansen played crucial roles in the victory.</li>
  <li>This win secures South Africa’s place at the top of the WTC standings.</li>
  <li>India and Australia now face pressure to secure their qualification, with critical matches on the horizon.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This result has put more pressure on India and Australia.”</blockquote>
<p>Looking ahead, both India and Australia must navigate their remaining matches carefully to qualify for the final, with numerous scenarios affecting their standings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/south-africa-qualify-for-wtc-final-what-india-and-australia-need-to-do-to-book-their-ticket-to-lords-101735470480876.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/south-africa-qualify-for-wtc-final-what-india-and-australia-need-to-do-to-book-their-ticket-to-lords-101735470480876.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:25:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Ego Took Over...": Sunil Gavaskar On His Brutal Criticism Of Rishabh Pant's Dismissal - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ego-took-over-sunil-gavaskar-on-his-brutal-criticism-of-rishabh-pants-dismissal-7356859</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ego-took-over-sunil-gavaskar-on-his-brutal-criticism-of-rishabh-pants-dismissal-7356859</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:08:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Is The Highest 4th Innings Test Total Ever Chased At MCG Before BGT 2024-25? - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/what-is-the-highest-4th-innings-test-total-ever-chased-at-mcg-before-bgt-2024-25-9171574.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/what-is-the-highest-4th-innings-test-total-ever-chased-at-mcg-before-bgt-2024-25-9171574.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:07:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma's Fiery Reaction To Yashasvi Jaiswal's Dropped Catches Draws Brutal Criticism - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharmas-fiery-reaction-to-yashasvi-jaiswals-dropped-catches-draws-brutal-criticism-7355206</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharmas-fiery-reaction-to-yashasvi-jaiswals-dropped-catches-draws-brutal-criticism-7355206</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:38:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Contenders for ICC Women's ODI Cricketer of the Year named - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNRjViT0ptSUd5c1JaTlIxVDZpRjd6Y0VwXzUtTE5VWXI5bHlzeW5tRDlYRlVsXzgwcFRBN3g0N0RIaEtNZE1Oc2FnelFyZTVRRWx3LW0tRlgtN3FjVDdIMmpPeW1jUzdHREFLSXpyS0NPMUw1RUtUTnY5M3VoSGpnQ2hVVUo4aWVNOFZsRlVHU21jWEMyaWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxNRjViT0ptSUd5c1JaTlIxVDZpRjd6Y0VwXzUtTE5VWXI5bHlzeW5tRDlYRlVsXzgwcFRBN3g0N0RIaEtNZE1Oc2FnelFyZTVRRWx3LW0tRlgtN3FjVDdIMmpPeW1jUzdHREFLSXpyS0NPMUw1RUtUTnY5M3VoSGpnQ2hVVUo4aWVNOFZsRlVHU21jWEMyaWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:34:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Ego took over…’: Sunil Gavaskar reacts to his fiery criticism of ‘stupid’ Rishabh Pant - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunil Gavaskar's Fiery Criticism of Rishabh Pant During Boxing Day Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/gavaskar_Pant_1624530453607_1735467037081.jpg" alt="Sunil Gavaskar gave an explanation after his criticism of Rishabh Pant's dismissal went viral on social media." title="Sunil Gavaskar gave an explanation after his criticism of Rishabh Pant's dismissal went viral on social media."><figcaption>Sunil Gavaskar gave an explanation after his criticism of Rishabh Pant's dismissal went viral on social media.</figcaption></figure><p>Former Indian cricketer Sunil Gavaskar expressed his intense passion for cricket while detailing his critical comments on Rishabh Pant's dismissal during the Melbourne Test against Australia, labeling the shot as 'stupid' and questioning Pant's shot selection during a crucial phase of the match.</p><ul><li>Gavaskar criticized Pant's careless shot that led to his dismissal on Day 3 of the Boxing Day Test.</li><li>The Twitter clip of the commentary garnered over 8.5 million views.</li><li>He expressed disappointment, stating, "the ego took over for the next ball" while emphasizing the need for better shot selection.</li><li>Gavaskar acknowledged Pant's talent but urged him to adopt a more orthodox approach under pressure.</li></ul><blockquote>“Yes, if he had connected and it had gone for a 6, I would’ve applauded the shot as well. But there you are, you get out, and it’s a fine line with the bat between being carefree and careless.”</blockquote><p>The legendary batter concluded that while Pant has the ability to turn situations around, his recent approach could jeopardize India's chances in crucial matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/sunil-gavaskar-blames-rishabh-pants-ego-for-his-dismissal-at-mcg-i-m-gonna-show-the-bowler-who-s-the-boss-101735466997388.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/sunil-gavaskar-blames-rishabh-pants-ego-for-his-dismissal-at-mcg-i-m-gonna-show-the-bowler-who-s-the-boss-101735466997388.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:23:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Bounce has got inconsistent': Marnus Labuschagne weighs in on MCG pitch - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bounce has got inconsistent: Marnus Labuschagne weighs in on MCG pitch</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116766274,imgsize-47896,width-400,resizemode-4/116766274.jpg" alt="Marnus Labuschagne (AP Photo)" title="Marnus Labuschagne (AP Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Marnus Labuschagne (AP Photo)</figcaption>
<p>Marnus Labuschagne, Australia's top scorer, expressed concerns about the inconsistent bounce of the MCG pitch, significantly impacting India’s chase.</p>
<ul>
<li>Australia concluded day four at 228 for 9, leading India by 333 runs.</li>
<li>Lower order contributions from Pat Cummins (41), Nathan Lyon (41 not out), and Scott Boland (10 not out) were crucial.</li>
<li>Labuschagne scored the highest individual run of 70 for Australia.</li>
<li>He noted the increased difficulty for batsmen with deliveries skidding through and hitting the stumps.</li>
<li>Labuschagne remained non-committal about Australia's declaration plans for the next day.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The seam movement's probably been the same. But just the amount of bounce is significantly lower. So that makes for pretty tricky batting there.”</blockquote>
<p>The lower order players received praise from Labuschagne for their performances under pressure, noting their resilience as key to Australia’s current position.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/bounce-has-got-inconsistent-marnus-labuschagne-weighs-in-on-mcg-pitch/articleshow/116766017.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/bounce-has-got-inconsistent-marnus-labuschagne-weighs-in-on-mcg-pitch/articleshow/116766017.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohammed Shami vs. Sania Mirza: Net worth comparison; Who is richer? - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammed Shami vs. Sania Mirza: Net worth comparison; Who is richer?</h1><p><strong>Published by:</strong> Unknown<br><strong>Date:</strong> Unknown</p><img src='https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/mohammed-shami-vs-sania-mirza-net-worth-comparison-who-is-richer-202412-1735466544.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700' alt='Mohammed Shami vs Sania Mirza Net worth comparison Who is richer ' /><figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption><p>In this collection of pics, let's compare the net worth of Mohammed Shami, who is the star bowler of the Indian Cricket Team, with India's former professional tennis player and find out who is richer.</p><ul><li>Sania Mirza's net worth is around Rs 240 crore.</li><li>Mohammed Shami's net worth is around Rs 55 crore.</li><li>Sania Mirza earns around 3 crores annually from tennis.</li><li>Shami's income sources include IPL and advertisements.</li><li>Sania also earns from brand endorsements and has opened her own tennis academy.</li></ul><blockquote>Sania Mirza has the highest net worth, being two and a half times richer than Mohammed Shami.</blockquote><p>This comparison shows a significant difference in the earnings of these two sports figures, highlighting the financial success of Sania Mirza in her career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/mohammed-shami-vs-sania-mirza-net-worth-comparison-who-is-richer-417008/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/mohammed-shami-vs-sania-mirza-net-worth-comparison-who-is-richer-417008/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:05:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arshdeep Singh nominated for ICC T20I Cricketer of the Year - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arshdeep Singh Nominated for ICC T20I Cricketer of the Year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 29, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Arshdeep Singh" /><figcaption>Arshdeep Singh in action during a match.</figcaption><p>In a significant recognition of his outstanding performance, Arshdeep Singh has been shortlisted for the ICC T20I Cricketer of the Year award.</p><ul><li>Arshdeep has made a substantial impact in the T20 format with remarkable statistics over the year.</li><li>His exceptional bowling skills and consistency have garnered attention on the international stage.</li><li>This nomination reflects his dedication and hard work throughout the year.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’m honored to be nominated alongside such talented players,” said Arshdeep Singh.</blockquote><p>This nomination not only enhances Arshdeep's reputation but also puts him in the spotlight as one of India's key players in T20 cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/arshdeep-singh-nominated-for-icc-t20i-cricketer-of-the-year/articleshow/116765618.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/arshdeep-singh-nominated-for-icc-t20i-cricketer-of-the-year/articleshow/116765618.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 09:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Advantage Australia as batting gets harder at the MCG? - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australia Takes Lead in Boxing Day Test at the MCG</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p>The Boxing Day Test is nearing a thrilling finish as Australia holds a significant lead against India, with all outcomes still possible on the final day.</p><ul><li>Australia leads by 333 runs with one wicket in hand.</li><li>They struggled at one point, being 91 for 6, but rallied to set a challenging target for India.</li><li>Marnus Labuschagne scored 70 runs and stated that the team felt ahead throughout the match.</li><li>The pitch's condition is affecting batting performance as the Test progresses into the fifth day.</li></ul><blockquote>“I felt like we were probably ahead of the game just the whole way,” said Marnus Labuschagne.</blockquote><p>India plans to rectify their earlier mistakes as they prepare for a challenging chase.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/bgt-aus-vs-india-mcg-test-advantage-australia-as-bounce-gets-more-inconsistent-1467079</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/bgt-aus-vs-india-mcg-test-advantage-australia-as-bounce-gets-more-inconsistent-1467079</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 09:46:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Murzin Wins Rapid World Championship, Humpy Earns 2nd Title In Women's - Chess.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Murzin Wins Rapid World Championship, Humpy Earns 2nd Title In Women's</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Chess.com</p><figure><img src="https://www.chess.com/bundles/web/images/image-default.445cb543.svg" alt="" width="2500" height="1667"> <figcaption>Spectators were captivated on the last day of rapid games. Photo: Maria Emelianova/Chess.com.</figcaption></figure><p>GM Volodar Murzin won the 2024 FIDE World Rapid Chess Championship with an undefeated 10/13 score, making him the second-youngest rapid world champion in history. GM Koneru Humpy also made a remarkable comeback to win the 2024 FIDE Women's World Rapid Chess Championship with 8.5/11, securing her second world title.</p><ul><li>Murzin, at just 18 years old, is celebrated for his impressive undefeated score.</li><li>Humpy, 37, lost her first game but recovered to claim the women's title, further elevating India's chess status after recent successes.</li><li>The tournament featured notable players like Magnus Carlsen, who withdrew mid-event.</li><li>Upcoming events include the FIDE World Blitz Chess Championship starting December 30.</li></ul><blockquote>“I hope this is not a dream. I don’t know what to say. I am really happy.” - Volodar Murzin</blockquote><p>Both champions received significant prize money and recognition for their achievements, marking important developments in the global chess scene.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championship-day-3</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.chess.com/news/view/2024-fide-world-rapid-chess-championship-day-3</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frontrunners for ICC Men's ODI Cricketer of The Year revealed - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Frontrunners for ICC Men's ODI Cricketer of The Year Revealed</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> N/A</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ICC</p>
<img src="https://images.icc-cricket.com/image/upload/t_ratio21_9-size60/prd/ICC_Awards_2024_-_Men_s_ODI_Cricketer_of_the_Year_-_Nominees_21x9" alt="ICC Awards 2024 - Men's ODI Cricketer of the Year - Nominees 21x9">
<figcaption>ICC Awards 2024 - Men's ODI Cricketer of the Year - Nominees</figcaption>
<p>The ICC has announced the nominees for the Men's ODI Cricketer of the Year award, showcasing talent from Sri Lanka, Afghanistan, and the West Indies.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wanindu Hasaranga (Sri Lanka)</strong> - 26 wickets at an average of 15.61.</li>
<li><strong>Azmatullah Omarzai (Afghanistan)</strong> - 417 runs at an average of 52.12.</li>
<li><strong>Kusal Mendis (Sri Lanka)</strong> - 742 runs at an average of 53.00.</li>
<li><strong>Sherfane Rutherford (West Indies)</strong> - 425 runs at an average of 106.25.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Hasaranga continues to cement his reputation as a wizard of white-ball cricket,”</blockquote>
<p>All players exhibited remarkable performances throughout the year, with standout matches helping their respective teams achieve significant milestones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/frontrunners-for-icc-men-s-odi-cricketer-of-the-year-revealed</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/frontrunners-for-icc-men-s-odi-cricketer-of-the-year-revealed</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 09:33:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last over drama at MCG! Jasprit Bumrah denied a fifer despite KL Rahul's lucky catch - Watch - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Last Over Drama at MCG: Bumrah Denied Fifer Despite Lucky Catch</h1><p><strong>Published on: Unknown</strong> | <strong>Source: Unknown</strong></p><p>In a thrilling last over of a cricket match at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG), Jasprit Bumrah was denied a five-wicket haul despite KL Rahul's lucky catch. The match showcased dramatic moments that kept fans on the edge of their seats.</p><ul><li>Bumrah showcased exceptional bowling skills.</li><li>KL Rahul's catch was pivotal in altering the game's momentum.</li><li>The incident highlighted the unpredictability of cricket.</li></ul><blockquote>“Cricket can be a game of inches; one moment can change everything.”</blockquote><p>This match will be remembered for its dramatic finish and the close calls that came with it.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/last-over-drama-at-mcg-jasprit-bumrah-denied-a-fifer-despite-kl-rahuls-lucky-catch-watch/articleshow/116765053.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/last-over-drama-at-mcg-jasprit-bumrah-denied-a-fifer-despite-kl-rahuls-lucky-catch-watch/articleshow/116765053.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 09:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Simon Katich's Reaction After Jasprit Bumrah Takes Travis Head's Wicket Goes Viral | Watch - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/simon-katichs-reaction-after-jasprit-bumrah-takes-travis-heads-wicket-goes-viral-watch-9171611.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/simon-katichs-reaction-after-jasprit-bumrah-takes-travis-heads-wicket-goes-viral-watch-9171611.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 09:22:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Famous Gabba run chase for India no relevance as Marnus plots MCG plan - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Famous Gabba run chase for India no relevance as Marnus plots MCG plan</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>As India's target remains unclear, Australia holds a significant lead with tailenders Nathan Lyon and Scott Boland contributing to their score, making it challenging for the tourists.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Australia's tailenders Lyon and Boland added an unbeaten 51 runs.</li>
  <li>Labuschagne mentions plans to declare but changes due to Bumrah's impressive bowling.</li>
  <li>Labuschagne highlights the team's strategy shift to accumulate runs for a substantial lead.</li>
  <li>He credits the lower-order batsmen for their performance during the last part of the innings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The perfect outcome for us would have probably looked like having a bowl tonight and putting them under pressure," said Labuschagne.</blockquote>
<p>This match highlights the ongoing challenges faced by Australia and the pressure India must navigate in their upcoming innings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/world-test-championship/news/famous-gabba-run-chase-for-india-no-relevance-as-marnus-plots-mcg-plan</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/tournaments/world-test-championship/news/famous-gabba-run-chase-for-india-no-relevance-as-marnus-plots-mcg-plan</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shortlist for ICC Women's T20I Cricketer of the Year announced - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPVkxwY01CQlpISm9vUVBQWmtJS2Q4N3B2TWJZdW5EVVhrMElQRGZOOW1yOVFWLWJwUzlnQTlVT01QNVNmYm5QOVRBMWRGbHVsS3dMYy03VnVfWXAtaWdGc051b2hzMjV5aEVvQ3NDYVY0R1doYXpJQjJzTEhuN19yTjROLU44V00xTXcxd0gyb1h6Y3laX25ZajZCdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxPVkxwY01CQlpISm9vUVBQWmtJS2Q4N3B2TWJZdW5EVVhrMElQRGZOOW1yOVFWLWJwUzlnQTlVT01QNVNmYm5QOVRBMWRGbHVsS3dMYy03VnVfWXAtaWdGc051b2hzMjV5aEVvQ3NDYVY0R1doYXpJQjJzTEhuN19yTjROLU44V00xTXcxd0gyb1h6Y3laX25ZajZCdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:33:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bumrah gets to 200 wickets with the best average in Test cricket - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah Achieves 200 Wickets with Record-Breaking Average</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p>Jasprit Bumrah reached the milestone of 200 Test wickets with impressive statistics, affirming his position as one of cricket's all-time great bowlers.</p><ul><li>Bumrah reached his 200th wicket with an average of 19.56, the best for any bowler.</li><li>He is the first bowler to take 200 wickets while conceding fewer than 4000 runs.</li><li>His strike rate stands at 42.4, placing him among legends like Waqar Younis and Dale Steyn.</li><li>Bumrah has the highest percentage of wickets among Indian fast bowlers in major cricketing nations.</li><li>He has dismissed top batters frequently, with Joe Root being the most dismissed player.</li><li>Injuries have led to significant workload management to keep him fit for critical matches.</li></ul><blockquote>Bumrah averages a remarkable 14.4 during India's 20 Test victories, the best among Indian bowlers.</blockquote><p>Jasprit Bumrah's career continues to inspire, and his record suggests he will play a crucial role in India's future successes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/bumrah-gets-to-200-wickets-with-the-best-average-in-test-cricket-1467050</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/bumrah-gets-to-200-wickets-with-the-best-average-in-test-cricket-1467050</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:33:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma Loses It On Field As Yashasvi Jaiswal Drops Three Catches In One Innings - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxQc2YzdDBXTi1rUWNJaWI3LUwwdVVIZnNVTTAwVGtCVm5INDlteHZsVVdraTdUcDg1aUpVUjhlNGdqTmtFRzZmSFZ2dXdmc2hNaEFHY1dRNnNRNTU1b1hNWm1zcTZhY1BGcFhwclJvclduWVIxWHVsRkxpRFZtVEZ4dmVncHhBRUd3aWZsLUtWRTg3ZTJMQm1EcEdFMFU4dFZFRW8zT0RyLWg3OTFCOGpvV2k3VDB2ekRIc0UySXJSOFdxOVg0Tld1MGUxQXlDaHFEdlI5RUppOGtvWTYz0gHkAUFVX3lxTE9qZjZHYXlTa0Z4QkNZZU1jWmkwV3UxcEZGOER2dlkxR0hvUm9IZG0wQ3ptNEUwT0JjV3h2ck5PWHBYMWs5bnFUaFJJMkZPV1BNU0hMYWhzeGFXOGFwbXdmNUNNUDlnWUtVUlJvUUlwODFNMnRXZGctMGFKck9qaW5iNElvdHkwMnJMY0ZjWlhBZElla3JRUGpmY3owOHdFYjNsNkU4WmVScG43XzFwT0o0VGFRV25ZU293VmVmd0lRamItX3MwRHNMSjVGVEhlUVp2VGwwUTUzck9DVVNzVW1vSHNQRw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxQc2YzdDBXTi1rUWNJaWI3LUwwdVVIZnNVTTAwVGtCVm5INDlteHZsVVdraTdUcDg1aUpVUjhlNGdqTmtFRzZmSFZ2dXdmc2hNaEFHY1dRNnNRNTU1b1hNWm1zcTZhY1BGcFhwclJvclduWVIxWHVsRkxpRFZtVEZ4dmVncHhBRUd3aWZsLUtWRTg3ZTJMQm1EcEdFMFU4dFZFRW8zT0RyLWg3OTFCOGpvV2k3VDB2ekRIc0UySXJSOFdxOVg0Tld1MGUxQXlDaHFEdlI5RUppOGtvWTYz0gHkAUFVX3lxTE9qZjZHYXlTa0Z4QkNZZU1jWmkwV3UxcEZGOER2dlkxR0hvUm9IZG0wQ3ptNEUwT0JjV3h2ck5PWHBYMWs5bnFUaFJJMkZPV1BNU0hMYWhzeGFXOGFwbXdmNUNNUDlnWUtVUlJvUUlwODFNMnRXZGctMGFKck9qaW5iNElvdHkwMnJMY0ZjWlhBZElla3JRUGpmY3owOHdFYjNsNkU4WmVScG43XzFwT0o0VGFRV25ZU293VmVmd0lRamItX3MwRHNMSjVGVEhlUVp2VGwwUTUzck9DVVNzVW1vSHNQRw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:15:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS, 4th Test Day 4 Highlights: Jasprit Bumrah's brilliance, last-wicket stand for Australia keep - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND vs AUS, 4th Test Day 4 Highlights: Jasprit Bumrah's brilliance, last-wicket stand for Australia keep MCG Test finely poised</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> NEW DELHI</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116763649,imgsize-65896,width-400,resizemode-4/116763649.jpg" alt="IND vs AUS, 4th Test Day 4 Highlights: Jasprit Bumrah's brilliance, last-wicket stand for Australia keep MCG Test finely poised" title="Jasprit Bumrah celebrates with teammates after the wicket of Australia's Mitchell Marsh. (PTI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah celebrates with teammates after the wicket of Australia's Mitchell Marsh. (PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>Day 4 of the Boxing Day Test saw Jasprit Bumrah lead India's bowling attack with a remarkable performance, claiming his 200th Test wicket. However, Australia managed to hold steady with crucial contributions from their lower order, leaving the match delicately poised heading into the final day.</p><ul><li>Jasprit Bumrah took 4 wickets for 56 runs, reaching a milestone of 200 Test wickets.</li><li>Australia ended the day at 228/9, leading by 333 runs.</li><li>Marnus Labuschagne scored 70 runs, while Pat Cummins contributed 41 runs.</li><li>A frustrating last-wicket stand of 55 runs between Nathan Lyon and Scott Boland was instrumental.</li><li>Yashasvi Jaiswal dropped three crucial catches, affecting India's chances.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bumrah reached the remarkable milestone in just his 44th Test, making him the fastest Indian pacer to achieve this feat.”</blockquote><p>The match remains finely balanced with all four results still possible. The final day will prove crucial as India attempts to chase down Australia’s lead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-day-4-highlights-jasprit-bumrahs-brilliance-last-wicket-stand-for-australia-keep-mcg-test-finely-poised/articleshow/116763575.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-4th-test-day-4-highlights-jasprit-bumrahs-brilliance-last-wicket-stand-for-australia-keep-mcg-test-finely-poised/articleshow/116763575.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slow Over Rate To Cost India A Spot In WTC Final After Australia’s Late Fightback - OneCricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Faces Slow Over-Rate Penalty as WTC Final Hopes Dwindle</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><img width="474" alt="Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma [Source: @CHIYANAKASH_07/x]" src="https://onecricketnews.akamaized.net/parth-editor/oc-dashboard/news-images-prod/1735457983323_virat_kohli_india.jpg?im=Resize=(650,450)" height="240"><figcaption>Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma [Source: @CHIYANAKASH_07/x]</figcaption><p>Team India’s hopes of reaching the WTC 2025 final are in jeopardy due to a potential slow over-rate penalty following the MCG Test against Australia.</p><ul><li>India may face points deduction for slow over-rate.</li><li>Australia's final wicket pair frustrated India, leading to the penalty possibility.</li><li>Deduction of one WTC point for every over bowled short of the required rate.</li><li>The ongoing WTC has seen the English team suffer greatly from over-rate penalties.</li><li>Current series is tied 1-1 in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li></ul><blockquote>“With India desperately needing a win over Australia at the MCG, their ambitions of securing a spot in the WTC 2025 final might well get hampered due to an over-rate induced point deduction.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the slow over-rate issue could significantly impact India's aspirations for the upcoming WTC finals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://cricket.one/cricket-news/indias-wtc-final-race-exit-looms-large-as-rohit-and-co-to-face-slow-over-rate-penalty/67710180703dbcd7d84a6d4e</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cricket.one/cricket-news/indias-wtc-final-race-exit-looms-large-as-rohit-and-co-to-face-slow-over-rate-penalty/67710180703dbcd7d84a6d4e</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bumrah, Siraj and Labuschagne headline fast-moving Day 4 at MCG - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxPWFNGNFdMeXU1c1R5dndTZE1zYmFXWTZjVlpSaW41aTRYRWtLWVFtTlgxRklYWTMxWVoydUZxSW4zLW40OVlUZmxKTVlYR3gyS2lpN3lucUdtZUJvSjBTWGZXaktLeHdzQWxkRkRZRW5ERmtEeUpnaENHa0diZHEtaC1xbk1fS2xzX0VPMVc4N0FlQmNMbXRkaWlXeHVCTkhkNDQwSVZzNGxGTWs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxPWFNGNFdMeXU1c1R5dndTZE1zYmFXWTZjVlpSaW41aTRYRWtLWVFtTlgxRklYWTMxWVoydUZxSW4zLW40OVlUZmxKTVlYR3gyS2lpN3lucUdtZUJvSjBTWGZXaktLeHdzQWxkRkRZRW5ERmtEeUpnaENHa0diZHEtaC1xbk1fS2xzX0VPMVc4N0FlQmNMbXRkaWlXeHVCTkhkNDQwSVZzNGxGTWs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 07:44:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nominees for ICC Men's T20I Cricketer of the Year unveiled - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ICC Men's T20I Cricketer of the Year Nominees Unveiled</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> ICC</p>
<img src="https://images.icc-cricket.com/image/upload/t_ratio21_9-size60/prd/ICC_Awards_2024_-_Men_s_T20I_Cricketer_of_the_Year_-_Nominees_21x9" alt="ICC Awards 2024 - Men's T20I Cricketer of the Year - Nominees 21x9" loading="lazy" width="630" height="270">
<figcaption>Nominees for the ICC Men's T20I Cricketer of the Year.</figcaption>
<p>Four exceptional players have been nominated for the ICC Men’s T20I Cricketer of the Year, showcasing their impressive performances over the past year.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Arshdeep Singh (India)</strong> - 18 matches, 36 wickets, average 13.5</li>
<li><strong>Sikandar Raza (Zimbabwe)</strong> - 24 matches, 573 runs, 24 wickets</li>
<li><strong>Babar Azam (Pakistan)</strong> - 24 matches, 738 runs, average 33.54</li>
<li><strong>Travis Head (Australia)</strong> - 15 matches, 539 runs, average 38.5</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"His 36 scalps over the years were the second-best by an India player in Men’s T20Is just one behind Bhuvneshwar Kumar’s 37 wickets in 2022."</blockquote>
<p>The nominees reflect a mix of emerging talent and established stars, each contributing significantly to their teams and the format in the past year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/nominees-for-icc-men-s-t20i-cricketer-of-the-year-unveiled</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.icc-cricket.com/news/nominees-for-icc-men-s-t20i-cricketer-of-the-year-unveiled</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 07:40:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>