<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:38:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:38:34 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement In India's Border Gavaskar Trophy Squad Named. Not Axar Patel Or Y.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement In India's Border Gavaskar Trophy Squad Named</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2d0t7bp_ashwin-afp_625x300_20_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin" width="639" height="479"><figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement in Squad</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team has selected young Mumbai off-spinner Tanush Kotian to replace Ravichandran Ashwin, who announced his retirement following the third Test in Brisbane.</p><ul><li>Tanush Kotian has played 33 First Class matches, taking 101 wickets.</li><li>Kotian has been included as a precautionary measure and will travel to Australia.</li><li>Originally, Axar Patel was considered for the replacement but opted out due to personal reasons.</li><li>Ashwin retired as India's second-highest wicket-taker in Test cricket.</li></ul><blockquote>"I made myself a promise in 2012, we lost a tricky series against England. I was very early in my career and I was just telling myself we are not gonna lose another one. Ever. And that is what I promised myself," said Ashwin.</blockquote><p>The addition of Kotian underscores the Indian team's strategy to maintain squad strength following Ashwin's retirement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ravichandran-ashwins-replacement-in-indias-border-gavaskar-trophy-squad-named-not-kuldeep-yadav-or-yuzvendra-chahal-7314817</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ravichandran-ashwins-replacement-in-indias-border-gavaskar-trophy-squad-named-not-kuldeep-yadav-or-yuzvendra-chahal-7314817</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:52:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli admitted to Thane hospital in critical condition - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli Admitted to Thane Hospital in Critical Condition</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Vinod Kambli, the former Indian cricketer, has been hospitalized in Thane and is reported to be in critical condition. His health has raised concerns among fans and the cricket community.</p><ul><li>Kambli has been experiencing severe health issues recently.</li><li>The exact cause of his critical condition has not been publicly disclosed.</li><li>Fans and former teammates have expressed their support and concern on social media.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are all praying for his speedy recovery." - A former teammate</blockquote><p>This incident has highlighted the importance of health awareness among athletes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-admitted-to-thane-hospital-in-critical-condition/articleshow/116598447.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-admitted-to-thane-hospital-in-critical-condition/articleshow/116598447.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A look at Team India's probable Schedule of ICC Champions Trophy 2025 - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Team India's Schedule for ICC Champions Trophy 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/hybrid-model-for-icc-champions-trophy-2025-202412-1734947359.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Hybrid model for ICC Champions Trophy 2025">
<figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption>
<p>The ICC Champions Trophy 2025 is approaching with a new hybrid model, ensuring India's matches are hosted in the UAE amidst security concerns over travel to Pakistan.</p>
<ul>
  <li>India will play group stage matches in Dubai against Bangladesh on February 20 and New Zealand on March 2.</li>
  <li>Pakistan will begin the tournament with their first match against New Zealand in Karachi on February 19.</li>
  <li>The semifinal matches are scheduled for March 4 and 5, with the final set for March 9.</li>
  <li>Neutral venues will be used for matches between India and Pakistan to maintain impartiality.</li>
  <li>Hosting all of India's matches in UAE aims to ensure a secure environment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Given the ongoing political tensions between India and Pakistan, any matches between these two nations will be played at impartial venues."</blockquote>
<p>This tournament promises to be an exciting event, with critical matches taking place in Dubai offering neutral grounds for competing teams.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/a-look-at-team-indias-probable-schedule-of-icc-champions-trophy-2025-415875/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/a-look-at-team-indias-probable-schedule-of-icc-champions-trophy-2025-415875/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:54:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia Boxing Day Test: Everything you should know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia Boxing Day Test: Everything You Should Know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116596469,imgsize-70580,width-400,resizemode-4/116596469.jpg" alt="India vs Australia Boxing Day Test" title="India vs Australia (AP Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>India vs Australia (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>The Border-Gavaskar Trophy is currently level at 1-1, with the third Test starting on December 26th. This Boxing Day Test is crucial for both teams before the final Test in Sydney.</p><ul><li>The Boxing Day Test is scheduled to be held at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG).</li><li>India won the last encounter at MCG in 2020.</li><li>Australia has historically performed well in Boxing Day Tests, having won five of the first seven matches against India.</li><li>The head-to-head record shows Australia with 46 wins, India with 33 wins, and 30 draws.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah is six wickets away from his 200th Test wicket.</li></ul><blockquote>Sachin Tendulkar leads most runs scored overall with 3630, and Nathan Lyon holds the record for most wickets overall with 124.</blockquote><p>This Boxing Day Test could shift team dynamics significantly, with implications for the World Test Championship.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/india-vs-australia-boxing-day-test-everything-you-should-know/articleshow/116595822.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/india-vs-australia-boxing-day-test-everything-you-should-know/articleshow/116595822.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Perfect' Man Utd Star Ruled Out Until March Due to Injury - GIVEMESPORT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Perfect' Man Utd Star Ruled Out Until March Due to Injury</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Give Me Sport</p><p>Manchester United's Mason Mount has suffered a serious hamstring injury, which could keep him sidelined for up to ten weeks. This setback significantly impacts the team's performance as they look to improve their season.</p><ul><li>Mount's injuries have plagued his time at Manchester United, having played only 14 Premier League matches last season.</li><li>The £55 million signing has become a favorite under new manager Ruben Amorim, despite limited appearances.</li><li>Mount's current injury is described as a hamstring issue caused by a hyperextended leg, with recovery expected to take around ten weeks.</li></ul><blockquote>"Mason Mount, Hamstring injury due to hyperextended leg, Tendon involved, horrible, around 10 weeks out depending on rehab and recovery!!"</blockquote><p>Mount's frustrating season continues as he struggles to maintain a consistent presence on the pitch, missing vital matches for Manchester United.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.givemesport.com/perfect-man-utd-star-ruled-out-until-march-due-to-injury/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.givemesport.com/perfect-man-utd-star-ruled-out-until-march-due-to-injury/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli's health deteriorates, admitted to Thane's Pragati hospital - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli's Health Deteriorates, Admitted to Hospital</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent | <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/e733fb15-15c8-426e-9623-2152735a8712-1734945576.webp" alt="Vinod Kambli" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>Vinod Kambli</figcaption>
<p>Former Indian cricketer Vinod Kambli has been admitted to hospital after his health deteriorated. Doctors are monitoring his condition as necessary tests are being conducted.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kambli was recently in the headlines after attending a memorial for Ramakant Achrekar, where he was seen in a wheelchair.</li>
  <li>He was admitted to the hospital late on Saturday night and is currently stable but remains critical.</li>
  <li>Members of the 1983 World Cup squad have offered financial support, which Kambli has accepted.</li>
  <li>Kambli expressed his willingness to undergo rehab and thanked friends, including Ajay Jadeja and Abey Kuruvilla, for their support.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I’m ready to go for rehab. I want to go there because I don’t fear anything. My family is with me,” said Kambli.</blockquote>
<p>Kambli has played 17 Tests and 104 ODIs for India, scoring over 3000 runs with six centuries.</p>
<p>This situation has highlighted Kambli's ongoing health issues, drawing support from fans and former teammates alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/sports/cricket/vinod-kambli-s-health-deteriorates-admitted-to-thane-s-pragati-hospital-2024-12-23-967564</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/sports/cricket/vinod-kambli-s-health-deteriorates-admitted-to-thane-s-pragati-hospital-2024-12-23-967564</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:19:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohammad Shami and Sania Mirza spotted together in Dubai, find the truth behind VIRAL pic - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammad Shami and Sania Mirza spotted together in Dubai, find the truth behind VIRAL pic</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/mohammad-shami-and-sania-mirza-spotted-together-in-dubai-find-the-truth-behind-viral-pic-202412-1734944319.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Mohammad Shami and Sania Mirza spotted together in Dubai">
<figcaption>Image credit: X (Formerly Twitter)</figcaption>
<p>This article explores the truth behind viral images of Indian cricketer Mohammad Shami and tennis star Sania Mirza, who were allegedly spotted together in Dubai.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Viral pictures of Shami and Mirza circulating widely on social media.</li>
  <li>Shami is currently in India preparing for the Vijay Hazare Trophy 2024.</li>
  <li>Sania Mirza recently divorced Shoaib Malik.</li>
  <li>Sania lives with her son in Dubai and Hyderabad.</li>
  <li>Shoaib Malik has remarried.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Mohammad Shami hasn’t played international cricket since the ODI World Cup 2023 final due to injury."</blockquote>
<p>The article clarifies misconceptions surrounding the leaked images and provides context about the personal lives of both Shami and Mirza.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/mohammad-shami-and-sania-mirza-spotted-together-in-dubai-find-the-truth-behind-viral-pic-415849/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/mohammad-shami-and-sania-mirza-spotted-together-in-dubai-find-the-truth-behind-viral-pic-415849/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:09:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Indian bowling looking a little weak': Cheteshwar Pujara raises concerns ahead of Boxing Day Test - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian bowling looking a little weak: Cheteshwar Pujara raises concerns ahead of Boxing Day Test</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> NEW DELHI<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116594627,imgsize-115126,width-400,resizemode-4/116594627.jpg" alt="'Indian bowling looking a little weak': Cheteshwar Pujara raises concerns ahead of Boxing Day Test" title="Getty Images" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Cheteshwar Pujara discusses the Indian bowling attack.</figcaption>
<p>As the Boxing Day Test against Australia approaches, veteran Indian batter Cheteshwar Pujara has expressed his worries regarding the bowling line-up's ability to perform effectively in the match.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pujara raises concerns about the Indian bowling's strength, doubting its ability to take 20 wickets.</li>
  <li>He highlights Jasprit Bumrah and Mohammed Siraj as standouts but notes others have underperformed.</li>
  <li>Pujara questions the team combination and the effectiveness of the supporting bowlers like Nitish Kumar and Ravindra Jadeja.</li>
  <li>He emphasizes the need to improve the bowling attack to win the match.</li>
  <li>Pujara praises Australian bowler Mitchell Starc for his recent performances and warns Indian batters to be cautious against him.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If you want to win a Test match, then you have to take 20 wickets, and the ability to take 20 wickets is not that good.” - Cheteshwar Pujara</blockquote>
<p>Pujara's insights underline the potential challenges India may face in delivering a robust bowling performance in the upcoming match against a strong Australian team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/indian-bowling-looking-a-little-weak-cheteshwar-pujara-raises-concerns-ahead-of-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116593792.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/indian-bowling-looking-a-little-weak-cheteshwar-pujara-raises-concerns-ahead-of-boxing-day-test/articleshow/116593792.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marcus Rashford told he'll never be in Man Utd squad again after brutal Amorim decision and with squad 'fuming' - TEAMtalk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Marcus Rashford told he'll never be in Man Utd squad again after brutal Amorim decision and with squad 'fuming'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> TeamTalk</p><img src="https://videos.skysports.com/image/v1/static/6057984924001/f8630e9c-f513-4fbc-9590-cd1fdf10fe99/c4b8854d-c318-4023-a2e3-ed0aae920a1a/160x90/match/image.jpg" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Marcus Rashford's absence from the squad has sparked controversy.</figcaption><p>Marcus Rashford faces a potential exit from Manchester United after being dropped for recent matches amid squad frustration over his public comments regarding a desire to leave the club.</p><ul><li>Rashford has not played since being left out of the derby match against Manchester City.</li><li>His public statement expressing a wish for a new challenge has reportedly angered his teammates.</li><li>Gary Neville has reversed his previous support for Rashford's position in the squad.</li><li>The situation has escalated, with reports indicating the club’s intent to transfer him in January.</li></ul><blockquote>“For me, personally, I think I’m ready for a new challenge and the next steps.” – Marcus Rashford</blockquote><p>The growing tensions suggest that Rashford’s future at Manchester United may be uncertain as he navigates this critical juncture in his career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.teamtalk.com/manchester-united/marcus-rashford-huge-step-nearer-man-utd-exit-squad-fuming-never-play-for-club-again</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.teamtalk.com/manchester-united/marcus-rashford-huge-step-nearer-man-utd-exit-squad-fuming-never-play-for-club-again</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:49:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PV Sindhu marries Venkata Datta, look at first pic - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu Marries Venkata Datta, Look at First Pic</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong><em>October 2023</em></p><p><strong>Source: </strong><em>Times of India</em></p><img src="https://example.com/path-to-image.jpg" alt="PV Sindhu Wedding Image"><figcaption>PV Sindhu and Venkata Datta's wedding image.</figcaption><p>PV Sindhu, the renowned badminton player, has tied the knot with Venkata Datta. The couple's wedding took place in a private ceremony, and fans are eager to see the first pictures of the event.</p><ul><li>The wedding was attended by family and close friends.</li><li>Sindhu shared a heartfelt message on her social media.</li><li>Fans have expressed their excitement and congratulations online.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are so happy to start this new chapter together." - PV Sindhu</blockquote><p>This joyous occasion marks a significant personal milestone for Sindhu as she embarks on a new journey with Venkata Datta.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/off-the-field/pv-sindhu-marries-venkata-datta-look-at-first-pic/articleshow/116592394.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/off-the-field/pv-sindhu-marries-venkata-datta-look-at-first-pic/articleshow/116592394.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian Cricket Team in a vicious state in Australia!! Horrific details emerge - Cricket Addictor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxPSTMxSnVNTHRWNkwtVDlEdTc3bVNXeVktc2pueFoxMUZHNUxsY1M2QnA4MVFjZnRWSzdmRWI1YlRXMjNhcHNfR1AweFZSc3h5SnN3LVVvWTVkempWUG1PamJGdFZmQTQtMWxNTEd4WWU5SFVweHV0SG9aZE04c0NVZm1CVkhlUmstRWxkMFE0b3dCZFNQd0QzOURrU1JnQlJteDg2bFdjbDRoSnN0bHhGZGdrdmtQYTNV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxPSTMxSnVNTHRWNkwtVDlEdTc3bVNXeVktc2pueFoxMUZHNUxsY1M2QnA4MVFjZnRWSzdmRWI1YlRXMjNhcHNfR1AweFZSc3h5SnN3LVVvWTVkempWUG1PamJGdFZmQTQtMWxNTEd4WWU5SFVweHV0SG9aZE04c0NVZm1CVkhlUmstRWxkMFE0b3dCZFNQd0QzOURrU1JnQlJteDg2bFdjbDRoSnN0bHhGZGdrdmtQYTNV?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:25:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star batter misses optional Aussie session; MCG curator rejects anti-India ‘conspiracy’ — Test Daily - Fox Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Travis Head Avoids Optional Training Ahead of Boxing Day Test as MCG Curator Addresses Pitch Controversy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Fox Sports</p><figure><img src="https://content.api.news/v3/images/bin/dab94169da45c6adfc736ffcee5b6e72" alt="Steve Smith training at the MCG ahead of the Boxing Day Test. Picture by Wayne Taylor 23rd December 2024" width="1024" height="768"/><figcaption>Steve Smith training at the MCG ahead of the Boxing Day Test. Picture by Wayne Taylor 23rd December 2024. Source: News Corp Australia</figcaption></figure><p>Australian cricket star Travis Head opted out of a non-compulsory training session as the country prepares for a crucial Test in the Border Gavaskar Trophy against India. Meanwhile, the MCG curator addressed claims of an anti-India bias regarding practice pitches.</p><ul><li>Travis Head did not train but is confident about his performance after strong previous matches, scoring 409 runs with an average of 81.2 in the series.</li><li>Senior players engaged in lengthy training, while new potential entrants Konstas and Carey benefitted from the session.</li><li>The MCG curator clarified that Australia prepared pitches standard procedure, and India chose to train on slower pitches.</li><li>Temperature on the day of the match is expected to reach 40C, prompting additional medical personnel to be onsite.</li></ul><blockquote>“For us, three days out, we prepare Test match pitches for here. If teams come and train before that, they get what pitches we have had.” - Matt Page, MCG Curator</blockquote><p>This training session sparks intrigue as Australia and India gear up for a vital Test match. The curator's remarks aim to placate potential tensions as international teams prepare for a high-stakes encounter.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.foxsports.com.au/cricket/australia/cricket-2024-boxing-day-test-preview-australia-vs-india-travis-head-doesnt-train-mcg-curator-on-antiindia-conspiracy-claims-latest-news/news-story/538e09a83f3d56ff2d461d5c2be10bdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foxsports.com.au/cricket/australia/cricket-2024-boxing-day-test-preview-australia-vs-india-travis-head-doesnt-train-mcg-curator-on-antiindia-conspiracy-claims-latest-news/news-story/538e09a83f3d56ff2d461d5c2be10bdf</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:24:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sania Mirza And Mohammad Shami Spotted Together In Dubai? AI Generated Photo Goes Viral - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sania Mirza And Mohammad Shami Spotted Together In Dubai? Photo Goes Viral</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024  | <strong>Source:</strong> Oneindia</p><img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2024/12/mohammad-shami-sania-mirza-jpg-1734935913391_1734935918761-600x338.jpg" alt="Sania Mirza And Mohammad Shami"><figcaption>Sania Mirza And Mohammad Shami</figcaption><p>The personal lives of celebrities constantly attract attention, and the recent focus has been on Indian tennis star Sania Mirza and cricketer Mohammad Shami, leading to speculation about their relationship.</p><ul><li>Rumors suggest Sania Mirza may be getting remarried, this time to cricketer Mohammad Shami.</li><li>These rumors gained traction after a photo of them together went viral on social media, although many questioned its authenticity.</li><li>Mirza is currently busy with commitments at the World Tennis League, while Shami is back in domestic cricket after an injury.</li><li>A fact check indicates that the viral photo is AI-generated, dispelling claims of them spending time together in Dubai.</li></ul><blockquote>"The claim is false; the video is AI-generated."</blockquote><p>The ongoing gossip highlights the public's interest in their lives, but both are focusing on their careers despite the speculation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/fact-check/sania-mirza-and-mohammad-shami-spotted-together-in-dubai-photo-goes-viral-011-4023671.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/fact-check/sania-mirza-and-mohammad-shami-spotted-together-in-dubai-photo-goes-viral-011-4023671.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:13:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First pic: PV Sindhu marries Venkata Datta Sai in Udaipur - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/sports/other-sports/story/pv-sindhu-wedding-photo-venkatta-datta-sai-udaipur-gajendra-singh-shekhawat-2653980-2024-12-23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/sports/other-sports/story/pv-sindhu-wedding-photo-venkatta-datta-sai-udaipur-gajendra-singh-shekhawat-2653980-2024-12-23</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First pics: PV Sindhu marries fiance Venkatta Datta Sai in Udaipur - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/sports/other-sports/story/pv-sindhu-wedding-photo-venkatta-datta-sai-udaipur-gajendra-singh-shekhawat-2653980-2024-12-23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/sports/other-sports/story/pv-sindhu-wedding-photo-venkatta-datta-sai-udaipur-gajendra-singh-shekhawat-2653980-2024-12-23</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First pic: PV Sindhu marries Venkata Datta Sai in Udaipur - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/sports/other-sports/story/pv-sindhu-wedding-photo-venkatta-datta-sai-udaipur-gajendra-singh-shekhawat-2653980-2024-12-23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/sports/other-sports/story/pv-sindhu-wedding-photo-venkatta-datta-sai-udaipur-gajendra-singh-shekhawat-2653980-2024-12-23</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First pics: PV Sindhu marries fiance Venkatta Datta Sai in Udaipur - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/sports/other-sports/story/pv-sindhu-wedding-photo-venkatta-datta-sai-udaipur-gajendra-singh-shekhawat-2653980-2024-12-23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/sports/other-sports/story/pv-sindhu-wedding-photo-venkatta-datta-sai-udaipur-gajendra-singh-shekhawat-2653980-2024-12-23</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Used Practice Pitches For India, New For Australia? Curator Breaks Silence As Another Row Erupts - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPcXdPNzZvSktEVm9KSmE5M2dHYWh5bFNhVDR5V0dGX21oZFFsM01UOUd4dGtNWmRjQUhzelBGSy1mVHRMS1F1Tkh1LUp5TG8yYU5QeTNQaG9lMzkzczkyNDRlLTAtRVlvLW5zUWx1bnhrd2p1RUxDa0c5WDR0S0l3aGdGT2p4ZFVaMHVaY0pVMFFhREJFZWhWaUpTa1YxbEM4Z3J4ZkFfalFBWUZ1WEd2NV94OWxfWkh6YTNBMGp4VmZ3aHZpUGFQQ0hqc0ltQUVLbTFXYUZKWdIB3wFBVV95cUxOXzBhNDUzUGt4czJvOExMc3UzM3Jvb3JXODEzWGVzNlNKeTV0WHp1UjVVd0VpNFVkNGRwQnNUdFc4aHZLZ0E3eWpKRGJPMGp3TVhnbHllNS1ZNkxndmFYNzRYdTBOS0tkSll4MmFFT1ZNRGcxZm9oYXdfZjVSWEtWOERQQWdQMklfOThiQmExVmhpQW0wSmZnWThhTjBxa2dNa0llNXJKZkhtZ1A0QTYtMGtYZk1HbGNvZ180TFJJX2RXYlJvam5PdW5JN3pUNUxQUHQ4MUgxNFJWRW1vNFRj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPcXdPNzZvSktEVm9KSmE5M2dHYWh5bFNhVDR5V0dGX21oZFFsM01UOUd4dGtNWmRjQUhzelBGSy1mVHRMS1F1Tkh1LUp5TG8yYU5QeTNQaG9lMzkzczkyNDRlLTAtRVlvLW5zUWx1bnhrd2p1RUxDa0c5WDR0S0l3aGdGT2p4ZFVaMHVaY0pVMFFhREJFZWhWaUpTa1YxbEM4Z3J4ZkFfalFBWUZ1WEd2NV94OWxfWkh6YTNBMGp4VmZ3aHZpUGFQQ0hqc0ltQUVLbTFXYUZKWdIB3wFBVV95cUxOXzBhNDUzUGt4czJvOExMc3UzM3Jvb3JXODEzWGVzNlNKeTV0WHp1UjVVd0VpNFVkNGRwQnNUdFc4aHZLZ0E3eWpKRGJPMGp3TVhnbHllNS1ZNkxndmFYNzRYdTBOS0tkSll4MmFFT1ZNRGcxZm9oYXdfZjVSWEtWOERQQWdQMklfOThiQmExVmhpQW0wSmZnWThhTjBxa2dNa0llNXJKZkhtZ1A0QTYtMGtYZk1HbGNvZ180TFJJX2RXYlJvam5PdW5JN3pUNUxQUHQ4MUgxNFJWRW1vNFRj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:07:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chess star Tania Sachdev slams Delhi government for failing to recognise her achievements: 'Disheartening' - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tania Sachdev Criticizes Delhi Government for Lack of Support</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Firstpost</p>
<img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/12/Tania-Sachdev-2024-12-4e6ed0fca935589d8aa17c18fb5e2f14-1200x675.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Chess star Tania Sachdev slams Delhi government for failing to recognise her achievements: 'Disheartening'" title="Chess star Tania Sachdev slams Delhi government for failing to recognise her achievements: 'Disheartening'"><figcaption>Tania Sachdev is the eighth woman chess grandmaster from India. Image: Tania Sachdev on X</figcaption>
<p>Indian chess star Tania Sachdev has expressed disappointment over the Delhi government’s lack of recognition for her achievements, stating that such acknowledgment is crucial for inspiring youth and fostering talent development.</p>
<ul>
<li>Tania Sachdev is the eighth woman chess grandmaster from India.</li>
<li>She criticized the Delhi government for not recognizing her and other athletes' achievements in chess.</li>
<li>She urged for more support from Delhi's Chief Minister and Aam Aadmi Party leaders.</li>
<li>She highlighted her achievements, including a historic gold medal at the Chess Olympiad in 2024.</li>
<li>Sachdev contrasted the lack of recognition with Tamil Nadu's celebration of chess champion D Gukesh.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Having played for India since 2008 it’s disheartening to see a lack of recognition from the Delhi government for achievements in chess. States that support and celebrate their champions inspire excellence and motivate talent.” — Tania Sachdev</blockquote>
<p>Sachdev's comments reflect a broader issue regarding the recognition and support given to athletes by their respective state governments, potentially impacting the motivation and development of future talent.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/sports/chess-tania-sachdev-slams-delhi-government-for-failing-to-recognise-her-achievements-13846888.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/sports/chess-tania-sachdev-slams-delhi-government-for-failing-to-recognise-her-achievements-13846888.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:07:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virat, Rohit, Shastri, Dravid, Gambhir come under fire for mistreating Ravichandran Ashwin - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Controversy Grows Over Ashwin's Treatment by Indian Cricket Team Management</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 2024-12-04<br><strong>Source:</strong> Crictoday</p><figure><img width="1200" height="675" src="https://crictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/R-Ashwin.webp" alt="Ashwin"><figcaption><span>Ravichandran Ashwin was made to warm the bench in overseas Test matches. </span></figcaption></figure><p>Ravichandran Ashwin, a veteran cricketer, faced significant scrutiny for being benched during crucial overseas Test matches due to team management decisions. His father described the situation as humiliating following Ashwin's retirement announcement from international cricket.</p><ul><li>Ashwin was often excluded from the Playing XI in SENA countries, playing only 26 matches in 14 years.</li><li>Sunil Gavaskar condemned the management's choices, suggesting that favoritism was evident in their decisions regarding batting and bowling selections.</li><li>Gavaskar highlighted the imbalance in treatment between Ashwin and underperforming batters in international matches.</li><li>Ashwin achieved 765 wickets across formats, including 537 in Test cricket, and won the Player of the Series award 11 times.</li></ul><blockquote>“If the excuse of the pitch and conditions was given for dropping him, why the same didn’t apply for the batters, who were below-par in the SENA countries?” - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote><p>The controversy not only questions the team management's strategy but also casts a shadow on how legendary players like Ashwin are valued in the current setup.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/virat-rohit-shastri-dravid-gambhir-come-under-fire-for-mistreating-ravichandran-ashwin/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/virat-rohit-shastri-dravid-gambhir-come-under-fire-for-mistreating-ravichandran-ashwin/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:58:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet Nat Yoannidis, Australian reporter who went viral after aggressive argument with Virat Kohli in Melbourne - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nat Yoannidis: The Australian Reporter Who Went Viral After an Argument with Virat Kohli</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/controversial-encounter-with-virat-kohli-202412-1734935554.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Controversial Encounter with Virat Kohli">
<figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption>
<p>Nat Yoannidis, an Australian reporter, has recently garnered attention after a heated argument with Indian cricketer Virat Kohli at Melbourne airport, stirring significant debates on social media.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nat was filming Kohli at Melbourne airport when the incident occurred.</li>
  <li>Kohli requested Yoannidis to delete footage of his family, leading to a public outcry.</li>
  <li>The clash highlighted cultural differences in media practices between Australia and India.</li>
  <li>Yoannidis is recognized for her work in sports journalism and has covered multiple major sporting events.</li>
  <li>Social media reactions were polarized, with discussions around family privacy and media responsibility.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"While some supported Kohli's plea for privacy, others viewed the interaction as an example of cultural differences in media practices."</blockquote>
<p>This incident not only highlights the challenges reporters face but also opens up dialogue on the expectations of privacy for celebrities in the public eye.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/meet-nat-yoannidis-australian-reporter-who-went-viral-after-aggressive-argument-with-virat-kohli-in-melbourne-415791/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/meet-nat-yoannidis-australian-reporter-who-went-viral-after-aggressive-argument-with-virat-kohli-in-melbourne-415791/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:42:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PV Sindhu Marries Venkatta Datta Sai In Udaipur. First Pic Out - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu Marries Venkatta Datta Sai In Udaipur. First Pic Out</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/m92itcc_pv-sindhu_625x300_23_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="PV Sindhu and Venkata Datta Sai Wedding" /><figcaption>PV Sindhu and Venkata Datta Sai on their wedding day.</figcaption><p>PV Sindhu, the ace Indian shuttler, married Venkata Datta Sai on Sunday in Udaipur, surrounded by family and close friends. The wedding was attended by notable guests, including Jodhpur's Culture and Tourism Minister, Gajendra Singh Shekhawat, who shared the first photo of the couple.</p><ul><li>The couple engaged on Saturday before their wedding.</li><li>They will be hosting a reception in Hyderabad on December 24.</li><li>A series of pre-wedding events included Sangeet, Haldi, Pellikuthuru, and Mehendi.</li><li>Sindhu's father noted that the wedding plans progressed quickly within a month.</li><li>Sindhu recently ended a two-year title drought in badminton, winning the Syed Modi India International tournament.</li></ul><blockquote>Pleased to have attended the wedding ceremony of our Badminton Champion Olympian PV Sindhu with Venkatta Datta Sai in Udaipur last evening and conveyed my wishes & blessings to the couple for their new life ahead. — Gajendra Singh Shekhawat (@gssjodhpur)</blockquote><p>The wedding was a joyous affair, marking a new chapter in Sindhu's life as she balances her athletic career with personal commitments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/badminton/pv-sindhu-marries-venkatta-datta-sai-in-udaipur-first-pic-out-7312512</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/badminton/pv-sindhu-marries-venkatta-datta-sai-in-udaipur-first-pic-out-7312512</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:39:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Step inside Manu Bhaker's lavish and designer home in Haryana worth Rs... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>An Inside Look at Manu Bhaker's Luxurious Home in Haryana</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/step-inside-manu-bhakers-lavish-and-designer-home-in-haryana-worth-rs-202412-1734934976.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&w=700" alt="Manu Bhaker's home image"><figcaption>Image credit: Source: Instagram</figcaption><p>This article provides a stunning visual tour of double Olympic medalist Manu Bhaker's designer home in Haryana. The luxurious interiors and thoughtful designs reflect the personality and success of the athlete.</p><ul><li>The home is filled with lavish decor and designer elements, showcasing Manu's achievements and style.</li><li>It features a spacious living room with Sabyasachi wallpaper, a yoga room for tranquility, and a leisure room for relaxation.</li><li>Manu's bedroom includes a cozy reading nook and a hand-painted doodle wall that adds a personal touch.</li><li>The trophy wall highlights her numerous accolades, giving a glimpse of her remarkable achievements in shooting.</li></ul><blockquote>“The interior decor of Paris Olympics 2024 medallist will leave you stunned.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Manu Bhaker's home is not just a living space; it's a reflection of her journey and personality, combining luxury with comfort and showcasing her impressive accomplishments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/step-inside-manu-bhaker-lavish-and-designer-home-in-haryana-worth-rs-415780/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/step-inside-manu-bhaker-lavish-and-designer-home-in-haryana-worth-rs-415780/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:37:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker snubbed from Khel Ratna nomination; officials state shooter didn’t apply, family denies claim: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manu Bhaker Snubbed from Khel Ratna Nomination</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/Manu_Bhaker_Indian_flag_1722846380672_1734935453314.jpg" alt="India's Manu Bhaker celebrates with the Indian flag, in Paris.(AP)"><figcaption>India's Manu Bhaker celebrates with the Indian flag, in Paris.(AP)</figcaption><p>Ace shooter Manu Bhaker has reportedly been snubbed for the Khel Ratna Award nomination. The sports ministry claims she did not apply, but her family denies this allegation.</p><ul><li>Manu Bhaker won two bronze medals at the 2024 Paris Olympics, becoming the first female shooter from India to win an Olympic medal.</li><li>Controversy arises as the sports ministry states Bhaker did not apply for the Khel Ratna Award.</li><li>Bhaker's family asserts that she did submit her application for the award.</li><li>In the past, Bhaker faced criticism on social media when she questioned if she deserved the Khel Ratna award.</li><li>She had a notable career, winning gold medals at both the CWG and Asian Games, and a remarkable comeback portrayal after a malfunction at the 2020 Tokyo Olympics.</li></ul><blockquote>“I reunited with coach Jaspal Rana to prepare for the 2024 Olympics, and his training helped me create history in Paris.” – Manu Bhaker</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the ongoing debates surrounding recognition and honor in Indian sports, particularly for rising athletes like Manu Bhaker.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/manu-bhaker-snubbed-for-khel-ratna-nomination-officials-state-shooter-didn-t-apply-family-denies-claim-report-101734935184238.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/manu-bhaker-snubbed-for-khel-ratna-nomination-officials-state-shooter-didn-t-apply-family-denies-claim-report-101734935184238.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Australian cricketers Pat Cummins, Steve Smith, Travis Head and others described BCCI and ICC: Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australian Cricketers Comment on ICC and BCCI in Fun Game</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/smith_head_icc_bcci_1734933452438_1734933463540.jpg" alt="Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket" title="Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket"><figcaption>Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket</figcaption><p>Australian cricketers, including Pat Cummins and Steve Smith, shared their thoughts on the ICC and BCCI during a light-hearted game ahead of a Test match.</p><ul><li>Pat Cummins described ICC, BCCI, and Indian cricket as “Big”.</li><li>Travis Head called BCCI “rulers” and ICC “second.”</li><li>Glenn Maxwell and Alex Carey described BCCI as “powerful” and ICC as “boss.”</li><li>Steve Smith initially joked that ICC is “not as powerful” as BCCI but later corrected himself to call ICC “leaders.”</li><li>Usman Khawaja chose to say “pass” in reference to ICC, hinting at previous conflicts with the organization.</li></ul><blockquote>“No, no I can't say that. It was a joke.” - Steve Smith</blockquote><p>The playful comments shed light on the dynamics between the cricketing boards and the players’ perspectives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/steve-smith-calls-icc-not-as-powerful-as-bcci-then-immediately-backtracks-travis-head-says-indian-board-rulers-101734930106913.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/steve-smith-calls-icc-not-as-powerful-as-bcci-then-immediately-backtracks-travis-head-says-indian-board-rulers-101734930106913.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:32:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steve Smith calls 'ICC not as powerful as BCCI', then immediately backtracks; Travis Head says Indian board 'rulers' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australian Cricketers Comment on ICC and BCCI in Fun Game</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/smith_head_icc_bcci_1734933452438_1734933463540.jpg" alt="Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket" title="Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket"><figcaption>Australia cricketers have their say on ICC, BCCI and Indian cricket</figcaption><p>Australian cricketers, including Pat Cummins and Steve Smith, shared their thoughts on the ICC and BCCI during a light-hearted game ahead of a Test match.</p><ul><li>Pat Cummins described ICC, BCCI, and Indian cricket as “Big”.</li><li>Travis Head called BCCI “rulers” and ICC “second.”</li><li>Glenn Maxwell and Alex Carey described BCCI as “powerful” and ICC as “boss.”</li><li>Steve Smith initially joked that ICC is “not as powerful” as BCCI but later corrected himself to call ICC “leaders.”</li><li>Usman Khawaja chose to say “pass” in reference to ICC, hinting at previous conflicts with the organization.</li></ul><blockquote>“No, no I can't say that. It was a joke.” - Steve Smith</blockquote><p>The playful comments shed light on the dynamics between the cricketing boards and the players’ perspectives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/steve-smith-calls-icc-not-as-powerful-as-bcci-then-immediately-backtracks-travis-head-says-indian-board-rulers-101734930106913.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/steve-smith-calls-icc-not-as-powerful-as-bcci-then-immediately-backtracks-travis-head-says-indian-board-rulers-101734930106913.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:32:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australian tennis star Max Purcell suspended for breaching doping rules - Sydney Morning Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxORmd1Y1lmN0tFTk5jaHFuVWtDZnM3NWpJcHZheXg1V3BfbUZUS01nMGlYbFBGWnc2UnJ6YVVhOVJzTmlKZmpSc3hOWVUzN2JZN0hhNkUwY0o5ME5Qb1NmQnFOS0laVWxmTkpFQ3FLRE5BSEMtek92ZldOUU5ZNkM0aXFyZVNxV0pLdV84eEFCNjA2VzBjVEstT05LQ2cwdURaS3hLNzMyVnhnNmpnRWJNWjh1b3BNcnZBUzlDQnh5UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxORmd1Y1lmN0tFTk5jaHFuVWtDZnM3NWpJcHZheXg1V3BfbUZUS01nMGlYbFBGWnc2UnJ6YVVhOVJzTmlKZmpSc3hOWVUzN2JZN0hhNkUwY0o5ME5Qb1NmQnFOS0laVWxmTkpFQ3FLRE5BSEMtek92ZldOUU5ZNkM0aXFyZVNxV0pLdV84eEFCNjA2VzBjVEstT05LQ2cwdURaS3hLNzMyVnhnNmpnRWJNWjh1b3BNcnZBUzlDQnh5UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:17:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan's batting sensation Saim Ayub joins Virat Kohli in this elite list - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan's batting sensation Saim Ayub joins Virat Kohli in this elite list</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>Pakistan's rising star, Saim Ayub, has achieved a remarkable feat, placing him among cricket legends, including Virat Kohli.</p><ul><li>Saim Ayub's outstanding performances have drawn comparisons to cricketing greats.</li><li>His inclusion in the elite list showcases his talent and potential for future success.</li><li>Ayub's contributions to the team have been pivotal in recent matches.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Saim’s talent is undeniable; he possesses a maturity beyond his years,” commented a senior cricket analyst.</p></blockquote><p>This achievement not only highlights Ayub's skills but also adds to Pakistan's cricketing legacy as they nurture young talents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/pakistans-batting-sensation-saim-ayub-joins-virat-kohli-in-this-elite-list/articleshow/116589098.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/pakistans-batting-sensation-saim-ayub-joins-virat-kohli-in-this-elite-list/articleshow/116589098.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker Surprise Absentee From Khel Ratna Nominations, Report Reveals Reason - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxNcUlXU1ZLS3lRdDN0TmlsWjdfVm1zalZTaXp0RUF0SWwwTUluQkkxRl9RajJ6b3N0SDBoamN2SUJ2X2VNQ3JMQWw4MW8wWlp0NzFNemN3ZTBRZFlDRFlKWjVTZUZBRzBmcS0tYUJ2VW80aWZjbjVuZ05QMk1XQ1RKMWNXR3pOWUlUS0xyNG83UGVtMzduQl90TkthQnlGZGo1NUp4a1FXTTBiVElsaTUwSWVyZlE3Wi1zaEFmeNIBxAFBVV95cUxPNUtzV0NZakVwdEdfZ3dENjl1T1FHTU44Z0FBRkoyS3pKRk5acFV5Sy1OVUFuMHFEbWRuSGxaNXQzc1QwMTMyc2RWZl9WN3FGcEpzOUNkSGZNaWlFX3M3dGd4ZDJ3MDhlWm1mNks2Q2FtZml2NnRtVmQ0aWVmSnlGZlRxMEtMQjNPWEJ5bVpTdmp5UkhXM2lUaUs5RjFPZUFvcm5sY3FJR1JQY2NObVFaeUFhbzVUMF9LTzlRRmxPQVBpTnNC?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxNcUlXU1ZLS3lRdDN0TmlsWjdfVm1zalZTaXp0RUF0SWwwTUluQkkxRl9RajJ6b3N0SDBoamN2SUJ2X2VNQ3JMQWw4MW8wWlp0NzFNemN3ZTBRZFlDRFlKWjVTZUZBRzBmcS0tYUJ2VW80aWZjbjVuZ05QMk1XQ1RKMWNXR3pOWUlUS0xyNG83UGVtMzduQl90TkthQnlGZGo1NUp4a1FXTTBiVElsaTUwSWVyZlE3Wi1zaEFmeNIBxAFBVV95cUxPNUtzV0NZakVwdEdfZ3dENjl1T1FHTU44Z0FBRkoyS3pKRk5acFV5Sy1OVUFuMHFEbWRuSGxaNXQzc1QwMTMyc2RWZl9WN3FGcEpzOUNkSGZNaWlFX3M3dGd4ZDJ3MDhlWm1mNks2Q2FtZml2NnRtVmQ0aWVmSnlGZlRxMEtMQjNPWEJ5bVpTdmp5UkhXM2lUaUs5RjFPZUFvcm5sY3FJR1JQY2NObVFaeUFhbzVUMF9LTzlRRmxPQVBpTnNC?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:06:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BBL 2024-2025: Match 10, REN vs SCO Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between REN vs SCO? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BBL 2024-2025: Match Prediction for REN vs SCO</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><figure><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1734865093616_image_2024_12_22T10_51_55_156Z.png" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The Melbourne Renegades will face the Perth Scorchers at Docklands Stadium, with both teams looking to secure their second win of the tournament.</p><ul><li>Renegades defeated Hobart Hurricanes with 66 balls to spare.</li><li>Scorchers were unable to defend their score against the Hurricanes.</li><li>The match will be the first at Docklands Stadium this season, typically favoring pacers early on.</li><li>Head-to-head record: 20 matches played; Renegades won 3, Scorchers won 16.</li></ul><blockquote>“Melbourne Renegades to win the match.”</blockquote><p>This prediction is based on analysis of team performances and conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-10-ren-vs-sco-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-ren-vs-sco-0053/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-10-ren-vs-sco-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-ren-vs-sco-0053/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>