<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:27:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:27:29 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One-handed stunner! 39-yo Dinesh Karthik lights up SA20 with glovework for Paarl Royals. Watch - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>One-handed stunner! 39-yo Dinesh Karthik lights up SA20 with glovework for Paarl Royals</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>Dinesh Karthik showcased exceptional glovework during the SA20 league match, impressing fans and teammates alike.</p><ul><li>Karthik executed an outstanding one-handed catch.</li><li>His performance is a highlight in his ongoing cricket career.</li><li>Fans and analysts praised his skills on social media.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was an unforgettable moment that exemplifies Karthik's talent.”</blockquote><p>Karthik continues to be a vital player and his performance adds excitement to the league.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/one-handed-stunner-39-yo-dinesh-karthik-lights-up-sa20-with-gloves-for-paarl-royals-watch/articleshow/117273655.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/one-handed-stunner-39-yo-dinesh-karthik-lights-up-sa20-with-gloves-for-paarl-royals-watch/articleshow/117273655.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI mulling addition to India Men's coaching staff - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQdXFvbWs2cS0xZW51dFNWS0RkbUVWbWRZUWhjX1RwMDcwUm9QSnN5WUs4QTRDZzZmZ1A0bTRDcFZiWnFWTmxKa0JnMHpKOUxHemxna0RIRWw4T2NfSHV5bjlpUllQWXF3Q1RPNjVlbmZiV1I5c0hGZ3U2S1BURTJWclFLVUExMXhuOWNPbmk3OE9zbnRaa1NXNW1uYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQdXFvbWs2cS0xZW51dFNWS0RkbUVWbWRZUWhjX1RwMDcwUm9QSnN5WUs4QTRDZzZmZ1A0bTRDcFZiWnFWTmxKa0JnMHpKOUxHemxna0RIRWw4T2NfSHV5bjlpUllQWXF3Q1RPNjVlbmZiV1I5c0hGZ3U2S1BURTJWclFLVUExMXhuOWNPbmk3OE9zbnRaa1NXNW1uYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:09:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alejandro Garnacho 'transfer agreement reached' as Man Utd 'target £42m replacement' - Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxOdUNlNGgwYUQ2MElGRlRDRFViUlFvdmhOekVuTFRBUXRXV29BWE02VlhXdFUtZXFOclNiNWZmQlp6dmt0eHU0OGtPQk5MZmYyMXZURTdiNFEzWkVJaFA1ZXV4ak1kS2ZIZnF6NGxmR1FSYkxxMk9UUDRxOHlKdVdaZzdlVDZpYXQtdE96VklTZ3ZuMjDSAZgBQVVfeXFMTjFmbVFyaG02WlZva18tamI1WEUyWHF4UktkZG51X2xFclNIOTNYYUl2WERuVWh3NEFGUERWWFAxYXc5RnpwcktYVThOM1VmZXJUSHIzSDBFX09pNXJQMEN0SVNQc0NxblZYOTh3WmdYcS1fT2hNeWFSeENmeVhYQndScnNUdFlWZzN3aTMzLWFPZnJybEZiRUo?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxOdUNlNGgwYUQ2MElGRlRDRFViUlFvdmhOekVuTFRBUXRXV29BWE02VlhXdFUtZXFOclNiNWZmQlp6dmt0eHU0OGtPQk5MZmYyMXZURTdiNFEzWkVJaFA1ZXV4ak1kS2ZIZnF6NGxmR1FSYkxxMk9UUDRxOHlKdVdaZzdlVDZpYXQtdE96VklTZ3ZuMjDSAZgBQVVfeXFMTjFmbVFyaG02WlZva18tamI1WEUyWHF4UktkZG51X2xFclNIOTNYYUl2WERuVWh3NEFGUERWWFAxYXc5RnpwcktYVThOM1VmZXJUSHIzSDBFX09pNXJQMEN0SVNQc0NxblZYOTh3WmdYcS1fT2hNeWFSeENmeVhYQndScnNUdFlWZzN3aTMzLWFPZnJybEZiRUo?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Ban Indian players from having PR agencies": Harsha Bhogle suggests a new rule for Team India - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>“Ban Indian players from having PR agencies”: Harsha Bhogle suggests a new rule for Team India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Crictoday</p>
<img src="https://crictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Harsha-Bhogle.webp" alt="Harsha Bhogle" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>He also suggested a rule that should be implemented by the apex body of Indian cricket.</figcaption>
<p>Harsha Bhogle, a renowned sports presenter, has suggested banning Indian cricket team members from having public relations (PR) agencies following recent changes introduced by the BCCI.</p>
<ul>
<li>The BCCI has implemented various rules for players after a recent defeat against Australia, including restrictions on travel and family visits.</li>
<li>Bhogle believes that banning PR agencies would be beneficial for the integrity of the team.</li>
<li>He expressed his views on social media, raising concerns about the impact of PR agencies on player reputation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Reading of the changes the BCCI is apparently suggesting for the Indian team. I don't know how much to believe but if I had to nominate one rule to be strictly applied, it would be to ban team members from having PR agencies”— Harsha Bhogle (@bhogleharsha) January 15, 2025</blockquote>
<p>The presence of PR agencies is said to encourage the spread of misinformation about players and can lead to conflicts of interest.</p>
<p>In conclusion, Bhogle's call for banning PR agencies highlights ongoing concerns about their influence in cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://crictoday.com/cricket/daily-cricket-news/ban-indian-players-from-having-pr-agencies-harsha-bhogle-suggests-a-new-rule-for-team-india/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crictoday.com/cricket/daily-cricket-news/ban-indian-players-from-having-pr-agencies-harsha-bhogle-suggests-a-new-rule-for-team-india/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:19:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vijay Hazare Trophy: Padikkal, Shetty step up as Karnataka storm into final - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Karnataka Dominates Haryana to Reach Vijay Hazare Trophy Final</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p>
<p>Karnataka secured a convincing victory over Haryana by five wickets, thanks to stellar performances from Devdutt Padikkal and Abhilash Shetty, propelling them into the Vijay Hazare Trophy final for the first time since the 2019-20 season.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Karnataka scored 238 runs for 5 wickets, overcoming Haryana's 237 for 9.</li>
  <li>Padikkal scored 86 runs and shared a crucial 128-run partnership with Ravichandran Smaran, who contributed 76 runs.</li>
  <li>Shetty excelled with the ball, taking 4 wickets for 34 runs, significantly impacting Haryana's batting order.</li>
  <li>Karnataka will face either Vidarbha or Maharashtra in the final.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>'I’m amazed myself' - Karun Nair reflects on record-breaking run.</blockquote>
<p>In summary, Karnataka showed resilience and skill, demonstrating their potential as they move forward in the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-1445828/haryana-vs-karnataka-1st-semi-final-1446240/match-report</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/series/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-1445828/haryana-vs-karnataka-1st-semi-final-1446240/match-report</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:08:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pep Guardiola's wife 'called time on marriage after reaching final Man City decision' - The Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pep Guardiola's Wife 'Ended Marriage After Reaching Final Man City Decision'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-15T15:56:19Z">15:56, 15 Jan 2025</time></p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> <a href="https://www.mirror.co.uk/sport/football/news/pep-guardiola-marriage-wife-mancity-34487970">Mirror</a></p>
<img src="https://i2-prod.dailystar.co.uk/sport/football/article34481342.ece/ALTERNATES/n615/0_FC-Internazionale-v-Manchester-City-FC-UEFA-Champions-League-Final-202223.jpg" alt="Pep Guardiola and his wife after City's Champions League Final triumph">
<figcaption>Pep Guardiola and his wife after City's Champions League Final triumph</figcaption>
<p>Pep Guardiola has separated from his wife, Cristina Serra, after 30 years together, influenced by his recent decision to extend his contract with Manchester City.</p>
<ul>
<li>Guardiola signed a two-year contract extension in November, which reportedly strained their marriage.</li>
<li>His wife Cristina had relocated to Barcelona in 2019 for her fashion business.</li>
<li>Friends of the couple mentioned unusual behaviors suggesting tensions in their relationship.</li>
<li>The couple had previously spent Christmas together in Barcelona but decided on their future separately.</li>
<li>Lorena Vazquez and Laura Fa, respected reporters, stated there was no third party involved.</li>
<li>Guardiola's daughter emphasized their parents' focus on love and support in their family dynamics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The confirmation that Pep would stay at the Citizens until 2027 ended up breaking what was already cracked.”</blockquote>
<p>This marital split highlights the personal sacrifices often involved in high-pressure careers, especially in the world of professional sports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mirror.co.uk/sport/football/news/pep-guardiola-marriage-wife-mancity-34487970</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mirror.co.uk/sport/football/news/pep-guardiola-marriage-wife-mancity-34487970</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Xiangqi Grandmasters Banned For Life In Chinese Chess Scandal - Chess.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Top Xiangqi Grandmasters Banned For Life In Chinese Chess Scandal</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: 2023-10-23</strong><br><strong>Source: Chess.com</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://www.chess.com/bundles/web/images/image-default.445cb543.svg" alt="The investigations revealed cases of match-fixing and bribery, according to Chinese media. Photo: CCTV News" width="1200" height="720">
<figcaption>The investigations revealed cases of match-fixing and bribery, according to Chinese media. Photo: CCTV News.</figcaption></figure>
<p>A major cheating scandal has rocked the world of Chinese chess, leading to lifetime bans for several top players, including Wang Yuefei and Wang Tianyi.</p>
<ul>
  <li>A number of top Xiangqi players have received lifetime bans due to cheating scandals.</li>
  <li>Wang Tianyi, a decorated player, is implicated in receiving bribes totaling 800,000 yuan.</li>
  <li>The scandal became public after the Chinese Xiangqi Association issued bans in September.</li>
  <li>Gai Hongyan stated that illegal activities have hindered the sport's development for over a decade.</li>
  <li>41 players have been penalized following a thorough investigation into match-fixing.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p><strong>For over a decade, such illegal activities have been hampering the healthy development of the sport...</strong></p>
  <footer>—Gai Hongyan</footer>
</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the extensive investigation uncovers a disturbing trend of corruption within the sport, threatening its integrity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.chess.com/news/view/cheating-scandal-in-chinese-chess-3-top-players-banned-for-life</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.chess.com/news/view/cheating-scandal-in-chinese-chess-3-top-players-banned-for-life</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Haryana vs Karnataka LIVE Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy semifinal: KAR beats HAR by 5 wickets - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/domestic/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-live-score-haryana-vs-karnataka-semifinal-updates-highlights-streaming-info/article69099333.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/domestic/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-live-score-haryana-vs-karnataka-semifinal-updates-highlights-streaming-info/article69099333.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:48:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Haryana vs Karnataka LIVE Score, Vijay Hazare Trophy semifinal: KAR beats HAR by 5 wickets - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/domestic/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-live-score-haryana-vs-karnataka-semifinal-updates-highlights-streaming-info/article69099333.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/domestic/vijay-hazare-trophy-2024-25-live-score-haryana-vs-karnataka-semifinal-updates-highlights-streaming-info/article69099333.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:48:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nortje ruled out of Champions Trophy with back injury - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Anrich Nortje Out of Champions Trophy Due to Back Injury</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Wed, Jan 15, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c600177/nortje-will-also-miss-the-rema.jpg" alt="Nortje will also miss the remainder of the SA20 tournament">
<figcaption>Nortje will also miss the remainder of the SA20 tournament © Getty</figcaption>
<p>Anrich Nortje has been ruled out of the Champions Trophy and the remainder of the SA20 tournament due to a back injury. His absence continues as scans revealed he is not expected to recover in time to participate.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Nortje was a highlight of South Africa's squad announcement but will miss the tournament starting February 21 against Afghanistan.</li>
  <li>He has not played international cricket since June last year and last appeared on the field on December 2 during the Abu Dhabi T10.</li>
  <li>Nortje opted out of the 2024/25 Test season to focus on his health and franchise career.</li>
  <li>He faced a broken toe injury from a David Miller yorker in the nets recently.</li>
  <li>This injury adds to his history of setbacks, including missing the 2019 and 2023 ODI World Cups.</li>
  <li>Gerald Coetzee is expected to replace him in the team.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Gerald Coetzee played very well in the 2023 World Cup... Anrich has more experience and attributes that will stand us in good stead in Pakistan.” - Rob Walter, South Africa's coach</blockquote>
<p>Nortje's future participation in the IPL remains uncertain as he continues to recover from his injury.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/133117/nortje-ruled-out-of-champions-trophy-with-back-injury</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/133117/nortje-ruled-out-of-champions-trophy-with-back-injury</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:26:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ihsanullah reverses decision to retire from all franchise cricket - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ihsanullah Reverses Retirement Decision from Franchise Cricket</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> ESPNcricinfo</p><p>Pakistan fast bowler <a href="https://www.espncricinfo.com/cricketers/ihsanullah-1283740">Ihsanullah</a> has changed his mind about retiring from franchise cricket less than a day after announcing it, citing emotional turmoil and a desire to prove himself.</p><ul><li>Ihsanullah stated he made the initial retirement decision in an emotional state.</li><li>He emphasized his commitment to work hard for the upcoming PSL season.</li><li>Franchise owner Ali Tareen expressed concern for Ihsanullah's wellbeing and support during his recovery.</li><li>Independent reports criticized the PCB for their handling of Ihsanullah's elbow injury.</li></ul><blockquote>“I take my decision back. No franchise picked me, and the comments of a lot of people sent me over the edge.” - Ihsanullah</blockquote><p>The fast bowler is determined to overcome his challenges and return to competitive cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/ihsanullah-reverses-decision-to-retire-from-all-franchise-cricket-1469187</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/ihsanullah-reverses-decision-to-retire-from-all-franchise-cricket-1469187</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:09:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Champions Trophy Ticket Price: Higher In Dubai, Dirt Cheap In Pakistan At Rs... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Champions Trophy Ticket Price: Higher In Dubai, Dirt Cheap In Pakistan At Rs...</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/otf54c6o_icc-champions-trophy-2025-_625x300_25_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Champions Trophy Ticket Price" width="639" height="479"><figcaption>Representative image. © AFP</figcaption><p>The Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) has set the initial ticket prices for the Champions Trophy matches, revealing a significant price gap compared to Dubai where matches involving India will be held.</p><ul><li>General enclosure tickets in Pakistan start at PKR 1000 (approximately INR 310), with increased pricing for higher-demand matches.</li><li>For the Pakistan vs. Bangladesh match in Rawalpindi, the ticket price escalates to PKR 2000 (INR 620).</li><li>VVIP ticket prices are set at PKR 12,000 (INR 3726) for all matches but rise to PKR 25,000 (INR 7764) for semi-finals.</li><li>The PCB expects to sell around 18,000 tickets for general spectators, but details on individual purchases remain unclear.</li><li>The ICC's decision to host matches in Dubai impacts revenue distribution for the PCB, which aims to collect gate money from those games.</li></ul><blockquote>“The ECB will obviously advise the ICC and PCB on the ticket rates for different enclosures in Dubai...”</blockquote><p>Overall, the ticket prices reflect the PCB's strategy to make matches accessible while also navigating additional pressures from hosting events in neutral venues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/tickets-for-champions-trophy-matches-in-pakistan-as-low-as-inr-310-prices-in-dubai-higher-report-7480706</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/tickets-for-champions-trophy-matches-in-pakistan-as-low-as-inr-310-prices-in-dubai-higher-report-7480706</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:55:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India squads for Champions Trophy, England ODIs LIVE Updates: Will Rohit Sharma travel to Pakistan for CT? - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India squads for England ODI series and Champions Trophy Highlights</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Firstpost</p><div id="nwartbximg"><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/03/Rohit-Babar-1200-image-2024-03-c395e2999103d9523aa41ade79c7f024-1200x675.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="India squads for Champions Trophy, England ODIs Highlights: India's squad yet to be announced" title="India squads for Champions Trophy, England ODIs Highlights: India's squad yet to be announced"><figcaption>India will be playing all of their matches in the ICC Champions Trophy in Dubai after refusing to travel to Pakistan. AP</figcaption></div><p>The BCCI is expected to announce the Team India squad for the 2025 ICC Champions Trophy in the coming days. While Rohit Sharma looks set to lead and Virat Kohli will also feature, India are sweating over the fitness of pacer Jasprit Bumrah, who sustained a back spasm during the fifth Test against Australia.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Team India will play all matches for the ICC Champions Trophy in Dubai; they will not travel to Pakistan.</li><li>The squad announcement is expected around January 18 or 19.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah's fitness concerns may impact squad selection.</li><li>The opening match for India against Bangladesh is scheduled for February 20, followed by a crucial match against Pakistan.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes</h2><blockquote>“Pakistan will have the upper hand against India... However, India has always been my favourite in big tournaments.” - Mohammad Amir</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>The anticipation builds around the finalization of India's squad as they gear up for significant matches in the ICC Champions Trophy and the series against England.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/firstcricket/sports-news/india-icc-champions-trophy-2025-england-odi-squad-announcement-live-updates-15-jan-13852872.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/firstcricket/sports-news/india-icc-champions-trophy-2025-england-odi-squad-announcement-live-updates-15-jan-13852872.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:43:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ruben Amorim fires Liverpool and Arsenal warning to Man Utd stars ahead of Southampton clash - The Mirror]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxPZG1ZeEhTUVIxOTU5bkJCYm5KSmZfQk9wX3VZYTVieXZKV0FEU2REWWJxaUpxT1pDYkxrNlpURlB1N3dqRi05dklHMks0S1ZuYzZuU1VHcEYxMDlkdDBMNk5DcDJ1YXJNdWFlZllJOWM0REJZZEp6SkZITVZiSHRQeWE5cDNZMXpTTl9Gbjl1VmlZS1ktQWx2NXlQTkFiUdIBowFBVV95cUxNMEliVGJUU1hiWHo2dzJNVzB2TWFrTEFFVExCSm8tUzlqNUs4d1Z2X0p2S3J6OXdsRlRCb1NsX3VnUmViZEdld2x1Smd4bU5zLVBBVVpHMWlsOWJrWVo2aEdFWTFwemFPdUhKZGJuWXlGYUxOeG9VTTZiRXNzX1N0Z25CMzJ5TXE4anpDMjZpSmtXTVhMd0poblFhc3lKVUpzZE5Z?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxPZG1ZeEhTUVIxOTU5bkJCYm5KSmZfQk9wX3VZYTVieXZKV0FEU2REWWJxaUpxT1pDYkxrNlpURlB1N3dqRi05dklHMks0S1ZuYzZuU1VHcEYxMDlkdDBMNk5DcDJ1YXJNdWFlZllJOWM0REJZZEp6SkZITVZiSHRQeWE5cDNZMXpTTl9Gbjl1VmlZS1ktQWx2NXlQTkFiUdIBowFBVV95cUxNMEliVGJUU1hiWHo2dzJNVzB2TWFrTEFFVExCSm8tUzlqNUs4d1Z2X0p2S3J6OXdsRlRCb1NsX3VnUmViZEdld2x1Smd4bU5zLVBBVVpHMWlsOWJrWVo2aEdFWTFwemFPdUhKZGJuWXlGYUxOeG9VTTZiRXNzX1N0Z25CMzJ5TXE4anpDMjZpSmtXTVhMd0poblFhc3lKVUpzZE5Z?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India’s Arjun Erigaisi defeats Magnus Carlsen, Fabiano Caruana to win online chess event - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India’s Arjun Erigaisi defeats Magnus Carlsen, Fabiano Caruana to win online chess event</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Tuesday, <strong>Source:</strong> First Post</p>
<p>Indian grandmaster Arjun Erigaisi won the Titled Tuesday weekly blitz competition on Chess.com, defeating World No 1 Magnus Carlsen and World No 2 Fabiano Caruana.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Erigaisi scored 10 points from 11 rounds in the competition.</li>
  <li>He defeated Carlsen in round 10 and Caruana in the final round.</li>
  <li>Erigaisi is ranked fourth in the world, while Hikaru Nakamura is third.</li>
  <li>The event hosted over 900 participants and required players to attend Zoom calls for fair play.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Nakamura has claimed to be the 'world’s strongest tournament'.”</blockquote>
<p>Arjun Erigaisi's journey in chess has been remarkable, leading to multiple prestigious wins including the Tata Steel Chess 2022 Challengers and the 2024 WR Chess Masters Cup.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/news/indias-arjun-erigaisi-defeats-magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-to-win-online-chess-event-11736946202400.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/news/indias-arjun-erigaisi-defeats-magnus-carlsen-fabiano-caruana-to-win-online-chess-event-11736946202400.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:10:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI says no to KL Rahul and Sanju Samson for Champions Trophy; Rishabh Pant, Jurel set to be India's keepers: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Excludes KL Rahul and Sanju Samson from Champions Trophy; Rishabh Pant and Dhruv Jurel Named Keepers</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 15, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/ANI-20240324119-0_1711294614371_1736949888742.jpg" alt="KL Rahul and Sanju Samson (ANI)" title="KL Rahul and Sanju Samson (ANI)">
<figcaption>KL Rahul and Sanju Samson (ANI)</figcaption>
<p>The BCCI has decided that KL Rahul and Sanju Samson will not be considered for the wicketkeeper positions in India's Champions Trophy squad. Instead, Rishabh Pant and Dhruv Jurel are expected to fill these roles.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sanju Samson's absence from the Vijay Hazare Trophy preparatory camp may cost him his spot in the Champions Trophy squad.</li>
<li>Rahul's lack of selection as a specialist keeper highlights a shift in the team's strategy moving forward.</li>
<li>Rishabh Pant is confirmed as the first-choice keeper, with Jurel likely securing the second keeper role over competitors Samson and Ishan Kishan.</li>
<li>Samson's omission stems from his decision to skip domestic tournaments, impacting his selection chances.</li>
<li>Ishan Kishan, previously a strong contender, has fallen out of favor due to recent performances and absences.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"KL Rahul's presence behind the stumps during the ODI World Cup gave the Indian team the balance but he is unlikely to don the big gloves in white-ball cricket going forward."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the BCCI's selections mark a crucial decision in shaping the future of India's cricket team, emphasizing the importance of participating in domestic tournaments for national selection.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/bcci-says-no-to-kl-rahul-and-sanju-samson-for-champions-trophy-rishabh-pant-jurel-set-to-be-indias-keepers-report-101736949737432.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/bcci-says-no-to-kl-rahul-and-sanju-samson-for-champions-trophy-rishabh-pant-jurel-set-to-be-indias-keepers-report-101736949737432.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 14:09:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir Accused Star Batter Of Leaking Team News In Australia? Report's Startling Claims - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxNdEpscER0X0dCWFJ3T1VVZkd5cldrTnYzdHRHUnJEWE9OWmFRVXI2TDd4Qm1RbmV4M0xOdGFFQ3FjaUMweVBndEoxQ2RxWVNqV2F1dmdjaHBGQlhXeERhSllPa0ZEM3VrUDlfWTRGU0VNcjAxcm9HQ2lkeVFxbWV6SF9FMzIydktVdGdSeFZQZGVJbkg3ZVBBcGZVa3FrTmVLYUFKeFFEU1FlV1k3XzluVFlranJNSWpuN2ZIQmlJcE5HdjZsZXh6ZWZUYmNrNm9tMlZZSXc1cGNyLWMxQ2x6N2lzS0XSAewBQVVfeXFMTmlCSjBpVnRWejE3c1lUbGlMOHZ4MTVZbjk2RlpCellHWUR6TWZkZlZhQnpRQkozU3NEVjcxYmlZLXR6RmdpMkhNX2w4UGVxYXRlNzB3ZXBpTC1Gd0NwNmRjNHgyV3BfbDhIQWM2MTBiMUl4QnNoM3lKWHp1VzJRQTAzTGNkY2RqbE9BOE82MUFuNDdvVzgyNC0zbXdMUmNkWldHMWtQZ0c5R1VlNEdiSWN3OThYS3dSdDZlZHFoX2tTOS1vSnRRZ25ZVmlkWV84Sl9QMXMxUXZ5M2Itb2U0dVNJM3dUS052TjZQeTA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxNdEpscER0X0dCWFJ3T1VVZkd5cldrTnYzdHRHUnJEWE9OWmFRVXI2TDd4Qm1RbmV4M0xOdGFFQ3FjaUMweVBndEoxQ2RxWVNqV2F1dmdjaHBGQlhXeERhSllPa0ZEM3VrUDlfWTRGU0VNcjAxcm9HQ2lkeVFxbWV6SF9FMzIydktVdGdSeFZQZGVJbkg3ZVBBcGZVa3FrTmVLYUFKeFFEU1FlV1k3XzluVFlranJNSWpuN2ZIQmlJcE5HdjZsZXh6ZWZUYmNrNm9tMlZZSXc1cGNyLWMxQ2x6N2lzS0XSAewBQVVfeXFMTmlCSjBpVnRWejE3c1lUbGlMOHZ4MTVZbjk2RlpCellHWUR6TWZkZlZhQnpRQkozU3NEVjcxYmlZLXR6RmdpMkhNX2w4UGVxYXRlNzB3ZXBpTC1Gd0NwNmRjNHgyV3BfbDhIQWM2MTBiMUl4QnNoM3lKWHp1VzJRQTAzTGNkY2RqbE9BOE82MUFuNDdvVzgyNC0zbXdMUmNkWldHMWtQZ0c5R1VlNEdiSWN3OThYS3dSdDZlZHFoX2tTOS1vSnRRZ25ZVmlkWV84Sl9QMXMxUXZ5M2Itb2U0dVNJM3dUS052TjZQeTA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:46:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yashasvi Jaiswal joins Mumbai Ranji camp; Rohit Sharma skips training, but spotted jogging at Bandra-Kurla complex - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Yashasvi Jaiswal Joins Mumbai Ranji Camp; Rohit Sharma Seen Jogging</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Australia-India-Cricket-16_1736945718419_1736945738992.jpg" alt="India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and India's Yashasvi Jaiswal during play on the last day of the fourth cricket test between Australia and India at the Melbourne Cricket Ground(AP)" title="India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and India's Yashasvi Jaiswal during play on the last day of the fourth cricket test between Australia and India at the Melbourne Cricket Ground(AP)"><figcaption>India's captain Rohit Sharma, right, and India's Yashasvi Jaiswal during play on the last day of the fourth cricket test between Australia and India at the Melbourne Cricket Ground(AP)</figcaption><p>Yashasvi Jaiswal has joined the Mumbai cricket team's Ranji Trophy camp, gearing up for the upcoming match against Jammu & Kashmir on January 23. Meanwhile, India captain Rohit Sharma missed practice but was spotted jogging at the Bandra Kurla Complex.</p><ul><li>Yashasvi Jaiswal confirms his availability for the Ranji Trophy after performing well in Australia.</li><li>Rohit Sharma skipped training but was seen jogging, raising questions about his readiness for the upcoming match.</li><li>Selectors will announce the squad on January 20, focusing on players' availability.</li></ul><blockquote>"Rohit will also be approached around the time for selection," said a Mumbai Cricket Association official.</blockquote><p>The training dynamics ahead of the Ranji Trophy are crucial as players seek to regain form and fitness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/yashasvi-jaiswal-joins-mumbai-ranji-camp-rohit-sharma-skips-training-but-spotted-jogging-at-bandra-kurla-complex-101736945427917.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/yashasvi-jaiswal-joins-mumbai-ranji-camp-rohit-sharma-skips-training-but-spotted-jogging-at-bandra-kurla-complex-101736945427917.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:27:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smith fifty helps Sixers jump to the top spot - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Smith fifty helps Sixers jump to the top spot</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Wed, Jan 15, 2025, 01:17 PM | <strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img height="396" width="595" alt="Smith played a decisive knock to anchor the Sixers to victory with 54 off 31 balls" title="Smith played a decisive knock to anchor the Sixers to victory with 54 off 31 balls" src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c600168/smith-played-a-decisive-knock.jpg" itemprop="contentUrl">
<figcaption>Smith played a decisive knock to anchor the Sixers to victory with 54 off 31 balls © Getty</figcaption>
<p>Sydney Sixers reclaimed the top spot on the table with a thrilling three-wicket win off the penultimate ball, continuing their push for the playoffs. Steve Smith's 54 off 31 balls was crucial in their victory.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sixers won by three wickets in a match that came down to the last ball.</li>
  <li>Smith's performance was pivotal with a quick fifty that guided the team.</li>
  <li>The win dealt a significant blow to the Adelaide Strikers’ playoff chances.</li>
  <li>Early wickets put pressure on the Sixers, but key partnerships helped secure the win.</li>
  <li>Adelaide Strikers posted 182 runs, but the Sixers chased it down scoring 183.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The hosts got off to a terrible start with the bat, but vital contributions led to a successful chase."</blockquote>
<p>This victory not only helps the Sixers secure their position at the top but also improves their momentum as they head into the playoffs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/133116/smith-fifty-helps-sixers-jump-to-the-top-spot</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/133116/smith-fifty-helps-sixers-jump-to-the-top-spot</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:18:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir Blames Sarfaraz Khan For Dressing Room Leaks During BGT: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Accuses Sarfaraz Khan of Dressing Room Leaks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='Sarfaraz Khan (PTI Photo)'><figcaption>Sarfaraz Khan (PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>Gautam Gambhir has reportedly accused Sarfaraz Khan of leaking information from the Indian dressing room during the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Gambhir believes Khan disclosed details about his speech after India's defeat in the fourth Test.</li><li>Khan did not participate in the Test series despite a strong previous performance.</li><li>Concerns about the dressing room dynamics and the impact on Khan's career were raised.</li><li>Gambhir emphasized the need for honesty within the team and criticized the media hype.</li><li>The report highlights ongoing pressure on Gambhir and the team's struggles in recent months.</li></ul><blockquote>“Debates between coach and player should remain in the dressing room. Stern words.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>Overall, this incident raises questions about team dynamics and the implications for player reputations and careers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/gautam-gambhir-blames-sarfaraz-khan-for-dressing-room-leaks-during-bgt-report-9189902.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/gautam-gambhir-blames-sarfaraz-khan-for-dressing-room-leaks-during-bgt-report-9189902.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:02:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SA20 2025: Match 9, PR vs MICT Match Prediction – Who will win today’s SA20 match between PR vs MICT? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SA20 2025: Match 9, PR vs MICT Match Prediction</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><figure><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736848216200_image_2025_01_14T09_49_52_220Z.png" loading="lazy"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>The SA20 tournament continues with Paarl Royals facing MI Cape Town in Match 9. Both teams have faced each other recently, with MI Cape Town securing a victory by 33 runs.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>Paarl Royals (PR) are currently fourth in the points table.</li><li>MI Cape Town (MICT) leads the table, having won two out of three matches.</li><li>The match will be played at Boland Park in Paarl.</li><li>Pitch conditions suggest low bounce and assistance for spinners.</li><li>Top performers are Lhuan-dre Pretorius for PR and Delano Potgieter for MICT.</li></ul><h3>Notable Quotes:</h3><blockquote>“Today's Match Prediction: Team bowling first to win the match.”</blockquote><p>This fast-paced encounter poses a solid prediction challenge, with teams looking to capitalize on pitch conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-9-pr-vs-mict-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-pr-vs-mict-2852/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/sa20-2025-match-9-pr-vs-mict-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-sa20-match-between-pr-vs-mict-2852/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ILT20 2025: Match 6, ADKR vs SWR Match Prediction – Who will win today’s ILT20 match between ADKR vs SWR? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ILT20 2025: Match 6, ADKR vs SWR Match Prediction</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736843554091_image_2025_01_14T08_29_54_926Z.png" alt="Match Prediction Image" width="700" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Predicted outcome of the match between ADKR and SWR.</figcaption><p>The Abu Dhabi Knight Riders (ADKR) face the Sharjah Warriorz (SWR) in Match 6 of the ILT20 2025 series. ADKR aims to rebound from their first match loss, while SWR looks to continue their winning momentum.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>ADKR lost their opening match against Desert Vipers.</li><li>SWR won their first match against Gulf Giants by three wickets.</li><li>The match will take place at Sheikh Zayed Stadium in Abu Dhabi at 8:00 PM IST.</li><li>ADKR's probable best batter is Phil Salt; SWR's is Tim Southee for bowling.</li><li>Pitch is favorable for batting with some assistance for spinners.</li></ul><blockquote>Prediction: The defending team is likely to win the match.</blockquote><p>Overall, the match is highly anticipated as both teams look to blaze ahead in the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/ilt20-2025-match-6-adkr-vs-swr-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-ilt20-match-between-adkr-vs-swr/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/ilt20-2025-match-6-adkr-vs-swr-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-ilt20-match-between-adkr-vs-swr/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3rd ODI: Smriti Mandhana's blazing 70-ball century powers India to record 304-run win - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>3rd ODI: Smriti Mandhana's blazing 70-ball century powers India to record 304-run win</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>In an impressive display of cricket, Smriti Mandhana achieved a stunning 70-ball century, contributing significantly to India's record 304-run victory.</p><ul><li>Mandhana's century was instrumental in setting a massive target.</li><li>This win marks a significant achievement in the series.</li><li>India demonstrated dominance throughout the match.</li></ul><blockquote>"Her performance was a game-changer and showcased her talent on the international stage."</blockquote><p>This match further cements India's position in the cricketing world, highlighting the exceptional skills of players like Mandhana.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/3rd-odi-smriti-mandhanas-blazing-70-ball-century-powers-india-to-record-304-run-win/articleshow/117268821.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/3rd-odi-smriti-mandhanas-blazing-70-ball-century-powers-india-to-record-304-run-win/articleshow/117268821.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bad News For India: Jasprit Bumrah Advised Bed Rest Ahead Of Champions Trophy - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxQbFJXcDIzVWxvT2tGOEMxRmpTenotV2ZrUkRwblpSMFdkeTdvTDAxU1dCWGlQdDBwcURjOGFXcXM2WmQyWnZwTm1pMGZtTFZIblZuQ1ZGYVMycUgyOVZQMDhQMWFOaFRyLTUyNU9BQ3dtVzlILVE2d05aYXRXNUZhcnNCVHBfMEx3TERKdU1ROGtlcVVFT0dMWVk4YzJfaE5wV2s5ZFNULUVCQ0Q5cUktZ2RGOERQRkExRC1RVVA2MmQ4QjNSUWdqYlhCRFFpVnfSAdcBQVVfeXFMT2RsMzFtcHk3OXdUQmNpaE1icV9SbVNTbnNHQjJwbjhQU0FlTWdrck1WXzFxVkNfUmRHbUU4dkRpRlFMQUlnLS1qREszTkpoZkV5enQ5aU1lUVJDZEdJMmdRV2ZVX0NWWm5zcDdDS0R0OFZHVFQ3RlJ2RkY3eFJRb0lST1pXeGxNQ3FlSWNtT2FyYlRuTVNROHBmNVZzeE5WQjJ5MExjMHV1WGI4YlJ4ZEFEWGVoWG5GU201ckhLdTFoQzItTjNHV2dZRVRvQzlsUEp2cXdKbnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxQbFJXcDIzVWxvT2tGOEMxRmpTenotV2ZrUkRwblpSMFdkeTdvTDAxU1dCWGlQdDBwcURjOGFXcXM2WmQyWnZwTm1pMGZtTFZIblZuQ1ZGYVMycUgyOVZQMDhQMWFOaFRyLTUyNU9BQ3dtVzlILVE2d05aYXRXNUZhcnNCVHBfMEx3TERKdU1ROGtlcVVFT0dMWVk4YzJfaE5wV2s5ZFNULUVCQ0Q5cUktZ2RGOERQRkExRC1RVVA2MmQ4QjNSUWdqYlhCRFFpVnfSAdcBQVVfeXFMT2RsMzFtcHk3OXdUQmNpaE1icV9SbVNTbnNHQjJwbjhQU0FlTWdrck1WXzFxVkNfUmRHbUU4dkRpRlFMQUlnLS1qREszTkpoZkV5enQ5aU1lUVJDZEdJMmdRV2ZVX0NWWm5zcDdDS0R0OFZHVFQ3RlJ2RkY3eFJRb0lST1pXeGxNQ3FlSWNtT2FyYlRuTVNROHBmNVZzeE5WQjJ5MExjMHV1WGI4YlJ4ZEFEWGVoWG5GU201ckhLdTFoQzItTjNHV2dZRVRvQzlsUEp2cXdKbnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:46:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah on bed rest, no clarity on injury diagnosis; unlikely to be rushed back as Champions Trophy fate bleak - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah on bed rest, no clarity on injury diagnosis; unlikely to be rushed back as Champions Trophy fate bleak</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-77_1736942039641_1736942053685.jpg" alt="India's Jasprit Bumrah prepares to bowl on day two of the fifth Test match between Australia and India at the Sydney Cricket Ground on January 4(AFP)" title="India's Jasprit Bumrah prepares to bowl on day two of the fifth Test match between Australia and India at the Sydney Cricket Ground on January 4(AFP)"><figcaption>India's Jasprit Bumrah prepares to bowl on day two of the fifth Test match between Australia and India at the Sydney Cricket Ground on January 4(AFP)</figcaption><p>Uncertainty surrounds Jasprit Bumrah's participation in the upcoming Champions Trophy tournament as he has been advised bed rest with no clarity on his injury diagnosis following back spasms during the Sydney Test match against Australia.</p><ul><li>Bumrah is currently on bed rest to aid recovery from back spasms.</li><li>A report suggests he may report to BCCI's Centre of Excellence in Bengaluru.</li><li>The BCCI has not provided an official update on the severity of his injury.</li><li>Selectors are awaiting the final medical report on Bumrah before finalizing the squad.</li></ul><blockquote>"Bed rest doesn't sound good. I hope it's not a disc bulge or a muscle swelling which is of a higher grade."</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical as Bumrah's health will determine his availability for the Champions Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-on-bed-rest-no-clarity-on-injury-diagnosis-unlikely-to-be-rushed-back-as-champions-trophy-fate-bleak-101736941933765.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-on-bed-rest-no-clarity-on-injury-diagnosis-unlikely-to-be-rushed-back-as-champions-trophy-fate-bleak-101736941933765.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pant available for Delhi's next Ranji Trophy game, but DDCA 'haven't heard from Kohli' - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rishabh Pant Confirmed for Delhi's Next Ranji Trophy Match, Uncertainty Surrounds Virat Kohli</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2023 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p>
<p>Rishabh Pant is available for Delhi's next Ranji Trophy match, while the participation of Virat Kohli remains unclear.</p>
<ul>
<li>Rishabh Pant last played a Ranji Trophy match in the 2017-2018 season.</li>
<li>Virat Kohli has not played in the Ranji Trophy since 2012.</li>
<li>Both players have been named in Delhi's list of probables for the season.</li>
<li>DDCA secretary Ashok Sharma confirmed Pant's availability for the match against Saurashtra starting January 23.</li>
<li>Sharma indicated that Kohli has not confirmed his participation.</li>
<li>Former players advocate for India's Test stars to return to domestic cricket for form recovery.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Yes, Pant has confirmed his availability for next Ranji game and will join the squad in Rajkot directly,” - Ashok Sharma</blockquote>
<p>As Delhi sits fourth in Group D with 14 points from five matches, the outcome of these games will be crucial for the remaining season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/rishabh-pant-available-for-delhis-next-ranji-trophy-game-but-ddca-havent-heard-from-virat-kohli-1469103</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/rishabh-pant-available-for-delhis-next-ranji-trophy-game-but-ddca-havent-heard-from-virat-kohli-1469103</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:20:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Match officials announced for Test series against West Indies - PCB]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Match officials announced for Test series against West Indies</h1><p><strong>Multan, 15 January 2025</strong></p><p>Sri Lanka’s Ranjan Madugalle, a member of the ICC Elite Panel of Match Referees, will lead the playing control teams for the two ICC World Test Championship 2023-25 fixtures between hosts Pakistan and West Indies.</p><ul><li>The two Tests are scheduled to take place in Multan from 17-29 January.</li><li>In the first Test, the on-field umpires will be Australia’s Rodney Tucker and England’s Richard Kettleborough, with Paul Reiffel as the third umpire and Pakistan’s Faisal Khan Aafreedi as the fourth umpire.</li><li>For the second Test starting on 25 January, Paul Reiffel will join Rodney Tucker as on-field umpires, while Richard Kettleborough will be the third umpire and Pakistan’s Rashid Riaz Waqar will be the fourth umpire.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pcb.com.pk/press-release-detail/match-officials-announced-for-test-series-against-west-indies.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pcb.com.pk/press-release-detail/match-officials-announced-for-test-series-against-west-indies.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:18:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND-W vs IRE-W, 3rd ODI: India crosses 400 for first time, records highest total in W-ODIs - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND-W vs IRE-W, 3rd ODI: India crosses 400 for first time, records highest total in W-ODIs</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://ss-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/kh7i4w/article69100045.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/VIS_5035.JPG" alt="India Women cricketer Pratika Rawal in action.">
<figcaption>File Photo: India Women cricketer Pratika Rawal in action. | Photo Credit: VIJAY SONEJI/ The Hindu</figcaption>
<p>In a historic match against Ireland, India achieved its highest-ever total in women’s ODIs, crossing the 400-run milestone for the first time with a score of 435/5.</p>
<ul>
  <li>India scored 435 runs, surpassing the previous record of 370 runs set earlier in the series.</li>
  <li>Pratika Rawal scored her first international century with 154 runs off 129 balls.</li>
  <li>Smriti Mandhana scored 135 runs off 80 balls, setting a record for the fastest century by an Indian woman.</li>
  <li>India previously scored 358 runs against Ireland in 2017, which was their highest total before this match.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"India posted its highest-ever total in women’s ODIs during the third 50-over game against Ireland, crossing the 400-run mark."</blockquote>
<p>India's achievement represents a significant milestone in women's cricket, marking their entrance into the elite club of teams that have scored over 400 runs in an ODI.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/womens-cricket/india-highest-total-record-odi-score-400-smriti-mandhana-pratika-rawal-news/article69100022.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/womens-cricket/india-highest-total-record-odi-score-400-smriti-mandhana-pratika-rawal-news/article69100022.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:13:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sania Mirza vs Sara Tendulkar: Look at the educational qualification of Shoaib Malik's ex-wife and Sachin Tendulkar's daughter - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sania Mirza vs Sara Tendulkar: Look at the educational qualification of Shoaib Malik's ex-wife and Sachin Tendulkar's daughter</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/sania-mirza-vs-sara-tendulkar-look-at-the-educational-qualification-of-shoaib-maliks-ex-wife-and-sachin-tendulkars-daughter-202501-1736942664.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Sania Mirza vs Sara Tendulkar">
<figcaption>Image credit: Instagram</figcaption>
<p>This article explores the educational qualifications of two prominent figures, Sania Mirza, the ex-wife of cricketer Shoaib Malik, and Sara Tendulkar, the daughter of cricketing legend Sachin Tendulkar.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sania Mirza attended Nasr School in Hyderabad and graduated from St. Mary's College.</li>
<li>She received an honorary Doctor of Letters degree.</li>
<li>Sara Tendulkar studied at Dhirubhai Ambani International School and later moved to London for further education.</li>
<li>Sara is motivated by her mother’s career in healthcare and has been admitted to London Medical College.</li>
<li>In terms of net worth, Sania's is approximately $26 million while Sara's net worth is estimated between Rs 50 lakh to Rs 1 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Sania Mirza boasts a remarkable net worth of $26 million, generating an annual income of Rs 25 crore.”</blockquote>
<p>The educational journeys of both women highlight their aspirations and achievements in their respective fields.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/sania-mirza-vs-sara-tendulkar-look-at-the-educational-qualification-of-shoaib-malik-ex-wife-and-sachin-tendulkar-daughter-420161/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/sania-mirza-vs-sara-tendulkar-look-at-the-educational-qualification-of-shoaib-malik-ex-wife-and-sachin-tendulkar-daughter-420161/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:13:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google’s Pichai Joins Tech CEOs in Bids for London Cricket Team - Bloomberg]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Google’s CEO Pichai Bids for London Cricket Team</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p><p>Alphabet Inc. Chief Executive Officer Sundar Pichai is reported to be joining Silicon Valley executives in a bid to acquire a London-based cricket team.</p><ul><li>The consortium is bidding over £80 million ($97 million).</li><li>The potential teams are the Oval Invincibles or London Spirit.</li><li>Both teams participate in The Hundred, a tournament gaining popularity among younger audiences.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Hundred is pulling in younger fans and more families.”</blockquote><p>This bid reflects tech executives' increasing interest in sports franchises as a way to engage with diverse audiences and capitalize on emerging markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-01-15/google-s-pichai-joins-tech-ceos-in-bids-for-london-cricket-team</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-01-15/google-s-pichai-joins-tech-ceos-in-bids-for-london-cricket-team</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>