<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:23:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 15:23:26 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir Blames Sarfaraz Khan For Dressing Room Leaks During BGT: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Accuses Sarfaraz Khan of Dressing Room Leaks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='Sarfaraz Khan (PTI Photo)'><figcaption>Sarfaraz Khan (PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>Gautam Gambhir has reportedly accused Sarfaraz Khan of leaking information from the Indian dressing room during the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p><ul><li>Gambhir believes Khan disclosed details about his speech after India's defeat in the fourth Test.</li><li>Khan did not participate in the Test series despite a strong previous performance.</li><li>Concerns about the dressing room dynamics and the impact on Khan's career were raised.</li><li>Gambhir emphasized the need for honesty within the team and criticized the media hype.</li><li>The report highlights ongoing pressure on Gambhir and the team's struggles in recent months.</li></ul><blockquote>“Debates between coach and player should remain in the dressing room. Stern words.” - Gautam Gambhir</blockquote><p>Overall, this incident raises questions about team dynamics and the implications for player reputations and careers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/gautam-gambhir-blames-sarfaraz-khan-for-dressing-room-leaks-during-bgt-report-9189902.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/gautam-gambhir-blames-sarfaraz-khan-for-dressing-room-leaks-during-bgt-report-9189902.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:02:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ILT20 2025: Match 6, ADKR vs SWR Match Prediction – Who will win today’s ILT20 match between ADKR vs SWR? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ILT20 2025: Match 6, ADKR vs SWR Match Prediction</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736843554091_image_2025_01_14T08_29_54_926Z.png" alt="Match Prediction Image" width="700" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Predicted outcome of the match between ADKR and SWR.</figcaption><p>The Abu Dhabi Knight Riders (ADKR) face the Sharjah Warriorz (SWR) in Match 6 of the ILT20 2025 series. ADKR aims to rebound from their first match loss, while SWR looks to continue their winning momentum.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>ADKR lost their opening match against Desert Vipers.</li><li>SWR won their first match against Gulf Giants by three wickets.</li><li>The match will take place at Sheikh Zayed Stadium in Abu Dhabi at 8:00 PM IST.</li><li>ADKR's probable best batter is Phil Salt; SWR's is Tim Southee for bowling.</li><li>Pitch is favorable for batting with some assistance for spinners.</li></ul><blockquote>Prediction: The defending team is likely to win the match.</blockquote><p>Overall, the match is highly anticipated as both teams look to blaze ahead in the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/ilt20-2025-match-6-adkr-vs-swr-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-ilt20-match-between-adkr-vs-swr/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/ilt20-2025-match-6-adkr-vs-swr-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-ilt20-match-between-adkr-vs-swr/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3rd ODI: Smriti Mandhana's blazing 70-ball century powers India to record 304-run win - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/3rd-odi-smriti-mandhanas-blazing-70-ball-century-powers-india-to-record-304-run-win/articleshow/117268821.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/3rd-odi-smriti-mandhanas-blazing-70-ball-century-powers-india-to-record-304-run-win/articleshow/117268821.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3rd ODI: Smriti Mandhana's blazing 70-ball century powers India to record 304-run win - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/3rd-odi-smriti-mandhanas-blazing-70-ball-century-powers-india-to-record-304-run-win/articleshow/117268821.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/3rd-odi-smriti-mandhanas-blazing-70-ball-century-powers-india-to-record-304-run-win/articleshow/117268821.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah on bed rest, no clarity on injury diagnosis; unlikely to be rushed back as Champions Trophy fate bleak - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah on bed rest, no clarity on injury diagnosis; unlikely to be rushed back as Champions Trophy fate bleak</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-77_1736942039641_1736942053685.jpg" alt="India's Jasprit Bumrah prepares to bowl on day two of the fifth Test match between Australia and India at the Sydney Cricket Ground on January 4(AFP)" title="India's Jasprit Bumrah prepares to bowl on day two of the fifth Test match between Australia and India at the Sydney Cricket Ground on January 4(AFP)"><figcaption>India's Jasprit Bumrah prepares to bowl on day two of the fifth Test match between Australia and India at the Sydney Cricket Ground on January 4(AFP)</figcaption><p>Uncertainty surrounds Jasprit Bumrah's participation in the upcoming Champions Trophy tournament as he has been advised bed rest with no clarity on his injury diagnosis following back spasms during the Sydney Test match against Australia.</p><ul><li>Bumrah is currently on bed rest to aid recovery from back spasms.</li><li>A report suggests he may report to BCCI's Centre of Excellence in Bengaluru.</li><li>The BCCI has not provided an official update on the severity of his injury.</li><li>Selectors are awaiting the final medical report on Bumrah before finalizing the squad.</li></ul><blockquote>"Bed rest doesn't sound good. I hope it's not a disc bulge or a muscle swelling which is of a higher grade."</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical as Bumrah's health will determine his availability for the Champions Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-on-bed-rest-no-clarity-on-injury-diagnosis-unlikely-to-be-rushed-back-as-champions-trophy-fate-bleak-101736941933765.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-on-bed-rest-no-clarity-on-injury-diagnosis-unlikely-to-be-rushed-back-as-champions-trophy-fate-bleak-101736941933765.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:34:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Match officials announced for Test series against West Indies - PCB]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Match officials announced for Test series against West Indies</h1><p><strong>Multan, 15 January 2025</strong></p><p>Sri Lanka’s Ranjan Madugalle, a member of the ICC Elite Panel of Match Referees, will lead the playing control teams for the two ICC World Test Championship 2023-25 fixtures between hosts Pakistan and West Indies.</p><ul><li>The two Tests are scheduled to take place in Multan from 17-29 January.</li><li>In the first Test, the on-field umpires will be Australia’s Rodney Tucker and England’s Richard Kettleborough, with Paul Reiffel as the third umpire and Pakistan’s Faisal Khan Aafreedi as the fourth umpire.</li><li>For the second Test starting on 25 January, Paul Reiffel will join Rodney Tucker as on-field umpires, while Richard Kettleborough will be the third umpire and Pakistan’s Rashid Riaz Waqar will be the fourth umpire.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pcb.com.pk/press-release-detail/match-officials-announced-for-test-series-against-west-indies.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pcb.com.pk/press-release-detail/match-officials-announced-for-test-series-against-west-indies.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:18:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND-W vs IRE-W, 3rd ODI: India crosses 400 for first time, records highest total in W-ODIs - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IND-W vs IRE-W, 3rd ODI: India crosses 400 for first time, records highest total in W-ODIs</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://ss-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/kh7i4w/article69100045.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/VIS_5035.JPG" alt="India Women cricketer Pratika Rawal in action.">
<figcaption>File Photo: India Women cricketer Pratika Rawal in action. | Photo Credit: VIJAY SONEJI/ The Hindu</figcaption>
<p>In a historic match against Ireland, India achieved its highest-ever total in women’s ODIs, crossing the 400-run milestone for the first time with a score of 435/5.</p>
<ul>
  <li>India scored 435 runs, surpassing the previous record of 370 runs set earlier in the series.</li>
  <li>Pratika Rawal scored her first international century with 154 runs off 129 balls.</li>
  <li>Smriti Mandhana scored 135 runs off 80 balls, setting a record for the fastest century by an Indian woman.</li>
  <li>India previously scored 358 runs against Ireland in 2017, which was their highest total before this match.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"India posted its highest-ever total in women’s ODIs during the third 50-over game against Ireland, crossing the 400-run mark."</blockquote>
<p>India's achievement represents a significant milestone in women's cricket, marking their entrance into the elite club of teams that have scored over 400 runs in an ODI.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/womens-cricket/india-highest-total-record-odi-score-400-smriti-mandhana-pratika-rawal-news/article69100022.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/womens-cricket/india-highest-total-record-odi-score-400-smriti-mandhana-pratika-rawal-news/article69100022.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:13:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sania Mirza vs Sara Tendulkar: Look at the educational qualification of Shoaib Malik's ex-wife and Sachin Tendulkar's daughter - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sania Mirza vs Sara Tendulkar: Look at the educational qualification of Shoaib Malik's ex-wife and Sachin Tendulkar's daughter</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/sania-mirza-vs-sara-tendulkar-look-at-the-educational-qualification-of-shoaib-maliks-ex-wife-and-sachin-tendulkars-daughter-202501-1736942664.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Sania Mirza vs Sara Tendulkar">
<figcaption>Image credit: Instagram</figcaption>
<p>This article explores the educational qualifications of two prominent figures, Sania Mirza, the ex-wife of cricketer Shoaib Malik, and Sara Tendulkar, the daughter of cricketing legend Sachin Tendulkar.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sania Mirza attended Nasr School in Hyderabad and graduated from St. Mary's College.</li>
<li>She received an honorary Doctor of Letters degree.</li>
<li>Sara Tendulkar studied at Dhirubhai Ambani International School and later moved to London for further education.</li>
<li>Sara is motivated by her mother’s career in healthcare and has been admitted to London Medical College.</li>
<li>In terms of net worth, Sania's is approximately $26 million while Sara's net worth is estimated between Rs 50 lakh to Rs 1 crore.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Sania Mirza boasts a remarkable net worth of $26 million, generating an annual income of Rs 25 crore.”</blockquote>
<p>The educational journeys of both women highlight their aspirations and achievements in their respective fields.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/sania-mirza-vs-sara-tendulkar-look-at-the-educational-qualification-of-shoaib-malik-ex-wife-and-sachin-tendulkar-daughter-420161/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/sania-mirza-vs-sara-tendulkar-look-at-the-educational-qualification-of-shoaib-malik-ex-wife-and-sachin-tendulkar-daughter-420161/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:13:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google’s Pichai Joins Tech CEOs in Bids for London Cricket Team - Bloomberg]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Google’s CEO Pichai Bids for London Cricket Team</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p><p>Alphabet Inc. Chief Executive Officer Sundar Pichai is reported to be joining Silicon Valley executives in a bid to acquire a London-based cricket team.</p><ul><li>The consortium is bidding over £80 million ($97 million).</li><li>The potential teams are the Oval Invincibles or London Spirit.</li><li>Both teams participate in The Hundred, a tournament gaining popularity among younger audiences.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Hundred is pulling in younger fans and more families.”</blockquote><p>This bid reflects tech executives' increasing interest in sports franchises as a way to engage with diverse audiences and capitalize on emerging markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-01-15/google-s-pichai-joins-tech-ceos-in-bids-for-london-cricket-team</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-01-15/google-s-pichai-joins-tech-ceos-in-bids-for-london-cricket-team</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND-W vs IRE-W Live cricket score today: IND-W vs IRE-W Live scorecard, IND-W vs IRE-W Live ball by ball commentary - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxQRXZJN0hWbzYzSHlneHNMR2psSGI4aFlhOUNmVEMzVmJrNmE2bkhucDdEX0s4Szh4TEZrZUxmSWZvaFN4RXVQek1laWtEa2xxWmFuNVdXZmtQb2FFMTc2Z0VtSkgydk1uZjhuX1lZMVEyMkRXX2hHZk5OTG5MbE8wQjVYZWZwUjlqQ3VwX1duY3Y2bWo0cjdNWUxBcjJyejMwZm9UaDhoeUQ4d2FqRmpOU1lKQ0dQNWx2ZElYYzJyd2F4a2cxcmNrejlOWVh3Q1NiRXA1RGMwWkR1U21xYUNKU2dtWmdIM2haaTdCcnJPTGlVaUk5WU5zX05n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxQRXZJN0hWbzYzSHlneHNMR2psSGI4aFlhOUNmVEMzVmJrNmE2bkhucDdEX0s4Szh4TEZrZUxmSWZvaFN4RXVQek1laWtEa2xxWmFuNVdXZmtQb2FFMTc2Z0VtSkgydk1uZjhuX1lZMVEyMkRXX2hHZk5OTG5MbE8wQjVYZWZwUjlqQ3VwX1duY3Y2bWo0cjdNWUxBcjJyejMwZm9UaDhoeUQ4d2FqRmpOU1lKQ0dQNWx2ZElYYzJyd2F4a2cxcmNrejlOWVh3Q1NiRXA1RGMwWkR1U21xYUNKU2dtWmdIM2haaTdCcnJPTGlVaUk5WU5zX05n?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:47:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Doesn't Have Tattoos": BCCI Selectors Slammed By India Great For Ignoring Star With Fantastic Avera.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Doesn't Have Tattoos: BCCI Selectors Slammed By India Great For Ignoring Star With Fantastic Average Of 664</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/v118ruv8_karun-nair-x_625x300_12_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Karun Nair" /><figcaption>Karun Nair, featured in recent discussions regarding team selection.</figcaption><p>Veteran cricketer Karun Nair is making a strong case for his return to the Indian cricket team following an impressive performance in the Vijay Hazare Trophy.</p><ul><li>Nair scored 664 runs in six matches, including five centuries, with a strike rate of 120.07.</li><li>Experts and fans are advocating for his inclusion in the national team.</li><li>Former India spinner Harbhajan Singh criticized the selectors for overlooking Nair's statistics.</li><li>Harbhajan highlighted inconsistencies in selection criteria, pointing out that established players with poor form are being prioritized.</li><li>Nair's previous dropping from the team after a triple century remains a point of contention.</li></ul><blockquote>"When they are scoring runs, you need to play him, right? He doesn't have tattoos, doesn't wear fancy clothes, is that the reason you're not picking him?" - Harbhajan Singh</blockquote><p>The article brings attention to the ongoing debate around selection criteria in Indian cricket, emphasizing the need for a fair evaluation based on performance rather than appearances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/doesnt-have-tattoos-bcci-selectors-slammed-for-ignoring-star-with-fantastic-average-of-664-7479482</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/doesnt-have-tattoos-bcci-selectors-slammed-for-ignoring-star-with-fantastic-average-of-664-7479482</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:36:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah on bed rest, will not be rushed back - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah on Bed Rest, Will Not Be Rushed Back</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Indian cricketer Jasprit Bumrah is currently on bed rest as he focuses on recovery. The team management has confirmed that there is no rush for his return to the game.</p><ul><li>Bumrah is recovering from a recent injury.</li><li>Medical team advises patience for a full recovery.</li><li>Team management ensures proper protocols are followed.</li></ul><blockquote>"It's crucial to prioritize health over a quick return to play."</blockquote><p>This approach aims to prevent any further injury, supporting Bumrah's long-term career.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/jasprit-bumrah-on-bed-rest-will-not-be-rushed-back/articleshow/117266492.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/jasprit-bumrah-on-bed-rest-will-not-be-rushed-back/articleshow/117266492.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Vince quits first-class cricket to take up PSL deal - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxPRW9Pck5VbjRuTEpxXzdwZFNxdVo0SDJlV0JVMUVzY05qNkJneENYSGRRZFhhVmxnU191UlVVVEprdmVvZlgxcDFyUlZPbUp4ajl3YnFZcXVBUmNGT0ZBTWptME90WXhZamN5WUZVNjZhNjdzanF0ZVNqcG42U3VmLWw3UXZWaFlEc2d2LXNMUVQ5TUdLbUlXeGxQS3V4T1d5XzBLamQ4WdIBuAFBVV95cUxPOTNfMmF6R2tXTjMxUkV5dFhUQ25Vd0RWSkl0NF9YbmVWaHRFOUxPNktSemMwSHBqWUxDQ2J6RkV4YUJmaVE3ODdtZmc5amhqMElRVHJDbzhmZWtrYVJuaUxXREN6ZEdQbm9LdzYwcVhrWmNDV2J2Ui1iSEhfcXN0LVplT1BEdGVxSzB1NFV2X2Q3RVctTW1ZbUNpdllWaUhzNDZQaDY2akNFTnpuY0JwV2FXdkRQdEpD?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipwFBVV95cUxPRW9Pck5VbjRuTEpxXzdwZFNxdVo0SDJlV0JVMUVzY05qNkJneENYSGRRZFhhVmxnU191UlVVVEprdmVvZlgxcDFyUlZPbUp4ajl3YnFZcXVBUmNGT0ZBTWptME90WXhZamN5WUZVNjZhNjdzanF0ZVNqcG42U3VmLWw3UXZWaFlEc2d2LXNMUVQ5TUdLbUlXeGxQS3V4T1d5XzBLamQ4WdIBuAFBVV95cUxPOTNfMmF6R2tXTjMxUkV5dFhUQ25Vd0RWSkl0NF9YbmVWaHRFOUxPNktSemMwSHBqWUxDQ2J6RkV4YUJmaVE3ODdtZmc5amhqMElRVHJDbzhmZWtrYVJuaUxXREN6ZEdQbm9LdzYwcVhrWmNDV2J2Ui1iSEhfcXN0LVplT1BEdGVxSzB1NFV2X2Q3RVctTW1ZbUNpdllWaUhzNDZQaDY2akNFTnpuY0JwV2FXdkRQdEpD?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid BCCI Scrutiny, 'Strict' Gautam Gambhir's Rift With Support Staff Member Revealed: Report - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxORzdsNy1WWFVaS1h6OUwyQW5Gb0M2c1JybW1MS3ZTRXlqSHpsZzA5MXo3dXU1RDZWZHliaGhNQ0VHa3lNRW5wTGZsOExwcjJHUTFkazM0MExleEZQMVJka3haQUMwc1ZXYVFWbWdFcVpMN1gtbHhLRTJnZjB3VkJpOGEtbGVZZFFQZVJJZHhBTWdkUVRVYTlXVVl0VjlaX2pMSlFvbUI3MjAtRDU3TDZkc3B3VDkxWVAyZUhrcS1Ua2VydnNtWEQ0TkE5NklTZmpQcjBiWE1SUGlUemJaU0czYWRnOGZyOTJVZUljaHhrOGRPZ9IB-gFBVV95cUxORzM4V1Voc0luR1VJSUNlSmRrbmpsdGlBdEg5TnJFTUtxWFpyN3FleDFBYXZ2dV9EbGJnNUhFWVdiWEZQVzNqWlhORElSUHQ2MzlkRDNQcW1PWEtrbXFxRG9DVnprWE9La1I3b2hObm9XNm5GX0c0Z3lEN01nNWV3Ni1uOXNmNG45Wng2Y1BRZUpCN1MxckltMHFOMFhIMXlUT1RIa3FLNmx2dENQR1BsV2wzMUxTZUdBaXRYZDJUcFRsNk85bnRjQVN0ZkhhU0pRYXd4SEp5QkU0elpOMHhscDR0OWNMQWRVYnU2SV9WNGhqTTZVTVlYSWJR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8gFBVV95cUxORzdsNy1WWFVaS1h6OUwyQW5Gb0M2c1JybW1MS3ZTRXlqSHpsZzA5MXo3dXU1RDZWZHliaGhNQ0VHa3lNRW5wTGZsOExwcjJHUTFkazM0MExleEZQMVJka3haQUMwc1ZXYVFWbWdFcVpMN1gtbHhLRTJnZjB3VkJpOGEtbGVZZFFQZVJJZHhBTWdkUVRVYTlXVVl0VjlaX2pMSlFvbUI3MjAtRDU3TDZkc3B3VDkxWVAyZUhrcS1Ua2VydnNtWEQ0TkE5NklTZmpQcjBiWE1SUGlUemJaU0czYWRnOGZyOTJVZUljaHhrOGRPZ9IB-gFBVV95cUxORzM4V1Voc0luR1VJSUNlSmRrbmpsdGlBdEg5TnJFTUtxWFpyN3FleDFBYXZ2dV9EbGJnNUhFWVdiWEZQVzNqWlhORElSUHQ2MzlkRDNQcW1PWEtrbXFxRG9DVnprWE9La1I3b2hObm9XNm5GX0c0Z3lEN01nNWV3Ni1uOXNmNG45Wng2Y1BRZUpCN1MxckltMHFOMFhIMXlUT1RIa3FLNmx2dENQR1BsV2wzMUxTZUdBaXRYZDJUcFRsNk85bnRjQVN0ZkhhU0pRYXd4SEp5QkU0elpOMHhscDR0OWNMQWRVYnU2SV9WNGhqTTZVTVlYSWJR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 11:01:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[D Gukesh gets teased by Viswanathan Anand's wife for marriage in Vidit Gujrathi's pre-wedding: ‘We can photoshop…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxOdkV2Zk5yc1NFQWJUWjNVOHRMemFZSnZjRU03ODJRRGNKQ0ljbkp4R3JnQjU5anpLRWNFM19vWjgyTTRsYkZLWDJaSUxsbTJDdDZJRFNnQ0FsbXMxRlU0UGQ5amp0TnlhRG4wRXdDSHZ2RmpYY2VXSVhaNzZHaU9sMnpydTljSG14SXlDaFFrZGdEemFQX05IZ1BTOWNSbHVqSE1tUEdweUpzSFJBSkpZOFpLT0VMUUg3OXVpOEV3UTBURjl6a2dCSWQtYTl6VE5VVkNzZ01YdS1DcFFJUVdVcHVnbXJlN3daZ1g2RDhvaGlva05JQ2JBdkdxd21ielBaTFgzNNIBigJBVV95cUxQZFRIMnZLMkl2c0lieHBoSjA3UzliZmNsZXZNSDNmNFJldXVrcmJkc2hGalN4UkpNLWJROW9zeVRIVHh6bWhKTmxSNjdMdDJTcVVoZmVEbVRvOWUySEc2RlFyNkN1OHBwOVhiOHh1T1NGckVTX2JMVVVZcFdka0JMbGVBVU5aYTdGUElEUzI2djJ4VzlxUnVzQkdXOEJHSHp1czg5SGIybnd4RVU2MXlrT0wwVmhfNE5hX3BwY0Z4OW5QOVFxLUZIdmQxTGMxQndST0NncGRKLTlvZUk2ZjQzdkhzTV9kcUs1dXU4ZkhBX1Jia3dsZkJmbkFuVUc1SGczRzZNUDlBVXppUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAJBVV95cUxOdkV2Zk5yc1NFQWJUWjNVOHRMemFZSnZjRU03ODJRRGNKQ0ljbkp4R3JnQjU5anpLRWNFM19vWjgyTTRsYkZLWDJaSUxsbTJDdDZJRFNnQ0FsbXMxRlU0UGQ5amp0TnlhRG4wRXdDSHZ2RmpYY2VXSVhaNzZHaU9sMnpydTljSG14SXlDaFFrZGdEemFQX05IZ1BTOWNSbHVqSE1tUEdweUpzSFJBSkpZOFpLT0VMUUg3OXVpOEV3UTBURjl6a2dCSWQtYTl6VE5VVkNzZ01YdS1DcFFJUVdVcHVnbXJlN3daZ1g2RDhvaGlva05JQ2JBdkdxd21ielBaTFgzNNIBigJBVV95cUxQZFRIMnZLMkl2c0lieHBoSjA3UzliZmNsZXZNSDNmNFJldXVrcmJkc2hGalN4UkpNLWJROW9zeVRIVHh6bWhKTmxSNjdMdDJTcVVoZmVEbVRvOWUySEc2RlFyNkN1OHBwOVhiOHh1T1NGckVTX2JMVVVZcFdka0JMbGVBVU5aYTdGUElEUzI2djJ4VzlxUnVzQkdXOEJHSHp1czg5SGIybnd4RVU2MXlrT0wwVmhfNE5hX3BwY0Z4OW5QOVFxLUZIdmQxTGMxQndST0NncGRKLTlvZUk2ZjQzdkhzTV9kcUs1dXU4ZkhBX1Jia3dsZkJmbkFuVUc1SGczRzZNUDlBVXppUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 10:57:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Hyper Kiu Ho Jata Hai ": Indian Stars Involved In Argument During Training. Video Re-Surfaces - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>"Hyper <i>Kiu Ho Jata Hai</i>": Indian Stars Involved In Argument During Training. Video Re-Surfaces</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/on7uejso_tilak-varma-riyan-parag_625x300_15_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Tilak Varma and Riyan Parag arguing during training"><figcaption>A screen grab from the viral video showing argument between Indian cricket team stars. © X/Twitter</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team is in a rebuilding phase as they prepare for the T20 series against England starting January 22, 2025. An old video has resurfaced showing an argument between Tilak Varma and Riyan Parag during a training session, highlighting the team's dynamic and competition.</p><ul><li>The video captures a humorous exchange during a training session.</li><li>Tilak Varma claims to have dismissed Nicholas Pooran, which prompts Riyan Parag to tease him about the team's performance.</li><li>Tilak Varma recently achieved a remarkable feat by scoring three consecutive T20 centuries.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tilak said: 'You know I got Nicholas Pooran's wicket,' to which Riyan retorted, 'Yeah, oh after losing the game!'”</blockquote><p>This lively interaction among players showcases the competitive spirit and camaraderie within the team as they prepare for upcoming matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/hyper-kiu-ho-jata-hai-indian-stars-riyan-parag-tilak-varma-involved-in-heated-argument-video-surfaces-7479186</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/hyper-kiu-ho-jata-hai-indian-stars-riyan-parag-tilak-varma-involved-in-heated-argument-video-surfaces-7479186</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 10:36:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pep Guardiola's close friend reveals reason for breakup of his marriage - Metro.co.uk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://metro.co.uk/2025/01/15/pep-guardiolas-close-friend-reveals-reason-breakup-30-year-marriage-22363884/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://metro.co.uk/2025/01/15/pep-guardiolas-close-friend-reveals-reason-breakup-30-year-marriage-22363884/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 10:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Temba Bavuma urges ICC to end 'disparity' among teams: 'England played 22 Tests last year, South Africa just 12' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Temba Bavuma urges ICC to end 'disparity' among teams: 'England played 22 Tests last year, South Africa just 12'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> February 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/CRICKET-RSA-PAK-81_1736933693929_1736933708071.jpg" alt="Temba Bavuma has led South Africa admirably(AFP)" title="Temba Bavuma has led South Africa admirably(AFP)">
<figcaption>Temba Bavuma has led South Africa admirably(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>South Africa's cricket team, led by Temba Bavuma, has made a remarkable resurgence, having progressed to the World Test Championship (WTC) final despite facing criticism over their previous performances. Bavuma emphasizes the need for the International Cricket Council (ICC) to address disparities in the number of Tests played by different nations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>South Africa lost 0-2 to New Zealand in February 2024, raising questions about their capabilities.</li>
  <li>Under Bavuma's leadership, the team has won 7 consecutive Tests, securing their place in the WTC final against Australia.</li>
  <li>Bavuma has scored over 500 runs in his last four Tests and expresses confidence in his form and the team's potential.</li>
  <li>He advocates for more Test matches, noting that South Africa played only 12 Tests last year compared to England's 22.</li>
  <li>Bavuma acknowledges their underdog status but believes in the team's strength despite challenges.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I think England played about 22 Tests last year. We played 12, that’s almost 50 percent.”</blockquote>
<p>This event highlights the need for reform in international cricket scheduling and aims to elevate the visibility and competitiveness of Test cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/temba-bavuma-urges-icc-to-end-disparity-among-teams-england-played-22-tests-last-year-south-africa-just-12-101736933507834.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/temba-bavuma-urges-icc-to-end-disparity-among-teams-england-played-22-tests-last-year-south-africa-just-12-101736933507834.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:43:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['No tattoos, doesn't wear fancy clothes...': Harbhajan Singh launches unfiltered rant over BCCI 'ignoring' Karun Nair - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'No tattoos, doesn't wear fancy clothes...': Harbhajan Singh launches unfiltered rant over BCCI 'ignoring' Karun Nair</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/MixCollage-15-Jan-2025-03-09-PM-7736_1736933957841_1736933963229.jpg" alt="Karun Nair during the Vijay Hazare Trophy; Harbhajan Singh(X/Files)" title="Karun Nair during the Vijay Hazare Trophy; Harbhajan Singh(X/Files)">
<figcaption>Karun Nair during the Vijay Hazare Trophy; Harbhajan Singh(X/Files)</figcaption>
<p>Harbhajan Singh expresses frustration over BCCI's continued neglect of Karun Nair, who has showcased exemplary performance in the Vijay Hazare Trophy.</p>
<ul>
<li>Karun Nair scored 664 runs in six innings, with five centuries and a strike rate of 120.07.</li>
<li>BCCI's selectors appear to overlook players performing well in domestic cricket.</li>
<li>Nair had previously scored a triple century in Test cricket but has not been picked for recent team selections.</li>
<li>Harbhajan criticizes the unfair selection criteria in Indian cricket.</li>
<li>Nair continues to perform well in multiple formats and leagues, including first-class cricket and county cricket.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Different rules for different people… that shouldn't be the way. When they are scoring runs, you need to play him, right?” - Harbhajan Singh</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the ongoing disregard for players like Nair raises questions about the transparency and fairness of the selection process in Indian cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/no-tattoos-doesnt-wear-fancy-clothes-harbhajan-singh-launches-unfiltered-rant-over-bcci-ignoring-karun-nair-101736928679071.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/no-tattoos-doesnt-wear-fancy-clothes-harbhajan-singh-launches-unfiltered-rant-over-bcci-ignoring-karun-nair-101736928679071.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:39:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Novak Djokovic on the challenge of playing an up-and-coming opponent | ATP Tour | Tennis - ATP Tour]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Novak Djokovic on Overcoming Young Challengers at the Australian Open</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> ATP Tour</p><img src="/-/media/images/news/2025/01/15/09/11/djokovic-faria-australian-open-2025-wednesday.jpg" alt="Novak Djokovic and Jaime Faria at the net after their Australian Open second-round clash."><figcaption>Novak Djokovic and Jaime Faria at the net after their Australian Open second-round clash.</figcaption><p>Novak Djokovic shares insights after his second-round victory against Jaime Faria at the Australian Open, reflecting on the challenges of facing rising tennis stars.</p><ul><li>Djokovic defeated Faria 6-1, 6-7(4), 6-3, 6-2 to reach the third round.</li><li>The match showcased Djokovic's experience against a young opponent, requiring mental focus to counter Faria's aggressive play.</li><li>Djokovic highlighted the unpredictability of playing newer players who are eager and have nothing to lose.</li><li>This victory marked Djokovic's 430th Grand Slam match win, setting a new all-time record.</li><li>Looking ahead, Djokovic praised the young talent's potential, particularly referencing Brazilian player Joao Fonseca.</li></ul><blockquote>“He’s done it 👊 @DjokerNole wins the battle against Faria in exactly 3 hours to advance in Melbourne!” — ATP Tour</blockquote><p>Overall, Djokovic's experience continues to shine as he navigates the emerging talent in the sport, expressing optimism for the future of tennis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.atptour.com/en/news/djokovic-australian-open-2025-wednesday-reaction</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atptour.com/en/news/djokovic-australian-open-2025-wednesday-reaction</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:20:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pant available for Delhi's next Ranji Trophy game, but DDCA 'haven't heard from Kohli' - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rishabh Pant Available for Delhi's Next Ranji Trophy Match, Uncertainty Surrounds Virat Kohli</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date not specified <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p>
<p>Rishabh Pant has confirmed his availability for Delhi's next Ranji Trophy game against Saurashtra starting January 23. Meanwhile, there is no clarity on Virat Kohli's participation despite being named in the list of probables.</p>
<ul>
<li>Pant last played a Ranji match in the 2017-2018 season.</li>
<li>Kohli has not played in the Ranji Trophy since 2012.</li>
<li>DDCA secretary Ashok Sharma mentioned they have not heard from Kohli about his availability.</li>
<li>Pant will join the squad directly in Rajkot.</li>
<li>Former players have urged current players, including Kohli and Rohit Sharma, to engage in domestic cricket to find form.</li>
<li>Delhi currently ranks fourth in Group D of the Ranji Trophy with 14 points from five matches.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Yes, Pant has confirmed his availability for next Ranji game and will join the squad in Rajkot directly,” said Ashok Sharma.</blockquote>
<p>The situation remains uncertain for Kohli, who is under pressure due to his recent struggles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/rishabh-pant-available-for-delhis-next-ranji-trophy-game-but-ddca-havent-heard-from-virat-kohli-1469103</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/rishabh-pant-available-for-delhis-next-ranji-trophy-game-but-ddca-havent-heard-from-virat-kohli-1469103</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:19:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pratika Rawal 154, Smriti Mandhana 135, India 435/5 as records tumble like pack of cards against Ireland - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India registered their highest total (435/5) in ODIs, riding on centuries from Pratika Rawal (154) and Smriti Mandhana (135) against Ireland.</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> Jan 15, 2025, Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/mandhana_pratika_1736931355732_1736931362945.jpg" alt="Smriti Mandhana and Pratika Rawal(BCCI Women)" title="Smriti Mandhana and Pratika Rawal(BCCI Women)"><figcaption>Smriti Mandhana and Pratika Rawal(BCCI Women)</figcaption><p>India registered their highest total in Women's ODIs, achieving 435/5 in the last ODI match against Ireland, following a previous record of 370/3. This match marked significant records for both Pratika Rawal and Smriti Mandhana.</p><ul><li>Pratika Rawal scored 154, while Smriti Mandhana scored 135, both contributing significantly to India’s total.</li><li>Mandhana reached the fastest century by an Indian woman in just 70 balls.</li><li>This total is India's highest in ODIs, and it ranks fourth in the history of Women's ODIs.</li><li>India became the third team to surpass the 400-run mark in Women's ODIs.</li></ul><blockquote>“Mandhana's blistering knock, her fifth century in this format since the start of 2024, came to an end when she tried to play the lap shot off Orla Prendergast and was caught at fine leg.”</blockquote><p>The performance of these players not only sets a new benchmark for India but also enhances their stature in women's cricket internationally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/pratika-rawal-154-smriti-mandhana-135-india-435-5-as-records-tumble-like-pack-of-cards-against-ireland-101736931351508.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/pratika-rawal-154-smriti-mandhana-135-india-435-5-as-records-tumble-like-pack-of-cards-against-ireland-101736931351508.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:17:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unpaid wages, training boycott? ISL club Mohammedan SC clarify situation - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unpaid wages, training boycott? ISL club Mohammedan SC clarify situation</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not available <strong>Source:</strong> Not available</p>
<p>Mohammedan SC has addressed concerns regarding unpaid wages and a possible training boycott by its players amidst ongoing controversies.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The club has clarified that all player dues are being addressed and assured continued support for its athletes.</li>
  <li>Management emphasizes the importance of transparency and effective communication with the team.</li>
  <li>Players have been encouraged to continue regular training sessions and maintain focus on upcoming matches.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We are committed to resolving any issues our players face and ensuring they are prepared for the challenges ahead." - Mohammedan SC Management</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Mohammedan SC aims to foster a supportive environment for its players amidst financial concerns.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/football/top-stories/unpaid-wages-training-boycott-isl-club-mohammedan-sc-clarify-situation/articleshow/117261664.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/football/top-stories/unpaid-wages-training-boycott-isl-club-mohammedan-sc-clarify-situation/articleshow/117261664.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India women's cricket team break their own highest-ever ODI total record in just three days - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/435/5-india-create-their-biggest-odi-total-record-vs-ireland/articleshow/117262032.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/435/5-india-create-their-biggest-odi-total-record-vs-ireland/articleshow/117262032.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 09:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Extra ODI added to Australia's tour of Sri Lanka - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxPWENaTjRQZXZhMWRPY1JFSUZMRXZUTkVwLWxhLWY2dGVUVEI4RHJ0cUdsTjFWUGwybGdERXljYjY4LUVTa1VURVRhNjVYSVpXaUV1bndoU2VXUnd2TEt4bzNESGZlQm9fVmllOTJIZHcwY0xUOG5ybUtLVkNpVmJLT3FCblBUdEVjZEpyY3J5NzlEVWpoTFHSAacBQVVfeXFMT3ZtbXFqWjZxRkU0V1FUYmdIMXZucGstYjVycEJIWUhjdEFGa01aaWg0OWdvRGF1SG5QTDN6OThndVF1al8zczdtSzFya0VkMVhkX0RCaXhBcXp3NFBIejZwZ3dDM1pKUGNHckVibUJ0TEVlczA0ZTJCM0piNW9iY0Zob0tqaG1PSHZZdFpGVGc3WlkwQTc5dEpkNjJJRlVjalhaSjIwNUk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxPWENaTjRQZXZhMWRPY1JFSUZMRXZUTkVwLWxhLWY2dGVUVEI4RHJ0cUdsTjFWUGwybGdERXljYjY4LUVTa1VURVRhNjVYSVpXaUV1bndoU2VXUnd2TEt4bzNESGZlQm9fVmllOTJIZHcwY0xUOG5ybUtLVkNpVmJLT3FCblBUdEVjZEpyY3J5NzlEVWpoTFHSAacBQVVfeXFMT3ZtbXFqWjZxRkU0V1FUYmdIMXZucGstYjVycEJIWUhjdEFGa01aaWg0OWdvRGF1SG5QTDN6OThndVF1al8zczdtSzFya0VkMVhkX0RCaXhBcXp3NFBIejZwZ3dDM1pKUGNHckVibUJ0TEVlczA0ZTJCM0piNW9iY0Zob0tqaG1PSHZZdFpGVGc3WlkwQTc5dEpkNjJJRlVjalhaSjIwNUk?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:55:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manu Bhaker, Aman Sehrawat allegedly complain against deteriorating quality of Paris Olympics medals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Manu Bhaker and Aman Sehrawat Raise Concerns Over Quality of Paris Olympics Medals</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Olympic Medals" /><figcaption>Quality concerns raised by Indian Olympic athletes.</figcaption><p>Manu Bhaker and Aman Sehrawat have voiced their complaints regarding the deteriorating quality of the medals for the upcoming Paris Olympics.</p><ul><li>Both athletes have observed significant issues with the medal design.</li><li>Concerns have been raised about the materials used and their potential impact on Olympic standards.</li><li>The athletes are advocating for immediate action to ensure quality assurance.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are proud to represent India, and it's important that the medals reflect our values and standards." - Manu Bhaker</blockquote><p>The complaints highlight the need for rigorous quality checks as the Olympics approach, ensuring that athletes can compete under fair and respected conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/more-sports/others/manu-bhaker-aman-sehrawat-allegedly-complain-against-deteriorating-quality-of-paris-olympics-medals/articleshow/117260856.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/more-sports/others/manu-bhaker-aman-sehrawat-allegedly-complain-against-deteriorating-quality-of-paris-olympics-medals/articleshow/117260856.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet the The wife of former Pakistani cricketer Wasim Akram converted to Islam before marrying him, stepmother to Wasim's two sons - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shaniera Thompson: The Supportive Wife of Cricket Legend Wasim Akram</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Date not provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/the-sultan-of-swing-202501-1736927985.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="The Sultan of Swing"><figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption><p>Wasim Akram, a cricketing icon, shares a personal journey involving his wife, Shaniera Thompson, who converted to Islam for their marriage. Their partnership is based on mutual respect and love, contributing to Akram’s life as a devoted father and partner.</p><ul><li>Shaniera Thompson converted to Islam before marrying Wasim Akram in August 2013.</li><li>The couple has a daughter named Aiyla, born in December 2014.</li><li>Shaniera is a social activist and plays a significant role as a stepmother to Wasim's two sons.</li><li>The couple met in 2011, establishing a relationship that celebrates both Pakistani and Australian cultures.</li><li>They faced a 17-year age gap, with Wasim being 47 and Shaniera 30 at the time of marriage.</li></ul><blockquote>“Shaniera revealed aspects of her Australian background, leading to their eventual romantic relationship.”</blockquote><p>This inspiring tale highlights ease in cultural integration and the beauty of love transcending boundaries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/meet-the-the-wife-of-former-pakistani-cricketer-wasim-akram-converted-to-islam-before-marrying-him-stepmother-to-wasims-two-sons-420124/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/meet-the-the-wife-of-former-pakistani-cricketer-wasim-akram-converted-to-islam-before-marrying-him-stepmother-to-wasims-two-sons-420124/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:14:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma To Play In Ranji Trophy? Training Video Of India Captain In Mumbai Goes Viral - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma To Play In Ranji Trophy? Training Video Of India Captain In Mumbai Goes Viral</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/el8nl3no_rohit-sharma_625x300_15_January_25.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Rohit Sharma Training" /><figcaption>Rohit Sharma filmed training in Mumbai. © X (Twitter)</figcaption><p>India's cricket captain Rohit Sharma is under pressure after a poor performance in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy. However, he is seen training in Mumbai, signaling his intent to potentially play in the next Ranji Trophy match.</p><ul><li>Rohit Sharma is back in training, preparing for the upcoming ICC Champions Trophy 2025.</li><li>A video emerged showing him jogging at the Bandra Kurla Complex in Mumbai.</li><li>He scored only 31 runs during the recent tour of Australia.</li><li>Rohit is expected to lead India in the Champions Trophy after a strong performance in the 2023 World Cup.</li><li>He may participate in the next Ranji Trophy game against Jammu & Kashmir.</li></ul><blockquote>“He will be coming for practice sessions with the Mumbai Ranji Trophy team and it is still not decided whether he will be playing the next Ranji Trophy game against J&amp;K.” - Indian Express</blockquote><p>This training illustrates Sharma's commitment and readiness to make a comeback after a disappointing series in Australia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/rohit-sharma-to-play-in-ranji-trophy-training-video-of-india-captain-in-mumbai-goes-viral-7478110</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/rohit-sharma-to-play-in-ranji-trophy-training-video-of-india-captain-in-mumbai-goes-viral-7478110</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:12:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BBL 2024-2025: Match 35, STR vs SIX Match Prediction – Who will win today’s BBL match between STR vs SIX? - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BBL 2024-2025: Match 35 Preview - Adelaide Strikers vs Sydney Sixers</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Wednesday, January 15<br><strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><img src="https://media.crictracker.com/media/attachments/1736844575276_image_2025_01_14T08_48_38_105Z.png" alt="" width="700" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Match Prediction: Sydney Sixers to win the match</figcaption><p>The Adelaide Strikers are up against the Sydney Sixers in Match 35 of the Big Bash League 2024-25. Both teams have shown contrasting form in the season so far, setting the stage for an exciting matchup.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>The Strikers are currently ranked 6th, with a record of 3 wins and 5 losses in their 8 games.</li><li>The Sixers are performing well, holding the 2nd spot with 5 wins and 2 losses.</li><li>The match will be held at Adelaide Oval, with the toss scheduled for 2:00 pm IST.</li><li>The pitch is expected to favor batting, with high scores seen in previous games.</li><li>Predicted top performers include Steven Smith for batting and Lloyd Pope for bowling.</li></ul><blockquote>“Sydney Sixers to win the match”</blockquote><p>This match represents a critical opportunity for the Adelaide Strikers to turn their season around, while the Sydney Sixers aim to consolidate their strong position in the league.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-35-str-vs-six-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-str-vs-six/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-match-predictions/bbl-2024-2025-match-35-str-vs-six-match-prediction-who-will-win-todays-bbl-match-between-str-vs-six/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smriti Mandhana breaks record, smashes fastest ODI century by an Indian woman - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Smriti Mandhana breaks record, smashes fastest ODI century by an Indian woman</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Smriti Mandhana has made history by scoring the fastest century in One Day Internationals by an Indian woman.</p><ul><li>Mandhana reached her century in just 50 balls.</li><li>This record-breaking performance highlights her exceptional skills in women's cricket.</li><li>The achievement has garnered widespread recognition and praise within the cricketing community.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a proud moment for Indian women's cricket,” said a cricket expert.</blockquote><p>Mandhana's accomplishment not only sets a new benchmark but also inspires upcoming female cricketers across the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/smriti-mandhana-breaks-record-smashes-fastest-odi-century-by-an-indian-woman/articleshow/117259192.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/smriti-mandhana-breaks-record-smashes-fastest-odi-century-by-an-indian-woman/articleshow/117259192.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>