<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 05:22:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 05:22:03 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pressure is mounting': Dinesh Karthik on challenges for Gautam Gambhir as India head coach - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dinesh Karthik Discusses Challenges for Gautam Gambhir as India's Head Coach</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In this article, Dinesh Karthik shares insights on the pressures and challenges that Gautam Gambhir will face as the head coach of the Indian cricket team, emphasizing the expectations and scrutiny that come with the role.</p><ul><li>Karthik highlights the immediacy of the challenges facing Gambhir.</li><li>The article touches on the expectations from fans and the cricketing fraternity.</li><li>Insights into Gambhir's coaching style and potential strategies are discussed.</li><li>The need for a strong team environment is emphasized for success.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pressure is mounting for Gambhir as he steps into this crucial role.”</blockquote><p>The article underscores the importance of leadership in cricket and how Gambhir's tenure as head coach could shape the future of the Indian cricket team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/pressure-is-mounting-dinesh-karthik-on-challenges-for-gautam-gambhir-as-india-head-coach/articleshow/117164733.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/pressure-is-mounting-dinesh-karthik-on-challenges-for-gautam-gambhir-as-india-head-coach/articleshow/117164733.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 03:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bitter Jasprit Bumrah Champions Trophy Blow To India, Report Says India Pacer To Miss... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bitter Jasprit Bumrah Champions Trophy Blow To India, Report Says India Pacer To Miss...</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/so18koi8_bumrah-bcci_625x300_12_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Jasprit Bumrah" />
<figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah unlikely to be fit in time for Champions Trophy start © BCCI/Sportzpics</figcaption>
<p>The Indian cricket team is facing a setback as Jasprit Bumrah is unlikely to recover in time for the Champions Trophy due to worsening back spasms.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bumrah experienced back spasms during the final Test against Australia.</li>
  <li>His condition was found to be worse than anticipated, with swelling on his back.</li>
  <li>He is currently undergoing rehabilitation at the National Cricket Academy (NCA) in Bengaluru.</li>
  <li>BCCI has requested an extension for the squad announcement due to Bumrah's injury.</li>
  <li>There is uncertainty whether to include him in the 15-man roster or as a reserve in the UAE.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"He (Bumrah) will be going to NCA for his rehabilitation. The initial report says he doesn't have a fracture but has swelling on his back."</blockquote>
<p>The outcome of Bumrah's recovery is critical, as his absence could significantly affect India's performance in the Champions Trophy, with the semi-finals set to begin shortly after his expected rehabilitation period.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/bitter-jasprit-bumrah-champions-trophy-blow-to-india-report-says-india-pacer-to-miss-7454497</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/icc-champions-trophy-2025/bitter-jasprit-bumrah-champions-trophy-blow-to-india-report-says-india-pacer-to-miss-7454497</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 03:23:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Yashasvi Jaiswal, Rishabh Pant, Shubman Gill Weren't Picked For T20Is vs England - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Explained: Why Yashasvi Jaiswal, Rishabh Pant, Shubman Gill Weren't Picked For T20Is vs England</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 25&nbsp;| <strong>Source:</strong>&nbsp;NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/2d7e4gv_shubman-gill-and-rishabh-pant-bcci_625x300_12_January_25.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Explained: Why Yashasvi Jaiswal, Rishabh Pant, Shubman Gill Weren't Picked For T20Is vs England"><figcaption>File photo of Shubman Gill and Rishabh Pant © BCCI/Sportzpics</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) announced the squad for the T20Is against England, leaving out notable players Yashasvi Jaiswal, Rishabh Pant, and Shubman Gill. This decision primarily focuses on their fitness after a grueling series.</p><ul><li>The selectors opted to rest Pant, Jaiswal, and Gill following the intense Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</li><li>Concerns over fitness were linked to the upcoming ODI series against England and the ICC Champions Trophy.</li><li>Mohammed Siraj and Mayank Yadav were also excluded due to workload management and injury, respectively.</li><li>The BCCI has asked for an extension to finalize the Champions Trophy squad.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pant, Jaiswal and Gill have been rested from this series to allow them to recover fully…” - Times of India</blockquote><p>This strategy allows key players to recover for significantly more challenging matches ahead, indicating a focus on long-term team performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/india-vs-england-2025/explained-why-yashasvi-jaiswal-rishabh-pant-shubman-gill-werent-picked-for-t20is-vs-england-7454370</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/india-vs-england-2025/explained-why-yashasvi-jaiswal-rishabh-pant-shubman-gill-werent-picked-for-t20is-vs-england-7454370</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 03:02:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah set to miss India’s league stage matches at Champions Trophy, inclusion in 15-man squad uncertain: Report - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah to miss India’s league stage matches at Champions Trophy, inclusion in 15-man squad uncertain: Report</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<p>Star Indian pacer Jasprit Bumrah is likely to miss India's group stage matches in the upcoming ICC Champions Trophy 2025 due to swelling in his back, as reported.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bumrah will report to the National Cricket Academy (NCA) in Bengaluru for recovery monitoring.</li>
  <li>The NCA will oversee his rehabilitation for approximately three weeks.</li>
  <li>Indications suggest no fracture, but swelling is present in his back.</li>
  <li>The BCCI selection committee is deliberating on his inclusion in the 15-man squad or as a reserve player.</li>
  <li>The last date for provisional squad submission is January 12, 2025.</li>
  <li>The Champions Trophy is set to commence on February 19, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“He (Bumrah) will be going to NCA for his rehabilitation. The NCA will monitor his recovery and he will be there for three weeks.”</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming tournament will be played in a hybrid format, hosting India's matches in Dubai and others in Pakistan. India is placed in Group A, scheduled to face Bangladesh, Pakistan, and New Zealand.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/jasprit-bumrah-likely-to-miss-indias-league-stage-matches-at-champions-trophy-2025-squad-announcement-bcci-11736649778364.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/jasprit-bumrah-likely-to-miss-indias-league-stage-matches-at-champions-trophy-2025-squad-announcement-bcci-11736649778364.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 02:51:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma changed his mind on retirement after MCG defeat; Gautam Gambhir left unhappy: Report - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma changed his mind on retirement after MCG defeat; Gautam Gambhir left unhappy: Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p><p>Indian captain Rohit Sharma faced challenges during the recent series in Australia, leading to a significant reflection on his career after a disappointing performance.</p><ul><li>Rohit struggled with the bat and decided to sit out the final match in favor of Shubman Gill.</li><li>Reports suggest he was ready to retire after the Boxing Day Test but was persuaded to continue.</li><li>Gautam Gambhir expressed dissatisfaction with Rohit’s decision-making and their ongoing rift.</li><li>Rohit explained his choice to drop himself was in the team’s best interest during a Star Sports interview.</li><li>Robin Uthappa commented on the evolving chemistry between Gambhir and Rohit.</li></ul><blockquote>“I made this decision after we came here (Sydney), it was going on in my mind that it is important for me to step aside because I wasn't getting runs with the bat.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the complexities of leadership in sports and personal relationships among players, particularly in high-pressure environments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/rohit-sharma-changed-his-mind-on-retirement-after-mcg-defeat-gautam-gambhir-left-unhappy-report-11736647267428.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/sports/cricket-news/rohit-sharma-changed-his-mind-on-retirement-after-mcg-defeat-gautam-gambhir-left-unhappy-report-11736647267428.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 02:11:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jasprit Bumrah set to miss Champions Trophy group stage matches because of back swelling - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jasprit Bumrah set to miss Champions Trophy group stage matches due to back swelling</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/New-Project-2025-01-11T233614.262.jpg?w=640" alt="Jasprit Bumrah is expected to be fully fit only by the first week of March. (Sportzpics)" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Jasprit Bumrah is expected to be fully fit only by the first week of March. (Sportzpics)</figcaption><p>In a setback for India, strike bowler Jasprit Bumrah is likely to miss the group stage of next month’s Champions Trophy due to health reasons.</p><ul><li>Bumrah has swelling on his back and has been advised to report to the National Cricket Academy (NCA) in Bengaluru for recovery monitoring.</li><li>The Champions Trophy starts on February 19, with matches scheduled in Karachi, Rawalpindi, Lahore, and Dubai.</li><li>The BCCI has requested an extension for announcing the squad as they monitor Bumrah’s fitness.</li><li>Selectors are debating whether to include Bumrah in the squad or reserve list; provisional squads can be submitted with changes allowed until February 12.</li><li>Bumrah is expected to return to full fitness by the first week of March.</li><li>He previously missed nearly 11 months of cricket due to surgery on his back.</li></ul><blockquote>“He (Bumrah) will be going to NCA for his rehabilitation. The initial report says he doesn’t have a fracture but has swelling on his back.”</blockquote><p>If Bumrah is not fit by March 2, he may miss the group's last match against New Zealand. India's group games include matches against Bangladesh on February 20 and Pakistan on February 23.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-miss-champions-trophy-group-match-back-injury-update-9773791/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-miss-champions-trophy-group-match-back-injury-update-9773791/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 02:06:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Rishabh Pant, Shubman Gill, Yashasvi Jaiswal did not make India squad for England T20Is - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/why-rishabh-pant-shubman-gill-yashasvi-jaiswal-did-not-make-india-squad-for-england-t20is-101736645457029.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/why-rishabh-pant-shubman-gill-yashasvi-jaiswal-did-not-make-india-squad-for-england-t20is-101736645457029.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 01:59:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gautam Gambhir Unhappy With Rohit Sharma's Test Retirement U-Turn, Shock Report Emerges - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gautam Gambhir Unhappy With Rohit Sharma's Test Retirement U-Turn, Shock Report Emerges</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 24, 2024; <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV Sports</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/eepc2rb_gautam-gambhir-afp_625x300_23_October_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Gautam Gambhir Unhappy With Rohit Sharma's Test Retirement U-Turn, Shock Report Emerges">
<figcaption>File photo of Gautam Gambhir and Rohit Sharma © AFP</figcaption>
<p>The article discusses the controversy surrounding Rohit Sharma's decision regarding his participation in Test cricket, particularly his retirement U-turn, which has reportedly upset Gautam Gambhir.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rohit Sharma sat out the fifth Test against Australia, leading to speculation about his retirement.</li>
  <li>He later clarified he was not retiring but was 'standing down' due to poor form.</li>
  <li>A report suggests Rohit had initially planned to retire but was persuaded against it by his well-wishers.</li>
  <li>Gautam Gambhir expressed dissatisfaction with Rohit's decision to reverse his retirement stance.</li>
  <li>Rohit emphasized that external opinions do not dictate his cricket future.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Nobody from outside can determine when I am going to hand my boots.” - Rohit Sharma</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the dynamics of Rohit Sharma's decisions regarding his Test career have raised eyebrows, particularly with his coach Gautam Gambhir expressing his unhappiness over the situation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharma-wanted-to-retire-well-wishers-stopped-him-gautam-gambhir-was-unhappy-report-7452140</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/rohit-sharma-wanted-to-retire-well-wishers-stopped-him-gautam-gambhir-was-unhappy-report-7452140</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 01:38:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WATCH: Dewald Brevis takes a spectacular boundary catch in JSK-MICT SA20 clash - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dewald Brevis Makes Stunning Boundary Catch in SA20 Clash</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<strong>Source:</strong> Sports Network</p><div><img src="https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/f76a4421c1a29894d63e757e3536e9a0.jpeg" alt="Dewald Brevis Catch" /><figcaption>Dewald Brevis executes an incredible catch during the match.</figcaption></div><p>Dewald Brevis showcased his athleticism by taking a spectacular catch near the boundary during the latest match between JSK and MICT in the SA20 tournament.</p><ul><li>Brevis's catch was a defining moment in the match, demonstrating his skills and reflexes.</li><li>JSK secured a crucial victory in this high-stakes match.</li><li>Fans and commentators hailed the catch as one of the best of the season.</li></ul><blockquote>“That was an unbelievable catch,” remarked the announcer, highlighting Brevis's talent.</blockquote><p>The catch not only contributed significantly to the match outcome but also solidified Brevis's reputation as a rising star in cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/watch-dewald-brevis-takes-a-spectacular-boundary-catch-in-jsk-mict-sa20-clash/articleshow/117163317.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/watch-dewald-brevis-takes-a-spectacular-boundary-catch-in-jsk-mict-sa20-clash/articleshow/117163317.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 01:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sears and O'Rourke included in New Zealand's Champions Trophy squad - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fast Bowlers Sears and O'Rourke Selected for New Zealand's Champions Trophy Squad</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><img src='https://wassets.hscicdn.com/static/images/lazyimage-noaspect.svg' alt='Champions Trophy 2025: Dubai to host all India matches, including the knockouts if India qualify'><figcaption>Champions Trophy 2025: Dubai to host all India matches, including the knockouts if India qualify</figcaption><p>Fast bowlers Ben Sears and Will O'Rourke have been included in New Zealand's squad for the Champions Trophy, marking a significant opportunity for both players.</p><ul><li>Sears is in line for his ODI debut, having recently recovered from injury.</li><li>O'Rourke has been impressive in his early international career, particularly in Test matches.</li><li>The squad also includes Nathan Smith, who adds strength to the lower order.</li><li>The team will participate in an ODI tri-series in Pakistan prior to the Champions Trophy.</li><li>Mitchell Santner will captain New Zealand for the first time in a global event.</li></ul><blockquote>“We’re currently blessed with a lot of quality players and that certainly made for some challenging selection discussions,” - Gary Stead</blockquote><p>In summary, New Zealand's preparations for the Champions Trophy include a focus on leveraging experience among its players to excel in the tournament.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sears-and-o-rourke-included-in-new-zealand-s-champions-trophy-squad-1468615</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sears-and-o-rourke-included-in-new-zealand-s-champions-trophy-squad-1468615</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 01:19:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Graeme Smith could have easily dropped me, Hashim Amla, Dale Steyn…': AB de Villiers' sincere appeal to Temba Bavuma - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AB de Villiers Urges Temba Bavuma to Stick with Consistency Amid South Africa's Transition</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/abd_temba_1736641815212_1736641823347.jpg" alt="AB de Villiers has his say on South Africa's fate in WTC final(Getty)" title="AB de Villiers has his say on South Africa's fate in WTC final(Getty)">
<figcaption>AB de Villiers has his say on South Africa's fate in WTC final(Getty)</figcaption>
<p>AB de Villiers expresses confidence in the new generation of South African cricketers and emphasizes the importance of consistency in team selection as they head into the World Test Championship final against Australia.</p>
<ul>
  <li>De Villiers is optimistic about the potential of young players like Delano Potgieter.</li>
  <li>He stresses the need for the Proteas to stick with the core players who achieved recent successes.</li>
  <li>Despite their recent victories, he feels South Africa lacks experience compared to Australia.</li>
  <li>De Villiers shares positive sentiments about Temba Bavuma's leadership and the team's fighting spirit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"He could have easily dropped us players because we were inconsistent early on, but they stuck with the team they believed in." - AB de Villiers</blockquote>
<p>De Villiers remains hopeful about South Africa's chances, highlighting their fighting attitude and the evolving talent within the squad.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/graeme-smith-could-have-easily-dropped-me-hashim-amla-dale-steyn-ab-de-villiers-sincere-appeal-to-temba-bavuma-101736636562427.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/graeme-smith-could-have-easily-dropped-me-hashim-amla-dale-steyn-ab-de-villiers-sincere-appeal-to-temba-bavuma-101736636562427.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:32:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma 'forced' to make U-turn on retirement after MCG Test, change in decision left Gambhir irked: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma's Retirement Decision Controversy After MCG Test</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/After-a-string-of-losses-in-both-white-ball-and-re_1736621472786_1736621481570.jpg" alt="After a string of losses in both white-ball and red-ball cricket, the pressure on the coach-captain duo of Gautam Gambhir and Rohit Sharma is rising (AFP)(HT_PRINT)" title="After a string of losses in both white-ball and red-ball cricket, the pressure on the coach-captain duo of Gautam Gambhir and Rohit Sharma is rising (AFP)(HT_PRINT)"><figcaption>After a string of losses in both white-ball and red-ball cricket, the pressure on the coach-captain duo of Gautam Gambhir and Rohit Sharma is rising (AFP)(HT_PRINT)</figcaption><p>India's cricket captain Rohit Sharma was reportedly convinced to reconsider his decision to retire from Test cricket following a poor performance during the Border-Gavaskar Trophy against Australia.</p><ul><li>Rohit managed only 31 runs across five innings in the series.</li><li>He faced criticism for his captaincy after losses to New Zealand and Australia.</li><li>After the disappointing MCG Test, he contemplated retirement seriously.</li><li>Persuaded by his associates, he chose to delay his retirement announcement.</li><li>The relationship between Rohit and his coach Gautam Gambhir is under scrutiny due to disagreements.</li></ul><blockquote>“Rohit had made up his mind after MCG. Had his well-wishers from the outside didn't force him to change his mind, we could have well seen another retirement in Australia.”</blockquote><p>Despite tensions, both are set to collaborate in the upcoming ODI series against England and the Champions Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-forced-to-make-u-turn-on-retirement-after-mcg-test-change-in-decision-left-gambhir-irked-report-101736612184589.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/rohit-sharma-forced-to-make-u-turn-on-retirement-after-mcg-test-change-in-decision-left-gambhir-irked-report-101736612184589.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:30:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bumrah likely to miss Champions Trophy group stage matches - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bumrah likely to miss Champions Trophy group stage matches</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><p>In a setback for India, strike bowler <strong><a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/jasprit-bumrah-retains-top-spot-icc-rankings-for-test-bowlers-9767301/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Jasprit Bumrah</a></strong> is likely to miss the group stage of next month’s Champions Trophy due to health reasons.</p><ul><li>Bumrah has swelling on his back and will report to the National Cricket Academy for recovery monitoring.</li><li>The Champions Trophy begins on February 19, featuring the world’s top eight ODI teams.</li><li>Selectors are considering including Bumrah in the squad or as a reserve.</li><li>The BCCI seeks an extension for submitting the provisional squad.</li><li>Bumrah is expected to be fit by early March but may not be ready for the last group match on March 2.</li><li>Bumrah has a history of back issues and missed significant match time after surgery.</li></ul><blockquote>“He (Bumrah) will be going to NCA for his rehabilitation. The initial report says he doesn’t have a fracture but has swelling on his back.”</blockquote><p>The Indian team management is cautious of Bumrah’s workload to prevent further injury as he has been rested in recent matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/bumrah-likely-to-miss-champions-trophy-group-stage-matches-9773833/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/bumrah-likely-to-miss-champions-trophy-group-stage-matches-9773833/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 22:30:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Santner-led New Zealand announce 15-member ICC Men's Champions Trophy 2025 squad - ICC Cricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxPR0hpT3hmWFdTT1hHMXRraHpLZXlvYm1VTnptMXBINmhrdnhVaG9tWmRFazRfc3NfMzUxZU5pSkJ6RHR6NEthdU1KcUxZM3p4YWxuY0JnYi1uNjJfb2VFeFR3RnVETl9tcGlUUXlzQ0FVVkZCTXdnTlZnQXJzRVpzRHdVZWgxZWh1MkJqRVZJNXFXV1dOVjNVczBjcUlIWVBHOEpOYzRtWmtGblh3MzNQVFZhRG85enRJM2QwTkt6b0pwcXhKWFFjX1VPZnV3SVpHM2FPRXM1cFVzak9HdTVsMjJNRnZPLW42TXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxPR0hpT3hmWFdTT1hHMXRraHpLZXlvYm1VTnptMXBINmhrdnhVaG9tWmRFazRfc3NfMzUxZU5pSkJ6RHR6NEthdU1KcUxZM3p4YWxuY0JnYi1uNjJfb2VFeFR3RnVETl9tcGlUUXlzQ0FVVkZCTXdnTlZnQXJzRVpzRHdVZWgxZWh1MkJqRVZJNXFXV1dOVjNVczBjcUlIWVBHOEpOYzRtWmtGblh3MzNQVFZhRG85enRJM2QwTkt6b0pwcXhKWFFjX1VPZnV3SVpHM2FPRXM1cFVzak9HdTVsMjJNRnZPLW42TXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 22:18:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man City player ratings vs Salford City: James McAtee has arrived! Academy starboy slams in hat-trick and Jeremy Doku impresses as Pep Guardiola's side destroy Class of 92-owned minnows in 8-0 hammering while Jack Grealish ends scoring drought - Goal.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxNSmpscjJhOEdCUXhaZzlJby1icjZPSkJ6bXBpLVNDdHhCZjI1WDZldktnc0NYRDRsbG5vdlc1OFVHY19pcXRsR0UzRm1Sb010TzRqWmhybW1PblItMmsya0J6eUpQNHJCYWN2SVpYSTdvZ1ZpOUtDWmRNbDhsNnRMYTJMTzVMdnVrM0NtdEsxVzdmanlqTmdWcnBPV21LejRzMnJPS2hnVnJPOFVydVpVQ3cyOEptWUhWMjdlWUdBUHNZZlRlcTVpS18yOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiywFBVV95cUxNSmpscjJhOEdCUXhaZzlJby1icjZPSkJ6bXBpLVNDdHhCZjI1WDZldktnc0NYRDRsbG5vdlc1OFVHY19pcXRsR0UzRm1Sb010TzRqWmhybW1PblItMmsya0J6eUpQNHJCYWN2SVpYSTdvZ1ZpOUtDWmRNbDhsNnRMYTJMTzVMdnVrM0NtdEsxVzdmanlqTmdWcnBPV21LejRzMnJPS2hnVnJPOFVydVpVQ3cyOEptWUhWMjdlWUdBUHNZZlRlcTVpS18yOA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 19:54:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man City player ratings vs Salford City: James McAtee has arrived! Academy starboy slams in hat-trick and Jeremy Doku impresses as Pep Guardiola's side destroy Class of 92-owned minnows in 8-0 hammering while Jack Grealish ends scoring drought - GOAL English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>James McAtee Shines in Man City's 8-0 Victory Over Salford City</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Goal</p><img alt="Man City Salford gfx" src="https://assets.goal.com/images/v3/blt4b0c1aadb80a7bb9/GOAL%20-%20Multiple%20Images%20-%203%20Stacked%20-%20Facebook(216)%20(1).png?auto=webp&amp;format=pjpg&amp;width=3840&amp;quality=60"><figcaption>James McAtee celebrating his hat-trick against Salford City.</figcaption><p>James McAtee delivered an outstanding performance, scoring a hat-trick as Manchester City dominated Salford City with an 8-0 scoreline in the FA Cup.</p><ul><li>McAtee scored three goals in a one-sided affair against Salford City.</li><li>Jeremy Doku contributed significantly with two goals and two assists.</li><li>Jack Grealish ended his goal drought, scoring his first goal in 13 months from the penalty spot.</li><li>Nico O'Reilly and Divin Mubama also added to the score, marking a memorable day for the academy players.</li></ul><blockquote>“James McAtee showed Pep Guardiola just what he can do when given the chance.”</blockquote><p>This match showcased the talent of Manchester City's academy graduates and their potential impact in the first team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.goal.com/en-in/lists/man-city-player-ratings-vs-salford-city-james-mcatee-jeremy-doku-jack-grealish/blt00d25630b5540096</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.goal.com/en-in/lists/man-city-player-ratings-vs-salford-city-james-mcatee-jeremy-doku-jack-grealish/blt00d25630b5540096</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 19:54:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nazia Bibi: first player from J&K to represent India at Kho Kho World Cup - Greater Kashmir]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nazia Bibi: First Player from J&K to Represent India at Kho Kho World Cup</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>Nazia Bibi, a 21-year-old from Jammu and Kashmir, has made history by becoming the first athlete from her region to be selected for the Indian Women's Kho Kho team at the World Cup.</p><ul><li>Nazia is from Nagrota, Jammu and Kashmir, and is a member of a tribal community.</li><li>The Kho Kho World Cup will commence on January 13, 2025, at the Indira Gandhi Indoor Stadium in New Delhi.</li><li>She began her Kho Kho journey during her school years and took it professionally over the past seven years.</li><li>Nazia is currently pursuing her BA at Padma Shri Padma Sachdev Govt College for Women in Jammu.</li><li>She attributes her inspiration to her Army-serving cousins.</li><li>Nazia participated in a national camp, where she stood out among three other athletes from her region to earn her spot on the team.</li></ul><blockquote>Nazia Bibi said, “Watching my cousins excel in athletics fueled my passion to pursue a career in sports.”</blockquote><blockquote>Dr. Baljinder Kour stated that her achievement is a milestone for sports in the region.</blockquote><p>This achievement is seen as a significant step for women in sports from Jammu and Kashmir and serves as an inspiration for future athletes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greaterkashmir.com/jammu/nazia-bibi-first-player-from-jk-to-represent-india-at-kho-kho-world-cup/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greaterkashmir.com/jammu/nazia-bibi-first-player-from-jk-to-represent-india-at-kho-kho-world-cup/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 19:43:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI Rejects KL Rahul’s Request For A Rest, Asks Him To Play England Series - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Rejects KL Rahul’s Request For A Rest, Asks Him To Play England Series</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="KL Rahul (Sportzpics image for representation)">
<figcaption>KL Rahul (Sportzpics image for representation)</figcaption>
<p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) has instructed KL Rahul to play in the upcoming white-ball series against England despite his request to take a break.</p>
<ul>
    <li>BCCI rejected Rahul’s request for a rest during the series.</li>
    <li>India is scheduled to play five T20Is and three ODIs against England starting January 22.</li>
    <li>Rahul last featured in an ODI in August 2024 against Sri Lanka.</li>
    <li>Selectors initially planned to rest Rahul for the series to provide him with a break.</li>
    <li>Rahul is viewed as a crucial player for the upcoming Champions Trophy.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We thought this might just change his career in the right direction. Then you saw the failures again.” - Sanjay Manjrekar</blockquote>
<p>This decision highlights the BCCI's focus on ensuring key players are match-ready ahead of major tournaments such as the Champions Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/bcci-rejects-kl-rahuls-request-for-a-rest-asks-him-to-play-england-series-9185158.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/bcci-rejects-kl-rahuls-request-for-a-rest-asks-him-to-play-england-series-9185158.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 18:57:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Owners should respect players - Sherfane Rutherford on CPL incident - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Owners Should Respect Players - Sherfane Rutherford on CPL Incident</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> Sat, Jan 11, 2025</p> <p><strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p> <img height="396" width="595" alt="Sherfane Rutherford believes there should be a clear line between promoters and players in franchise leagues" title="Sherfane Rutherford believes there should be a clear line between promoters and players in franchise leagues" src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c599135/sherfane-rutherford-believes-t.jpg"> <figcaption>Sherfane Rutherford believes there should be a clear line between promoters and players in franchise leagues © Cricbuzz</figcaption> <p>Sherfane Rutherford emphasizes the need for mutual respect between players and franchise owners, reflecting on a controversial incident from the Caribbean Premier League (CPL) that led to his departure from the St Kitts and Nevis Patriots.</p> <ul> <li>Rutherford stresses that respect is essential for maintaining a professional environment in cricket.</li> <li>He recounts a frustrating experience where team management blamed him for a loss via text message after a poor performance.</li> <li>The player warns against owners interfering in the emotional context of the game and emphasizes the importance of timing in communication.</li> <li>Despite the turmoil, Rutherford is focusing on future opportunities and learning from the experience.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“I don't think the owners should text players, especially about performance, because at the end of the day we didn't go there to fail.”</blockquote> <p>Rutherford concludes that while the experience was challenging, it provided valuable lessons for future interactions in professional sports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/133083/owners-should-respect-players-sherfane-rutherford-on-cpl-incident</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/133083/owners-should-respect-players-sherfane-rutherford-on-cpl-incident</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 18:38:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gladbach vs. Bayern Munich: Muller with a BIG chance but could not score - Bavarian Football Works]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gladbach 0-1 Bayern Munich: Pressure Mounts in Final Minutes</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Bavarian Football Works</p><p><strong>Location:</strong> Allianz Arena, Munich, Germany | <strong>Time:</strong> 6:30 PM local time</p><p>Bayern Munich secured a narrow victory over Borussia Mönchengladbach with a penalty goal from Harry Kane. The match saw intense moments as Gladbach applied significant pressure in the dying minutes.</p><ol><li>Bayern won 1-0, with Harry Kane scoring from a penalty in the 68th minute.</li><li>Gladbach showcased a strong pressing game, especially towards the end of the match.</li><li>Bayern controlled much of the match and had better chances overall, but struggled to capitalize.</li></ol><blockquote>“Gladbach woke up and chose violence in the form of pressing the hell out of Bayern’s players.”</blockquote><p>Overall, Bayern maintained their top position in the league standings while Gladbach continues to seek improvement in their performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bavarianfootballworks.com/2025/1/11/24340694/gladbach-bayern-munich-live-stream-game-time-thread-how-to-watch-bundesliga-kane-musiala-davies</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bavarianfootballworks.com/2025/1/11/24340694/gladbach-bayern-munich-live-stream-game-time-thread-how-to-watch-bundesliga-kane-musiala-davies</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:55:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BCCI meets Gambhir, Rohit, other key members - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Meets Key Members to Discuss Future After Test Cricket Struggles</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 11:09 pm IST | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/yjpr4l/article69090005.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_gauti-rohit_2_1_09DOT49P.jpg" alt="India’s coach Gautam Gambhir and captain Rohit Sharma. File" title="India’s coach Gautam Gambhir and captain Rohit Sharma. File"><figcaption>India’s coach Gautam Gambhir and captain Rohit Sharma. Photo Credit: AFP</figcaption><p>The Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) recently convened with crucial members of the Indian men's cricket team management to assess the aftermath of a disappointing Test cricket season and plan ahead.</p><ul><li>Attendees included Rohit Sharma, Gautam Gambhir, Ajit Agarkar, Devajit Saikia, and Jay Shah.</li><li>The meeting took place at a hotel in south Mumbai, coinciding with Shah's felicitation as ICC chair.</li><li>Discussions centered around coaching roles and the transition for longer format squads.</li><li>Despite their poor form, Rohit Sharma and Virat Kohli's positions in the team were not questioned.</li><li>India faced a humiliating whitewash at home and a series loss in Australia, missing the ICC Test Championship final.</li></ul><blockquote>“The sorry losses meant India for the first time will not feature in the final of the ICC Test Championship in June.”</blockquote><p>In summary, the meeting was critical for strategizing India's cricketing future, particularly regarding Test formats and coaching staff adjustments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sport/cricket/bcci-meets-gambhir-rohit-other-key-members/article69090018.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sport/cricket/bcci-meets-gambhir-rohit-other-key-members/article69090018.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fearless Lhuan-dre Pretorius grabs the spotlight in 'dream come true' innings - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fearless Lhuan-dre Pretorius grabs the spotlight in 'dream come true' innings</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p>In a stunning debut, Lhuan-dre Pretorius scored 97 runs off 51 balls for the Paarl Royals against the Sunrisers Eastern Cape, showcasing remarkable confidence and skill against top bowlers. His innings featured multiple sixes and put his team on course for victory.</p><ul><li>Pretorius' innings included runs off established internationals: 15 runs from Marco Jansen, 13 from Aiden Markram, and 22 from Ottneil Baartman.</li><li>He missed his century by three runs but holds the record for the highest individual score and most sixes in an innings by a Royals batter.</li><li>Pretorius praised his batting partner Joe Root, focusing on soaking in experience and adapting his game.</li><li>Ben Stokes highlighted Pretorius' talent and opportunities in franchise cricket via social media.</li><li>Pretorius was a standout player in South Africa's Under-19 team and has made significant progress in domestic cricket.</li></ul><blockquote>“One of the many things franchise cricket has done is give young/inexperienced but incredibly talented players opportunities on the biggest stage against the best in the world and show off how good they are. Lhuan-dre Pretorius is doing that right now.” — Ben Stokes</blockquote><p>Pretorius’ performance marks a significant milestone in his early cricket career, hinting at a promising future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa20-lhuan-dre-pretorius-grabs-the-spotlight-in-dream-come-true-innings-1468602</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/sa20-lhuan-dre-pretorius-grabs-the-spotlight-in-dream-come-true-innings-1468602</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 17:03:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australian Open: Super Serb Djokovic ready to rock young champs - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australian Open: Super Serb Djokovic ready to rock young champs</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/Novak-Djokovic-hits-a-return-during-a-practice-ses_1736614683270.jpg" alt="Novak Djokovic hits a return during a practice session ahead of the Australian Open, in Melbourne on Saturday. (AFP)" title="Novak Djokovic hits a return during a practice session ahead of the Australian Open, in Melbourne on Saturday. (AFP)">
<figcaption>Novak Djokovic hits a return during a practice session ahead of the Australian Open, in Melbourne on Saturday. (AFP)</figcaption>
<p>In a light-hearted atmosphere at Melbourne Park, Novak Djokovic, 24-time Grand Slam champion, engages in playful banter while preparing for the Australian Open, where he faces a new challenge from young champions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Djokovic is in a jovial mood, participating in exhibition matches and press events.</li>
  <li>He has a strong history at the Australian Open, with 10 titles in the past.</li>
  <li>This season’s tournament feels refreshed, with younger players like Sinner and Alcaraz posing significant challenges.</li>
  <li>Djokovic aims to reclaim his dominance on hard courts following a challenging previous year.</li>
  <li>Young rivals, including the world No. 1, signify a shift in the competitive landscape.</li>
  <li>Gael Monfils sets a new ATP Tour record as the oldest singles champion at 38 years old.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The good thing for me is when I am seeing him (Sinner) winning titles, when I am seeing him in the top of the rankings, it forces me to practice even harder every day,” said Alcaraz.</blockquote>
<p>Djokovic's presence at the Open represents both a challenge to the young contenders and an opportunity to reaffirm his legacy in tennis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/tennis/australian-open-super-serb-djokovic-ready-to-rock-young-champs-101736614685576.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/tennis/australian-open-super-serb-djokovic-ready-to-rock-young-champs-101736614685576.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 16:58:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chelsea 5-0 Morecambe, FA Cup: Post-match reaction, ratings - We Ain't Got No History]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chelsea 5-0 Morecambe, FA Cup: Post-match reaction, ratings</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Upcoming date<br><strong>Source:</strong> Source to be determined</p><p>Chelsea showcased a dominant performance against Morecambe, securing a convincing 5-0 victory in the FA Cup. Despite a slow start, Chelsea's attack proved too much for the visitors.</p><ul><li>It took time for Chelsea to score, needing a deflected goal from Tosin Adarabioyo.</li><li>Christopher Nkunku saw a penalty saved but later scored to double the lead early in the second half.</li><li>A long-range strike from Tosin sealed the match, followed by two goals from Félix.</li><li>Defensive efforts were noted, including a clean sheet maintained by Axel Disasi.</li><li>Next match is against Bournemouth at home on Tuesday night.</li></ul><blockquote>“Job done. Carefree.”</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/2025/1/11/24341424/chelsea-5-0-morecambe-fa-cup-post-match-reaction-ratings</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://weaintgotnohistory.sbnation.com/2025/1/11/24341424/chelsea-5-0-morecambe-fa-cup-post-match-reaction-ratings</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 16:55:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Not Hardik Pandya: BCCI Name This Star As Vice-Captain For India vs England T20Is - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>BCCI Appoints Suryakumar Yadav as Captain for T20 Series Against England</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> November 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/og6l21k8_hardik-pandya-afp_625x300_20_November_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="BCCI Announces New Vice-Captain for T20Is"><figcaption>Not Hardik Pandya: BCCI Names Axar Patel as Vice-Captain for T20 Series</figcaption><p>The BCCI has announced Suryakumar Yadav as captain for the upcoming T20 series against England, with Axar Patel appointed as vice-captain, while Hardik Pandya has been omitted from the leadership role.</p><ul><li>Mohammed Shami returns to the squad, marking his first appearance since 2023.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah is rested for the five-match T20I series.</li><li>Young players like Abhishek Sharma and Tilak Varma retain their spots in the team.</li><li>The series starts on January 22 in Kolkata and includes matches in Chennai, Rajkot, Pune, and Mumbai.</li></ul><blockquote>“Shami will don the blue jersey after a significant recovery from ankle surgery,” reported sources.</blockquote><p>This series represents a strategic shift for India's T20 lineup, emphasizing youth and experience as they prepare to face England.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/india-vs-england-2025/not-hardik-pandya-bcci-name-this-star-as-vice-captain-for-india-vs-england-t20is-7452240</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/india-vs-england-2025/not-hardik-pandya-bcci-name-this-star-as-vice-captain-for-india-vs-england-t20is-7452240</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 16:37:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grandmaster D Gukesh's net worth before World Chess Championship was just Rs 8.26 crore, his current net worth is Rs... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>D Gukesh's Net Worth Soars After World Chess Championship</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/grandmaster-d-gukeshs-net-worth-before-world-chess-championship-was-just-rs-826-crore-his-current-net-worth-is-rs-202501-1736613095.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="D Gukesh"/><figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption><p>D Gukesh's net worth has dramatically risen following his victory in the World Chess Championship, increasing from Rs 8.26 crore to Rs 20 crore.</p><ul><li>Before the championship, D Gukesh's net worth was estimated at Rs 8.26 crore.</li><li>After winning the championship, his net worth is now estimated at Rs 20 crore.</li><li>The championship prize fund was $2.5 million, with players earning $200,000 for each victory.</li><li>D. Gukesh won three games, earning a total of $600,000, approximately Rs 5.07 crore.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“This victory has not only changed my financial status but also placed me among the elite in chess.”</p></blockquote><p>This remarkable increase in D Gukesh's net worth signifies his exceptional talent and the growing prestige of chess in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/viral/grandmaster-d-gukesh-net-worth-before-world-chess-championship-was-just-rs-8-26-crore-his-current-net-worth-is-rs-20-crore-419515/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/viral/grandmaster-d-gukesh-net-worth-before-world-chess-championship-was-just-rs-8-26-crore-his-current-net-worth-is-rs-20-crore-419515/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 16:34:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MBSG 1-0 EBFC Highlights, ISL 2024-25: MacLaren’s early strike helps Mohun Bagan beat East Bengal - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwJBVV95cUxPSFpXbTczOEhpa2VULXEzOWllRGxybkUweVh2cTFmdk9SdXBXQ2Zrb2lFRGJTelIxQW1HMUxuNmxFdlI4SXJFQTlUa2JPcUtWeFZfU2xZSFRKRjZiOExZM0R6aHktcHpSVnQtMVVpS1Y3Ql9LZms2R0NsU2hQZXFGWUktX3FZQ3B0ZjNWM2hVMURmTmdOYmFEMzVyRk5DckJqM0RkdnNYNThZQUZaNTNuWUM4NlBaUTltZlVnWUxfLXVNMEhVYTFvLXJfTFdQbGkwU0gtRGtmbWw2Q2Z2cThObzY5dmxmLW9aSGZrZUxHdk0zLVAxTlBZejVrVk9ZSmNSemJWOW9XdjRreTEyQnRj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwJBVV95cUxPSFpXbTczOEhpa2VULXEzOWllRGxybkUweVh2cTFmdk9SdXBXQ2Zrb2lFRGJTelIxQW1HMUxuNmxFdlI4SXJFQTlUa2JPcUtWeFZfU2xZSFRKRjZiOExZM0R6aHktcHpSVnQtMVVpS1Y3Ql9LZms2R0NsU2hQZXFGWUktX3FZQ3B0ZjNWM2hVMURmTmdOYmFEMzVyRk5DckJqM0RkdnNYNThZQUZaNTNuWUM4NlBaUTltZlVnWUxfLXVNMEhVYTFvLXJfTFdQbGkwU0gtRGtmbWw2Q2Z2cThObzY5dmxmLW9aSGZrZUxHdk0zLVAxTlBZejVrVk9ZSmNSemJWOW9XdjRreTEyQnRj?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 16:18:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Serie A line-ups: Torino vs. Juventus - Football Italia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTE1wMkdycE9aeVI0NVdQUDM1eEpqRUZPZlVhbkJKa2NXdXlFSXczbWRJcmtEcW5IS0kyZXNzeE9ta0ItTng3VG9NM3FGQ1N2dHJ4VnhGN19JZVY2aDduTlNvRWJfcmF3SklUeDNSRjlEdGR0NDE5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTE1wMkdycE9aeVI0NVdQUDM1eEpqRUZPZlVhbkJKa2NXdXlFSXczbWRJcmtEcW5IS0kyZXNzeE9ta0ItTng3VG9NM3FGQ1N2dHJ4VnhGN19JZVY2aDduTlNvRWJfcmF3SklUeDNSRjlEdGR0NDE5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 16:07:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mohun Bagan vs East Bengal Highlights, ISL 2024-25: Jamie Maclaren Scores As MBSG Beat EBFC 1-0 - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohun Bagan vs East Bengal Highlights, ISL 2024-25: Jamie Maclaren Scores As MBSG Beat EBFC 1-0</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>In a thrilling encounter in the Indian Super League, Mohun Bagan Super Giant triumphed over East Bengal FC, with Jamie Maclaren scoring the decisive goal to secure a 1-0 victory.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The match featured a strong performance from both teams, but Mohun Bagan showcased superior tactics.</li>
  <li>Jamie Maclaren's goal was pivotal, solidifying MBSG's position in the league.</li>
  <li>Fans celebrated the hard-fought victory, with highlights showcasing key plays and moments from the match.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This win is crucial for our season. We showed resilience and skill on the field today.” - Coach of Mohun Bagan</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the match reflected the competitive spirit of the ISL, reinforcing the rivalry between these two storied clubs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/indian-super-league/mohun-bagan-vs-east-bengal-live-score-indian-super-league-2024-25-football-match-live-scorecard-updates-7450753</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/indian-super-league/mohun-bagan-vs-east-bengal-live-score-indian-super-league-2024-25-football-match-live-scorecard-updates-7450753</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:54:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Reasons Gambhir Selected Samson Over Pant For England T20Is - OneCricket]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>3 Reasons Why Sanju Samson Has Been Selected Over Rishabh Pant In England T20Is</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Publication date unavailable] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source unavailable]</p><img width="474" alt="Sanju Samson has been preferred over Rishabh Pant" src="https://onecricketnews.akamaized.net/parth-editor/oc-dashboard/news-images-prod/1736609878415_Sanju_Samson_Pant.jpg" height="240"><figcaption>Sanju Samson has been preferred over Rishabh Pant (Source:@riseup_pant17/X.com)</figcaption><p>India's squad for the England T20Is has significant changes, including the return of Mohammed Shami and the selection of Sanju Samson as the preferred wicketkeeper over Rishabh Pant.</p><ul><li>Sanju Samson has demonstrated impressive form in recent T20Is, scoring three centuries in five matches.</li><li>Rishabh Pant's exclusion is also due to workload management as he recovers from a major accident, with an upcoming Champions Trophy on the horizon.</li><li>Competition in India's middle order has increased, making Pant's spot less secure due to the presence of versatile players.</li></ul><blockquote>“Rishabh Pant deserves to get some rest.”</blockquote><p>The Indian selectors' decision to favor Sanju Samson over Rishabh Pant reflects both performance metrics and strategic planning for upcoming tournaments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://cricket.one/cricket-analysis/3-reasons-why-sanju-samson-has-been-selected-over-rishabh-pant-in-england-t20is/67829243e58fb45f95ca66bc</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cricket.one/cricket-analysis/3-reasons-why-sanju-samson-has-been-selected-over-rishabh-pant-in-england-t20is/67829243e58fb45f95ca66bc</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 15:46:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>