<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Sports Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:24:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Sports.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:24:16 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive | Father played with Joe Root’s dad, son to partner Virat Kohli: Jacob Bethell’s rise to RCB’s - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/ipl/top-stories/exclusive-father-played-with-joe-roots-dad-son-to-partner-virat-kohli-jacob-bethells-rise-to-rcbs-rs-2-6-crore-star/articleshow/116604857.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/ipl/top-stories/exclusive-father-played-with-joe-roots-dad-son-to-partner-virat-kohli-jacob-bethells-rise-to-rcbs-rs-2-6-crore-star/articleshow/116604857.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Don't cry because its over': Heartfelt sentiments from R Ashwin with the Indian flag as the backdrop - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Don't cry because its over': Heartfelt sentiments from R Ashwin with the Indian flag as the backdrop</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116605370,imgsize-38078,width-400,resizemode-4/116605370.jpg" alt="R Ashwin (X Photo)"><figcaption>R Ashwin shares a heartfelt moment as he announces his retirement.</figcaption><p>India's premier off-spinner, R Ashwin, announced his retirement from international cricket while reflecting on his journey, expressing gratitude and fond memories.</p><ul><li>Ashwin retired mid-series against Australia, marking the end of a storied international career.</li><li>He is India's second-highest wicket-taker in Test cricket, with 537 wickets.</li><li>The farewell photo featured a smiling Ashwin with the Indian national flag in the background.</li><li>Despite his retirement, he affirmed he still has cricket left in him.</li><li>Ashwin's career spanned various formats, amassing significant wicket totals in ODIs and T20Is as well.</li></ul><blockquote>“Don't cry because it's over, smile because it happened.”</blockquote><p>R Ashwin's retirement emphasizes the end of an era for Indian cricket, celebrated for his skill, intellect, and contributions to the game.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/dont-cry-because-its-over-heartfelt-sentiments-from-r-ashwin-with-the-indian-flag-as-the-backdrop/articleshow/116604394.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/dont-cry-because-its-over-heartfelt-sentiments-from-r-ashwin-with-the-indian-flag-as-the-backdrop/articleshow/116604394.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Clots In Brain": On Vinod Kambli's Urgent Hospitalisation, Doctor Gives Worrying Update - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxQektwVjVodlRfdmdha2pxM1AwUVBLaUxjV0JzV1VxU3BQS21tdjg1a3BINWxjQ2luS0NhbFRrQlNHSHZqR2ZrRjNDam5TdEFNemhwdHhVMHVLekEtOE94MHlkX3VpX2JremhzTzgxQ2N0OGlDRElNS3k1MWxvdzNaellDZExsV01VWXBNUy1RMV9Qa3JDM0lUWG9obmJ6UnlfYkV4d3FoUGJaektOZ2dXeXl3NE5UVzlhLWY5dzRjME02d9IBygFBVV95cUxNVnl1d0oxc3NTbGU1TEFyS1N5MmN2aTJPckFneGxud2NhbFR1WUhGOG5iSWRmc0t0MWdDMGpkdFZ2ckx2V3lwcW5qX0ROTmRUMzZwcVFlVmhKWkVsRFI2aDQxbERMdEx1b2cyVHRhY3NqS0dzMFdDY01tc3JXclhMWXBjRTVPUG9RUGttWU5GRWt0dnR3b19uTXRHaE1kczJlZGptTkZYWThEc3ZTSDFkOENxdmpSb0pkNzMwSEVTUkZUcnhqSlhjMXdn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxQektwVjVodlRfdmdha2pxM1AwUVBLaUxjV0JzV1VxU3BQS21tdjg1a3BINWxjQ2luS0NhbFRrQlNHSHZqR2ZrRjNDam5TdEFNemhwdHhVMHVLekEtOE94MHlkX3VpX2JremhzTzgxQ2N0OGlDRElNS3k1MWxvdzNaellDZExsV01VWXBNUy1RMV9Qa3JDM0lUWG9obmJ6UnlfYkV4d3FoUGJaektOZ2dXeXl3NE5UVzlhLWY5dzRjME02d9IBygFBVV95cUxNVnl1d0oxc3NTbGU1TEFyS1N5MmN2aTJPckFneGxud2NhbFR1WUhGOG5iSWRmc0t0MWdDMGpkdFZ2ckx2V3lwcW5qX0ROTmRUMzZwcVFlVmhKWkVsRFI2aDQxbERMdEx1b2cyVHRhY3NqS0dzMFdDY01tc3JXclhMWXBjRTVPUG9RUGttWU5GRWt0dnR3b19uTXRHaE1kczJlZGptTkZYWThEc3ZTSDFkOENxdmpSb0pkNzMwSEVTUkZUcnhqSlhjMXdn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Clots In Brain": On Vinod Kambli's Urgent Hospitalisation, Doctor Gives Worrying Details - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli Hospitalized Due to Brain Clots: Doctor Provides Update</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/0g2i692o_vinod-kambli_625x300_23_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Vinod Kambli Hospitalized" /><figcaption>Vinod Kambli was hospitalized on Saturday night.</figcaption><p>Vinod Kambli, the former India cricketer, has been hospitalized with brain clots following initial complaints of a urinary infection. Doctors have reported that his condition remains critical but stable.</p><ul><li>Kambli was admitted to Akruti Hospital in Thane after experiencing urinary issues and cramps.</li><li>Medical examinations revealed clots in his brain; ongoing monitoring and further tests are scheduled.</li><li>Dr. Vivek Trivedi stated that Kambli's health is being closely observed.</li><li>Life-long free treatment has been pledged by the hospital in-charge, S Singh.</li><li>Kambli's recent health struggles have gained public attention, particularly due to viral videos showing his condition.</li></ul><blockquote>Kambli said, "I am better now. My wife takes care of me a lot... My son picked me up and brought me back to my feet."</blockquote><p>The situation remains serious as doctors continue to monitor Kambli's health, and further updates are anticipated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/clots-in-brain-on-vinod-kamblis-urgent-hospitalisation-doctor-gives-worrying-details-7315795</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/cricket/clots-in-brain-on-vinod-kamblis-urgent-hospitalisation-doctor-gives-worrying-details-7315795</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:02:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Not Able To Do The Job": Cheteshwar Pujara's Unfiltered Dig At India Duo Ahead of Boxing Day Test - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Not Able To Do The Job: Cheteshwar Pujara's Unfiltered Dig At India Duo Ahead of Boxing Day Test</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/ncp464uo_cheteshwar-pujara-insta_625x300_10_December_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" title="Not Able To Do The Job: Cheteshwar Pujara's Unfiltered Dig At India Duo Ahead of Boxing Day Test">
<figcaption>Cheteshwar Pujara working as a pundit during Border-Gavaskar Trophy</figcaption>
<p>Cheteshwar Pujara expresses concerns over the Indian bowling attack's ability to take 20 wickets in Tests ahead of the critical Boxing Day Test against Australia, emphasizing the team's need for improvement in their bowling depth and top-order batting performance.</p>
<ul>
<li>Pujara questions the current effectiveness of India’s bowling attack, particularly their fourth and fifth bowlers.</li>
<li>The series is currently tied at 1-1, with crucial matches in Melbourne and Sydney ahead.</li>
<li>Concerns about the top-order batting alongside the bowling dilemma, with specific reference to Mitchell Starc's outstanding performance.</li>
<li>Pujara criticizes the lack of support for Jasprit Bumrah and the need for a stronger team composition.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Pujara stated, "To win a Test match, you have to take 20 wickets, and the ability to take 20 wickets is not that good." </blockquote>
<p>Overall, Pujara emphasizes the need for strategic adjustments in both bowling and batting if India aims to secure victory in the remaining Test matches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/not-able-to-do-the-job-cheteshwar-pujaras-unfiltered-dig-at-india-duo-7313114</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/not-able-to-do-the-job-cheteshwar-pujaras-unfiltered-dig-at-india-duo-7313114</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:46:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kuldeep Yadav doubtful for Champions Trophy, inclusion for England series under threat - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kuldeep Yadav Doubtful for Champions Trophy as Recovery Continues</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CricTracker</p><p>The Indian cricket team is preparing for the Champions Trophy 2025 but faces uncertainty with star spinner Kuldeep Yadav's upcoming participation due to a groin injury.</p><ul><li>India is set to participate in the Champions Trophy in February 2025, hosted by UAE and Pakistan.</li><li>Kuldeep Yadav is recovering from a groin injury and recent surgery, limiting his chances for selection in upcoming matches against England.</li><li>His coach remains hopeful of his early return to training and potential inclusion in the Champions Trophy.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kuldeep is yet to start bowling... it’s not impossible but tough (for Kuldeep to return) as just over a month remains for those games to begin.”</blockquote><p>The situation regarding Kuldeep's fitness is critical as the tournament approaches, with his coach optimistic about his chances of recovery in time for the Champions Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-news/kuldeep-yadav-doubtful-champions-trophy-inclusion-england-series-threat/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.crictracker.com/cricket-news/kuldeep-yadav-doubtful-champions-trophy-inclusion-england-series-threat/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tanush Kotian to join India squad; Shami deemed unfit - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tanush Kotian Joins India Squad as Shami Remains Unfit</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Mon, Dec 23, 2024, 01:04 PM</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Cricbuzz</p>
<img src="/a/img/v1/595x396/i1/c590494/kotian-was-recently-a-part-of.jpg" alt="Kotian was recently a part of the India A side which toured Australia">
<figcaption>Kotian was recently a part of the India A side which toured Australia © Getty</figcaption>
<p>Tanush Kotian, a promising offspinning all-rounder from Mumbai, is set to join India’s squad for the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy after Ravichandran Ashwin's retirement announcement.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kotian is expected to arrive in Melbourne ahead of the third Test.</li>
  <li>He has been a key player in Mumbai's cricket scenes, especially in the Vijay Hazare Trophy.</li>
  <li>Statistics: Kotian has played 33 first-class games, scoring 1525 runs and taking 101 wickets.</li>
  <li>Shami has been ruled unfit to play due to a knee issue, hampering his return to international cricket.</li>
  <li>Shami's progress will be closely monitored by the BCCI Medical Team for future matches.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Shami experienced swelling in his left knee due to bowling workload, indicating he is not ready for selection.”</blockquote>
<p>This move represents a significant shift in the team as they prepare for the high-stakes matches ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132879/tanush-kotian-to-join-india-squad-shami-deemed-unfit</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cricbuzz.com/cricket-news/132879/tanush-kotian-to-join-india-squad-shami-deemed-unfit</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 13:07:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pat Cummins story: The Aussie in habit of turning lemons into lemonade - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Journey of Pat Cummins: Turning Challenges into Success</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Cummins_c3dff9.jpg?resize=600,338" alt="Cummins in action"><figcaption>Pat Cummins in action. (FILE photo)</figcaption><p>Pat Cummins, Australian cricket captain, has faced numerous challenges throughout his career, from injuries to personal crises, but he has consistently turned these adversities into opportunities for growth and success.</p><ul><li>Cummins experienced a heartfelt moment before the 2021 Ashes, contemplating his newborn son.</li><li>As a child, he suffered a finger injury that affected his bowling style but did not deter his passion for cricket.</li><li>After a promising debut, Cummins faced injuries that caused him to restructure his approach to the game with mentoring from legends.</li><li>His experiences include a significant weight loss episode during a Bangladesh tour, which motivated him to prioritize fitness.</li><li>During the COVID-19 pandemic, he dealt with his mother's cancer diagnosis, leading to personal growth and reflection.</li><li>He faced public criticism over his environmental stance as a captain, which led to him founding 'Cricket for Climate'.</li></ul><blockquote>“I learned a few things about the impermanence of life and the importance of each day.” - Pat Cummins</blockquote><p>Overall, Cummins exemplifies resilience, utilizing every crisis as a stepping stone for personal and professional development in his cricketing journey.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/india-vs-australia-border-gavaskar-trophy-pat-cummins-9740806/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/sports/cricket/india-vs-australia-border-gavaskar-trophy-pat-cummins-9740806/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:42:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rogers, middle order help Renegades edge past Scorchers despite late hiccups - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxOZkk0emdySW5SOC02YlZjYXpHZF9FcHEyaXdESHNtZ0Z0VGZPUldwVl9pcU1QVEl0V1Qyb29HV2lSS1dQNFBsY1B0V3hXTktrR0gxem43R0F3ektxekdiSVEzOF9MQjUyNzZ3REVnNGpwcHVqcGtZNkJJdU9DYTg5ejhVV2Zkc0diQ1RGakVVQ0g3T3pSb2t6RjJfWllILWo4R3ZzMXJqa3RLU1kxdHVYM1ZfWXRiX0p1N094aDRYT3o4YWdYbWpGc1ZwODlCNDJJblVXSg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxOZkk0emdySW5SOC02YlZjYXpHZF9FcHEyaXdESHNtZ0Z0VGZPUldwVl9pcU1QVEl0V1Qyb29HV2lSS1dQNFBsY1B0V3hXTktrR0gxem43R0F3ektxekdiSVEzOF9MQjUyNzZ3REVnNGpwcHVqcGtZNkJJdU9DYTg5ejhVV2Zkc0diQ1RGakVVQ0g3T3pSb2t6RjJfWllILWo4R3ZzMXJqa3RLU1kxdHVYM1ZfWXRiX0p1N094aDRYT3o4YWdYbWpGc1ZwODlCNDJJblVXSg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:23:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shami ruled out of remaining two Border-Gavaskar Trophy Tests - ESPNcricinfo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mohammed Shami Ruled Out of Remaining Two Tests in Border-Gavaskar Trophy</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> ESPN Cricinfo</p><p>Indian cricketer <a href="https://www.espncricinfo.com/cricketers/mohammed-shami-481896">Mohammed Shami</a> has been ruled out of the fourth and fifth Tests in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy due to swelling in his left knee, as per a BCCI press release.</p><ul><li>Shami recently played for Bengal and had a busy schedule leading up to the Tests.</li><li>His knee swelling is attributed to increased workload from recent bowling activities.</li><li>The BCCI medical team recommends more time for recovery before he can return to play.</li></ul><blockquote>“The swelling is on the expected lines, owing to the increased bowling after a prolonged period.”</blockquote><p>Shami has been recovering from a heel injury and will continue strength and conditioning work. His participation in the ongoing Vijay Hazare Trophy will depend on his knee condition.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/mohammed-shami-ruled-out-of-last-two-border-gavaskar-trophy-tests-1466329</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.espncricinfo.com/story/mohammed-shami-ruled-out-of-last-two-border-gavaskar-trophy-tests-1466329</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 12:21:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who is Tanush Kotian? R Ashwin's replacement for India vs Australia series - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who is Tanush Kotian? R Ashwin's Replacement for India vs Australia Series</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116602932,imgsize-50236,width-400,resizemode-4/116602932.jpg" alt="Who is Tanush Kotian? R Ashwin's replacement for India vs Australia series" title="Tanush Kotian (X Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Tanush Kotian (X Photo)</figcaption><p>Tanush Kotian, an all-rounder from Mumbai, is set to join the Indian cricket team as a potential replacement for Ravichandran Ashwin ahead of the Boxing Day Test in Melbourne.</p><ul><li>Kotian has been instructed to prepare for a departure to Australia.</li><li>He recently impressed during his tour with the India A team.</li><li>Kotian performed notably at the Melbourne Cricket Ground, scoring 44 runs batting at No. 8.</li><li>He is currently participating in the Vijay Hazare Trophy with Mumbai.</li><li>Kotian won 'Player of the Tournament' in the Ranji Trophy, contributing to Mumbai's 42nd title.</li><li>His first-class statistics include 2523 runs and 101 wickets across 33 matches.</li></ul><blockquote>“His consistent performance in domestic cricket has propelled him into contention for a spot in the national team.”</blockquote><p>The inclusion of Tanush Kotian marks a significant development in his career and highlights his rising profile in Indian cricket.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/who-is-tanush-kotian-r-ashwins-replacement-for-india-vs-australia-series/articleshow/116600862.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/who-is-tanush-kotian-r-ashwins-replacement-for-india-vs-australia-series/articleshow/116600862.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement In India's Border Gavaskar Trophy Squad Named. Not Axar Patel Or Y.. - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement In India's Border Gavaskar Trophy Squad Named</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/2d0t7bp_ashwin-afp_625x300_20_December_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=806,height=605" alt="Ravichandran Ashwin" width="639" height="479"><figcaption>Ravichandran Ashwin's Replacement in Squad</figcaption><p>The Indian cricket team has selected young Mumbai off-spinner Tanush Kotian to replace Ravichandran Ashwin, who announced his retirement following the third Test in Brisbane.</p><ul><li>Tanush Kotian has played 33 First Class matches, taking 101 wickets.</li><li>Kotian has been included as a precautionary measure and will travel to Australia.</li><li>Originally, Axar Patel was considered for the replacement but opted out due to personal reasons.</li><li>Ashwin retired as India's second-highest wicket-taker in Test cricket.</li></ul><blockquote>"I made myself a promise in 2012, we lost a tricky series against England. I was very early in my career and I was just telling myself we are not gonna lose another one. Ever. And that is what I promised myself," said Ashwin.</blockquote><p>The addition of Kotian underscores the Indian team's strategy to maintain squad strength following Ashwin's retirement.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ravichandran-ashwins-replacement-in-indias-border-gavaskar-trophy-squad-named-not-kuldeep-yadav-or-yuzvendra-chahal-7314817</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/ravichandran-ashwins-replacement-in-indias-border-gavaskar-trophy-squad-named-not-kuldeep-yadav-or-yuzvendra-chahal-7314817</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:52:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horner opens up on Perez’s exit from Red Bull as he says it was Mexican’s decision to ‘take time out’ - Formula 1]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Christian Horner Discusses Sergio Perez’s Decision to Leave Red Bull</h1>
<p><strong>Date: November 14, 2024 | Source: Formula 1</strong></p>
<img src="https://media.formula1.com/image/upload/f_auto,c_limit,w_1440,q_auto/t_16by9Centre/f_auto/q_auto/trackside-images/2024/F1_Grand_Prix_of_Abu_Dhabi___Qualifying/2188679512" alt="Sergio Perez" loading="lazy">
<figcaption><p>Perez enjoyed a strong start to the 2024 campaign but endured a tougher time as the season progressed</p></figcaption>
<p>Christian Horner has provided insight into Sergio Perez’s exit from Red Bull Racing, explaining that the decision was made by Perez himself as he takes time to reflect on his future decisions.</p>
<ul>
<li>Perez had been struggling with performance after a strong start to the 2024 season.</li>
<li>Despite having a contract extension, Perez and Red Bull agreed to part ways.</li>
<li>Liam Lawson is set to replace Perez as Max Verstappen’s teammate in 2025.</li>
<li>Horner emphasizes Perez’s positive contributions to the team, including his role in previous championships.</li>
<li>Perez ended the season eighth in the drivers' championship, significantly behind Verstappen.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We’re sad to see him leave the team, but obviously it’s time for him to spend with his young family as well and reflect on what he wants to do for the future.” - Christian Horner</blockquote>
<p>This exit marks a significant change for Red Bull, with the team now looking ahead to the 2025 season without Perez.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.formula1.com/en/latest/article/horner-opens-up-on-perezs-exit-from-red-bull-as-he-says-it-was-mexicans.6hJV0NVzLqgFbM2ApCMjTh</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.formula1.com/en/latest/article/horner-opens-up-on-perezs-exit-from-red-bull-as-he-says-it-was-mexicans.6hJV0NVzLqgFbM2ApCMjTh</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:31:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: $300 At Stake As Sarfaraz Khan Captains Virat Kohli Ahead Of Boxing Day Test - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sarfaraz Khan Leads Team India in Fun Fielding Drill Ahead of Boxing Day Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><img width="639" height="479" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/8srgsqtg_virat-kohli-sarfaraz-khan-instagram_625x300_23_December_24.jpeg" title="Watch: $300 At Stake As Sarfaraz Khan Captains Virat Kohli Ahead Of Boxing Day Test"><figcaption>Virat Kohli, Sarfaraz Khan in fielding drill</figcaption><p>Ahead of the Boxing Day Test against Australia, Team India participated in an engaging fielding drill with a prize of 300 dollars at stake. The third Test ended in a draw, making the series tied at 1-1.</p><ul><li>India's fielding coach T Dilip explained the target hitting system with three stumps.</li><li>Key objective was to energize the team before net practice.</li><li>Dhruv Jurel's group won the cash prize for the drill.</li></ul><blockquote>“Target hitting with points system. 3 groups led by young captains. Cash reward on the line. Fun, energy and intensity - #TeamIndia gears up for the Melbourne Test with a lively fielding drill with Fielding coach T Dilip,” BCCI announced.</blockquote><p>The Boxing Day Test is set to commence on December 26 at the Melbourne Cricket Ground.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/300-at-stake-as-sarfaraz-khan-captains-virat-kohli-ahead-of-boxing-day-test-watch-7313778</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sports.ndtv.com/australia-vs-india-2024-25/300-at-stake-as-sarfaraz-khan-captains-virat-kohli-ahead-of-boxing-day-test-watch-7313778</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:11:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian chess GM Tania Sachdev slams authorities for lack of recognition in hard-hitting post: ‘Sadly, Delhi has yet to…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian Chess GM Tania Sachdev Calls for Greater Recognition from Delhi Government</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/taniasachdev_1734951508962_1734951513364.jpg" alt="Women's GM Tania Sachdev" title="Women's GM Tania Sachdev asked the Delhi government for more recognition for chess players from the nation's capital.(X)"><figcaption>Women's GM Tania Sachdev asked the Delhi government for more recognition for chess players from the nation's capital.(X)</figcaption><p>In a heartfelt social media post, Women's Grandmaster Tania Sachdev expressed disappointment at the lack of recognition for chess players in Delhi, especially in light of recent successes in Indian chess.</p><ul><li>Tania Sachdev criticizes the Delhi government's lack of support for chess achievers.</li><li>Highlights disparity in recognition compared to Gukesh's celebration in Tamil Nadu.</li><li>Emphasizes her achievements, including a historic bronze in the 2022 Chess Olympiad.</li><li>Calls on Delhi officials to value and support their chess athletes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Having played for India since 2008, it’s disheartening to see a lack of recognition from the Delhi government for achievements in chess.” - Tania Sachdev</blockquote><p>Sachdev's impassioned plea seeks to inspire the government to celebrate and support chess achievements in Delhi, similar to other states in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/indian-chess-gm-tania-sachdev-slams-authorities-for-lack-of-recognition-in-hard-hitting-post-sadly-delhi-has-yet-to-101734951296257.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/sports/others/indian-chess-gm-tania-sachdev-slams-authorities-for-lack-of-recognition-in-hard-hitting-post-sadly-delhi-has-yet-to-101734951296257.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:09:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mumbai all-rounder Tanush Kotian to join India squad ahead of Melbourne Test - Sportstar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mumbai All-Rounder Tanush Kotian Joins India Squad Ahead of Melbourne Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://ss-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/mdny0z/article69019228.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/11908_13_3_2024_18_15_17_1_EMM_8526.JPG" alt="Tanush Kotian" title="Tanush Kotian"><figcaption><p><b>File photo: </b>Kotian has been one of the best off-spinning all-rounders in the Indian domestic circuit. He was previously part of the India A team, which toured Australia ahead of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy series. | Photo Credit: Emmanual Yogini/The Hindu</p></figcaption><p>Tanush Kotian, an impressive off-spinning all-rounder from Mumbai, is set to join the Indian cricket squad for the upcoming Melbourne Test.</p><ul><li>Kotian has been performing exceptionally in the Indian domestic circuit.</li><li>He was a member of the India A team that toured Australia recently.</li><li>His inclusion comes as part of the preparations for the Border-Gavaskar Trophy series.</li></ul><blockquote>"Kotian has been one of the best off-spinning all-rounders in the Indian domestic circuit."</blockquote><p>Kotian's addition to the squad reflects India's commitment to bolster their team with talented individuals ahead of a crucial series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/tanush-kotian-border-gavaskar-trophy-australia-vs-india-squad-mumbai-test-team-call-up-vijay-hazare-trophy/article69018668.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sportstar.thehindu.com/cricket/tanush-kotian-border-gavaskar-trophy-australia-vs-india-squad-mumbai-test-team-call-up-vijay-hazare-trophy/article69018668.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 11:08:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli's Health Deteriorates, Admitted To Hospital. Report Says Condition Stable But... - NDTV Sports]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPem0yVDY3T2dNdWZxOHk3Z0Z0SDVrUEdNekx5ME9ZclN6RmZUa0pTTnI2ZnAwNTF6eFdiaWJsSE9tUkpZQjZhems1YUNXQmdITmtOellBOHFaeVdPMC0ybEdLVHpwZ0MzRVgxeVlHNnhJRm91ZXVOeHFtaFY1ZC1XdG5RNVpNdnQ2LWtXQ1pZMy00dnBZMUVyYVB4eG45bkV5WkRlMi1SX1N5Z3lFajBpd3dONXVLS1dpb1I3bmpvTG5KNUJBY2fSAc4BQVVfeXFMT0pxOXU1TVctWXJ2U1BPSzY0VXFCWDdqWmJqZEJ3NlkzWnVpWFo3bzRHaWphWTlmbXl5ZUtYQUhuN3JkSjRlM3gtSkF5SFcyMEtfYmdJR1l6NVdTRU1zTTRrbzU0UU5vWFhIQmNwWDRCZ0JYaTE4cWhjT1dFcDdFcnFjVElSNGRDN0poQk1EdEJPem95LUI1enNpbTZtcE85YnNJLXVzZjJGTmxvSjJIOGtHS1lpRVBlRXVKS3RZV1p4Rm9yaGVVZXBZLWs5VEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPem0yVDY3T2dNdWZxOHk3Z0Z0SDVrUEdNekx5ME9ZclN6RmZUa0pTTnI2ZnAwNTF6eFdiaWJsSE9tUkpZQjZhems1YUNXQmdITmtOellBOHFaeVdPMC0ybEdLVHpwZ0MzRVgxeVlHNnhJRm91ZXVOeHFtaFY1ZC1XdG5RNVpNdnQ2LWtXQ1pZMy00dnBZMUVyYVB4eG45bkV5WkRlMi1SX1N5Z3lFajBpd3dONXVLS1dpb1I3bmpvTG5KNUJBY2fSAc4BQVVfeXFMT0pxOXU1TVctWXJ2U1BPSzY0VXFCWDdqWmJqZEJ3NlkzWnVpWFo3bzRHaWphWTlmbXl5ZUtYQUhuN3JkSjRlM3gtSkF5SFcyMEtfYmdJR1l6NVdTRU1zTTRrbzU0UU5vWFhIQmNwWDRCZ0JYaTE4cWhjT1dFcDdFcnFjVElSNGRDN0poQk1EdEJPem95LUI1enNpbTZtcE85YnNJLXVzZjJGTmxvSjJIOGtHS1lpRVBlRXVKS3RZV1p4Rm9yaGVVZXBZLWs5VEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:48:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chelsea dealt transfer blow as Enzo Maresca looks to sell exiled star - Metro.co.uk]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://metro.co.uk/2024/12/23/chelsea-dealt-transfer-blow-enzo-maresca-looks-sell-exiled-star-22239427/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://metro.co.uk/2024/12/23/chelsea-dealt-transfer-blow-enzo-maresca-looks-sell-exiled-star-22239427/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PV Sindhu and Venkat Datta make first public appearance as married couple in stunning ethnic attire: Pics - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PV Sindhu and Venkat Datta's Stunning First Appearance as a Married Couple</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/a8cb63be-fd5c-4117-a9d7-3c6aabcf2122_1734949495807_1734949499059.jpg" alt="Badminton star PV Sindhu and entrepreneur Venkat Datta made a stylish debut as a married couple in Hyderabad.(Instagram)"><figcaption>Badminton star PV Sindhu and entrepreneur Venkat Datta made a stylish debut as a married couple in Hyderabad.(Instagram)</figcaption><p>Badminton champion PV Sindhu and entrepreneur Venkat Datta made their first appearance in glam ethnic looks as a married couple in Hyderabad after tying the knot in Udaipur.</p><ul><li>The couple tied the knot on December 22 in an intimate ceremony in Udaipur, Rajasthan.</li><li>Sindhu wore a bright orange Anarkali suit with intricate white embroidery and a matching Bandhani-print dupatta.</li><li>Venkat Datta paired a white kurta with a purple bandhani-printed waistcoat.</li><li>They spoke about their love for family traditions and upcoming wedding reception events.</li></ul><blockquote>“We both love celebrating festivals, and family traditions are incredibly important to us.”</blockquote><p>The couple celebrated their wedding in a private ceremony and plans to continue their family traditions with joy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/fashion/pv-sindhu-and-venkat-datta-make-first-public-appearance-as-married-couple-in-stunning-ethnic-attire-pics-101734948793529.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/fashion/pv-sindhu-and-venkat-datta-make-first-public-appearance-as-married-couple-in-stunning-ethnic-attire-pics-101734948793529.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:42:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli health issues: From alcohol addiction to two heart attacks and other diseases he is suffering - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/vinod-kambli-health-issues-from-alcohol-addiction-to-two-heart-attacks-and-other-diseases-he-is-suffering-415903/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/vinod-kambli-health-issues-from-alcohol-addiction-to-two-heart-attacks-and-other-diseases-he-is-suffering-415903/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:35:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinod Kambli admitted to Thane hospital in critical condition - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vinod Kambli Admitted to Thane Hospital in Critical Condition</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Vinod Kambli, the former Indian cricketer, has been hospitalized in Thane and is reported to be in critical condition. His health has raised concerns among fans and the cricket community.</p><ul><li>Kambli has been experiencing severe health issues recently.</li><li>The exact cause of his critical condition has not been publicly disclosed.</li><li>Fans and former teammates have expressed their support and concern on social media.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are all praying for his speedy recovery." - A former teammate</blockquote><p>This incident has highlighted the importance of health awareness among athletes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-admitted-to-thane-hospital-in-critical-condition/articleshow/116598447.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/news/vinod-kambli-admitted-to-thane-hospital-in-critical-condition/articleshow/116598447.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The puzzle around shooter Manu Bhaker's name missing from Khel Ratna list, now NRAI contacts Sports Minis - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Controversy Over Manu Bhaker's Absence from Khel Ratna Award List</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Unknown | <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='Manu Bhaker'><figcaption>Manu Bhaker, Indian shooter</figcaption><p>The National Rifle Association of India (NRAI) has contacted the Sports Ministry after noticing that shooter Manu Bhaker's name was omitted from the prestigious Khel Ratna award list, raising questions about the selection process.</p><ul><li>The NRAI is concerned about the absence of Manu Bhaker from the Khel Ratna awards.</li><li>Bhaker is a prominent shooter with various accolades to her name.</li><li>The issue brings to light potential flaws in the recognition system for athletes.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have made a formal request to the Sports Ministry to address this oversight.” - NRAI Official</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the challenges faced by athletes in receiving due recognition for their accomplishments, stirring discussions among sports enthusiasts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/more-sports/shooting/the-puzzle-around-shooter-manu-bhakers-name-missing-from-khel-ratna-list/articleshow/116598391.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/more-sports/shooting/the-puzzle-around-shooter-manu-bhakers-name-missing-from-khel-ratna-list/articleshow/116598391.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I laugh when comparisons are made between Virat Kohli and Babar Azam, Steve Smith, or Joe Root: Mohammad Amir - CricTracker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxOQ2F5Z3hLdDY5dmxRV2JBN3hkMmdpVkg1LXhNUDlwQ1dQdmdLSTczQVpUSkJUTVBtV0ZMU19ON25TY3dRNEV6bHdVNVFURFVnNHBmamRZaFpDdmN0X0pYNWo1NzFNRDd0QmU4MldkZHZNTmRveEZIWnhrX2pna2dmZGVVRkpnUGY0YXczNGE3WGhPU0lvYWtYeW1uUTdJT1hnUWEtWF9nVVhwc0N3ZkdjVmY5UC16QWhUNGx1MWVSWVNobGRFeWtQUWZKSWZnT3dTcExfM205c0NJM0VKYXExT2xwUldXTUpz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxOQ2F5Z3hLdDY5dmxRV2JBN3hkMmdpVkg1LXhNUDlwQ1dQdmdLSTczQVpUSkJUTVBtV0ZMU19ON25TY3dRNEV6bHdVNVFURFVnNHBmamRZaFpDdmN0X0pYNWo1NzFNRDd0QmU4MldkZHZNTmRveEZIWnhrX2pna2dmZGVVRkpnUGY0YXczNGE3WGhPU0lvYWtYeW1uUTdJT1hnUWEtWF9nVVhwc0N3ZkdjVmY5UC16QWhUNGx1MWVSWVNobGRFeWtQUWZKSWZnT3dTcExfM205c0NJM0VKYXExT2xwUldXTUpz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunil Gavaskar Slams India For Mistreating R Ashwin: 'Was Denied Even The Honor Of Vice-Captaincy' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunil Gavaskar Criticizes India for Ashwin's Treatment: Denied Vice-Captaincy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="R Ashwin announced his retirement from international cricket on December 18. (Picture Credit: AP)" title="R Ashwin announced his retirement from international cricket on December 18. (Picture Credit: AP)"><figcaption>R Ashwin announced his retirement from international cricket on December 18. (Picture Credit: AP)</figcaption></figure><p>Legendary cricketer Sunil Gavaskar has expressed his disappointment at the Indian team management for not allowing Ravichandran Ashwin the opportunity to serve as vice-captain, despite his leadership capabilities.</p><ul><li>Gavaskar criticized the team management's decision to deny Ashwin the chance to lead in a token Test or bilateral series.</li><li>Ashwin retired with significant contributions, featuring in 106 Tests, and having taken 537 Test wickets.</li><li>Gavaskar pointed out that Ashwin's leadership potential was overlooked in favor of team balance.</li><li>Many believe that Ashwin's exclusion in favor of Washington Sundar for the first Test prompted his retirement decision.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ashwin would have made a fine captain for India, but he was denied even the honor of being the vice-captain.” - Sunil Gavaskar</blockquote><p>The commentary by Gavaskar underlines a broader discussion on how veteran players are treated in the Indian team setup.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/cricket/sunil-gavaskar-slams-india-for-mistreating-r-ashwin-was-denied-even-the-honor-of-vice-captaincy-9165358.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/cricket/sunil-gavaskar-slams-india-for-mistreating-r-ashwin-was-denied-even-the-honor-of-vice-captaincy-9165358.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:56:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A look at Team India's probable Schedule of ICC Champions Trophy 2025 - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Team India's Schedule for ICC Champions Trophy 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://st1.photogallery.ind.sh/wp-content/uploads/indiacom/hybrid-model-for-icc-champions-trophy-2025-202412-1734947359.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Hybrid model for ICC Champions Trophy 2025">
<figcaption>Image credit: X</figcaption>
<p>The ICC Champions Trophy 2025 is approaching with a new hybrid model, ensuring India's matches are hosted in the UAE amidst security concerns over travel to Pakistan.</p>
<ul>
  <li>India will play group stage matches in Dubai against Bangladesh on February 20 and New Zealand on March 2.</li>
  <li>Pakistan will begin the tournament with their first match against New Zealand in Karachi on February 19.</li>
  <li>The semifinal matches are scheduled for March 4 and 5, with the final set for March 9.</li>
  <li>Neutral venues will be used for matches between India and Pakistan to maintain impartiality.</li>
  <li>Hosting all of India's matches in UAE aims to ensure a secure environment.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Given the ongoing political tensions between India and Pakistan, any matches between these two nations will be played at impartial venues."</blockquote>
<p>This tournament promises to be an exciting event, with critical matches taking place in Dubai offering neutral grounds for competing teams.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/photos/sports/a-look-at-team-indias-probable-schedule-of-icc-champions-trophy-2025-415875/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/photos/sports/a-look-at-team-indias-probable-schedule-of-icc-champions-trophy-2025-415875/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:54:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Real Madrid Decides Surprise Signing Of Former Player, Reports SPORT - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Real Madrid Plans Surprise Return for Rafa Marin</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> July 10, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> SPORT</p>
<img src="https://specials-images.forbesimg.com/imageserve/65be17cb80f5c798a03e7762/Real-Madrid-wants-to-sign-Rafa-Mar-n-/960x0.jpg?fit=scale" alt="Real Madrid wants to sign Rafa Marín." />
<figcaption><small>Real Madrid has decided to make a surprise signing according to SPORT, citing anonymous sources, which would see a "prodigal" son return to the Bernabeu if the transfer is really completed.</small></figcaption>
<p>Real Madrid is reportedly looking to sign back Rafa Marin, who was sold to Napoli. This potential transfer is part of their ongoing strategy to strengthen the squad amidst injury challenges.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rafa Marin was sold to Napoli for €12 million, with potential increases to €22 million based on conditions.</li>
  <li>The deal included a buyback clause, a common practice for players from Madrid's academy.</li>
  <li>Marin's return could happen as soon as January 2025 due to the club's defensive injuries.</li>
  <li>The buyback clause is structured with escalating costs depending on the timing of the exercise.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Madrid made sure to include a $27.1 million (€25 million) buy back clause which can be exercised in 2026.”</blockquote>
<p>This strategic move indicates Madrid's confidence in Marin's potential and necessity in addressing current team deficiencies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/tomsanderson/2024/12/23/real-madrid-decides-surprise-signing-of-former-player-reports-sport/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/tomsanderson/2024/12/23/real-madrid-decides-surprise-signing-of-former-player-reports-sport/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:53:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Ashwin has taken retirement...': Cheteshwar Pujara's blunt assessment on India's 'weak' bowling - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cheteshwar Pujara's Concerns About India's Bowling Weakness Post-Ashwin Retirement</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 <br> <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/cricket-sri-ind_e640a040-a9ab-11e7-9239-41e72d00a67f_1734947026996.jpg" alt="Cheteshwar Pujara reckons India's bowling has gotten weaker after the retirement of Ravichandran Ashwin. (AFP)" title="Cheteshwar Pujara reckons India's bowling has gotten weaker after the retirement of Ravichandran Ashwin. (AFP)">
<figcaption>Cheteshwar Pujara reckons India's bowling has gotten weaker after the retirement of Ravichandran Ashwin. (AFP)</figcaption>
<p>In light of Ravinchandran Ashwin's retirement, Cheteshwar Pujara has expressed concerns over the strength of India's bowling unit ahead of the Boxing Day Test.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pujara emphasizes the lack of experience in the bowling department after Ashwin's retirement.</li>
  <li>He highlights that new choices like Nitish Kumar Reddy may not provide strong support.</li>
  <li>Pujara questions the team's ability to take 20 wickets necessary for Test victories.</li>
  <li>India won their first Test at Perth but has been experimenting with different spinner options.</li>
  <li>Border-Gavaskar Trophy is currently tied at 1-1.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“My biggest question and the reason for a little bit of concern is that the Indian bowling is looking a little weak.” - Cheteshwar Pujara</blockquote>
<p>Pujara urges the team management to strengthen their bowling approach to win the upcoming matches in the Border-Gavaskar Trophy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ashwin-has-taken-retirement-cheteshwar-pujaras-blunt-assessment-on-indias-weak-bowling-101734944996196.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/ashwin-has-taken-retirement-cheteshwar-pujaras-blunt-assessment-on-indias-weak-bowling-101734944996196.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:47:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India vs Australia Boxing Day Test: Everything you should know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India vs Australia Boxing Day Test: Everything You Should Know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116596469,imgsize-70580,width-400,resizemode-4/116596469.jpg" alt="India vs Australia Boxing Day Test" title="India vs Australia (AP Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>India vs Australia (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>The Border-Gavaskar Trophy is currently level at 1-1, with the third Test starting on December 26th. This Boxing Day Test is crucial for both teams before the final Test in Sydney.</p><ul><li>The Boxing Day Test is scheduled to be held at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG).</li><li>India won the last encounter at MCG in 2020.</li><li>Australia has historically performed well in Boxing Day Tests, having won five of the first seven matches against India.</li><li>The head-to-head record shows Australia with 46 wins, India with 33 wins, and 30 draws.</li><li>Jasprit Bumrah is six wickets away from his 200th Test wicket.</li></ul><blockquote>Sachin Tendulkar leads most runs scored overall with 3630, and Nathan Lyon holds the record for most wickets overall with 124.</blockquote><p>This Boxing Day Test could shift team dynamics significantly, with implications for the World Test Championship.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/india-vs-australia-boxing-day-test-everything-you-should-know/articleshow/116595822.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/india-vs-australia-boxing-day-test-everything-you-should-know/articleshow/116595822.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wanindu Hasaranga returns for New Zealand ODIs - Cricbuzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQdExlaDVuWW1EVW1SN2kydExUU1JXQUNSOVJPMGcwcV83dEo4YTA5MkFYWUFlSTAyX2VKU1RaR0M4ZHo0TnFwYlpHRTEwWjh3Tk50MGVwTVZRSVhYWFdLOGp1X29pbkhneklMdVV3UXVSZlR0YU9falp3M18wcGNEbzdMTFhKZWl6UElEVXZEdVA5NFgtenc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilgFBVV95cUxQdExlaDVuWW1EVW1SN2kydExUU1JXQUNSOVJPMGcwcV83dEo4YTA5MkFYWUFlSTAyX2VKU1RaR0M4ZHo0TnFwYlpHRTEwWjh3Tk50MGVwTVZRSVhYWFdLOGp1X29pbkhneklMdVV3UXVSZlR0YU9falp3M18wcGNEbzdMTFhKZWl6UElEVXZEdVA5NFgtenc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Perfect' Man Utd Star Ruled Out Until March Due to Injury - GIVEMESPORT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Perfect' Man Utd Star Ruled Out Until March Due to Injury</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Give Me Sport</p><p>Manchester United's Mason Mount has suffered a serious hamstring injury, which could keep him sidelined for up to ten weeks. This setback significantly impacts the team's performance as they look to improve their season.</p><ul><li>Mount's injuries have plagued his time at Manchester United, having played only 14 Premier League matches last season.</li><li>The £55 million signing has become a favorite under new manager Ruben Amorim, despite limited appearances.</li><li>Mount's current injury is described as a hamstring issue caused by a hyperextended leg, with recovery expected to take around ten weeks.</li></ul><blockquote>"Mason Mount, Hamstring injury due to hyperextended leg, Tendon involved, horrible, around 10 weeks out depending on rehab and recovery!!"</blockquote><p>Mount's frustrating season continues as he struggles to maintain a consistent presence on the pitch, missing vital matches for Manchester United.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.givemesport.com/perfect-man-utd-star-ruled-out-until-march-due-to-injury/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.givemesport.com/perfect-man-utd-star-ruled-out-until-march-due-to-injury/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>