<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Technology articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:20:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:20:57 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Facebook, Instagram, and Threads are down]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="The Facebook logo on a blue background with circles" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YKaWLMPTE67yz111ygAOHJn6STE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780875/STK040_VRG_Illo_N_Barclay_7_facebook.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Illustration by Nick Barclay / The Verge</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="xCthAv">A bunch of Meta apps are down right now. For many staffers at <em>The Verge</em>, Facebook, Instagram, and Threads aren’t loading right now and are showing error messages when you try to load them. Reports across Bluesky, X, and Reddit show that many people see the same thing.</p>
<p id="FgpciO">On Facebook, it simply says “We’re working on getting this fixed as soon as we can.”</p>
<p id="J01Ud0">Downdetector is showing big and sudden spikes for Facebook, WhatsApp, Messenger, and Instagram with <em>a lot</em> of people affected by the outages. On the <a href="https://downdetector.com/status/instagram/">Instagram Downdetector</a> page, for example, there have been more than 23,000 reports of issues with the platform, indicating that this is a massive and widespread problem. And more than 25,000 reports have apparently <a href="https://downdetector.com/status/facebook/">come in about Facebook</a>.</p>
<p id="GXSF8L">This big outage follows another large Meta outage <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/5/24091207/meta-outage-facebook-instagram-threads-down-signed-out">from March</a> that took down Facebook, Instagram, and Threads. Meta also saw a major outage affecting Instagram and Facebook <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/10/28/23428969/instagram-facebook-not-loading-refresh-outage">in October 2022</a>.</p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318908/facebook-instagram-threads-down-outage-meta</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318908/facebook-instagram-threads-down-outage-meta</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jay Peters]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:11:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Homey adds new energy management features and a dongle]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wkkRi-tE4I1gbEtVAHaSBuMBI-o=/0x160:3840x2720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780832/Homey_Bridge___Homey_Pro___Mobile_App___Web_App.0.png" />
        <figcaption><em>The Homey smart home platform, which works with the Homey Pro or Homey Bridge hubs, has launched a Home Energy Dongle and energy management tab for its app.</em></figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="ntRUff">Smart home company <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24087882/smart-home-hub-apple-google-alexa#:~:text=other%20platforms%2C%20too).-,Homey%20Pro,-The%20Homey%20Pro">Homey</a> has added a new <a href="https://homey.app/en-us/news/introducing-the-homey-energy-dongle/?draft">energy management tab</a> to its app to track and monitor energy use from compatible smart devices such as plugs, appliances, thermostats, and EV chargers. This week, the company also announced the <a href="https://homey.app/en-us/news/introducing-the-homey-energy-dongle">Homey Energy Dongle</a> for Europe, which can connect directly to a smart meter to monitor a home’s energy consumption.</p>
<p id="foZCHS">Together, the software and hardware are a big step toward a full <a href="https://www.gridx.ai/knowledge/home-energy-management-system-hems">home energy management system</a>. Homey says it plans to bring support for <a href="https://homey.app/en-us/news/introducing-the-homey-energy-dongle/?draft#:~:text=Once%20dynamic%20tariffs,at%20their%20lowest.">automatic dynamic energy pricing</a> next year, so users could set up automations to do things like charge their EV when electricity prices are low. </p>
<p id="EZBCpe">The new energy management tab is available in public beta to all <a href="https://homey.app/en-us/homey-pro/">Homey Pro</a> and <a href="https://homey.app/en-us/homey/">Homey Cloud</a> customers, and the <a href="https://homey.app/homey-energy-dongle/">dongle can be preordered</a> for €39 if you’re in the Netherlands, Belgium, Luxembourg, Denmark, Sweden, Finland, Lithuania, Austria, Switzerland, and Hungary, with shipping expected in March 2025.</p>
<figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4ZLd77vHSGUL9vvTC7rzE9OpD60=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25785060/Homey_Energy_Dongle___4.png">
      <cite>Image: Homey</cite>
      <figcaption><em>The Homey Energy Dongle works with European smart meters and uses the P1 standard to monitor electricity and gas usage.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="6XKzgK">Homey is a smart home platform centered around a smart home hub, either the powerful, locally based <a href="https://homey.app/en-us/homey-pro/">Homey Pro ($399)</a> or the lighter <a href="https://homey.app/en-us/homey-bridge/">Homey Bridge ($69)</a>. Depending on which hub you have, Homey can connect to and control a <a href="https://homey.app/en-us/apps/homey-pro/">wide range of smart home devices</a> thanks to radios for Zigbee, Z-Wave, Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, Thread, IR, and more; there’s also the option of cloud-based connections and compatibility with other bridges, such as Philips Hue. Homey also supports the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23568091/matter-compatible-devices-accessories-apple-amazon-google-samsung">Matter smart home standard</a>.</p>
<p id="9EvJOt">“The Energy Management functionality works with all devices connected to a Homey setup, no matter if they use a proprietary local/cloud API, Zigbee, Z-Wave or Matter to connect to Homey,” explained Homey commercial director Stefan Witkamp in an email to <em>The Verge</em>. A full list of <a href="https://homey.app/en-us/apps/browse/#filter?category=energy&amp;platform=local">currently compatible devices</a> is on Homey’s website.</p>
<figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n7GpraN_sviMba6gR8YhZnkHF0M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25785054/Mobile_App___Energy__Dark_.png">
      <cite>Image: Homey</cite>
      <figcaption><em>The new energy management tab in Homey can track energy usage across connected devices in your home. </em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="5zZrgA">The energy tab uses charts to show a home’s live electricity, gas, and water usage (with compatible hardware) and can provide historical data. Homey says it “can also track solar generation, monitor EV charging, and show energy supply to, or consumption from, the grid.” It’s compatible with smart batteries and can show a list of your top energy consumers, helpful for figuring out where to cut down on usage. You can enter your energy price to get cost estimates, and Homey says it plans to add support for dynamic pricing next year.</p>
<p id="IWDwi2"><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/3/24191422/lg-homey-athom-acquisition-samsung-smartthings">LG acquired Homey</a> earlier this year and has said it plans to incorporate Homey’s connectivity and software <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/16/24243056/lg-thinq-smart-home-platform-thinq-on-hub">into its ThinQ platform</a>. However, Homey will continue to operate independently. While LG plans to integrate its appliances with Homey, official support is still on the roadmap, says Witkamp. </p>
<p id="xrR0OR">Energy management is set to play a key part in the smart home as a compelling reason to connect all your devices. Allowing a system to automate energy use in your home could save you energy and money. Several smart home companies already offer some functionality here. Samsung’s <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.samsung.com%2Fus%2Fhome-appliances%2Fsmartthings%2Fenergy%2F&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F11%2F24318680%2Fhomey-lg-smart-home-energy-management-features" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">SmartThings Energy</a> platform, which works with its appliances and several partner devices, was the first platform to be recognized by the Environmental Protection Agency as an <a href="https://www.energystar.gov/products/recent_program_updates/samsungs-smart-home-energy-service-earns-energy-star">Energy STAR Smart Home Energy Management System</a>. Others, such as Home Assistant, offer some energy management features, and Apple introduced an electricity usage page to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/10/24172054/apple-home-homekit-robot-vacuum-support-smart-locks-wwdc24#:~:text=A%20new%20electricity%20usage%20page%20in%20the%20Home%20app%E2%80%99s%20Energy%20section%20will%20show%20your%20electricity%20usage%20through%20a%20connection%20to%20your%20utility.%20It%20will%20launch%20with%20a%20partnership%20with%20PG%26E%20in%20California%20but%20hopefully%20expand%20to%20more%20utilities%20in%20the%20future.">its Home app this year</a> (although it’s limited to PG&amp;E customers). </p>
<p id="uMBjBp">The new Matter smart home standard just <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/7/24289972/matter-smart-home-standard-1-4-spec-new-features-device-types">added energy management</a> to its spec along with support for several key devices in the space — electrical vehicle supply equipment, solar panel inverters, home batteries, and more. All of this shows significant momentum in home energy management, and Homey’s latest move is another option for people looking to use smart home tech to maximize the efficiency of their energy use and minimize their costs. </p>
<p id="uT4Fud"></p>
<p id="NX3WvQ"></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318680/homey-lg-smart-home-energy-management-features</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318680/homey-lg-smart-home-energy-management-features</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Pattison Tuohy]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft starts testing iPhone file sharing for Windows PCs]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="Illustration of Microsoft’s Windows logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4X1Fi6270URCT93DSB-O1-BX-W0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780827/acastro_STK109_microsoft_02.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="n7KlcW">Microsoft has started testing some improvements to its Phone Link app for iPhone users. Windows Insiders <a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2024/12/11/sharing-files-between-your-iphone-and-windows-pc-rolling-out-to-windows-insiders/">can now try out</a> a new way to share a file from an iPhone to a PC and vice versa, making the experience a little more like file sharing with an Android device.</p>
<p id="o1O1kK">Windows Insiders can download the latest Phone Link app update, version 1.24112.89.0 or higher, and it will include a new setup dialog to enable sharing files between iPhones and PCs. The sharing works by using the share sheet on iOS to send files to the “Link to Windows” app, which then lets you select a Windows device to share the file with.</p>
<p id="DRVGJk">On a Windows PC you can also share local files by right clicking on a file and selecting share and then “my phone” to get a file from your PC to your iPhone. </p>
<figure class="e-image">
        <img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/N91ZmZCRtkBXb8v6iFic9cChDp0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25785677/phone_link_ios_setup.png">
      <cite>Image: Microsoft</cite>
      <figcaption><em>The new file sharing dialog for iPhone users.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="7TWGot">Microsoft has been gradually improving its Phone Link app for both iOS and Android in recent years, but the iOS version is still very limited thanks to Apple’s OS restrictions. Last year Microsoft did manage to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/3/24/23654672/microsoft-phone-link-hands-on-imessage-ios">update Phone Link</a> with the ability to send and receive messages via iMessage. Even this integration is limited though, only supporting sending and receiving messages to single contacts and not groups (via iMessage).</p>
<p id="naTaW6">You still can’t use the Phone Link app to mirror phone apps onto your PC like you can with Android, and you have to have the app open for messages to be sent over iMessage as Microsoft is using a Bluetooth and system notifications workaround to read send messages.</p>
<p id="ys9aP7">The latest file sharing update is live now for Windows Insiders and should start rolling out to all Phone Link users in the coming months.</p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318886/microsoft-phone-link-file-sharing-ios-windows-pcs</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318886/microsoft-phone-link-file-sharing-ios-windows-pcs</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tom Warren]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:59:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Xbox tests streaming your Xbox games to your Xbox]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="Vector collage of the Xbox logo." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tciD1LrGlvCbeHk4TumOKz9z6Oo=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780825/STK048_XBOX2__A.5.png" />
        <figcaption>Image: The Verge</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="dtLomd">Microsoft is going to let Xbox Insiders who also subscribe to Game Pass Ultimate test the ability to stream some Xbox games they already own to their Xbox <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/12/11/xbox-insiders-with-game-pass-ultimate-stream-your-own-game-on-xbox-consoles/">starting today</a>. The feature could be useful if you want to jump into a game without having to install the whole thing; given how big game file sizes can be nowadays, streaming a game via the cloud might be a faster way to play or save you from hitting a data cap. </p>
<p id="XMGHfs">Microsoft has published a list of games that support the feature <a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fplay%2Fgallery%2Fbuy-and-stream&amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F11%2F24318876%2Fxbox-tests-streaming-games-console" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank">on its website</a>. There are some great games on the list, including <em>Animal Well</em>, <em>Balatro</em>, <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>, <em>Cyberpunk 2077,</em> and <em>Price of Persia: The Lost Crown</em>.</p>
<p id="tSZbUv">You’ll be able to stream games on Xbox Series X / S and Xbox One consoles, Microsoft says, and the feature is set to come out of testing next year. The company started letting Xbox players stream select games they own on TVs and browsers <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/20/24300547/xbox-cloud-gaming-game-library-streaming">last month</a>.</p>
<p id="3PJikO"></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318876/xbox-tests-streaming-games-console</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318876/xbox-tests-streaming-games-console</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jay Peters]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:59:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Here’s how OpenAI uses your data when you use ChatGPT through Apple’s integrations]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Following Apple’s integration of OpenAI’s ChatGPT within iOS 18, iPadOS 18, and macOS Sequoia, OpenAI has detailed how your data is handled when you use ChatGPT through Apple’s integration.  You can use ChatGPT through Apple’s integrations without logging into a ChatGPT account, but you get access to additional features if you log into your account. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/11/heres-how-openai-uses-your-data-when-you-use-chatgpt-through-apples-integrations/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/11/heres-how-openai-uses-your-data-when-you-use-chatgpt-through-apples-integrations/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:12:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stigg makes it easy to change your SaaS pricing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Stigg (not The Stig, just Stigg) describes itself as &#8220;the first scalable monetization platform for the modern billing stack.&#8221; There&#8217;s a lot going on in that sentence, but what it comes down to is that the startup, which on Wednesday announced a $17.5 million Series A round, helps SaaS companies model pricing, create pricing pages, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/11/stigg-makes-it-easy-to-change-your-saas-pricing/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/11/stigg-makes-it-easy-to-change-your-saas-pricing/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:04:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[GM Is Restructuring Cruise. Tesla and Waymo Will Fight for the Robotaxi Market. - Barron's]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE9oVW51Rnd6cm5SVnFwV2REMFEwUFI0ejY1VjBoQjlUOVJMU2dzYS1GR0g2cVVGaDRBeWFUQmFvT1FMTllkbGRaeEhKT2lVY3lpbnE2TFRzQjcySTkxLXdDYmZwNnRYd3NtLTg4S0lEdkRlX3lsaU1SaGxMbETSAYIBQVVfeXFMTjRST0l2bGUyTVFpejlqbk1iRDZwVnZPUTBVU19MaWJXN1REY29Xb1dfdFJtTEZtNW13VFdCM0cyWVJLWi1QWmREOEhBQ1BXVVRwZGdmdmtvVm10eFJWR0UySE51NUc1cEtIdDl3OThoQzlqZUhXY0hlQXFVT1B2VlhKUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">GM Is Restructuring Cruise. Tesla and Waymo Will Fight for the Robotaxi Market.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Barron's</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxQSFJLaWpNRlg0SVA4THQ2QnRFYzRYSFN2T3hHS01PLUNkTW0tQjMxRkNLLWVNV250RkZxLUZxY1lMOEtGMXlNaVhXRXZIYmlNS3BGVlZKODFCcWhDcHlwT0xaU3NReXUtTFp3LTVVNU9YVHh1allZc0hvbV9JVkR3WnlPdWhNdkRzcWE5SzRlZFHSAZYBQVVfeXFMTjhha0trRENlQXhHNUF4eUZvVldrOW1fUjhCUkdfY0R6QmhaSEJXVDl2NXRaLTdueG1uN2pyWU1FRjM0eGRRTjVVV19QSDlfUEd3UEJIT3hOWHBabjNONlhqYmJDUGhLekhyR0dhdjYxcVd3NmR6a2hYd3U3RU1tc2tocDZMSWlSaTdzbHlOZVF6eldzSWh3?oc=5" target="_blank">GM exits robotaxi market, will bring Cruise operations in house</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxOenV5QWltRGFubTNiNHlmcTB0aDctZDFZQWdSczlWU3BKSTNWT0R0VXppV3AySHhtODFxODJBR3pxanBZSGxxMlBUNDVJcENvbl9LNlFnZkc5MDhvN2V0TW9jQlpFVnNCZ2hZbGk1aXJjNTdYc1MwMVM5bjRicWlhN05kZFFsa0kxT29rMHM4Rzd6TzJCNk1CS1Y5cERNT3JBOC1RSWxtN0RxRG5ROFE?oc=5" target="_blank">Honda to end self-driving tie-up with GM as Cruise unit founders</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Nikkei Asia</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxQZENiMHBEMVNYTkxzQVIwNVVTY1g2cW9lNFJYR2NQY01laFQ3X0pnWU50QjIwdFUwQ2V0WDRIelhrT2JrZXlGSjZYTjA1Nk1WUjlsbE9SUGZjVGhVVUVHYk4weTVlOHBfcTZIVGVHNnZSQU5wWHFZZ0ctNC1leW9fVy1jUlN3eEVTSWY1NA?oc=5" target="_blank">GM's Cruise Overhaul Sparks Uncertainty Over Uber AV Alliance and 2025 Plans</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo Finance</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidkFVX3lxTFByRlRUbDJTUlI4ZUhXV0VEaGxwT0lGd3hQaVd6b1hab2JRUzE4Y0Z2VFNhcVhESlBQcFdwbk1wNmdvMDJjX0lYTmxoNG5CUUMtcDgyMWFBX1lMM01aX2VuN0NBRG1abzlScFA0azItdTBMQ3NSbGc?oc=5" target="_blank">GM to Shut Down Its Cruise Robotaxi Project</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE9oVW51Rnd6cm5SVnFwV2REMFEwUFI0ejY1VjBoQjlUOVJMU2dzYS1GR0g2cVVGaDRBeWFUQmFvT1FMTllkbGRaeEhKT2lVY3lpbnE2TFRzQjcySTkxLXdDYmZwNnRYd3NtLTg4S0lEdkRlX3lsaU1SaGxMbETSAYIBQVVfeXFMTjRST0l2bGUyTVFpejlqbk1iRDZwVnZPUTBVU19MaWJXN1REY29Xb1dfdFJtTEZtNW13VFdCM0cyWVJLWi1QWmREOEhBQ1BXVVRwZGdmdmtvVm10eFJWR0UySE51NUc1cEtIdDl3OThoQzlqZUhXY0hlQXFVT1B2VlhKUQ?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE9oVW51Rnd6cm5SVnFwV2REMFEwUFI0ejY1VjBoQjlUOVJMU2dzYS1GR0g2cVVGaDRBeWFUQmFvT1FMTllkbGRaeEhKT2lVY3lpbnE2TFRzQjcySTkxLXdDYmZwNnRYd3NtLTg4S0lEdkRlX3lsaU1SaGxMbETSAYIBQVVfeXFMTjRST0l2bGUyTVFpejlqbk1iRDZwVnZPUTBVU19MaWJXN1REY29Xb1dfdFJtTEZtNW13VFdCM0cyWVJLWi1QWmREOEhBQ1BXVVRwZGdmdmtvVm10eFJWR0UySE51NUc1cEtIdDl3OThoQzlqZUhXY0hlQXFVT1B2VlhKUQ?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 16:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[HomePod 18.2 upgrades Siri’s most used feature with one big change - 9to5Mac]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNZDNTbXVhc0tDczlRd0FVRjhxclRzZHVVaDlyRldLT0dLdU5yLTNvdkV6ZVIwU0NXZGs4RWswN0M2eTRtQVBnREVxWjJyTTFLZHFTVzJvY2JrVG5tOTg4U0V1cTMwQnh5eXFNbHk4QU85ejZpbEVmX2w4VXhWWldJQVdn?oc=5" target="_blank">HomePod 18.2 upgrades Siri’s most used feature with one big change</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">9to5Mac</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxNRjZDWlo2dTNqdFpydzd5YXlIclRLOEQyOWNrM0NNaUZZR3FIV1Z6aV9JMEF3bUdRT2dWTThsVWk3eVZZeW5GU3V6MDFpUEZXZXA4VUg4b3BTNTJPSVpLTHh4Sk5XdzdsUF9JLXR0TlZWSUExYjJVSVJQZjAyckV6S1FLbHMybXFQM25qUmM0Zkk4MXFCeFZGcQ?oc=5" target="_blank">iOS 18.2 enhances Apple TV and Apple Music with natural language search</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Cult of Mac</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxQLXFObTc2d3dRcU94LTQtVGlNTXJSczBmb0JKMVVZNmd1YzhSZmx5dWI5aDcwUkFhai1EcTlWMWxwaUhGMnZKUVlHbHVfTkozSFlPRnNlWEkyZVF0WllxWU8tR0JrQ0lNSi16eVRYV1RyUU9VTW96dkhtblFhVlVPcnR4cGRnQmdQSjMyTG90N0gycnZQNVNUZzQ1TkVBcW_SAaQBQVVfeXFMTm9CbGxfell1bGFKMlE2RDRULUJXejNyUlN4YTdxX2NKQjNVSjFqREF6OUpoSVpDblRnM243VVN0X0Zoa3B4dEpVOERvSk9WeXBuVjBDOHRrdTNLNFdMLUx0RDhYYXlSTk1LTkVfRXNmMmVVY2x4ay1UTTMyVjljVy1VaW1tYktDaGNvMjVKSHFSMDZ0MHdkQ3VlSlMtZDJuNDc0ajg?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple Seeds HomePod Software Update 18.2 RC to Developers [Download]</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">iClarified</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxOUURpSENqOUVFQml6Ri1LdDFvZ0VzZTc4TEw3TTA0OUJNUnVkVC1RTEVFaXlibHVSUi1LUzI1YTNCMkFfSmRGWE1DR25KSkxwR0I2ZW9OSDVEamV1bDJsR2hlRWVPWTh2YXpGTmtTZS1TcWJXd0JKMmNGSXlLQXBaQXd5U1ROV2xjdUM0dGhzT1A2V2lyNzNyeGtLakJDWHNlMXhiYWRNd0llWnRaaGZDTHhwVGRvdkxnRFFENnJEYWQxZ9IBxwFBVV95cUxOX3NmU1BYQThUMlFpT2gtUVJzakJJQkdsWUtxRWZuLTQxcF9LZE5ldHRFdjVZSTNzM3h0MkFzeE9NNUNZeHV6SExFUlNPMWg0bkRkMV90TnI0TTlTeGpudF81d2dzcGRDZEhQQ2ktYXhaSlFLeEFrVVZVdzdSbmlFY1A5YldYUG5maTJHanNPUHY4V2pwQlh2Rno0ZHkyY0MyRUE2MXhtUTFHZ25oNGltSFVVOWZTUTZibWdhd1UtT1VXazV2Q3Fj?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple releases HomePod 18.2 with new Siri feature: natural language Apple Music requests</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MacDailyNews</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMia0FVX3lxTFBrWG9rcHVZa2lkWlpFS0REb2t2bV9xOVlGOFRIMzVLQzRlS1VDS0EzUHd5QkpCMEFoUTlpZ1hQNGZURjhCdTlvVUEzUUJtT3NLdHZZRGdpdUNTWUFoMUtXTXlLeTltYkp6Q2Zz?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple Releases HomePod Software 18.2 With Natural Language Search for Apple Music</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MacRumors</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNZDNTbXVhc0tDczlRd0FVRjhxclRzZHVVaDlyRldLT0dLdU5yLTNvdkV6ZVIwU0NXZGs4RWswN0M2eTRtQVBnREVxWjJyTTFLZHFTVzJvY2JrVG5tOTg4U0V1cTMwQnh5eXFNbHk4QU85ejZpbEVmX2w4VXhWWldJQVdn?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNZDNTbXVhc0tDczlRd0FVRjhxclRzZHVVaDlyRldLT0dLdU5yLTNvdkV6ZVIwU0NXZGs4RWswN0M2eTRtQVBnREVxWjJyTTFLZHFTVzJvY2JrVG5tOTg4U0V1cTMwQnh5eXFNbHk4QU85ejZpbEVmX2w4VXhWWldJQVdn?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 15:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mysterious, repeating radio bursts from space may finally have an explanation - Livescience.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPRV95VTd0T3FET2M4blhJVXBJVEVGV3lBRzJZTXpkYkd5SXNXdXVCN0FMXy01eFNWMjBkOFpMN1RTakxzeGVSaU16ZURNci10SVo0Z2lzZTNHRWlkeHVOVWVqd1c2RHFOUExleW1fa0FKUlJGQWJfNFUyT1N2MHJib2FJaFc0OWRTQWhLMHo3QVN3WS1jRE9VSVBXWk9rbVJteVVFSWN0QzJsQ1ZJLWlRMnc1Ny0wN19idngtbg?oc=5" target="_blank">Mysterious, repeating radio bursts from space may finally have an explanation</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Livescience.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxNS0JXOS00MnFVVUt5dHc2T3NJQzVpLTdEQnZ1UnRIRUVOR243Z29Mei14bmVJQUpyWThXZ29RcUxwQ3VOSU05aGtIb25oaWFFaVBzMjZLdFVUeWs1UXVsUUFlRjJoTXNwODN1Z3F3R3pNMUtVUTBWUnhvVmYwZWRRYzNIazd4N0o0RzB2Q1RRUV9LZnB5bU82TG9hWnRFV2tNVEs1Q01QenJMWUpiaFpJeXhxVnBrMlN4ZU11dWx6d0VmYjU1bWhvMNIBzgFBVV95cUxQaW1iVWh5S0I5UjFTWUJzZ0RNdGVPTUkwcWFSQW4yT2J4aU95MGtQX1FQVm5lLXJQOVdzTXcwQzFfYVZJSTRxVnBLMUJyTzF5MmZxSERGQW5maEhlVWgxcHlxeXlWWERpcUZHc1lGYkViekdOVjd3STNpZjFoYm1ZdFhLWVR3aEYzcmI2eko2N1ZtSktiTUFuZVJDTVNDbzkzR28wX3dqbXpUTFFLcDdGT3o3bENuN19rbFZjd3BSc1ltUDJNZFg2bDNFck1IUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Asteroids Impacting Neutron Stars May Be the Cause of Fast Radio Bursts</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Gadgets 360</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxQZ25KLUc1bDZMb1FHdnlRMlZZbGJFZ3ctaHJzakRwYy02a2NTM29UUXU5SHJZcHVyNXQ0TXdVY3pfekYyZVhMTmNuY2lrWTdjWlpHY2dpaXd6MW9PQzEzMDBXaFVFZjNpeF9PbGppV0J0bzNLYlh3ZGtfeC1RdGdFSWU2Wm95TmxCTkpLbTJpRVNmOFM1cm9TLTh3SW5oZw?oc=5" target="_blank">A cosmic enigma solved? Astronomers unveil a possible explanation</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Daily Galaxy --Great Discoveries Channel</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxOWDVWWDVpLV9MY2MxUmdUTHpxcTJhWDY4dFFwVENIWlU2Smt6NEpJVTZ2SmxreG9fT1J0bEZBZW9CN2tQOE1WQmFPUkVuYlI0ZURMZmJ1d0FsVm9pczJnaldJU01RR2FhNE91ZGZycVFRQnVxX2I0Qzdaa1hIdnk0blp3?oc=5" target="_blank">Scientists Propose Interesting Explanation for Mysterious Signals From Space</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Futurism</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPRV95VTd0T3FET2M4blhJVXBJVEVGV3lBRzJZTXpkYkd5SXNXdXVCN0FMXy01eFNWMjBkOFpMN1RTakxzeGVSaU16ZURNci10SVo0Z2lzZTNHRWlkeHVOVWVqd1c2RHFOUExleW1fa0FKUlJGQWJfNFUyT1N2MHJib2FJaFc0OWRTQWhLMHo3QVN3WS1jRE9VSVBXWk9rbVJteVVFSWN0QzJsQ1ZJLWlRMnc1Ny0wN19idngtbg?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPRV95VTd0T3FET2M4blhJVXBJVEVGV3lBRzJZTXpkYkd5SXNXdXVCN0FMXy01eFNWMjBkOFpMN1RTakxzeGVSaU16ZURNci10SVo0Z2lzZTNHRWlkeHVOVWVqd1c2RHFOUExleW1fa0FKUlJGQWJfNFUyT1N2MHJib2FJaFc0OWRTQWhLMHo3QVN3WS1jRE9VSVBXWk9rbVJteVVFSWN0QzJsQ1ZJLWlRMnc1Ny0wN19idngtbg?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dollars from doughnuts: Krispy Kreme online orders disrupted in cyber-attack]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Doughnut maker said it was investigating attack, which affects its online operations but not in-person sales</p><p>Krispy Kreme is struggling to meet online orders of its doughnuts, after a cybersecurity attack that continues to disrupt the company’s operations almost two weeks after it was noticed.</p><p>The doughnut maker said on Wednesday that it became aware of “unauthorized activity” on a portion of its computer systems on 29 November.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2024/dec/11/krispy-kreme-cyber-attack">Continue reading...</a>]]></description><link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2024/dec/11/krispy-kreme-cyber-attack</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2024/dec/11/krispy-kreme-cyber-attack</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:42:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Boeing (BA) Shares Skyrocket, What You Need To Know]]></title><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/boeing-ba-shares-skyrocket-know-205826334.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://finance.yahoo.com/news/boeing-ba-shares-skyrocket-know-205826334.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 20:58:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Improved Fuel Economy and Big Price Hikes: 2025 Toyota 4Runner Numbers Are In]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/tech/improved-fuel-economy-big-price-120000299.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/tech/improved-fuel-economy-big-price-120000299.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>