<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Technology articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:46:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:46:16 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[What if AI can actually help with your burnout?]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="An orb-shaped robot hovering over a supermarket cart filled with groceries." data-caption="I recently asked AI to create my shopping list. It was a simple request but an astonishing breakthrough for me." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/12/GettyImages-1447827502.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>I recently asked AI to create my shopping list. It was a simple request but an astonishing breakthrough for me.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">I recently had a breakthrough by talking to a computer while walking my dog. Creating a family meal plan had been on my to-do list for about a year and it had been gnawing at me. Writing out what everyone, including my 1-year-old, would eat at each meal for the next week and then figuring out what to get at the grocery store — it’s a real chore. So, dog leash in hand, I asked an AI assistant to do it for me.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It took roughly three seconds, and I had the meal plan and the grocery list done. Some of the meals matched what we’d been doing, which is how I knew it was on point. Others were more creative than I expected, like giving our baby a bean salad. I somehow felt both productive and humbled. I also felt a little less burned out.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That probably sounds so obvious, if you’re someone who’s been optimizing life with ChatGPT since its launch two years ago. Yes, AI can take boring tasks you don’t want to do and complete them quickly, without complaint. But I’m guessing most people still aren’t quite sure how to use generative AI tools, so <a href="https://reutersinstitute.politics.ox.ac.uk/what-does-public-six-countries-think-generative-ai-news#header--2">they aren’t using them</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Take my advice: Tell it to do something annoying that you’ve been meaning to do but haven’t had the time.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Maybe you need to write a thoughtful birthday card to an aunt you don’t know that well, or maybe you need to come up with a new workout plan. You might be surprised at how well AI does annoying chores like these, and how relieved you are to see AI doing basic helpful things <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/368537/ai-artificial-intelligence-capabilities-risks-warning-system">rather than destroying humankind</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The tension between AI as a problem-solver and AI as a source of new problems is something you have to reconcile if you want to understand the technology, according to <a href="https://mgmt.wharton.upenn.edu/profile/emollick/">Ethan Mollick</a>, an associate professor at Wharton and author of the newsletter One Useful Thing. Mollick has written a lot about <a href="https://www.oneusefulthing.org/p/how-to-use-ai-to-do-practical-stuff">the practical uses of AI</a>, and he says that <a href="https://www.wsj.com/lifestyle/careers/ai-beginner-tips-guide-5c8cf7eb">using an AI tool for about 10 hours</a> is the best way to figure out how it will work for you.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I feel like you have to move on from relief to amazement and existential dread to really get this product,” Mollick told me recently.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The thing is, I’d probably spent about 10 hours trying to figure out how to use AI before it finally clicked for me in my daily life. Most of those hours were at work, as I tried to get ChatGPT or Claude to explain complex topics and struggled to know what was accurate. It was ultimately getting AI to do one annoying chore — write up a complicated meal plan complete with grocery list — that brought me to that point of amazement. And I’m currently dealing with some dread as I try to figure out how to get AI to solve more problems.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">AI models are getting more powerful and sophisticated every day. Many companies are burning through billions of dollars as they compete to build better and better models. OpenAI <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/27/technology/openai-chatgpt-investors-funding.html">is on track to lose $5 billion</a> this year, while Microsoft <a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/ai/microsofts-ai-dreams-make-for-an-expensive-reality-90a8c8e4">spent a staggering $19 billion</a> in one quarter alone as it ramps up various AI-related projects. Mark Zuckerberg even <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/30/metas-mark-zuckerberg-seems-surprised-by-pace-of-spending-on-ai.html">said he was surprised</a> by how much his company, Meta, was spending on the data centers and chips needed to keep up in the AI race.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of these big numbers tell me that AI is only going to become more prevalent in our everyday lives. This push isn’t just about populating the web with smarter chatbots, and the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/11/style/ai-search-slop.html">flood of AI slop</a> is hardly the biggest problem we’ll face as we shift paradigms. Researchers can’t even agree on <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/3/13/24093357/ai-risk-extinction-forecasters-tetlock">what the biggest dangers of AI will be</a>. At the very least, we should all start questioning reality more often, as AI <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/371827/openai-chatgpt-artificial-intelligence-ai-risk-strawberry">is getting frightfully good at deception</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We’re already starting to see some of the next-generation AI products that tech companies have been throwing money at. OpenAI is doing a <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/openai-is-sending-mixed-signals-with-its-shipmas.html">holiday-themed “12 days of OpenAI” series of new product announcements</a> that include breakthroughs like a photorealistic video generator and ChatGPT integration on iOS and macOS devices <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318915/openai-demos-new-apple-intelligence-features-for-ship-mas">using Apple Intelligence</a>. Microsoft, meanwhile, <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/390582/microsoft-chatgpt-copilot-vision-ai">announced Copilot Vision</a>, an AI that can see what you’re doing on the web and talk to you about it. In a recent interview, Microsoft AI CEO Mustafa Suleyman told me that this is the first step toward a future in which AI can do more for us.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It should be able to take actions on your behalf, fill in forms, buy things, book things, plan, navigate, click on drop-down menus, and so on,” Suleyman said. “All of that is coming down the road and in the foreseeable future.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The tech industry’s big ambitions are a bit of a distraction for the average user. The mind-bending things AI could do isn’t actually impacting my life on a daily basis, but if I can get the technology to hammer out a few more annoying chores, I’d be thrilled. Mollick covers this concept a lot in his writing. I’d even argue that his latest newsletter addition bluntly titled “<a href="https://www.oneusefulthing.org/p/15-times-to-use-ai-and-5-not-to">15 Times to use AI, and 5 Not to</a>,” got me to ask that meal plan question.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It did take me about 10 hours of failing at using AI before I started to succeed and feel amazed. It’s easy for me to say now that it was time well spent because it certainly didn’t feel like it when I was tinkering with it and failing to find it useful. Then again, one reason why I put off annoying chores is I usually feel too burned out to do them. If an all-knowing computer-based intelligence is a solution to that burnout problem, I’ll take it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story was also published in the Vox Technology newsletter. </em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here</a></em></strong><em> so you don’t miss the next one!</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/technology/390866/technology-artifical-intelligence-chores-burnout</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/technology/390866/technology-artifical-intelligence-chores-burnout</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Clark Estes]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Inside the launch — and future — of ChatGPT]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="Photo illustration of hands typing on a laptop in front of the Chat GPT logo." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pPbQ7HF-_GvgBGAXMul8tBL_mKI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73782222/247422_ChatGPT_anniversary_CVirginia.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Image: Cath Virginia / The Verge, Getty Images</figcaption>
    </figure>


  <p>OpenAI worried that ChatGPT would be a dud two years ago. Now, the stakes have never been higher.</p>
  <p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24318650/chatgpt-openai-history-two-year-anniversary">Read the full story at The Verge.</a></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24318650/chatgpt-openai-history-two-year-anniversary</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24318650/chatgpt-openai-history-two-year-anniversary</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Kylie Robison]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Voicemod launches its voice-changing dongle for Xbox, PlayStation, and Switch]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w-s7QnWF5HapaTle7ulTulOG6B4=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73782192/Voicemod_Key_hed.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Image: Voicemod</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="o5HRES">Voicemod has released a hardware solution that enables its popular soundboard and voice-changing desktop software to work on Xbox, PlayStation, and Nintendo Switch consoles. <a href="https://www.voicemod.net/en/vmkey/">The Voicemod Key dongle</a> is now available in the US after <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/18/24200304/voicemod-key-xbox-playstation-voice-changer-soundboard">initially being teased in July</a>, with Voicemod planning to launch it in additional countries “soon.”</p>
<p id="9k8dq4">Universal voice changers have previously been limited to desktop PCs and Macs, with software limitations preventing Voicemod from building an app for consoles. The Voicemod Key serves as a workaround — it sports a USB-C connection that plugs into a tablet or smartphone (including older iPhones thanks to an included lightning adapter), and two audio jacks that connect to your console and a wired gaming headset. The Voicemod mobile app can then be used to access the platform’s soundboard and real-time voice-changing features in console chats.</p>
<figure class="e-image">
        
      <cite>Image: Voicemod</cite>
      <figcaption><em>Here’s an example of how the setup works — it’s worth noting that Voicemod Key will only work with wired headsets.</em></figcaption>
  </figure>
<p id="riO24h">The Voicemod Key is supported on iOS 16 and Android 8.1 or higher. Availability is restricted to paid Voicemod subscribers, and the Key price will depend on your...</p>
  <p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319463/voicemod-key-voice-changing-dongle-availability-xbox-ps5-switch">Read the full story at The Verge.</a></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319463/voicemod-key-voice-changing-dongle-availability-xbox-ps5-switch</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319463/voicemod-key-voice-changing-dongle-availability-xbox-ps5-switch</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jess Weatherbed]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:06:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Harvard and Google to release 1 million public-domain books as AI training dataset]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>AI training data has a big price tag, one best-suited for deep-pocketed tech firms. This is why Harvard University plans to release a dataset that includes in the region of 1 million public-domain books, spanning genres, languages, and authors including Dickens, Dante, and Shakespeare, which are no longer copyright-protected due to their age. The new [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/12/harvard-and-google-to-release-1-million-public-domain-books-as-ai-training-dataset/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/12/harvard-and-google-to-release-1-million-public-domain-books-as-ai-training-dataset/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:04:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gigs, an ‘MVNO in a box,’ gets $73M to power mobile network services for any company]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Gigs, a platform that makes it easier for any company to become a mobile virtual network operator (MVNO), has raised $73 million in a Series B round of funding. The announcement comes as countless companies have added mobile networking services to their product lineup this past year, including neobanks such as Nubank (a Gigs customer) [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/12/gigs-mvno-73m-mobile-network-services/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/12/gigs-mvno-73m-mobile-network-services/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft quietly axes Skype credit and phone number sales to push subscriptions]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Bad news for anyone out there who still uses Skype: the Microsoft-owned phone and messaging platform has quietly stopped letting users top-up accounts with credit and buy Skype phone numbers. Instead, Skype is locking into SaaS mode: it&#8217;s pushing users to take monthly subscriptions for regional and global Skype-to-phone plans, for a set monthly fee, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/12/microsoft-quietly-axes-skype-credit-and-phone-number-sales-to-push-subscriptions/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/12/microsoft-quietly-axes-skype-credit-and-phone-number-sales-to-push-subscriptions/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:23:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cartesia claims its AI is efficient enough to run pretty much anywhere]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s becoming increasingly costly to develop and run AI. OpenAI&#8217;s AI operations costs could reach&#160;$7 billion&#160;this year, while Anthropic&#8217;s CEO recently suggested that models costing over $10 billion could arrive soon. So the hunt is on for ways to make AI cheaper. Some researchers are focusing on techniques to optimize existing model architectures — i.e. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/12/cartesia-claims-its-ai-is-efficient-enough-to-run-pretty-much-anywhere/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/12/cartesia-claims-its-ai-is-efficient-enough-to-run-pretty-much-anywhere/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Unveils Latest AI Model, Gemini 2.0]]></title><description><![CDATA[Google on Wednesday announced the launch of Gemini 2.0, its most advanced artificial intelligence model to date, as the world's tech giants race to take the lead in the fast developing technology.]]></description><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-unveils-latest-ai-model-gemini-2-0-7231053</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-unveils-latest-ai-model-gemini-2-0-7231053</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 09:09:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[iOS 18.2—Update Now Warning Issued To All iPhone Users - Forbes]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNRVNUbmdSaVlpWEliX0laN2kwTlExOFdVNHNmSnhWd2VTVUJiUFpuNlBLTnluUGNFQzVuOUNHSVdRLVJzYVl0NWt1Nnh4RDd1dTNKYXc2bE5GWEpvZWJFMnZqMkFrSFdZNDlEZjd5ekRmU3hicDNld2V0Z1hpNUZaSmlLY2g3dEpKU21jcEhldEIzX0x1VGxIdEdQS3czMjhKVS1yVGJQOWlJeV9RVXhB?oc=5" target="_blank">iOS 18.2—Update Now Warning Issued To All iPhone Users</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Forbes</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxQTTlud2g0UDNQV29aZVF0eGZ2bnJqTTJPRkR1WTRMVjQ3bWo2YVY2Q3VzSXB1ZV9pelhTdzU5ZzNQS05XV3JKNlJacmdVWFQwTXlLVzJGOUJ2WWZWUi1LMDJhSXJNUGlCZzBPdlJHLXBzaXFhblA5RV95TlhoNnFKN0NPNWpoY3dhWDM3dkZHZ1luV2NZVjBxNmEwTGRxcER3VnA4bmRTbmg?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple Intelligence now features Image Playground, Genmoji, and more</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Apple Newsroom</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxNd2wydUs4dDJWR2syVkVQT2k2Sk8tR19CaF9tVlhHWUR3UHJReEFwa1ExQ0RfMlZJekJkbVl6THhfWjc3WTUyak01WDVndTNWNUhNemhFWkNJVWppNVVjVWlqMkJwSml6aGU4X2NSajFnLTZkTUp3aHFBN2RKeS1nbmlXbFFsR1VWMFRwUVRB0gGTAUFVX3lxTE9mVE1DQ1lkZF9JRm5ORjFvSUhnOVZNWmVEQlR2ZUVrVlFQVFRKNnVWMUZndS0yUDhJQzVsMU5NSzh1QWtWelhxbDI1Z28zWmdaem5MMWp0SjNaanJPSHQ5VVVZY0d3Yi1lTHhjb0VreUhPbU5mUEdLbFRFcUJSbGNXTTUzTTJZTElSTy1MdzRMNkp2SQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple launches its ChatGPT integration with Siri</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNBC</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQZXpnRDI1dWc3eFRYaktIYUNvb1JoQXhWTy1TdVFwRFZFZVJBU1hONllfUWd0T2JwR0V2T2psMWNPX2dfMlBvQlNiUVR3V1lWMTg5aEdjLTFYQy1rQV9ua19iWGE5NlBtbHBoV1NsR2R0SVB1aFVKRG1xNFVWR3puTXkzd2FNZHY5NGsxNWhKWmMzOWVNTlk5ckIza9IBoAFBVV95cUxPUnVFcXV0VjlURTJDS1FOQzh4WGxuQmFkcUlOQUd1UUd1d2hxZnJZc3NwQnZMcGotY3NPc21lMkwtMmJWR3QwZklEclg2YnhmcER1c3g5SHVlYmhuV2phM1RZeUVkRml1VlIxRklsdjY1RjJybEYyTlVBLVRmQmpxZnRSN18welQ3emRMcGJLT1E2d1hFMGNrR2tNdUJncy1k?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple rolls out new 'Genmoji' feature powered by AI</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ABC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisAFBVV95cUxOLTdOWUVBWUZjQWRZMksyYzhxNXJFWE5sMzF6THMtUk92cU1ka1dPQUVZRUxjZU81bHZkZEZtWXFDOVJuTnhiSGdzQmc0ZHVqcE5RMzdKaUptRG92WmdYQUlyVXVwajNOaElUSHVGckJPUWV2R2tUMWp1VzBDeEtvRmxYOUp6b0ZSZHI0QXpxZ0k2WjV2RHg3a3BfTVVGajFOcUhjVVdSVi1MUS1jQ0xsUg?oc=5" target="_blank">The Best 8 New iPhone Messages Features in iOS 18.2 to Try Now</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNET</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNRVNUbmdSaVlpWEliX0laN2kwTlExOFdVNHNmSnhWd2VTVUJiUFpuNlBLTnluUGNFQzVuOUNHSVdRLVJzYVl0NWt1Nnh4RDd1dTNKYXc2bE5GWEpvZWJFMnZqMkFrSFdZNDlEZjd5ekRmU3hicDNld2V0Z1hpNUZaSmlLY2g3dEpKU21jcEhldEIzX0x1VGxIdEdQS3czMjhKVS1yVGJQOWlJeV9RVXhB?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNRVNUbmdSaVlpWEliX0laN2kwTlExOFdVNHNmSnhWd2VTVUJiUFpuNlBLTnluUGNFQzVuOUNHSVdRLVJzYVl0NWt1Nnh4RDd1dTNKYXc2bE5GWEpvZWJFMnZqMkFrSFdZNDlEZjd5ekRmU3hicDNld2V0Z1hpNUZaSmlLY2g3dEpKU21jcEhldEIzX0x1VGxIdEdQS3czMjhKVS1yVGJQOWlJeV9RVXhB?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:34:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Alphabet Stock Hits a Record High on New AI Models - Barron's]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxOcS05TV9kNkJhX0ZFNGZBUlo0bElxMGV1SlBhTGg2Mk9pcFhvdUZDSWFZUTdUcFFWeE94TEkzU25YbnRKN2xhSzJQZWNQbDRDMk95WnpjREVST2J5ZWYyS3VGRU10UDc0VExEN0J4dlRyVC0wNVRJNGZoN0RPSERSY2xGV3dqUi10RWV3NU9MTlhQdzho0gGaAUFVX3lxTE1aNl9TQUtvQmlvZ05yRnlyYVdoTlRIdi1fNEJQaGlEMFdnTkNWQlJBMkRITWxQeGdnTmlpS1VzUVN5WjJVZWNDa1JQSWROdzJJci1CQVVXSC1XMnkxcVoyME0xN3Y5eFhYdFkyZ2ZxZ3dfMXR3dDZFZTI0c29NNTQwYXFDbG80cnhyWkp0MmJVRXRwZ3Y1Wl9VWUE?oc=5" target="_blank">Alphabet Stock Hits a Record High on New AI Models</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Barron's</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxPTlozTEZKejN4d1RRNUZFbXBzTnhJOFY1d1JaWXZQVDh4YWlETW9zSU82Rl91QUtyNFJBUU9VV3JqS3k0alp2YVJUYkJGbXlGY01aM3pJck1TaUlyOXp5T3hvZVlMa1F3cmhNeVdPOUxLVU5vT2lRaUtHMFItRmtYX2d1RzNxRkFTUDhWM2tR?oc=5" target="_blank">Introducing Gemini 2.0: our new AI model for the agentic era</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Keyword</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxNTmFfeEFBaG96T2x4dkFMNXVRdkRvWG9mYjNVbFVHRDVOMF8yUDZHZHdWaXRGUEtSMkdBdFd5ci13Mmw0QjF4MWdxZ3hyR2R4UUhIelFMdGgwQy15WUhmTnMzU2hWSW9OS0FUUTJmY1E3WEJJQ2tCNEQ0dHN3aFF1RzlmWF9VcmROMi1QWVdqWnNpSUt0d2xRaF9fdm41cGVSZGJqZUktbzRZMWJyZGdqZ3FBV0tjTnluQ3p2MDNhcm53UEl0dXZONG5NZTZKcmFiUnJkT05ra3BnUnpPXzJGMzlJRE1GSlBSelE?oc=5" target="_blank">Google's Gemini 2.0 AI agents are being trained to offer gameplay advice and suggestions</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Tom's Hardware</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE5KT1EydVlGN1hRYnVfYVZCNm9QbksweGUzb001d25tMVRoa3FMTk9sUFNXZGJFelVaSmhZcjNacm9NaktwUTZXT3hRajZKV0l4Q3JhV3FXTmpuNHNzY2VhNm1rZkJST081NjVvZFRwYkVIMmUtbU45ekpNdnB3UQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Google Unveils A.I. Agent Based on Gemini 2.0</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The New York Times</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxQM3ZVQW9zUjN3ZTVCdnM2azNmUXlaSFZwcm1HRGE4Q0k5aWRZTmxxWEZxRUJCMzlqTzlqYnBaZGZvRWVMalQzb1c1dEVURVhFTkpuWjgyX3N3WXRnSjlvOGE0UFBTbzBfb1J3LVBZOVVDN1hBSUpkcXM0aVc4VzJQdkktdzJkdElIc250UEQ4WlhQc3d0c19uQ285UDNOYWt0QzRJWXpiMl9RWVRvUlJEbFFWUQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Google’s new Project Astra could be generative AI’s killer app</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MIT Technology Review</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxOcS05TV9kNkJhX0ZFNGZBUlo0bElxMGV1SlBhTGg2Mk9pcFhvdUZDSWFZUTdUcFFWeE94TEkzU25YbnRKN2xhSzJQZWNQbDRDMk95WnpjREVST2J5ZWYyS3VGRU10UDc0VExEN0J4dlRyVC0wNVRJNGZoN0RPSERSY2xGV3dqUi10RWV3NU9MTlhQdzho0gGaAUFVX3lxTE1aNl9TQUtvQmlvZ05yRnlyYVdoTlRIdi1fNEJQaGlEMFdnTkNWQlJBMkRITWxQeGdnTmlpS1VzUVN5WjJVZWNDa1JQSWROdzJJci1CQVVXSC1XMnkxcVoyME0xN3Y5eFhYdFkyZ2ZxZ3dfMXR3dDZFZTI0c29NNTQwYXFDbG80cnhyWkp0MmJVRXRwZ3Y1Wl9VWUE?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxOcS05TV9kNkJhX0ZFNGZBUlo0bElxMGV1SlBhTGg2Mk9pcFhvdUZDSWFZUTdUcFFWeE94TEkzU25YbnRKN2xhSzJQZWNQbDRDMk95WnpjREVST2J5ZWYyS3VGRU10UDc0VExEN0J4dlRyVC0wNVRJNGZoN0RPSERSY2xGV3dqUi10RWV3NU9MTlhQdzho0gGaAUFVX3lxTE1aNl9TQUtvQmlvZ05yRnlyYVdoTlRIdi1fNEJQaGlEMFdnTkNWQlJBMkRITWxQeGdnTmlpS1VzUVN5WjJVZWNDa1JQSWROdzJJci1CQVVXSC1XMnkxcVoyME0xN3Y5eFhYdFkyZ2ZxZ3dfMXR3dDZFZTI0c29NNTQwYXFDbG80cnhyWkp0MmJVRXRwZ3Y1Wl9VWUE?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 21:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Leak reveals the Galaxy S25 series will get the Galaxy Z series Kindsuit case but you might want to avoid it - Notebookcheck.net]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxNQ3ItaThqTXM4NGVpU2Ztb1pEYk1UVzBEZXUwT3M1aU41cHpKZEhBQThTUWdDZGttMHA1Ymt6bjhHcFhTYlJKVEIwcV9IZEpQSTM0TFduRjJYLXhVYlVWQ1lsVVlIbGlmRWNpekVyOU5NNFpmdVJST1RnLUowcHpUVFViSm9YRU9hVC1IOVhjd1ZHNlF1YXU0Y21EbGI5NmE1WGRTV3g0eEZ4bTQtNDFsUm5XelZpMDZydHRyQnMwTm5la0ZreWJLV3VXRXpQbnJOTVNTd1gyN1FhblBrM0hxb3RNS21VNms?oc=5" target="_blank">Leak reveals the Galaxy S25 series will get the Galaxy Z series Kindsuit case but you might want to avoid it</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Notebookcheck.net</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxORXAwNUI4dFd1TEhIdGNvZ3ZJMWR6Zmd1ZDNJSjNkUG9KWi1oaGtoZjF0NEgtTlA3VnZnbHRvLWoxZU16eHVJU3c5N2oyYlNjYS1pSzM3MmxNS2VnQzhCbV9kaE5sa3RyenM2SWY4Zk00Rmo1TE54S2o3TElpaWRNRVFPUFhwZGhnUnpPU3JrNHNJS29nRWVOSFE0aGdEWmJoT3VoRE5OWTAxUmxTVDZMRU92NFYyaGZtRUJFVE9JODFHdlhp?oc=5" target="_blank">The latest Samsung Galaxy S25 pricing and storage leaks have me worried</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">TechRadar</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMisgFBVV95cUxPeDJWV3VsOW56YWJBaVlRZHBRVm9ZT29iZWxaS2Nya2t5aW1qWUlocFBMVzBhNWU0b0xGdVVTUks0TlowUlgySkpGbFp4dzZZQ1lSTU9aaXQtWWdfX3gweG5Tb2hqTWtMTGs5dUFFQnNsTTJKVDkxTm9VYXhTUTBJbmowWTQ2MndOTDM3OWRpVEpJNjNlTnZObExaMzFpM2FRMzhvTnhQdTVZNWZUMHlZNTR30gGuAUFVX3lxTE13bnVVVmw0RXBqQkhmV2pqaEpaQlpXN1BrY2xHUzhadU5vS25TTUd2VG1LSjZwV2stT00zbFVadHdUdDhrT0p0alRyLTVZdW5Mazc5dmZqY1Q3b2J6V2ZtYXpxcXliYjk2Szdqakl1U29ySzBDeXRXajRZQmJqM3BCNmhZLVdCTzdMLThjSlh6ZkxfMy1JT0VaMkZJYXJrQnNqRHN3ak5qMDNHeXlSQQ?oc=5" target="_blank">The prices of Samsung Galaxy S25, S25+ and S25 Ultra could remain the same - GSMArena.com news</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">GSMArena.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxQVjEtZ2xnaTVoN3hsZU9jQTFvTGhRN3c5NHNEVWxIek1iVkRyT3RaMG9iMGRQMWtMMXcycXhhazQxOExNS255clh5V3pGYXdZV3dQWENwazF3bVlMUll0QnY1Z3lUZVNzaUpkREdoV1htMzNVU2dxR3c4d3VMVXpBNjU5US01MkxiWUpNcG5ldWdFa3ZMZk5oY1NBVQ?oc=5" target="_blank">Here’s How Leaked Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra Camera Specs Differ From S24 Ultra</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">ExtremeTech</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxPdVpBYzBheXBmRnI4ai0zY01EX0tFblZObzBZbUpGQlF1VkVlSFlLUnc5d3kxWjFJa0hfM2lfc0hoN1YzM3dBQ0lTbEpOSWdmU19PanVMUVhUd0VSbGNMb21WUWhHdzFoTWs1RXNHb0Fxal9LVzhTSG5vdUpvVmNCWG05RVY?oc=5" target="_blank">These are the color names for all Galaxy S25 models</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">PhoneArena</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxNQ3ItaThqTXM4NGVpU2Ztb1pEYk1UVzBEZXUwT3M1aU41cHpKZEhBQThTUWdDZGttMHA1Ymt6bjhHcFhTYlJKVEIwcV9IZEpQSTM0TFduRjJYLXhVYlVWQ1lsVVlIbGlmRWNpekVyOU5NNFpmdVJST1RnLUowcHpUVFViSm9YRU9hVC1IOVhjd1ZHNlF1YXU0Y21EbGI5NmE1WGRTV3g0eEZ4bTQtNDFsUm5XelZpMDZydHRyQnMwTm5la0ZreWJLV3VXRXpQbnJOTVNTd1gyN1FhblBrM0hxb3RNS21VNms?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxNQ3ItaThqTXM4NGVpU2Ztb1pEYk1UVzBEZXUwT3M1aU41cHpKZEhBQThTUWdDZGttMHA1Ymt6bjhHcFhTYlJKVEIwcV9IZEpQSTM0TFduRjJYLXhVYlVWQ1lsVVlIbGlmRWNpekVyOU5NNFpmdVJST1RnLUowcHpUVFViSm9YRU9hVC1IOVhjd1ZHNlF1YXU0Y21EbGI5NmE1WGRTV3g0eEZ4bTQtNDFsUm5XelZpMDZydHRyQnMwTm5la0ZreWJLV3VXRXpQbnJOTVNTd1gyN1FhblBrM0hxb3RNS21VNms?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:57:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Back where it started: “Do Not Track” removed from Firefox after 13 years - Ars Technica]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxOM29JSTVYcGVvRHd5bE1XMmJBN3YzamZHc0s0allrWXN1Vm1lbE9JSUxremxyTUFFS2NhbDA5ZDZWUjYxdEZLSm9meHh0T2lQeEpndjhwbnhnZ2w2ZkdjbG1qT2U0czNWXzllT0FBVnJWaUtKZ1J6REVmUHpRZFFLeE1NX2VRQ0pzSUlkZmRSY01jWmtTYXRIanVjaHdfR3ZtWkRrTGpEWENyTHJHRlE?oc=5" target="_blank">Back where it started: “Do Not Track” removed from Firefox after 13 years</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Ars Technica</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibEFVX3lxTFBlVmNHZGZyRmhWOWNiazE1UjUyZnYxQm9YNGZYdWJHakZHWHl6VVZJQkI0c2JtazVVd1ExYW9scENJUEpNRW1qZ1NDT2tGTXIyNVlSWnpneWs1azZUeHpPNHpHTnRIQWNYeXR2NdIBckFVX3lxTFBZZDVwSWkyZnJwVnFQVlZoNVJtcTNvUE1tcm92UjVJYTU1a3hzeTl3TlVpeTNTUlVBaVRBUmkxQnZndS1iMU5rRjB4dGdtYnlDTmdjNUtmWjUySWhBajJsaGxUa2VZd0ZENXFfZWFTXzFqZw?oc=5" target="_blank">Firefox ditches Do Not Track because nobody was listening anyway</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Register</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxPRHo2TjFWNnd1ZXJzemZ3R2Rwa1lrdU1Sbi04cEpja1hBNWhMZi1hNlVEbTFZbDZ2R1FlbW9vbXV3dEp0a2haWno1NUhxTHRqNVE5ZEppa3FfSmVUVGZlR2lRbE11akhlajVGeVlLOUxhVHpEQl9fekthZzFEXzZCR1UzV3htZ1dyQ1dyVjhheWoxSFA4RWxYb3UxX1pwU09CZ2dOdVpDWDZ3RWUzcFFwZi1mQXh6SkxLSnd6Z0w4UHlWeWxoNF9lN01JMTZzU2htQndIc0JR?oc=5" target="_blank">Firefox is ending Do Not Track, but there are better ways to protect your privacy – here's what I recommend</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">TechRadar</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxObEI5ME95MjcxSlpTTjBzR0FXMlN0SnBobWZkaWM0VTR5eDdCeVZDQ0I5S0JZTW1rdWFsc3dJX2dEck51U2llN3NPTkNTN3ktSG9sRzRHR2RfQ3JkMGtkLW1xOUdnWnQyRHFGaEpCM08tbTBkMU4xdEtwcDUybHVRYkpzcVJnbzBxdGxVVWtHejFsVy1oM1pTS3lVdFF4YVZ1RVZKOUNrMkZIa00?oc=5" target="_blank">Mozilla removes ‘Do Not Track’ from Firefox because it was useless</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">TechCrunch</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxQT0w0UWlpOHJBb29ES1dkeEJMTllFeG9RR0xRb1puUVJDQTFfZkcySWdMLW5iYkRfcWJNVXl0MkxEZGNZZmc3dW9tYUxud3V5MG45bl91azhTZDY1STlieGR0d1MwMUNrM1FPMTgwbzhiQkNSWmtsNlhNRC1JTWM4bzFsNndZYUNSWWZJYkNxd015Y0p4UVdnQW1OcVVLdXFOdDI3MWM2MzU?oc=5" target="_blank">Firefox will no longer support “do not track” feature</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Engadget</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxOM29JSTVYcGVvRHd5bE1XMmJBN3YzamZHc0s0allrWXN1Vm1lbE9JSUxremxyTUFFS2NhbDA5ZDZWUjYxdEZLSm9meHh0T2lQeEpndjhwbnhnZ2w2ZkdjbG1qT2U0czNWXzllT0FBVnJWaUtKZ1J6REVmUHpRZFFLeE1NX2VRQ0pzSUlkZmRSY01jWmtTYXRIanVjaHdfR3ZtWkRrTGpEWENyTHJHRlE?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxOM29JSTVYcGVvRHd5bE1XMmJBN3YzamZHc0s0allrWXN1Vm1lbE9JSUxremxyTUFFS2NhbDA5ZDZWUjYxdEZLSm9meHh0T2lQeEpndjhwbnhnZ2w2ZkdjbG1qT2U0czNWXzllT0FBVnJWaUtKZ1J6REVmUHpRZFFLeE1NX2VRQ0pzSUlkZmRSY01jWmtTYXRIanVjaHdfR3ZtWkRrTGpEWENyTHJHRlE?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:00:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple's iOS 18.2 is here, and it brings a ton of Apple Intelligence features]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/tech/apples-ios-18-2-brings-140635480.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/tech/apples-ios-18-2-brings-140635480.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 14:06:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apples iOS 18.2 arrives: Heres 4 new features to be excited about]]></title><description><![CDATA[Apple Intelligence reached something close to its final form with the release of iOS 18.2.]]></description><link>https://mashable.com/article/ios-18-2-release-apple-intelligence-features</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mashable.com/article/ios-18-2-release-apple-intelligence-features</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 11:04:14 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>