<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:17:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:17:49 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Galaxy Unpacked on January 22: Samsung opens pre-reservations for S25 series in India - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Galaxy Unpacked on January 22: Samsung opens pre-reservations for S25 series in India</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p><img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Samsung-1_20241226183043.jpg?w=300" alt="Samsung’s One UI 7 update will let you turn off bright HDR content across all apps"><figcaption>Samsung’s One UI 7 update will let you turn off bright HDR content across all apps</figcaption><p>Samsung announced today that its next Unpacked event will take place on January 22 in San Jose, California, where the Galaxy S25 series will be revealed.</p><ul><li>Pre-reservations for the Galaxy S25 series are now live in India.</li><li>Customers can reserve a unit by paying a refundable amount of Rs 2,000.</li><li>The pre-reserved customers will receive exclusive launch offers worth up to Rs 5,000.</li><li>The devices are expected to feature the Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Elite chip.</li><li>Samsung will introduce its XR headset, Project Moohan, at the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pre-reserved customers will be eligible for early access and receive benefits of up to Rs 5,000 on purchasing the new Galaxy S series devices.”</blockquote><p>In summary, Samsung is gearing up for an exciting launch with the new Galaxy S series and the introduction of its XR headset.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-galaxy-unpacked-on-january-22-samsung-opens-pre-reservations-for-s25-series-in-india-3709445/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-galaxy-unpacked-on-january-22-samsung-opens-pre-reservations-for-s25-series-in-india-3709445/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:40:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CES 2025: Nvidia announces RTX 50 Series GPUs with 2x performance boost and DLSS 4.0 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CES 2025: Nvidia announces RTX 50 Series GPUs with 2x performance boost and DLSS 4.0</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 <br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/7ea1ef7762a64eadebf8c838ea44b481.jpg" alt="Image related to Nvidia RTX 50 Series"/>
<figcaption>Nvidia unveils new graphics technology at CES 2025.</figcaption>
<p>Nvidia has announced the launch of its RTX 50 Series GPUs at CES 2025, featuring a significant performance increase and the integration of DLSS 4.0 technology.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Introduction of RTX 50 Series GPUs with double the performance of previous models.</li>
  <li>New DLSS 4.0 technology promises enhanced graphics rendering.</li>
  <li>Improvements aimed at both gamers and professionals in graphic-intensive applications.</li>
  <li>Expected release date and pricing to be announced later this year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This new generation sets a new standard for performance and visual fidelity,” said Nvidia's CEO.</blockquote>
<p>The unveiling of the RTX 50 Series at CES 2025 marks another milestone in Nvidia's commitment to pushing graphics technology forward, appealing to a wide range of users from gamers to creative professionals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/laptops-pc/ces-2025-nvidia-announces-rtx-50-series-gpus-with-2x-performance-boost-and-dlss-4-0/articleshow/117021944.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/laptops-pc/ces-2025-nvidia-announces-rtx-50-series-gpus-with-2x-performance-boost-and-dlss-4-0/articleshow/117021944.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Brings ‘Vision AI’ Features For Smart TVs And Home At CES 2025: All Details - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Introduces Vision AI for Smart TVs at CES 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2025/01/samsung-ai-home-ces-2025-2025-01-431b1a9771ef65ca1cea12ddfa536a5b.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Samsung AI Home Ecosystem" /><figcaption>The AI home ecosystem from Samsung will focus on security and uniformity across products.</figcaption><p>Samsung is showcasing its latest AI advancements at CES 2025, introducing a range of features for its Smart TVs termed ‘Vision AI’.</p><ul><li>New AI features include real-time content translation and personalized content recommendations through partnerships with Microsoft and Google.</li><li>Generative Wallpaper allows for personalized artwork display.</li><li>The company is also enhancing its Home AI ecosystem aimed at a hyper-personalized smart home experience.</li><li>Other offerings include a flagship Neo QLED 8K TV model boasting advanced AI capabilities.</li></ul><blockquote>"The company is bringing AI to homes as well with the Home AI ecosystem that looks to unify the UI experience and features across different products available in the segment."</blockquote><p>This launch marks a significant step in integrating AI into home entertainment and technology ecosystems.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/tech/samsung-brings-vision-ai-features-for-smart-tvs-at-ces-2025-all-details-9179562.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/tech/samsung-brings-vision-ai-features-for-smart-tvs-at-ces-2025-all-details-9179562.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R India Launch LIVE Updates: Next-gen OnePlus smartphones arrive tonight - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R India Launch LIVE Updates</h1><p><strong>Date: January 7, 2025 | Source: Indian Express</strong></p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/OnePlus-13.png?w=640" alt="OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R Price in India, Specifications Launch Live Updates: What we know so far." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R Price in India, Specifications Launch Live Updates: What we know so far. (Image Source: OnePlus)</figcaption><p>OnePlus is set to unveil its latest smartphones, the OnePlus 13 and OnePlus 13R, during its 2025 Winter Launch event today. The launch will also include a variant of the OnePlus Buds Pro 3 and is speculated to introduce the OnePlus Watch 3.</p><ul><li>Launch event scheduled for 9PM IST.</li><li>The OnePlus 13 and 13R are the highly-anticipated next-gen smartphones.</li><li>Live updates and impressions will be provided during the event.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/tech-news-technology/oneplus-13-oneplus-13r-price-in-india-specifications-launch-live-updates-9764207/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/tech-news-technology/oneplus-13-oneplus-13r-price-in-india-specifications-launch-live-updates-9764207/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 09:32:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia launches RTX 50 series GPUs at CES 2025: See prices, specs, AI features, other details - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nvidia Unveils RTX 50 Series GPUs at CES 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/CES-2025-13_1736238252323_1736238262723.jpg" alt="Jensen Huang at CES 2025" title="Jensen Huang at CES 2025"><figcaption>Jensen Huang, co-founder and chief executive officer of Nvidia Corp., speaks while holding the company's new GeForce RTX 50 series graphics cards during CES 2025.</figcaption><p>Nvidia has launched its new RTX 50-series graphics cards at CES 2025, promising significant upgrades in performance and efficiency for PC gamers.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The RTX 50-series GPUs feature performance enhancements, efficiency improvements, and a sleek redesign.</li><li>The top-tier RTX 5090 boasts twice the performance of the RTX 4090, suitable for smaller PC cases.</li><li>Specs of RTX 5090: 32GB GDDR7 memory, 21,760 CUDA cores, 1,792GB/sec bandwidth.</li><li>Mid-range models RTX 5070 Ti and RTX 5070 offer double the performance of their predecessors.</li><li>Nvidia's new GPUs support advanced AI features like DLSS 4 and Neural Shaders.</li><li>Prices range from $549 for the RTX 5070 to $1,999 for the RTX 5090.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes:</h2><blockquote>“These GPUs are likely to become highly sought after, especially for PC gamers.”</blockquote><p>The RTX 50-series GPUs for laptops will launch in March 2025.</p><h2>Conclusion:</h2><p>The RTX 50-series represents Nvidia's continued commitment to leading the graphics technology market, emphasizing performance, efficiency, and innovative AI features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/nvidia-launches-rtx-50-series-gpus-at-ces-2025-see-prices-specs-ai-features-other-details-nvidia-geforce-rtx-5070-101736238151517.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/nvidia-launches-rtx-50-series-gpus-at-ces-2025-see-prices-specs-ai-features-other-details-nvidia-geforce-rtx-5070-101736238151517.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung sets date for Galaxy Unpacked 2025 event - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Announces Galaxy Unpacked 2025 Event Date</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 07 January 2025, 08:37 IST</p><p>Samsung has officially set the date for its Galaxy Unpacked 2025 event, which will take place on January 22, 2025, in San Jose at 10:00 am PT. The event will be live streamed on Samsung's official channels.</p><figure><img src="https://images.deccanherald.com/deccanherald%2F2024-01%2F420ce295-78d9-45a5-a744-71fc72bb207f%2FSamsung_Galaxy_S24_Ultra_Cover_Photo_selected_3.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra."><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra. Photo Credit: DH Photo/KVN Rohit</figcaption></figure><p>Samsung is expected to announce the successor to the Galaxy S24 series, including a new model named Galaxy S25 Slim. This model will feature a thinner design and improved specifications, including a 200MP camera and a robust Snapdragon processor. In total, there will be four variants of the Galaxy S25 series.</p><ul><li>Galaxy Unpacked 2025 is scheduled for January 22, 2025, at 10:00 am PT.</li><li>Live streaming will be available on Samsung's official websites and YouTube channel.</li><li>The new Galaxy S25 series will include four variants: S24, S25 Plus, S25 Slim, and S25 Ultra.</li><li>Notable features include a high-resolution display, advanced camera systems, and enhanced AI capabilities.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Galaxy S25 Slim is the first of its kind in the Galaxy S series, featuring a 6.66-inch screen and a powerful Snapdragon chipset."</blockquote><p>This event is highly anticipated as Samsung prepares to showcase its new innovations in mobile technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/technology/gadgets/samsung-sets-date-for-galaxy-unpacked-2025-event-3344431</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/technology/gadgets/samsung-sets-date-for-galaxy-unpacked-2025-event-3344431</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:37:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Galaxy Unpacked 2025: Samsung Set To Unveil Galaxy S25 Series With Cutting-Edge AI Features; Check Expected Specs and Pre-Booking Offers - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Galaxy Unpacked 2025: Samsung Set To Unveil Galaxy S25 Series With AI Features</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 22, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Zee News</p><p>Samsung is set to launch its Galaxy S25 Series featuring new AI capabilities at the Galaxy Unpacked event in San Jose. The event will be live-streamed on various platforms.</p><img src="image-url.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S25 Series"/><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S25 Series Advertisement</figcaption><p>The Galaxy S25 series will include Galaxy S25, S25+, and S25 Ultra with pre-reserve offers starting from Rs 1,999.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>Event date: January 22, 2025 at 10 am PT</li><li>New AI features aimed at enhancing user interaction</li><li>Pre-reservations in India started at Rs 1,999</li><li>Expected sale date: February 7, 2025</li><li>Featuring Snapdragon 8 Elite processor with 12GB RAM</li><li>Potential for a Galaxy S25 Slim variant later in the year</li><li>Upgraded cameras and improved charging speeds</li></ul><blockquote>“More natural and intuitive Galaxy AI” - Samsung</blockquote><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 Series promises to introduce innovative features that will enhance how users engage with their devices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/technology/galaxy-unpacked-2025-samsung-set-to-unveil-galaxy-s25-series-with-cutting-edge-ai-features-check-expected-specs-and-pre-booking-offers-2840563.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/technology/galaxy-unpacked-2025-samsung-set-to-unveil-galaxy-s25-series-with-cutting-edge-ai-features-check-expected-specs-and-pre-booking-offers-2840563.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 08:19:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CES 2025: NVIDIA brings AI to PC gaming with GeForce RTX 50 Series GPUs - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NVIDIA Unveils GeForce RTX 50 Series GPUs at CES 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Major News Outlet</p>
<p>NVIDIA announced the GeForce RTX 50 Series GPUs at CES 2025, featuring AI-powered technologies for enhanced graphics performance.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The GPUs are based on NVIDIA's new Blackwell architecture.</li>
  <li>RTX 5090 leads the series, boasting 92 billion transistors and significant computing power.</li>
  <li>New DLSS 4 technology enhances gameplay, outpacing previous models by up to 2x.</li>
  <li>AI-powered shaders provide film-quality visuals in real-time.</li>
  <li>NVIDIA ACE technology introduces autonomous game characters.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Blackwell, the engine of AI, has arrived for PC gamers, developers and creatives." - Jensen Huang, CEO of NVIDIA</blockquote>
<p>The launch of the RTX 50 series marks a major advancement in PC gaming technology, promising unprecedented performance and realism.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/ces-2025-nvidia-brings-ai-to-pc-gaming-with-geforce-rtx-50-series-gpus-125010700423_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/ces-2025-nvidia-brings-ai-to-pc-gaming-with-geforce-rtx-50-series-gpus-125010700423_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:16:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung introduces Vision AI for smart TVs and display technologies- Know what it is and how it will work - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Unveils Vision AI to Enhance Smart Devices at CES 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Samsung-TVs-and-Displays-CES-2025-Samsung-Vision-A_1736233010930_1736233011198.jpg" alt="Know what Samsung's Vision AI is and how it aims to transform AI experiences. (Samsung)"><figcaption>Know what Samsung's Vision AI is and how it aims to transform AI experiences. (Samsung)</figcaption><p>Samsung has launched its new AI technology, Vision AI, at CES 2025, aimed at empowering smart TVs and appliances with advanced AI features.</p><ul><li>Vision AI will be integrated into Samsung's 2025 smart TV lineup including Neo QLED, OLED, QLED, and The Frame.</li><li>Personalized features like Click to Search and Live Translate will enhance user interaction with smart displays.</li><li>Integration with the SmartThings ecosystem for smart home management.</li><li>Real-time updates for family and pet monitoring, along with environmental alerts.</li><li>Advanced On-device AI for picture and sound enhancements.</li><li>Collaboration with Microsoft for content recommendations and 3D audio technology with Google.</li></ul><blockquote>“Samsung Vision AI transforms screens into smart companions that enhance entertainment, and simplify interactions.”</blockquote><p>This innovative AI approach by Samsung is set to redefine user interactions with screens and smart home devices, making them more intuitive and responsive to user needs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/samsung-introduces-vision-ai-for-smart-tvs-and-display-technologies-know-what-it-is-and-how-it-will-work-101736232938822.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/samsung-introduces-vision-ai-for-smart-tvs-and-display-technologies-know-what-it-is-and-how-it-will-work-101736232938822.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Medtech BP monitors: Top 6 clinically accurate and easy-to-use blood pressure monitors for at-home health tracking - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwJBVV95cUxPX1lzajZoVU95UVdRVkJrZy0wRXI5WGMtTDNHQXJWaG9JT1dxRzF4TUdoV0k3dFQwazBLamtYcFR2NWJrY0Yyb1FEd3RzOW45MGtsSXpRUGpuNnBRcGMtUGY5ZmlfLWFWV2JVaFRmVEJkakY1eGlNblh0aF9LeERRc0tEa0pRZDdyVEc2bWNGMFBPNkcwM3FYa3ljRzREN3I4ZWFXUmhQdVFLYWt2WXktNzV3S2pfNnpDclhMX3gyUTkwcGZ4d1lGZktpLUU4aGlFN3hXcUx3YUhwaFFlMEZqN3VldWJNN0lFY2FUSWl4emJwSUxqV2ptb1Y5czRGTlpzUm9YYzZaekZhNWlyMUlJ0gGUAkFVX3lxTE1NQ3BobEtJX1VoWFA1UHlrX3VOSWtMV0pmNkllUF9OSkVpNkpCLXg2Z1NMbTJYbjllYTVjNFNJRDNsMjB0aUpHSGxPYmh0NkxWa3dXWXNCMS10aDRjWUxzSmZkeGkxaUV6VEs2LUpjRll3Nm5GN2FNR05MZ3R6cWlibnFOY1VxTDlTTVY4TUNxZTViM0o5cTFXOWVPelY1NHdBcmtjcndwbnBQRFREQnhraU9TQlRlaWJtVmM4MlNUSmx6NGFhMUdWTFh5SlhRbEVDQ3piTG1HNFJKbTFoSWMtUWNsb05yeFZFTGFNZm9LMXctdHZta2VyeG5QcF9fNDJlcFAxY3RLVnh3cjNxRHgzZGh4OQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwJBVV95cUxPX1lzajZoVU95UVdRVkJrZy0wRXI5WGMtTDNHQXJWaG9JT1dxRzF4TUdoV0k3dFQwazBLamtYcFR2NWJrY0Yyb1FEd3RzOW45MGtsSXpRUGpuNnBRcGMtUGY5ZmlfLWFWV2JVaFRmVEJkakY1eGlNblh0aF9LeERRc0tEa0pRZDdyVEc2bWNGMFBPNkcwM3FYa3ljRzREN3I4ZWFXUmhQdVFLYWt2WXktNzV3S2pfNnpDclhMX3gyUTkwcGZ4d1lGZktpLUU4aGlFN3hXcUx3YUhwaFFlMEZqN3VldWJNN0lFY2FUSWl4emJwSUxqV2ptb1Y5czRGTlpzUm9YYzZaekZhNWlyMUlJ0gGUAkFVX3lxTE1NQ3BobEtJX1VoWFA1UHlrX3VOSWtMV0pmNkllUF9OSkVpNkpCLXg2Z1NMbTJYbjllYTVjNFNJRDNsMjB0aUpHSGxPYmh0NkxWa3dXWXNCMS10aDRjWUxzSmZkeGkxaUV6VEs2LUpjRll3Nm5GN2FNR05MZ3R6cWlibnFOY1VxTDlTTVY4TUNxZTViM0o5cTFXOWVPelY1NHdBcmtjcndwbnBQRFREQnhraU9TQlRlaWJtVmM4MlNUSmx6NGFhMUdWTFh5SlhRbEVDQ3piTG1HNFJKbTFoSWMtUWNsb05yeFZFTGFNZm9LMXctdHZta2VyeG5QcF9fNDJlcFAxY3RLVnh3cjNxRHgzZGh4OQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia's CEO revealed new Graphic Cards based on the Blackwell architecture, how one AI project uses Apple Vision Pro during his CES Keynote - Patently Apple]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nvidia Unveils New Graphic Cards and AI Initiatives at CES 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Patently Apple</p>
<img src="https://patentlyapple.typepad.com/.a/6a0120a5580826970c02e860f627f2200d-800wi" alt="Nvidia Graphic Cards" title="Nvidia Graphic Cards">
<figcaption>Nvidia unveils new graphic cards and AI projects at CES 2025.</figcaption>
<p>Nvidia's CEO Jensen Huang announced the GeForce RTX 50-series graphic cards and showcased new AI projects, including the use of Apple Vision Pro for robotics, during his CES 2025 keynote.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The new graphics cards are based on Blackwell architecture, targeting both consumer and data center markets.</li>
  <li>Prices for the GeForce RTX 50-series cards range from $550 to $2,000, with laptop models shipping in March.</li>
  <li>Nvidia aims for its technology to be central to a future with autonomous robots, factories, and vehicles.</li>
  <li>The Nvidia Isaac GROOT Blueprint utilizes Apple Vision Pro for synthetic motion generation in humanoid robots.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“GeForce allowed AI to reach the masses, and now AI is coming home to GeForce.” - Jensen Huang</blockquote>
<p>In summary, Nvidia's announcements focus on expanding AI capabilities along with enhancing graphics processing power, indicating a significant push towards integrating technology into everyday automation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.patentlyapple.com/2025/01/nvidias-ceo-revealed-new-graphic-cards-based-on-the-blackwell-architecture-how-one-ai-project-uses-apple-vision-pro-during.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.patentlyapple.com/2025/01/nvidias-ceo-revealed-new-graphic-cards-based-on-the-blackwell-architecture-how-one-ai-project-uses-apple-vision-pro-during.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:52:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R India Launch LIVE Updates: OnePlus set to unveil much-awaited flagship series - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R India Launch LIVE Updates</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 7, 2025</strong><br><strong>Source: Indian Express</strong></p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Tech-feature-images82.jpg?w=640" alt="OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R Price in India, Specifications Launch Live Updates" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R Price in India, Specifications Launch Live Updates: What we know so far.</figcaption>
<p>OnePlus is set to unveil its latest smartphone series today, including the OnePlus 13 and OnePlus 13R, alongside new audio products.</p>
<ul>
<li>Launch event scheduled for 9 PM IST.</li>
<li>Introduction of OnePlus Buds Pro 3 variant.</li>
<li>Speculated release of OnePlus Watch 3 with advanced health features.</li>
<li>Live updates and first impressions to follow.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>We’ll be bringing you live updates as OnePlus takes the wraps off these highly-anticipated devices.</blockquote>
<p>This launch marks an important development in OnePlus's offerings, aiming to attract a broader audience in the premium smartphone segment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/tech-news-technology/oneplus-13-oneplus-13r-price-in-india-specifications-launch-live-updates-9764207/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/tech-news-technology/oneplus-13-oneplus-13r-price-in-india-specifications-launch-live-updates-9764207/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:36:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Electronics Unveils Samsung Vision AI and New Innovations at First Look 2025, Transforming Screens Into AI-Powered Companions and Elevating Everyday Life - Samsung Newsroom Malaysia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Launches Vision AI for Enhanced Smart Living at CES 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Samsung News</p>
<img src="https://img.global.news.samsung.com/my/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Samsung-TVs-and-Displays-CES-2025-Samsung-Vision-AI-and-Display-Lineups_dl1.jpg" alt="Samsung Vision AI at CES 2025" width="8256" height="5504">
<figcaption>Samsung unveiled Vision AI, transforming screens into intelligent companions.</figcaption>
<p>Samsung Electronics showcased Samsung Vision AI at CES 2025, introducing AI-driven screens designed to enrich daily life and enhance user interactions.</p>
<ul>
<li>Vision AI integrates personalized features to transform screens into adaptable companions.</li>
<li>New flagship Neo QLED 8K QN990F launched with cutting-edge AI features.</li>
<li>Expanded Samsung Art Store and The Frame line for a premium art experience at home.</li>
<li>Partnership with Microsoft enhances Smart TVs with Microsoft Copilot for improved user interaction.</li>
<li>Innovative new projectors and mirror displays redefine home technology applications.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Samsung sees TVs not as one-directional devices for passive consumption but as interactive, intelligent partners that adapt to your needs,” - SW Yong, President and Head of Visual Display Business.</blockquote>
<p>Samsung's innovations at CES 2025 illustrate its commitment to leading the future of display technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.samsung.com/my/samsung-electronics-unveils-samsung-vision-ai-and-new-innovations-at-first-look-2025-transforming-screens-into-ai-powered-companions-and-elevating-everyday-life</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.samsung.com/my/samsung-electronics-unveils-samsung-vision-ai-and-new-innovations-at-first-look-2025-transforming-screens-into-ai-powered-companions-and-elevating-everyday-life</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:16:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia is bringing a native GeForce Now app to Steam Deck - The Verge]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nvidia Introduces Native GeForce Now App for Steam Deck</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Later this year</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Nvidia Blog</p><p>Nvidia is set to launch a native GeForce Now app for the Steam Deck, making cloud gaming more accessible and efficient for users.</p><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='GeForce Now on Steam Deck'><figcaption>Nvidia GeForce Now on Steam Deck</figcaption><p>The new app aims to simplify the installation process and enable higher performance gaming.</p><ul><li>Nvidia will release a GeForce Now app for Steam Deck later this year.</li><li>The app will support up to 4K resolution and 60 fps with HDR when connected to a TV.</li><li>The current setup requires a special script, making the native app a more user-friendly option.</li><li>GeForce Now will also be available on major VR headsets including Apple Vision Pro and Meta Quest 3.</li><li>Upcoming Microsoft titles like <em>Avowed</em> and <em>DOOM: The Dark Ages</em> will be accessible via GeForce Now.</li></ul><blockquote>“Nvidia plans to bring GeForce Now to some major VR headsets later this month.”</blockquote><p>This new native application and the expansion to VR headsets reflect Nvidia's commitment to enhancing user experiences in cloud gaming.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337977/nvidia-native-geforce-now-app-steam-deck-vr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337977/nvidia-native-geforce-now-app-steam-deck-vr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asus’ latest ROG Flow Z13 gaming tablet uses AMD’s new integrated graphics - The Verge]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335012/asus-rog-flow-z13-gaming-tablet-amd-ryzen-max-plus-price-specs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24335012/asus-rog-flow-z13-gaming-tablet-amd-ryzen-max-plus-price-specs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The ROG Strix Scar 16 and 18 come with a lid that lights up and more RGB - The Verge]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Asus ROG Strix Scar 16 and 18 Unveiled with Exciting RGB Features</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Verge</p><img src="https://duet-cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0x0:2040x1360/2400x1599/filters:focal(1020x680:1021x681):format(webp)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25814836/247458_CES_2025_Asus_ROG_Strix_Scar_laptop_ADiBenedetto_0003.jpg" alt="Asus ROG Strix Scar Laptop"><figcaption>Asus ROG Strix Scar 16 and 18</figcaption><p>Asus has launched its latest ROG Strix Scar gaming laptops, which embrace a vibrant gamer aesthetic with customizable RGB lighting and a unique lid display.</p><ul><li>The Scar 16 and 18 feature a programmable LED dot-matrix display on the lid.</li><li>Specifications include an Intel Core Ultra 9 275HX processor and Nvidia GeForce RTX 5090 GPU.</li><li>Up to 64GB of RAM and a 2TB PCIe Gen4 SSD are available for configuration.</li><li>The ROG Nebula HDR display includes a 2.5K Mini LED panel with 1,200 nits brightness and a 240Hz refresh rate.</li><li>Asus claims low fan noise levels, thanks to advanced cooling technology.</li></ul><blockquote>“Asus claims it can keep fan noise levels to a library-like 45dB.”</blockquote><p>The ROG Strix Scar starts at $2,599 and will begin shipping in February 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24336394/asus-rog-strix-scar-16-18-specs-price-ces-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24336394/asus-rog-strix-scar-16-18-specs-price-ces-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Asus just announced the world’s first Thunderbolt 5 eGPU — the 2025 XG Mobile - The Verge]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/24336135/asus-thunderbolt-5-external-gpu-graphics-xg-mobile-ces-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24336135/asus-thunderbolt-5-external-gpu-graphics-xg-mobile-ces-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dell Announces Unified Branding With a 3-Category Lineup at CES 2025; AI Pro Studio Unveiled - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxORHFfME9UWU5WVUVENVMxQi11ZF9JZW9tRFprOHRhMmZ4SFlsWE1JRXdNRXVmTmxLVmpHZHR4TTRuczVLdkh4TGRwSVFnMkNCQk4tdjFYLTdlNEZlTFcwcWo0d0xvSVV3S1I5Nml4OFNUZnNQdEpSalp6Vjc1UHdCT256dXFsbEp0RUZXQTA4ZVRaVVhPWUJn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxORHFfME9UWU5WVUVENVMxQi11ZF9JZW9tRFprOHRhMmZ4SFlsWE1JRXdNRXVmTmxLVmpHZHR4TTRuczVLdkh4TGRwSVFnMkNCQk4tdjFYLTdlNEZlTFcwcWo0d0xvSVV3S1I5Nml4OFNUZnNQdEpSalp6Vjc1UHdCT256dXFsbEp0RUZXQTA4ZVRaVVhPWUJn?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:17:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD announces new processors for desktops, laptops, and handheld gaming PCs - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxPY2lxUThCLUg5bFRuVjd0M05oMWhPTUdYVUM4WXp3aEg4RUdwVC1hVnBfM3JPcWlWczlHcHJLU0prMDBZdVZYYi0yeWtqZVhrMHBFdGNyNHdOQlM2NGxKeXhWdEFvZ1RYQkZsc1owMnFSaEI4c0JQMTYxSVpUSHBfN1JtdExRalpkLTBzSnV2RDVDV1lSNlhhRFB0eUg2QXZOQUhGSGpZYl9yaTdrWl9fV0FmZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiswFBVV95cUxPY2lxUThCLUg5bFRuVjd0M05oMWhPTUdYVUM4WXp3aEg4RUdwVC1hVnBfM3JPcWlWczlHcHJLU0prMDBZdVZYYi0yeWtqZVhrMHBFdGNyNHdOQlM2NGxKeXhWdEFvZ1RYQkZsc1owMnFSaEI4c0JQMTYxSVpUSHBfN1JtdExRalpkLTBzSnV2RDVDV1lSNlhhRFB0eUg2QXZOQUhGSGpZYl9yaTdrWl9fV0FmZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:16:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alienware Goes Big at CES 2025: Announces New Desktops, Laptops And Monitors - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Alienware Goes Big at CES 2025: Announces New Desktops, Laptops And Monitors</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Tech News Network</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-117008428,thumbsize-1218867,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/117008428.jpg" alt="New products by Alienware that came out in CES 2025"><figcaption>New products by Alienware that came out in CES 2025</figcaption><p>Alienware, Dell's gaming powerhouse, has unveiled a range of new hardware at CES 2025, including Area-51 desktops and laptops, a 27-inch QD-OLED gaming monitor, and a customer support initiative named Alienware Elite Care.</p><ul><li>Revival of the iconic Alienware Area-51 desktops and laptops.</li><li>The new desktops support high-performance components, including next-gen NVIDIA graphics.</li><li>Introduction of a 27-inch 4K QD-OLED gaming monitor.</li><li>Launch of Alienware Elite Care for enhanced customer support.</li></ul><blockquote>“With this launch, Alienware appears to be solidifying its commitment to delivering high-performance gaming solutions.”</blockquote><p>This announcement by Alienware highlights its aim to cater to gamers' needs with powerful products and dedicated support, setting an ambitious tone for the year ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/gadgets/alienware-goes-big-at-ces-2025-announces-new-desktops-laptops-and-monitors-article-117007842</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/gadgets/alienware-goes-big-at-ces-2025-announces-new-desktops-laptops-and-monitors-article-117007842</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:04:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13 series India launch: Date, timings, and how to watch live stream - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 series India launch: Date, timings, and how to watch live stream</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/oneplus-13-series-launch-live-streaming.jpg?w=640" alt="OnePlus 13 series" width="640" height="360" />
<figcaption>OnePlus is expected to launch at least four products at its winter event. (Image credit: OnePlus)</figcaption>
<p>OnePlus is set to launch multiple new products during its winter event, which will be live-streamed on YouTube starting at 9:00 PM IST today.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The OnePlus 13 and 13R smartphones are among the key products being released.</li>
  <li>The flagship OnePlus 13 is powered by the Snapdragon 8 Elite chip, featuring innovative camera technology and a quad-curved display.</li>
  <li>The OnePlus 13R is expected to be a more affordable option with the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chip.</li>
  <li>Both models will feature large batteries with fast charging capabilities.</li>
  <li>Pricing is expected to be between Rs 65,000 - Rs 70,000 for the OnePlus 13 and under Rs 50,000 for the OnePlus 13R.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The OnePlus 13 will come with a quad-curved display, offering 2K resolution and a 120Hz refresh rate.”</blockquote>
<p>This launch event marks an exciting time for OnePlus fans in India, as the new models promise significant upgrades and enhanced features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/oneplus-13-oneplus-13r-india-launch-how-to-live-stream-9764039/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/oneplus-13-oneplus-13r-india-launch-how-to-live-stream-9764039/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:04:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dell resurrects Area-51 for the third time with Alienware 16 Area-51 and Alienware 18 Area-51 featuring Arrow Lake-HX and GeForce RTX 50 graphics sans DGFF - Notebookcheck.net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dell Revives Area-51 with New Alienware Gaming Laptops</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 2025-01-07 <strong>Source:</strong> Notebookcheck</p>
<img src="fileadmin/_processed_/5/c/csm_Alienware-Area-51-Laptops-4_259e5bfbca.jpg" loading="lazy" width="240" height="192" alt="Alienware Area-51 is offered in 16 and 18-inch variants. (Image Source: Dell)">
<figcaption>Alienware Area-51 is offered in 16 and 18-inch variants. (Image Source: Dell)</figcaption>
<p>Dell is once again introducing the Area-51 branding with the new Alienware 16 and 18 Area-51 laptops, powered by Intel's Arrow Lake-HX CPUs and Nvidia's RTX 50 GPUs.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Alienware 16 and 18 Area-51 are redesigned versions of the previous m16 and m18 models.</li>
<li>These laptops feature a zero-hinge design with a visible cooling area and enhanced thermal systems.</li>
<li>They are powered by Intel's Core Ultra 7 and 9 options and feature Nvidia's latest GPUs.</li>
<li>Displays are QHD+ (2560x1600) at 300 Hz, with a starting price of $1,999.</li>
<li>Availability is set for later in Q1 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Alienware 16 Area-51 and Alienware 18 Area-51 will be available later in Q1 in select configuration for a launch price of $3,199, with the entry-level configuration starting from $1,999."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the return of the Area-51 line marks a significant step forward for Dell in the gaming laptop market, emphasizing innovation in design and performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.notebookcheck.net/Dell-resurrects-Area-51-for-the-third-time-with-Alienware-16-Area-51-and-Alienware-18-Area-51-featuring-Arrow-Lake-HX-and-GeForce-RTX-50-graphics-sans-DGFF.942359.0.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.notebookcheck.net/Dell-resurrects-Area-51-for-the-third-time-with-Alienware-16-Area-51-and-Alienware-18-Area-51-featuring-Arrow-Lake-HX-and-GeForce-RTX-50-graphics-sans-DGFF.942359.0.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Unpacked 2025 to Take Place on January 22; New Galaxy S Series Launch Teased - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy Unpacked 2025 Confirmed to Be Held on January 22</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 22, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/rE84dndRLec/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Unpacked 2025" />
<figcaption>Promotional image for Samsung Galaxy Unpacked 2025</figcaption>
<p>Samsung has announced that the Galaxy Unpacked 2025 event will take place in San Jose, California, featuring the expected launch of the Galaxy S25 series.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The launch event is scheduled for January 22, 2025, at 10 am PT.</li>
  <li>The Galaxy S25 series is expected to deliver significant advancements in mobile AI experiences.</li>
  <li>Pre-reservations for the Galaxy S25 series are available in India, offering exclusive benefits to early customers.</li>
  <li>Three models of the Galaxy S25 are anticipated: Galaxy S25, Galaxy S25+, and Galaxy S25 Ultra.</li>
  <li>New features may include improved battery life and design changes for the Ultra model.</li>
  <li>Potential announcements for additional products like the Project Moohan XR headset and Galaxy Ring 2 are also expected.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The annual event will witness the launch of the new generation Galaxy S series.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the upcoming Galaxy Unpacked 2025 is set to be a key moment for Samsung, highlighting its latest innovations in mobile technology and AI.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/galaxy-unpacked-2025-date-galaxy-s25-launch-7416701</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/galaxy-unpacked-2025-date-galaxy-s25-launch-7416701</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:58:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia CEO unveils more powerful graphics cards at CES event - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nvidia CEO Unveils Powerful New Graphics Cards at CES 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu Business Line</p><img src="https://bl-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/9fkjtz/article69070962.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2025-01-02T091344Z_65255514_RC2K1CAUNRX5_RTRMADP_3_GLOBAL-MARKETS-MARKETCAP.JPG" alt="Nvidia CES 2025"/><figcaption>Jensen Huang presenting at CES 2025.</figcaption><p>Nvidia's new GeForce graphics cards, revealed by CEO Jensen Huang at CES 2025, are designed to leverage AI for enhanced gaming experiences, marking a shift towards more realistic graphics.</p><ul><li>Nvidia announced new GeForce 50 series graphics cards utilizing Blackwell design.</li><li>The flagship RTX 5090 will retail for $1,999 and be available later this month.</li><li>The RTX 5070, priced at $549, will launch in February 2025.</li><li>These new GPUs promise to enhance battery life for laptops and blend responsive gameplay with realism.</li><li>Nvidia's gaming division remains a significant revenue source, generating approximately $10 billion annually.</li></ul><blockquote>“GeForce allowed AI to reach the masses, and now AI is coming home to GeForce.” - Jensen Huang</blockquote><p>The unveiling of Nvidia's new graphics cards highlights the company's commitment to integrating AI into gaming technology, promising advancements that could redefine user experiences in the gaming industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/info-tech/nvidia-ceo-unveils-more-powerful-graphics-cards-at-ces-event/article69070950.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/info-tech/nvidia-ceo-unveils-more-powerful-graphics-cards-at-ces-event/article69070950.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:55:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NVIDIA announces DLSS4 with Multi Frame Generation exclusive to NVIDIA RTX 50 series - VideoCardz.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://videocardz.com/newz/nvidia-announces-dlss4-with-multi-frame-generation-exclusive-to-nvidia-rtx-50-series</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://videocardz.com/newz/nvidia-announces-dlss4-with-multi-frame-generation-exclusive-to-nvidia-rtx-50-series</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony and Honda's new Afeela electric car to start at $89,900, but only for buyers in California - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sony and Honda Launch Afeela Electric Car Starting at $89,900, Initially for California Buyers</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 08:30 AM IST <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/top_mv_01_pc_1736216542648_1736216556303.webp" alt="The Afeela will come in two trims; The Afeela 1 Origin, costing $89,900 and the Afeela 1 Signature, costing $102,900, revealed Sony Honda Mobility, the company formed as a result of the joint venture(shm-afeela.com)" title="The Afeela will come in two trims; The Afeela 1 Origin, costing $89,900 and the Afeela 1 Signature, costing $102,900, revealed Sony Honda Mobility, the company formed as a result of the joint venture(shm-afeela.com)">
  <figcaption>The Afeela will come in two trims; The Afeela 1 Origin, costing $89,900 and the Afeela 1 Signature, costing $102,900.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Sony and Honda have teamed up to introduce the 'Afeela,' an electric vehicle (EV) available for pre-orders at CES 2025 in Las Vegas. Initially, the car will be sold only in California.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Afeela comes in two trims: Afeela 1 Origin at $89,900 and Afeela 1 Signature at $102,900.</li>
  <li>Includes a three-year subscription to in-car features like Level 2+ driver assist and AI-powered personal assistant.</li>
  <li>Offers up to 300 miles of EPA-estimated range and supports Tesla's Supercharger network.</li>
  <li>Initial delivery for Signature trim starts in 2026, while Origin will follow in 2027.</li>
  <li>Features advanced technology including 40 sensors, cameras, and potential augmented reality integration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Come on out, Afeela” - Yasuhide Mizuno, CEO of Sony Honda Mobility.</blockquote>
<p>The Afeela represents a significant step in Sony and Honda's collaboration, reflecting the rising demand for EVs. Details on shopping for the vehicle will be announced soon.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/sony-and-hondas-new-afeela-electric-car-to-start-at-89-900-but-only-for-buyers-in-california-101736216409301.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/sony-and-hondas-new-afeela-electric-car-to-start-at-89-900-but-only-for-buyers-in-california-101736216409301.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:00:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple working to update AI feature after BBC complaint - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple to Update AI Feature Following BBC Complaints</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent<br /><strong>Source:</strong> BBC News</p><p>Apple is responding to concerns over its new AI feature that has produced inaccurate news alerts, stating it will implement a software update to clarify notifications generated by its AI system.</p><img src="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cd0elzk24dno/image.jpg" alt="Apple AI News Alerts" /><figcaption>Image illustrating Apple's AI feature.</figcaption><p>The company's flaws were highlighted after erroneous summaries of BBC notifications, including false claims about high-profile news events.</p><ul><li>Apple acknowledges issues with its AI news summarizations.</li><li>BBC complained about inaccuracies in notifications related to crucial news events.</li><li>Apple plans to roll out updates to improve notification clarity in the coming weeks.</li><li>Errors include misinformation about the PDC World Darts Championship and false claims about Rafael Nadal.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is critical that Apple urgently addresses these issues as the accuracy of our news is essential in maintaining trust.” - BBC Spokesperson</blockquote><p>In response, Apple has promised improvements and supports user feedback for better performance of its AI notifications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cge93de21n0o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cge93de21n0o</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:00:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R Launch In India Today: Price, Specs, How To Watch LIVE - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13, OnePlus 13R Launch In India Today: Price, Specs, How To Watch LIVE</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> TNN</p>
<img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-117005602,thumbsize-739291,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/117005602.jpg" alt="OnePlus 13 Series" title="OnePlus 13 Series">
<figcaption>OnePlus 13 Series</figcaption>
<p>The OnePlus 13 series is set to launch today in India at 9:00 PM IST, featuring the flagship OnePlus 13 and the more affordable OnePlus 13R.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The launch event will also include the introduction of the OnePlus Buds Pro 3.</li>
  <li>The OnePlus 13 boasts a Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Elite processor and a 6,000mAh battery.</li>
  <li>The device features a triple rear camera system with three 50MP sensors.</li>
  <li>The OnePlus 13R, powered by Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, includes a 50MP telephoto lens.</li>
  <li>Expected pricing: OnePlus 13R around Rs 50,000 and OnePlus 13 under Rs 70,000.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Rumours suggest that the OnePlus Buds Pro 3 could be priced at Rs 13,999 in India.</blockquote>
<p>The launch event promises to redefine smartphone expectations, showcasing advanced features and performance enhancements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/gadgets/oneplus-13-oneplus-13r-launch-in-india-today-price-specs-how-to-watch-live-article-117005606</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/gadgets/oneplus-13-oneplus-13r-launch-in-india-today-price-specs-how-to-watch-live-article-117005606</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s your touch that will push an AI co-worker to do better | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AI Co-Workers: Enhancing Productivity and Collaboration</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>As AI technology advances, artificial intelligence is becoming a vital part of the workplace, redefining the nature of co-working through collaboration rather than replacement.</p><ul><li>AI co-workers are seen as intelligent entities that improve productivity by automating repetitive tasks.</li><li>Rather than replacing human roles, AI collaborates with workers, enhancing teamwork.</li><li>These AI tools are rapidly integrating into various industries, reshaping operations and problem-solving processes.</li></ul><blockquote>"AI co-workers are not just tools; they are intelligent entities that enhance productivity and streamline operations."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, AI co-workers represent an evolution in workplace dynamics, aiding human colleagues rather than supplanting them, thereby paving the way for more innovation and efficiency in various sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/ideas/its-your-touch-that-will-push-an-ai-co-worker-to-do-better-11736070281021.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/ideas/its-your-touch-that-will-push-an-ai-co-worker-to-do-better-11736070281021.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 02:30:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Brings ‘Vision AI’ Features For Smart TVs At CES 2025: All Details - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Unveils ‘Vision AI’ Features for Smart TVs at CES 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="CES 2025 is starting this week and we could see a lot of AI-centric launches."><figcaption>CES 2025 is starting this week and we could see a lot of AI-centric launches.</figcaption><p>Samsung is revolutionizing their premium TV lineup by introducing a range of AI features dubbed ‘Vision AI’ at CES 2025.</p><ul><li>Samsung is launching AI features for Smart TVs, termed ‘Vision AI’.</li><li>Notable features include Click to Search, Live Translate, and Generative Wallpaper.</li><li>New collaborations with Microsoft and Google enhance the capabilities of Samsung’s AI features.</li><li>The flagship models include advanced AI processing capabilities with enhancements like 8K AI Upscaling Pro.</li><li>Samsung’s Vision AI provides real-time subtitle translations for live content.</li></ul><blockquote>“Samsung claimed that they would work with Google to expand what Vision AI can do.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Samsung’s focus on AI at CES 2025 marks a significant step forward in enhancing user experience through innovative applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/tech/samsung-brings-vision-ai-features-for-smart-tvs-at-ces-2025-all-details-9179562.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/tech/samsung-brings-vision-ai-features-for-smart-tvs-at-ces-2025-all-details-9179562.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 02:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>