<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:20:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:20:16 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xiaomi Pad 7’s purple patch emerges from an unconventional generational transition - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Xiaomi Pad 7 Review: A New Contender in the Tablet Market</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 13, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/The-Xiaomi-Pad-7-tablet---Vishal-Mathur--HT-Photo-_1736751775977.jpg" alt="The Xiaomi Pad 7 tablet. (Vishal Mathur/ HT Photo)" title="The Xiaomi Pad 7 tablet. (Vishal Mathur/ HT Photo)"><figcaption>The Xiaomi Pad 7 tablet. (Vishal Mathur/ HT Photo)</figcaption><p>The Xiaomi Pad 7 aims to build upon the success of its predecessor, the Pad 6, with aggressive pricing and improved features. This article reviews its performance, pricing options, and competition in the market.</p><ul><li>The Pad 7 is priced starting at ₹26,999 for the 8GB+128GB variant, and ₹29,999 for the 12GB+256GB option.</li><li>A unique nano-texture display option is available at ₹31,999, potentially reducing glare.</li><li>The Pad 7 features an 11.2-inch display, upgraded from 11 inches in Pad 6, with a new aspect ratio of 3:2.</li><li>It utilizes a Snapdragon 7+ Gen3 processor, which performs well despite being a lower spec chip compared to its predecessor's Snapdragon 870.</li><li>Battery life is impressive, lasting days on a single charge with an 8850mAh battery.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Xiaomi Pad 7 as a tablet is almost perfect... worth your time and money."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while the Xiaomi Pad 7 excels as a standalone tablet, some inconsistencies with the keyboard's touchpad detract from its overall appeal as a multifunctional device. Improvements in future software updates may address these concerns.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/xiaomi-pad-7-s-purple-patch-emerges-from-an-unconventional-generational-transition-101736751783233.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/xiaomi-pad-7-s-purple-patch-emerges-from-an-unconventional-generational-transition-101736751783233.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 07:03:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim spotted on Geekbench- Know about its benchmark scores - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim spotted on Geekbench- Know about its benchmark scores</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 22, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><h2><strong>Introduction</strong></h2><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim is expected to launch in early 2025 and has recently appeared on the Geekbench database, revealing its performance specifications.</p><h2><strong>Key Points</strong></h2><ul><li>Official debut at Galaxy Unpacked event slated for January 22, 2025.</li><li>Galaxy S25 Slim may launch in March or April 2025.</li><li>Geekbench scores show 3005 points in single-core and 6954 points in multi-core tests.</li><li>Expected to feature a Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset.</li><li>Specifications include a 6.66-inch display and a triple camera setup with a 200 MP main camera.</li></ul><h2><strong>Notable Quotes or Statistics</strong></h2><blockquote>“The multicore test was significantly lower than competitors as well as the Galaxy S25 Ultra benchmarks.”</blockquote><h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2><p>As the launch date approaches, more details are expected about the Galaxy S25 Slim's performance and features, which could influence buyer decisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tech.hindustantimes.com/mobile/news/samsung-galaxy-s25-slim-spotted-on-geekbench-know-about-its-benchmark-scores-71736749774907.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tech.hindustantimes.com/mobile/news/samsung-galaxy-s25-slim-spotted-on-geekbench-know-about-its-benchmark-scores-71736749774907.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:52:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[vivo T3 Pro and T3 Ultra 5G Now Available at Attractive New Prices - vivo Newsroom India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxOYTFyYS1sc0FKTmlaa2FNR1M2elExempaaU15cHNKTllvck1Fblo3VU9KQmFaZmh0bEZJS2FqX3RZRDYwREJSUmM4UFdwQTRPZkEyRm1BdmpSMlAxbGRONjJSNk91QWZDTkEzYVI5ejV4NWxnLXhuMzhOUjdWVW5NRXdpSUZLSzNJd29vX1VHZ0YtQUFPVEpwMkdvZzQ2NUstempldXI2a24?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxOYTFyYS1sc0FKTmlaa2FNR1M2elExempaaU15cHNKTllvck1Fblo3VU9KQmFaZmh0bEZJS2FqX3RZRDYwREJSUmM4UFdwQTRPZkEyRm1BdmpSMlAxbGRONjJSNk91QWZDTkEzYVI5ejV4NWxnLXhuMzhOUjdWVW5NRXdpSUZLSzNJd29vX1VHZ0YtQUFPVEpwMkdvZzQ2NUstempldXI2a24?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:38:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple could launch the iPhone Air later this year: Report - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Could Launch the iPhone 17 Air Later This Year: Report</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/84rxtt/article69094666.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-24T151505Z_1544621023_RC2U7S9D6GNF_RTRMADP_3_TECH-ANTITRUST-GOOGLE-SEARCH-APPLE.JPG" alt="Apple iPhone Air concept image"><figcaption>FILE PHOTO: Apple could be introducing the iPhone 17 Air as the new addition to their smartphone lineup.</figcaption><p>Apple might introduce the iPhone 17 Air, reportedly emphasizing its ultra-thin design, later this year, according to tech reporter Mark Gurman.</p><ul><li>The iPhone 17 Air could be “about 2 millimetres thinner” than standard models.</li><li>This phone may serve as a “testing ground for future technologies,” potentially paving the way for foldable devices.</li><li>Apple plans to debut its in-house modem alongside the new iPhone SE.</li><li>The upcoming iPhone lineup will feature WiFi and Bluetooth chips designed by Apple.</li><li>Other Apple products, like a new smart home hub, are expected to launch in 2025.</li></ul><blockquote>“The iPhone 17 Air could be a testing ground for future technologies.” — Mark Gurman</blockquote><p>Apple continues to innovate in its smartphone offerings, potentially positioning the iPhone 17 Air as a significant milestone in its product lineup.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/apple-could-launch-the-iphone-air-later-this-year-report/article69094704.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/apple-could-launch-the-iphone-air-later-this-year-report/article69094704.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Arcade Gets 10 New Games For iPhone and iPad Users: Full Details - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Arcade Introduces 10 New Games for iPhone and iPad Users</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="10 new games coming to iPhone and iPad users with Arcade"><figcaption>10 new games coming to iPhone and iPad users with Arcade</figcaption><p>Apple Arcade is expanding its game library with ten new titles, including a professional golf game, PGA TOUR Pro Golf. These games will enhance the gaming experience for iPhone and iPad users.</p><ul><li>The first new game, PGA TOUR Pro Golf, launches on February 6, 2025.</li><li>Seven games were released on January 10, 2025, with three more coming in early February.</li><li>Games allow multiplayer competitions on various popular PGA TOUR courses.</li><li>Subscription costs Rs 99 per month in India, allowing access for up to six family members.</li><li>Prominent titles include remasters of classic games like FINAL FANTASY+ and Trials of Mana+.</li></ul><blockquote>"Apple Arcade offers unlimited access to over 200 games without ads or in-app purchases."</blockquote><p>This expansion reflects Apple's commitment to enriching its gaming platform, providing exciting new experiences for subscribers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/tech/apple-arcade-gets-10-new-games-for-iphone-and-ipad-users-full-details-9186874.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/tech/apple-arcade-gets-10-new-games-for-iphone-and-ipad-users-full-details-9186874.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:22:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xiaomi Pad 7 goes on sale in India with introductory offers: Watch unboxing - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Xiaomi Pad 7 Now Available for Purchase in India with Special Offers</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> BS Tech, New Delhi</p><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" title="Xiaomi Pad 7" alt="Xiaomi Pad 7" width="826" height="465"><figcaption>Xiaomi Pad 7</figcaption><p>The Xiaomi Pad 7 has officially launched in India, introducing new features for productivity-focused users.</p><ul><li>The tablet is powered by the Qualcomm Snapdragon 7 Plus Gen 3 and runs Android 15-based HyperOS 2.0.</li><li>Available in 8GB and 12GB RAM variants with storage options of 128GB and 256GB.</li><li>Price ranges from Rs 27,999 to Rs 32,999 depending on the variant.</li><li>Introductory offer includes a Rs 1,000 discount for select ICICI Bank card users.</li><li>Accessories include a magnetic cover, focus pen, and keyboard available separately.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Xiaomi Pad 7 comes equipped with features tailored for improved productivity and user experience."</blockquote><p>This launch signifies Xiaomi's continued push into the Indian tablet market, emphasizing productivity and performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/xiaomi-pad-7-goes-on-sale-in-india-with-introductory-offers-watch-unboxing-125011300257_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/xiaomi-pad-7-goes-on-sale-in-india-with-introductory-offers-watch-unboxing-125011300257_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:45:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Redmi 14C 5G review in 10 points - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Redmi 14C 5G Review in 10 Points</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source: </strong> India Today</p>
<img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2025/01/cropped-IMG-20250106-WA0096ITG-1736746082635-scaled-1.jpg" alt="Redmi 14C 5G" />
<figcaption>Redmi 14C 5G</figcaption>
<p>Xiaomi’s sub-brand Redmi has launched the Redmi 14C 5G, refreshing its budget-friendly C series with a significant design overhaul and impressive features.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Redmi 14C features a 6.88-inch display with a 120Hz refresh rate.</li>
  <li>It is powered by a Snapdragon 4 Gen 2 chipset and runs on HyperOS 14 based on Android 14.</li>
  <li>The phone delivers satisfactory performance with minimal heating during charging.</li>
  <li>Battery capacity is 5,600mAh, lasting easily throughout the day.</li>
  <li>Charging is supported at 18W, which is relatively slow, taking about 1.5 hours to fully charge.</li>
  <li>Camera setup includes a 50-megapixel primary camera and a 2-megapixel secondary sensor.</li>
  <li>Selfies are decent but may lack sharpness, suitable for social media.</li>
  <li>The starting price is Rs 9,999, offering significant value in its category.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The Redmi 14C 5G offers great value for its price range."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the Redmi 14C 5G is a competitively priced smartphone that excels in design and battery life while providing satisfactory performance for budget-conscious consumers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/redmi-14c-5g-review-in-10-points-201994-13-01-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/redmi-14c-5g-review-in-10-points-201994-13-01-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:40:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[realme 14 Pro Series 5G redefines performance with best optimisation of Snapdragon 7s Gen 3 By IANS - Investing.com India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>realme 14 Pro Series 5G redefines performance with best optimisation of Snapdragon 7s Gen 3</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> IANS</p>
<p>In an era of digital innovation, the smartphone industry is evolving from traditional devices to advanced 'superphones.' These new devices balance power, power efficiency, and performance, particularly with the launch of the realme 14 Pro Series 5G.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Powered by the Snapdragon 7s Gen 3 5G chipset, built on a 4nm process.</li>
  <li>AnTuTu benchmarks exceed 820,000.</li>
  <li>Supports up to 12GB+14GB of LPDDR4X RAM and UFS 3.1 storage.</li>
  <li>Gaming performance achieves 90fps in popular games.</li>
  <li>Features a 50 MP Sony IMX896 camera sensor for high-quality photography.</li>
  <li>Supports simultaneous photo and video capture.</li>
  <li>Equipped with a 120Hz refresh rate on a 6.83-inch 1.5K AMOLED screen.</li>
  <li>Launch scheduled for January 16, 2024.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“With its groundbreaking features and segment-leading performance metrics, the realme 14 Pro Series 5G represents a significant step forward in democratising premium smartphone technology.”</blockquote>
<p>This device is setting new benchmarks for user expectations in mobile technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://in.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/realme-14-pro-series-5g-redefines-performance-with-best-optimisation-of-snapdragon-7s-gen-3-4608897</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://in.investing.com/news/stock-market-news/realme-14-pro-series-5g-redefines-performance-with-best-optimisation-of-snapdragon-7s-gen-3-4608897</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:18:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flipkart Republic Day Sale goes live with up to 50 percent off on select iPhone models - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Flipkart Republic Day Sale goes live with up to 50 percent off on select iPhone models</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/flipkart-republic-day-sale-1736745326.webp" alt="Flipkart Republic Day Sale" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>Flipkart Republic Day Sale</figcaption>
<p>Customers can look forward to amazing discounts on a variety of products in Flipkart's Republic Day Sale, which officially begins on January 14, 2025, with early access for Plus and VIP members starting January 13.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Discounts of up to 50 percent on select smartphones, including iPhones and Samsung models.</li>
  <li>Early access is available for Flipkart Plus and VIP members.</li>
  <li>Sale includes significant discounts on other categories such as smart TVs, home appliances, clothing, and beauty products.</li>
  <li>Noteworthy deals include the iPhone 16 dropping to Rs 63,999 and Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus going for Rs 59,999.</li>
  <li>Smart TVs up to 67 percent off, 32-inch TVs priced under Rs 7,000.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Flipkart is promoting its Republic Day Sale as a Monumental Sale, offering fantastic discounts across multiple categories."</blockquote>
<p>The Flipkart Republic Day Sale presents a golden opportunity for shoppers with substantial savings on popular products across various categories.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/flipkart-republic-day-sale-goes-live-with-up-to-50-percent-off-on-select-iphone-models-2025-01-13-970978</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/flipkart-republic-day-sale-goes-live-with-up-to-50-percent-off-on-select-iphone-models-2025-01-13-970978</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:15:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sharma East Ind Standalone December 2024 Net Sales at Rs 8.15 crore, up 39.35% Y-o-Y - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sharma East Ind Standalone December 2024 Net Sales at Rs 8.15 crore, up 39.35% Y-o-Y</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2017/04/shutterstock_310523045.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Sharma East Ind" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>Sharma East Ind has shown remarkable financial performance.</figcaption>
<p>The article discusses the impressive financial results of Sharma East India for the month of December 2024, highlighting a significant increase in net sales and profit compared to the previous year.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Net Sales reached Rs 8.15 crore, marking a 39.35% increase from Rs 5.85 crore in December 2023.</li>
  <li>Quarterly Net Profit was reported at Rs 0.29 crore, up 22.53% from Rs 0.23 crore in the same period last year.</li>
  <li>EBITDA increased to Rs 0.90 crore, reflecting a growth of 1.12% from Rs 0.89 crore in December 2023.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Net Sales at Rs 8.15 crore in December 2024 up 39.35% from Rs. 5.85 crore in December 2023."</blockquote>
<p>This growth reflects strong performance for Sharma East India, indicating robust market demand and effective operational management.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings/sharma-east-ind-standalone-december-2024-net-sales-at-rs-8-15-crore-up-39-35-y-o-y-12908656.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/earnings/sharma-east-ind-standalone-december-2024-net-sales-at-rs-8-15-crore-up-39-35-y-o-y-12908656.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:03:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple iOS 18.3 beta 2 introduces new features and enhancements - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxQLWlsa0tzTGFDMmthMFBUVkRNQXNyd2JmLTFiVk1GTFFMWFItMEY2TFBVOVNuTnU2Y29jT3JfOS1UQUt4bmZJRHJ5dmhqS3JIUWJYM2ZkQzR0dGVPOU1lNUktMlZ2eXpOVkh6OWlfNXBmY2hLS25hQmI2T3MtcWxITlNDeVFqd0ZwZUMzRnhMMnI5bEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxQLWlsa0tzTGFDMmthMFBUVkRNQXNyd2JmLTFiVk1GTFFMWFItMEY2TFBVOVNuTnU2Y29jT3JfOS1UQUt4bmZJRHJ5dmhqS3JIUWJYM2ZkQzR0dGVPOU1lNUktMlZ2eXpOVkh6OWlfNXBmY2hLS25hQmI2T3MtcWxITlNDeVFqd0ZwZUMzRnhMMnI5bEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:52:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Jio launches 5.5G network in India with speed boost - Tech in Asia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNOXRoZDlTNnFWSGdEbk9feENvbDl3d3pRbi1QQklnMmxBQ09INlV0NnNoUTA5ZXprZDZGMl94bHZhZlgtT01CSUh3SkRRWUlFVElTZUZRME16Q1JibldHN0pxbk9pcG1UVEpfWTduQjh6LVpfT3JIWkE4ZFpCN0R2MFhiYmk5eDUzY2NF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwFBVV95cUxNOXRoZDlTNnFWSGdEbk9feENvbDl3d3pRbi1QQklnMmxBQ09INlV0NnNoUTA5ZXprZDZGMl94bHZhZlgtT01CSUh3SkRRWUlFVElTZUZRME16Q1JibldHN0pxbk9pcG1UVEpfWTduQjh6LVpfT3JIWkE4ZFpCN0R2MFhiYmk5eDUzY2NF?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Republic Day Sale: Prime members get 12-hour early access, up to 70% off on dumbbells, yoga mats and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/amazon-republic-day-sale-prime-members-get-12-hour-early-access-up-to-70-off-on-dumbbells-yoga-mats-and-more-101736426934724.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/amazon-republic-day-sale-prime-members-get-12-hour-early-access-up-to-70-off-on-dumbbells-yoga-mats-and-more-101736426934724.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:25:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Republic Day Sale: Prime members get 12-hour early access, up to 70% off on dumbbells, yoga mats and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/amazon-republic-day-sale-prime-members-get-12-hour-early-access-up-to-70-off-on-dumbbells-yoga-mats-and-more-101736426934724.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/amazon-republic-day-sale-prime-members-get-12-hour-early-access-up-to-70-off-on-dumbbells-yoga-mats-and-more-101736426934724.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:25:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra Price In India, Dubai, USA And More, What To Expect On January 22 - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra Price In India, Dubai, USA And More, What To Expect On January 22</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-117189218,thumbsize-13446,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/117189218.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra" title="Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra"><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra</figcaption><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra is set to launch on January 22, 2025, boasting high-end features such as a 200MP camera and Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Launch date confirmed for January 22, 2025.</li><li>Estimated price in India: Rs 1,35,000.</li><li>Estimated price in the USA: starting at $1,300.</li><li>Expected price in Dubai: approximately AED 3,799.</li><li>Features include a 6.8-inch Dynamic AMOLED 2X display, 120Hz refresh rate, and Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset.</li><li>Advanced camera setup with 200MP sensor and new 50MP ultrawide lens.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics:</h2><blockquote>“The Galaxy S25 Ultra is expected to redefine the flagship smartphone experience.”</blockquote><p>Including competitive pricing to stay aligned with high-end devices like Apple’s iPhone 16 Pro Max.</p><h2>Conclusion:</h2><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra promises to be a flagship device packed with premium features, generating considerable anticipation ahead of its official launch.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/gadgets/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-price-in-india-dubai-usa-and-more-what-to-expect-on-january-22-article-117189233</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/gadgets/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-price-in-india-dubai-usa-and-more-what-to-expect-on-january-22-article-117189233</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:22:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clarity in Complexity: How People Matters Octopus Can Simplify Your HR Tech Decisions - People Matters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQY0JKVzJnSVdlMG9jWXFKNGNWMGV1VU1pdWNqdy1BQ3h4R0JBWEJWMDg1d2FSdXN1dHhXWl96SmE0NlFVRnJIMEhmME0wMjh6VmpINHNvS1NWazBnYlB5Z0RDWFVGU2lZYjRkY3JqSldLeXJFZzFzaXAwcS14ZURtYXJkdVlhY0FBSW01WjNkY2Z5TDEwdTBkb1hBUUNRMUwzUzVBRDY2cjhleXJvMTZSZjdDdDA0RUp4bGxPYVNqX1cyQ0RlekszZHZmS2J6Um1YMExkUdIBzwFBVV95cUxOWkFyY0pwZmMyNEVMNTA1T2tJUndpeXRQVjhRNFZzdmNNWTd6bW41ME10M0pNdnBHU05zQlQ2WDdRdzMweURaZ2I3UE5odmZjbzQ0eWVXLWNyV0NIT2I5TUxsRHJmZ3A4b2FSYWNIZmpVeEdFbHlLelRla291SmJrcGt0VFdjVDBXRS02Q0gtVmR1RFVVV01JeDZzLVVUUVpjd05xS0U3VGhmT3hKWW10bV9ZdTlaa2NBbGlON3I4NC1PdlhrZGlPX3Ayd1RCb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1AFBVV95cUxQY0JKVzJnSVdlMG9jWXFKNGNWMGV1VU1pdWNqdy1BQ3h4R0JBWEJWMDg1d2FSdXN1dHhXWl96SmE0NlFVRnJIMEhmME0wMjh6VmpINHNvS1NWazBnYlB5Z0RDWFVGU2lZYjRkY3JqSldLeXJFZzFzaXAwcS14ZURtYXJkdVlhY0FBSW01WjNkY2Z5TDEwdTBkb1hBUUNRMUwzUzVBRDY2cjhleXJvMTZSZjdDdDA0RUp4bGxPYVNqX1cyQ0RlekszZHZmS2J6Um1YMExkUdIBzwFBVV95cUxOWkFyY0pwZmMyNEVMNTA1T2tJUndpeXRQVjhRNFZzdmNNWTd6bW41ME10M0pNdnBHU05zQlQ2WDdRdzMweURaZ2I3UE5odmZjbzQ0eWVXLWNyV0NIT2I5TUxsRHJmZ3A4b2FSYWNIZmpVeEdFbHlLelRla291SmJrcGt0VFdjVDBXRS02Q0gtVmR1RFVVV01JeDZzLVVUUVpjd05xS0U3VGhmT3hKWW10bV9ZdTlaa2NBbGlON3I4NC1PdlhrZGlPX3Ayd1RCb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:05:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Online Court Hearing Hacked: Urgent Call for Stronger Cybersecurity in Courts - The420.in]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOVkt2TzcxcDl2TVk1NV9CaXQwQVhETTlfdlZycFBlREpxWWRMdUJLQm9RVldNMWdURmVhSDBSVFRaMV9DZk9lUXVIRGdCY0g3UkhZeTFHWUZYUTZoY1hsN2hWdnF6Q1F2TzRTZGNWSGFxRWd0cWREcVE3WGJmY0Ewb2I4ckpKSlRPZ3ZJMXpETFlxZU1oS09EaC1EVFozeDkxMnhGdmk3emNMVjJUTElESHA1NnZYdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOVkt2TzcxcDl2TVk1NV9CaXQwQVhETTlfdlZycFBlREpxWWRMdUJLQm9RVldNMWdURmVhSDBSVFRaMV9DZk9lUXVIRGdCY0g3UkhZeTFHWUZYUTZoY1hsN2hWdnF6Q1F2TzRTZGNWSGFxRWd0cWREcVE3WGJmY0Ewb2I4ckpKSlRPZ3ZJMXpETFlxZU1oS09EaC1EVFozeDkxMnhGdmk3emNMVjJUTElESHA1NnZYdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:01:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX Redeem Codes today on January 13: How to redeem codes and win new skins, diamonds, a - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX Redeem Codes today on January 13</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13<br><strong>Source:</strong> Garena</p>
<p>An overview of the latest redeem codes for Garena Free Fire MAX on January 13, offering players a chance to win exciting skins, diamonds, and more.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Players can use specific redeem codes to unlock various in-game items.</li>
  <li>These codes are time-sensitive and may expire quickly, so players are encouraged to redeem them promptly.</li>
  <li>New skins and diamonds are among the available rewards for redemption.</li>
  <li>Instructions are provided on how to redeem these codes effectively.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Redeem these codes for exclusive items and enhance your gaming experience!"</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, players need to keep an eye on the latest codes and redeem them quickly to benefit from the game's offerings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-today-on-january-13-how-to-redeem-codes-and-win-new-skins-diamonds-and-more/articleshow/117188680.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-today-on-january-13-how-to-redeem-codes-and-win-new-skins-diamonds-and-more/articleshow/117188680.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple users, beware of Banshee Stealer: Malware targeting macOS devices - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple users, beware of Banshee Stealer: Malware targeting macOS devices</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Nandini Yadav</p><p>The Banshee Stealer malware has resurfaced, targeting macOS devices and stealing sensitive information such as browser credentials and passwords.</p><ul><li>The malware targets macOS users and can extract critical data while remaining undetected.</li><li>It first emerged in mid-2024, being offered as a “stealer-as-a-service” to cybercriminals.</li><li>On September 2024, an updated version was found which evaded antivirus systems.</li><li>Distributed through phishing websites and fake repositories, disguising itself as legitimate software.</li><li>Experts warn users to reassess their security practices and take proactive measures.</li></ul><blockquote>“This stealthy malware doesn’t just infiltrate; it operates undetected, blending seamlessly with normal system processes while stealing browser credentials...” - Check Point Research</blockquote><p>Banshee Stealer highlights the need for increased vigilance among macOS users as cyber threats continue to evolve.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/apple-users-beware-of-banshee-stealer-malware-targeting-macos-devices-2663831-2025-01-13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/apple-users-beware-of-banshee-stealer-malware-targeting-macos-devices-2663831-2025-01-13</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 03:59:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25, Galaxy S25+ and Galaxy S25 Ultra Design and Specifications Leak Ahead of Launch - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Series Renders and Specifications Leak Ahead of Launch</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/samsung_galaxy_s25_evan_blass_1736739555010.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S25 Series Renders" loading="lazy"><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S25 Series Renders<br>Photo Credit: Evan Blass</figcaption><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 series is set to launch on January 22, 2024, and ahead of this event, leaked renders and specifications reveal notable design changes and features for the new devices.</p><ul><li>The standard Galaxy S25 and Galaxy S25+ maintain similarities to their predecessors.</li><li>The Galaxy S25 Ultra features rounded corners and significant design tweaks.</li><li>All models will be powered by Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite SoC with 12GB of RAM and will run on Android 15-based One UI 7.</li><li>The base Galaxy S25 will have a 6.2-inch Dynamic AMOLED 2X screen and a 4,000mAh battery.</li><li>The Galaxy S25 Ultra will have a quad camera setup, including a 200-megapixel primary lens.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Galaxy S25 Ultra may come with rounded corners, ditching the traditional boxy design.”</blockquote><p>This series is poised to become a major player in the mobile market with its advanced features and design. Consumers are eagerly anticipating the official launch to see what the Galaxy S25 series will bring.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/samsung-s25-series-renders-specifications-leak-galaxy-report-7460924</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/samsung-s25-series-renders-specifications-leak-galaxy-report-7460924</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 03:43:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Redmi Note 14 and Note 14 Pro with 6.67″ FHD+ 120Hz AMOLED display, 5500mAh battery announced - FoneArena]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Xiaomi Launches REDMI Note 14 and Note 14 Pro Smartphones</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Fone Arena</p>
<img src="https://images.fonearena.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Redmi-Note-14-and-Note-14-Pro-1024x856.jpg" alt="REDMI Note 14 and Note 14 Pro" width="575" height="480">
<figcaption>Image of the REDMI Note 14 and Note 14 Pro smartphones</figcaption>
<p>Xiaomi has introduced the REDMI Note 14 and Note 14 Pro smartphones for global markets, featuring impressive specifications including high-resolution cameras and large batteries.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The REDMI Note 14 features a 6.67-inch FHD+ AMOLED display, 120Hz refresh rate, and a MediaTek Helio G99-Ultra processor.</li>
  <li>It includes a 108MP main camera and a 5500mAh battery with 33W fast charging.</li>
  <li>The REDMI Note 14 Pro boasts a 6.67-inch curved AMOLED display, 200MP main camera, and a MediaTek Helio G100-Ultra processor.</li>
  <li>Both devices run Android 14 with Hyper OS and feature Google Gemini assistant.</li>
  <li>Pricing starts at USD 199 for the Note 14 and USD 299 for the Note 14 Pro.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These smartphones are versatile with advanced AI features and fast charging, catering to a diverse user base.” - Xiaomi Representative</blockquote>
<p>The REDMI Note series continues to innovate in providing powerful specifications at competitive prices, appealing to consumers worldwide.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fonearena.com/blog/444155/redmi-note-14-note-14-pro-price-specifications.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fonearena.com/blog/444155/redmi-note-14-note-14-pro-price-specifications.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 03:40:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Great Republic Day Sale: iPhone 15, Realme GT 7 Pro, and more phones on discounts - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amazon Great Republic Day Sale 2025: Check out the list of top 5 discounted smartphones including iPhone 15, Realme GT 7 Pro, and others.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/1730780862086902ba1e31759444ba2c92aea91953104_1730975620781_1736736797673.jpg" alt="Amazon is providing massive price drops on phones during the Great Republic Day Sale, check details.(Realme)"><figcaption>Amazon is providing massive price drops on phones during the Great Republic Day Sale, check details.(Realme)</figcaption></figure><p>Amazon has launched its Great Republic Day Sale for 2025, offering significant discounts on various smartphones including popular models like the iPhone 15 and Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra.</p><ul><li>iPhone 15 price dropped from ₹69,990 to ₹56,999.</li><li>Realme GT 7 Pro available for ₹59,998, down from ₹69,999.</li><li>iQOO 12 now priced at ₹45,999, previously ₹59,999.</li><li>Vivo X200 Pro discounted to ₹94,999 from ₹1,01,999.</li><li>Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra now ₹71,999 with a 52% discount from ₹1,49,999.</li></ul><blockquote>“Buyers can avail bank and exchange offers to further reduce prices.”</blockquote><p>This sale provides a great opportunity for buyers looking to upgrade their smartphones at discounted rates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-iphone-15-realme-gt-7-pro-and-more-phones-on-discounts-101736736675363.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-great-republic-day-sale-iphone-15-realme-gt-7-pro-and-more-phones-on-discounts-101736736675363.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 03:07:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes, January 13, 2025, edition: Grab these exclusive perks before they disappear - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for January 13, 2025: Exclusive Perks Available Now</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p><img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/South-Western-Railway-4.png?w=300" alt="South Western Railway" width="198" height="110"><figcaption>South Western Railway announces partial cancellation, diversion of trains for track maintenance</figcaption><p>Garena Free Fire MAX is experiencing a surge in popularity in India, offering redeem codes that unlock exclusive in-game rewards like skins and weapons. The game's regular updates keep players engaged, making it a strong competitor in the battle royale genre.</p><ul><li>Redeem codes are limited to 500 redemptions and valid for 24 hours.</li><li>Codes provide access to weapons, skins, and other enhancements for free.</li><li>There is significant competition from other battle royale games such as PUBG Mobile.</li><li>Redeeming is done via the official Rewards Redemption website.</li></ul><blockquote>“These codes are extremely time sensitive. They’re only valid for 24 hours.”</blockquote><p>Stay updated with daily codes to enhance your gameplay experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-january-13-2025-edition-grab-these-exclusive-perks-before-they-disappear-3713398/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-january-13-2025-edition-grab-these-exclusive-perks-before-they-disappear-3713398/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:47:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Siri settlement: A discretion jolt for advertisers - Campaign India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxPRnlqWFNqV0VaMERQdkF5UUUzcUpHc2RHTndSMkppUV9tZm5pb3RvT2hfNlJEbl9VcWpmQkFHX05GdzBEVDhOTFQ2dXpPazVQckQ0ekVjeVVJeXdXbURWQl9XaW8taW05Ym56aWRVOHF2NG1kWHBlVUFvZVJZMUpaSF82YWhBc3FQMlhGOE5iN2Z4bTJKRHIwbjRFWGZCMmU2?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxPRnlqWFNqV0VaMERQdkF5UUUzcUpHc2RHTndSMkppUV9tZm5pb3RvT2hfNlJEbl9VcWpmQkFHX05GdzBEVDhOTFQ2dXpPazVQckQ0ekVjeVVJeXdXbURWQl9XaW8taW05Ym56aWRVOHF2NG1kWHBlVUFvZVJZMUpaSF82YWhBc3FQMlhGOE5iN2Z4bTJKRHIwbjRFWGZCMmU2?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:45:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Galaxy S25 Ultra: Everything we know so far about Samsung’s next flagship smartphone - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Galaxy S25 Ultra: Everything We Know So Far About Samsung’s Next Flagship Smartphone</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra.jpg' alt='Galaxy S25 Ultra'><figcaption>Galaxy S25 Ultra offers a 6.9-inch screen. (Image credit: Android Headlines)</figcaption><p>Samsung is set to unveil the Galaxy S25 series on January 22, with the Galaxy S25 Ultra expected to be a highly sought-after smartphone for 2025. Rumors indicate subtle design changes and impressive hardware upgrades.</p><ul><li>The Galaxy S25 Ultra maintains a similar design ethos to its predecessor but with a boxier design and flat frame.</li><li>It features a large 6.9-inch flat screen with WQHD+ resolution and a 120Hz refresh rate.</li><li>It includes a quad-camera setup with a 200 MP primary camera and an upgraded 50 MP ultra-wide lens.</li><li>Powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite for Galaxy, it will support up to 1 TB storage and 12 GB RAM.</li><li>Shipping with Android 15-based OneUI 7, the device promises seven years of updates.</li><li>The battery capacity remains at 5,000 mAh, with 45W fast charging.</li><li>Expected pricing for the base variant ranges from Rs 1,20,000 to Rs 1,30,000.</li></ul><blockquote>“Samsung seems to be playing it safe when it comes to battery and fast charging.”</blockquote><p>The Galaxy S25 Ultra is shaping up to be a significant upgrade and is anticipated to attract considerable attention upon its launch.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-features-specs-price-launch-9774373/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-features-specs-price-launch-9774373/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13 vs iPhone 16 Plus: Which premium phone wins? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 vs iPhone 16 Plus: Which premium phone wins?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>The comparison between OnePlus 13 and iPhone 16 Plus highlights significant differences in design, performance, and software capabilities, leading to varying user preferences.</p><ul><li>The iPhone 16 Plus features a frosted glass back and a 6.7-inch OLED screen with 60Hz refresh rate.</li><li>OnePlus 13 offers a faux leather or glass finish, a slightly larger 6.82-inch AMOLED screen with 120Hz refresh rate, and IP69 water resistance.</li><li>In terms of software, iOS 18 offers extensive AI features, whereas OnePlus’s OxygenOS 15 provides customizable options.</li><li>Camera-wise, OnePlus 13 has a superior triple camera setup compared to the dual camera on the iPhone 16 Plus.</li><li>Battery performance favors OnePlus 13 with a 6,000mAh capacity compared to iPhone's lower capacity and slower charging.</li></ul><blockquote>“The OnePlus 13 is the clear winner with its smoother screen, bigger battery, more capable camera system, and open-sourced customisable operating system.”</blockquote><p>Ultimately, the decision between the two devices depends on individual preferences regarding operating systems and desired features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/oneplus-13-vs-apple-iphone-16-plus-design-display-camera-battery-9773523/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/oneplus-13-vs-apple-iphone-16-plus-design-display-camera-battery-9773523/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oppo Reno 13 Series Launched In India: Price, Features - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Oppo Reno 13 Series Launched In India: Price, Features</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The Reno 13 and 13 Pro models get new hardware and design."><figcaption>The Reno 13 and 13 Pro models get new hardware and design.</figcaption><p>Oppo has officially launched the Reno 13 and Reno 13 Pro 5G models in India, aimed primarily at camera enthusiasts. These devices were unveiled in China a few months ago and have received some design tweaks tailored for the Indian market.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Reno 13 5G starts at Rs 37,999 for 8+128GB and Rs 39,999 for 8+256GB versions.</li><li>Reno 13 Pro 5G starts at Rs 49,999 for 12+256 GB and Rs 54,999 for 12+512GB options.</li><li>Both models are powered by MediaTek Dimensity chipsets and run on Android 15.</li><li>The basic Reno 13 features a dual camera setup with a 50MP main sensor and 50MP front camera.</li><li>The Reno 13 Pro has a triple camera setup, including a 50MP main sensor and a 50MP telephoto sensor.</li><li>Both models offer significant battery life with fast charging support.</li></ul><blockquote>“The premium version gets a 5,800 mAh battery that supports 80W charging speed.”</blockquote><p>The launch of the Oppo Reno 13 series emphasizes the brand's commitment to improving photographic capabilities and overall user experience in the mid-range smartphone segment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/tech/oppo-reno-13-series-launched-in-india-price-features-9184191.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/tech/oppo-reno-13-series-launched-in-india-price-features-9184191.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:30:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iOS 18.3 Update Coming Soon For iPhone Users: What You Can Expect - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iOS 18.3 Update Coming Soon For iPhone Users: What You Can Expect</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The new iOS 18 update should be rolling in the next few weeks."><figcaption>The new iOS 18 update should be rolling in the next few weeks.</figcaption><p>Apple is set to release the iOS 18.3 update for iPhone users later this month, following the bug-fixing iOS 18.2.1 update. Users are eagerly anticipating the new AI features with this update.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The iOS 18.3 beta is currently in its second stage.</li><li>A potential new Invites app has been spotted in the beta code, which might assist in organizing events and meetings.</li><li>Further details about the features in the upcoming public release are expected soon.</li><li>Siri's AI capabilities are anticipated to be a significant focus in this update.</li></ul><blockquote><p>"The Siri AI integration still feels half baked... we might see some glimpses of that with the iOS 18.3 and the iPadOS 18.3 versions."</p></blockquote><p>The iOS 18.3 update is being awaited by users looking for new features and improvements, especially in AI functionalities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/tech/ios-18-3-update-coming-soon-for-iphone-users-what-you-can-expect-9186557.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/tech/ios-18-3-update-coming-soon-for-iphone-users-what-you-can-expect-9186557.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:00:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX Redeem Codes Today January 13, 2025: Grab Kakashi Bundle, Naruto Emote – Ninja Run, Clone Jutsu And… - News24]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX Redeem Codes Today January 13, 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News24</p>
<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>Garena Free Fire MAX is an enhanced version of the classic battle royale game that offers players improved graphics, gameplay, and new features. Today, several redeem codes are available for players to claim exciting rewards.</p>
<h2>Steps to Redeem Garena Free Fire MAX Redeem Codes</h2>
<ul>
<li>Log on to the official website – <a href="https://reward.ff.garena.com/en">Garena Reward</a></li>
<li>Use your Facebook, Google, Twitter, or VK IDs to log in</li>
<li>Copy and paste the redeem codes into the text box</li>
<li>Click on the confirm button to continue</li>
<li>A dialogue box will pop up to cross-check. Click ‘OK’</li>
<li>After successfully redeeming the codes, collect your reward in the in-game mail section</li>
</ul>
<h2>Available Redeem Codes</h2>
<ul>
<li>FFKSY7PQNWHG – Kakashi Bundle</li>
<li>FF4MTXQPFDZ9 – Poker MP40 Ring</li>
<li>FFSP9XQ2TNZK – Super Emote – Gamabunta Summoning</li>
<li>FFSUTXVQF2NR – Sasuke (Without Katana) Special Gold Royale Bundle + Rasegan Emote</li>
<li>FFNRWTQPFDZ9 – Naruto Ascension + Rasengan + Gloo Wall – Hokage Rock + Loot Box – Body Substitution</li>
<li>FFMGY7TPWNV2 – Naruto Emote – Ninja Run, Clone Jutsu</li>
<li>FFMSTXP2FWCK – Mystery Shop – Sakura Bundle, Grand Slam Bundle</li>
<li>FFXT7SW9KG2M – 1875 Diamonds</li>
<li>NPFT7FKPCXNQ – M1887 One Punch Man Skin</li>
<li>... [additional codes as listed in the original article]</li>
</ul>
<h2>Important Note For Players</h2>
<p>Players must link their game accounts to one of the supported platforms to redeem these codes. The codes are valid for a limited time only (24 hours) and can be used once.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Garena Free Fire MAX offers exciting opportunities for players to enhance their gaming experience with special redeem codes. Make sure to redeem them promptly to enjoy exclusive in-game rewards.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news24online.com/tech/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-today-january-13-2025-grab-kakashi-bundle-naruto-emote-ninja-run-clone-jutsu-and/440367/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news24online.com/tech/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-today-january-13-2025-grab-kakashi-bundle-naruto-emote-ninja-run-clone-jutsu-and/440367/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:45:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech Next | POCO X7 Pro: Unleashing speed, powerful performance and long lasting battery - DTNEXT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxOMnVvamM2eWJaNGkzYTVINTU3Wjh0RjRhd0FOMEhSQS05WF9wX1UzeXRucU1aaWRrbjlUOTFseFRmZGFLdVRlN3JiNk53b2ZBWnp3NXo0ZE5SUnlZZGNoNm5NeGwyZzJlNnYtbHRSU0hyUmxuT0d4c0dmSkVoOWlsSndJc2duVEo1Y3MxenUzVVZYTjJsVHVfVG1pRmVmMEJYUlRiQUJHS3BQZkh6ZVpnaW1UZTEyd1p5SndPY1dzVE1KUdIBxwFBVV95cUxPNXdlT290MTA0NXo1MWtocHVvX2gtVWlNaEdXUEJvTFNmb2Y5MjFnd2FiUlhRaEJVQlFXam44UTU0MFdna1NWWUlhYl9xWlE2TGhMejRvdGJoSFUzUzVfMUtTMWNIRmc4eU82bXRram5LNDhNX0ZZMHRnNk9mNVdTMExoRDJGQ0FOaWhhWnVFQjlsLV9iQ1A1S08wWXI2dnRRN2ZIaVNnTzRaZ0YwaEpzZ21PNEw1MnRBQk95STd3dU93ODB4N21r?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwgFBVV95cUxOMnVvamM2eWJaNGkzYTVINTU3Wjh0RjRhd0FOMEhSQS05WF9wX1UzeXRucU1aaWRrbjlUOTFseFRmZGFLdVRlN3JiNk53b2ZBWnp3NXo0ZE5SUnlZZGNoNm5NeGwyZzJlNnYtbHRSU0hyUmxuT0d4c0dmSkVoOWlsSndJc2duVEo1Y3MxenUzVVZYTjJsVHVfVG1pRmVmMEJYUlRiQUJHS3BQZkh6ZVpnaW1UZTEyd1p5SndPY1dzVE1KUdIBxwFBVV95cUxPNXdlT290MTA0NXo1MWtocHVvX2gtVWlNaEdXUEJvTFNmb2Y5MjFnd2FiUlhRaEJVQlFXam44UTU0MFdna1NWWUlhYl9xWlE2TGhMejRvdGJoSFUzUzVfMUtTMWNIRmc4eU82bXRram5LNDhNX0ZZMHRnNk9mNVdTMExoRDJGQ0FOaWhhWnVFQjlsLV9iQ1A1S08wWXI2dnRRN2ZIaVNnTzRaZ0YwaEpzZ21PNEw1MnRBQk95STd3dU93ODB4N21r?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:00:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>