<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Latest Technology articles]]></description><link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 02:39:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 02:39:46 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><ttl>600000</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Why bitcoin is booming]]></title><description><![CDATA[
											

						
<figure>

<img alt="A cartoon image of US President-elect Donald Trump holding a Bitcoin token to mark the cryptocurrency reaching over $100,000." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Justin Chin/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/12/gettyimages-2187851174.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The price of bitcoin surged past $100,000 for the first time on Thursday, continuing a post-election run buoyed by the pro-<a href="https://www.vox.com/crypto">crypto</a> promise of the incoming Trump administration.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Election Day, bitcoin — one of the most popular decentralized digital assets available — was worth $69,374, according to the cryptocurrency trading platform Coinbase. Within a month, it had spiked more than 44 percent. Other cryptocurrencies like ethereum and XRP also shot up during that period.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Cryptocurrencies’ sudden increase in value is a sign of investor optimism about President-elect Donald Trump’s policies and those of his picks to head several key regulatory agencies, some of whom have explicitly promised deregulation of the crypto industry.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That bitcoin hit the $100,000 mark reflects the expectation of both political support and regulatory latitude under the incoming administration,” said <a href="https://www.libarts.colostate.edu/people/ramaa/">Ramaa Vasudevan</a>, an economics professor at Colorado State University who has been critical of crypto. “The nomination of crypto-enthusiasts for administrative posts is a clear signal of the embrace of bitcoin and crypto triggering the flood of money into these markets.” <br>Bitcoin’s rally is also a product of its increased legitimacy. Trump’s election may have sparked its rally, but the financial establishment’s embrace of the asset in recent months provided the tinder. While bitcoin was once a niche curiosity, it is now a mainstream digital currency that everyday Americans can now buy through reputable retail investment accounts. Even if bitcoin ultimately turns out to be a bubble, as <a href="https://www.miamiherald.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/andres-oppenheimer/article295793799.html">many economists have argued</a> it may, these investment vehicles have assured it some staying power.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The policies of the incoming Trump administration are fueling optimism</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump has been an ardent cryptocurrency supporter throughout his most recent presidential campaign, and his choices to lead key government agencies related to its regulation reflect that enthusiasm.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bitcoin hit its highest valuation ever following the nomination of <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/12/04/paul-atkins-trump-sec-crypto">Paul Atkins</a> on Wednesday to head the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), which is in charge of <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/security.asp">regulating tradable securities like stocks</a>. Atkins was previously an SEC commissioner for six years during former President George W. Bush’s administration.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Atkins is “not necessarily the sort of burn-it-all-down type of nominee that Trump has decided upon for other positions,” Molly White, a cryptocurrency researcher and critic, told Vox. “He&#8217;s fairly establishment; he has the SEC background, but he also was a very strong advocate for deregulation when he was in the SEC and certainly since then.” Atkins is also a co-chair of the <a href="https://digitalchamber.org/priorities/digital-tokens/">Chamber of Digital Commerce’s Token Alliance</a>, an industry lobbying group that advocates for lax regulation of cryptocurrencies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2024/12/04/trump-considers-pro-crypto-perianne-boring-caroline-pham-as-possible-cftc-chairs">Perianne Boring</a>, the CEO of the Chamber of Digital Commerce, is rumored to be one of Trump’s top picks for another key position: head of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), which makes rules around the trading of futures and commodities. Currently, cryptocurrency is under the purview of the SEC, but the Trump administration is <a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/markets/trump-admin-eyes-cftc-lead-digital-asset-regulation">reportedly weighing</a> regulating it as a commodity instead. If that change is made, cryptocurrency would come under the purview of the CFTC, which is often seen to be more hands-off in its approach to regulation. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Billionaire crypto enthusiast David Sacks, whom Trump named Thursday <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-appoints-former-paypal-coo-david-sacks-ai-crypto-czar-2024-12-06/">as his crypto and AI czar</a>, will be tasked with helping formulate crypto and AI policy from the White House. In that role, Trump said in a post on Truth Social, Sacks will work closely with both the SEC and CTFC to <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/crypto-industry-hails-david-sacks-czar/">develop a legal framework to regulate crypto.</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump himself is also connected to cryptocurrency via his <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-29/trump-s-crypto-project-was-a-bust-until-justin-sun-stepped-in?sref=qYiz2hd0">family’s cryptocurrency and trading venture World Liberty Financial</a>. Pro-cryptocurrency groups <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/11/05/cryptos-245-million-campaign-finance-operation-funded-non-crypto-ads.html">spent $245 million in this year’s elections</a>, more than any other industry, to support candidates across the country seen as friendlier to crypto.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of that likely means that the regulatory landscape under a Trump administration will be much friendlier for crypto following heavier regulations and <a href="https://www.wsj.com/finance/regulation/trump-crypto-us-war-0b91cc21">a slew of lawsuits against crypto companies</a> during current SEC chair Gary Gensler’s tenure.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The recent wave of investment in the crypto space is largely driven by the growing belief that years of regulatory uncertainty and lawfare may finally be giving way to clarity,” said Christian Catalini, founder of the MIT Cryptoeconomics Lab.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gensler’s SEC cracked <a href="https://www.wsj.com/finance/regulation/trump-crypto-us-war-0b91cc21">down on trading platforms like Coinbase, Binance, and Kraken</a>, arguing that the buying and selling of cryptocurrency should have the same oversight as something like a stock or bond, and that investors should have access to the same kinds of information about crypto companies as they would have about a company that they are buying stock in. Crypto trading platforms and associated companies, however, argue that crypto tokens aren’t the same as stocks and therefore shouldn’t have the same regulations applied.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The SEC has brought lawsuits against several major crypto platforms, including Coinbase, which are ongoing. But they could be dropped under the Trump administration, and regulation around bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies is likely to change significantly under Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Under a Trump regulatory regime, cryptocurrency exchanges like Binance and Coinbase could operate with less threat of litigation, making it easier for people to trade on their platforms. Enthusiasts say this will spur innovation in the industry, but it could also mean that individual traders using such platforms are more exposed to fraud, theft, and the volatile nature of the currency.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Bitcoin has become an established digital asset</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the past five years, and particularly following the downfall of crypto trading platform FTX in 2022, <a href="https://www.ecb.europa.eu/press/key/date/2023/html/ecb.sp230623_1~80751450e6.en.html">the narrative around cryptocurrency’s utility</a> has changed. Now, it’s being touted more as an investment instrument rather than a form of currency that can be used like cash, White said. And that pivot is also helping its valuation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In January, the SEC gave the green light to the <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/01/11/heres-what-a-bitcoin-etf-actually-means-for-investors.html">first bitcoin exchange-traded funds</a> (or ETFs) in the US. ETFs are baskets of financial instruments (such as <a href="https://www.vox.com/stock-market">stocks</a>, bonds, commodities, or in this case, cryptocurrencies like bitcoin or ethereum) that are bought and sold on a regulated stock exchange.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">ETFs offer anyone indirect access to cryptocurrency, if they choose to invest. Put simply, if the value of bitcoin increases, so does the value of these ETFs — but because of the bundled nature of ETFs and their presence on a regulated exchange, investors are more insulated from loss if bitcoin’s value declines. Firms including BlackRock, Invesco, Fidelity, Grayscale, and Ark Invest have rolled out bitcoin funds, which offer new investors, especially those who might be more risk-averse, easy ways to purchase or gain exposure to cryptocurrency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Previously, investors had limited options for trading bitcoin. They could go on a cryptocurrency exchange to directly buy bitcoin, but then would have to figure out how to safely and conveniently store it long-term. (Cryptocurrency held on an exchange can be vulnerable to theft, <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/cold-storage.asp">while crypto stored offline is safer but difficult to trade</a>.) They could also invest in <a href="https://www.cftc.gov/LearnAndProtect/AdvisoriesAndArticles/BitcoinFuturesETF.html#:~:text=Bitcoin%20and%20bitcoin%20futures%20can,some%20point%20in%20the%20future.">risky bitcoin futures</a>, agreeing to buy or sell the currency at a later date at a certain price. Now, ETFs offer an establishment-backed option.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“While no one can predict the exact inflection point or when the price will stabilize, the long-term driver of bitcoin’s rise is its evolution — not just as digital gold, but as a foundational layer of global financial infrastructure,” Catalini said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, Vasudevan said that there is still reason to believe that crypto’s climb won’t last forever. Bitcoin has surged before, only to crash precipitously. In November 2022, bitcoin’s value dropped 20 percent, to below $16,000, in a matter of days <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/23458837/sam-bankman-fried-ftx-sbf-downfall-explained">after the spectacular downfall of the crypto exchange FTX</a>. The concern remains that the price of crypto is based purely on speculation, rather than any inherent value.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This has all the makings of another bubble, one that is being stoked by the prospect of a more favorable regulatory environment and the possibilities it is opening for new products and funds that can draw in more and more people into these markets,” Vasudevan said.</p>
						
									]]></description><link>https://www.vox.com/bitcoin/390096/bitcoin-crypto-etf-trump-ethereum-sec-ctf-david-sacks</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.vox.com/bitcoin/390096/bitcoin-crypto-etf-trump-ethereum-sec-ctf-david-sacks</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ellen Ioanes]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Verge’s 2024 holiday gift guide for dads ]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="Gifts for dads on a vibrant background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lFucruWW-PM1Ncdht3UK-StdoSk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73738095/247215_Holiday_GG_2024_AKrales_DADS_LEDE_2040x1360.5.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Photo: Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge</figcaption>
    </figure>


  <p>If you’re unsure what to gift the father figure in your life this year, we have more than a few suggestions.</p>
  <p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24224045/best-gift-ideas-dad-holiday-unique-2024-tech-gadgets">Read the full story at The Verge.</a></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/24224045/best-gift-ideas-dad-holiday-unique-2024-tech-gadgets</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/24224045/best-gift-ideas-dad-holiday-unique-2024-tech-gadgets</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Brandon Widder]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 23:47:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Valve’s master plan for Steam Machines is finally coming into focus]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EK9ZlZwkAwDt1l62tyf-PyaNaXk=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73771613/vpavic_220210_5030_0079.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Photo by Vjeran Pavic / The Verge</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="oLrwah">If I told you that Valve could make a play to dethrone the Sony PlayStation and Microsoft Xbox in your living room this next year while simultaneously challenging the Meta Quest as the gamer’s VR headset of choice, would you believe me? Because Valve may have a <em>lot</em> of SteamOS hardware on the way.</p>
<p id="OkNs2o">If there’s fire where we currently see smoke, Valve is currently preparing a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/17/23172293/valve-deckard-vr-headset-rumor-patent-images-leak">wireless VR headset codename Deckard</a>, a pair <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2024/11/19/24300757/valve-steam-controller-2-roy-deckard-leak">of trackable wands codename Roy</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2024/11/19/24300757/valve-steam-controller-2-roy-deckard-leak">a Steam Controller 2 gamepad codename Ibex</a>, and a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/5/24314279/what-could-valve-possibly-be-cooking-with-amd-chromeos-and-hdmi-cec">codename Fremont living room console</a> too. (That last one <a href="https://twitter.com/SadlyItsBradley/status/1864960200924450934">now looks likelier</a> than it did yesterday.) And Valve has also now seemingly revealed plans for partners to create third-party SteamOS hardware too.</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="OaxjoQ"><div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Sony’s making a handheld console to compete with Nintendo and Microsoft","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/25/24305337/sony-handheld-gaming-console-playstation-nintendo-microsoft"},{"title":"Don’t expect an Xbox handheld any time soon.","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295461/dont-expect-an-xbox-handheld-any-time-soon"}]}'></div></aside></div>
<p id="QLS1S2">It won’t be easy to take on Sony, Microsoft, or Meta. Those companies have a lot to lose, and they’re deeply entrenched. But the Steam Deck has revealed a massive weakness in each of their businesses that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/25/24305337/sony-handheld-gaming-console-playstation-nintendo-microsoft">may take</a> them <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295461/dont-expect-an-xbox-handheld-any-time-soon">years to correct</a> — the desire to play a huge library of games anytime, anywhere. </p>
<p id="aSJ4mj">And while they figure <em>that</em> out, Valve may be building an entire new ecosystem of SteamOS hardware, one that could finally let PC and peripheral makers tap into the huge and growing...</p>
  <p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24315098/valve-steam-machines-steamos-steam-deck-vr">Read the full story at The Verge.</a></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24315098/valve-steam-machines-steamos-steam-deck-vr</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24315098/valve-steam-machines-steamos-steam-deck-vr</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Sean Hollister]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 23:26:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface rumors point to a big Copilot Plus refresh next year]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="A photo of Microsoft’s 2024 Surface Laptop." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/28BW5a7jwMX7HAIrnhOP2Rp0KU8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73771515/DSCF7835_Enhanced_NR.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="gTfDoC">Microsoft’s first Copilot AI-ready Surface laptop arrived earlier this year, and now <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/hardware/surface/whats-next-for-surface-in-2025-intel-powered-copilot-pcs-and-an-11-inch-surface"><em>Windows Central</em> reports</a> that the rest of the lineup is due for a refresh in 2025. </p>
<p id="HIoVDM">According to the report, we can expect new Surface Pro and Surface Laptop computers — and we’ve already seen a possible prototype <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/16/24271612/microsoft-surface-laptop-prototype-leak-intel-lunar-lake">pop up in October</a> — with Intel Lunar Lake chips, that will be Copilot Plus PCs with AI features, just like the current Snapdragon versions. </p>
<p id="pq0SKi">That would make them the first Intel-powered Surfaces with the label after Microsoft didn’t extend the label and those features to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/21/24107513/microsoft-ai-pc-surface-pro-10-laptop-6-specs-release-date-price">the Surface Pro 10 and Surface Laptop 6</a>. Those machines had Intel Metor Lake chips with NPUs that didn’t meet the necessary mark. The new Surface Pro and Surface Laptop are also expected to get anti-reflective screen coating, and the Laptop version might get a card reader and 5G options.</p>
<p id="nvSxdS">It also says the Surface Laptop Studio is due for an upgrade from the current model’s 13th-gen Intel chips that could use Intel or AMD. Whatever the case, I hope it will have better battery life than we saw <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23900932/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-2-2023-intel-review">in our review of the current model</a>. Meanwhile, Microsoft confirmed to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23900932/microsoft-surface-laptop-studio-2-2023-intel-review"><em>Windows Central</em></a> that the Surface Studio 2 Plus all-in-one is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314732/microsoft-surface-studio-2-plus-end-of-production">g...</a></p>
  <p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24315105/microsoft-surface-pro-laptop-intel-lunar-lake-rumors">Read the full story at The Verge.</a></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24315105/microsoft-surface-pro-laptop-intel-lunar-lake-rumors</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24315105/microsoft-surface-pro-laptop-intel-lunar-lake-rumors</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Umar Shakir]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 22:29:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Wallet’s new passport ID feature won’t help you enter the country]]></title><description><![CDATA[  

    <figure>
      <img alt="An illustration of the Google logo." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ze8PNPdc2vKUoyL-gyoVhr2lMQ0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73771291/STK093_Google_02.0.jpg" />
        <figcaption>Illustration: The Verge</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p id="CApQUG">Google is now rolling out the ability to make a digital ID from your passport that you can store in Google Wallet and use at select TSA checkpoints — but only as a generic form of ID. It does not serve as a passport itself, Google spokesperson Liz Schulten tells <em>The Verge</em>: “The digital ID can’t be used at immigration and border control.”</p>
<p id="ascYLV">Here’s how to make the ID, per <a href="https://blog.google/products/google-pay/google-wallet-update-september-2024/">Google’s September blog post</a> where it initially announced the feature:</p>
<blockquote><p id="ZgMgIJ">Select the prompt in the Google Wallet app to “create an ID pass with your U.S. passport” and follow the instructions to scan the security chip in the back of your passport. You’ll be asked to take a selfie video to verify your identity, and Google Wallet will notify you when your ID pass is ready (typically within a few minutes).</p></blockquote>
<p id="RLT7gH">However, in that blog post, Google also cautions that a digital ID in Google Wallet is “not a replacement for your physical ID” and that you should still carry a physical ID when traveling “for now.”</p>
<div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"><aside id="th9i5j"><div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Don’t ever hand your phone to the cops","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/24/24252235/police-unlock-phone-password-face-id-apple-wallet-id"}]}'></div></aside></div>
<p id="BbWelE">The digital ID feature will be available to “all eligible users in the coming weeks,” according to Jenny Cheng, VP and GM of Google Wallet. You can see a map of which airports accept digital IDs <a href="https://www.tsa.gov/travel/digital-id/map">on the TSA’s website</a>.</p>
<p id="fdkrao">Cheng also shared that New Mexico driver’s licenses and state IDs can be saved in Google Wallet. New Mexico is the sixth state to support the feature, <a href="https://9to5google.com/2024/12/05/google-wallet-id-new-mexico/"><em>9to5Google</em> reports</a>.</p>
<p id="LjnxI7"><em><strong>Correction, December 6th</strong></em><em>: Our original headline said Google Wallet can replace your passport with this new digital ID feature, but Google now tells us that the ID can’t be used at immigration and border control.</em></p>

]]></description><link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24315065/google-wallet-digital-id-passport-airports</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24315065/google-wallet-digital-id-passport-airports</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jay Peters]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:50:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Grok is now free for all X users]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The AI chatbot within X, Grok, is now free for all users - but with some limits.</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/06/2927301/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/06/2927301/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 02:14:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Will people really pay $200 a month for OpenAI’s new chatbot?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>On Thursday, OpenAI released what&#8217;s effectively a $200-a-month chatbot — and the AI community didn&#8217;t know quite what to make of it. The company&#8217;s new ChatGPT Pro plan grants access to &#8220;o1 pro mode,&#8221; which OpenAI says &#8220;uses more compute for the best answers to the hardest questions.&#8221; A souped-up version of OpenAI&#8217;s o1 reasoning [&#8230;]</p>
<p>© 2024 TechCrunch. All rights reserved. For personal use only.</p>
]]></description><link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/06/will-people-really-pay-200-a-month-for-openais-new-chatbot/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/06/will-people-really-pay-200-a-month-for-openais-new-chatbot/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 23:19:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apple’s custom modems could put 5G in Macs and Vision Pro - The Verge]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxOdmJibXctbjlDcnVoR3ZUNVNlcXNWbnZ6Yjhza28zOEtaTldiZ2JWVjZWbjU0WHpBOUxaUm5zeUpGXzdtZkd2bEh3LVM3elF1azBxWjRXQXhjNUhwMTA4TDlRMjhseGZkbThhVlc5bTFiUWtmbk9sYUszMlN1bXlMcEJ1eWFUUVhDN0E?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple’s custom modems could put 5G in Macs and Vision Pro</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Verge</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxOdy1ieVZmZFdXRl9Vb2dQaHEtdmQ2Tjhsdnlfd1dsd3dmTTAzYTRqWkdSeXBVVnI1T0t6UDVCZTc5YndBQ19VMWNJdElLem04YWhFemkxbGRQUzVTck1rVDFlZjZsZEZYejYxeUlUWnJJaFRzNTFFNFFZVndYanNWOXZ6SzRGQlBtZXNsZWpvVGtJUldqZENQbC1SaW4tb3JYaFFhR2pwMm1ZN0pJeFpXNXNyYkVCUDNHdVM5M2NpZTRvSlk?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple Explores Macs, Headsets With Built-In Cellular Data</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Bloomberg</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxNaFByOUVrc2hkRGlWU3ZhSEk4NU9NNjA1MU4yRUhhX2lqNllRbzF2emVqd0EwbEkzZUpRNXAzVUZqbFdOdW9ycUNKcUlXSGxfTzZ4WFpYa1dsRUJtcHlia2pOM2R2OTVEQWJPZ2VsLVpaMFZ0U2ZPbGxrMFNpQ0ZYZEUyZk9oR2c?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple Plans Three-Year Modem Rollout in Bid to Top Qualcomm</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Yahoo Finance</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxOcHFCUFpVX3lRV3lwYzFRYVAxaVlabjA3YThRU25QcWVXR1Zpb1FLNFQxVE1pZVN3aTdJNnAwRm9jR180dUN0ZkktVFlNdm43b1otdnVjSjJ0amhpMzZ3VG9MczVNdVptLWNuWE1OaHJJSlVvdkpudDI5aDRCSms1RDlPTEp5WUNZanhiNm1vc215cHh2aXAyZGRTV0ZrRFN5VnFZMXhXNzBwbEQ0MW00UXNCaTZMbkoyTGYzVA?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple plans three-year modem rollout to compete with Qualcomm, Bloomberg News reports</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Reuters</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaEFVX3lxTE90UWlOb0g2YjE5ZUdXdjNDcGpGaEROcWdzYW1KWE5uVGdnRUNrcTUzTE5PYnJ2MUFnMExqd3lZWF9iTnRkb1V6bDY3M3lNYXJYbUd0SElYY2prUUxkWXI0WlZ3RjRUbjhP0gFuQVVfeXFMT2tJbmg1SDRpVUppZFNoUmRDTExnd2QyQnFJaDZUQk14UlN1SFh4ZEluWk5sQXY0bExUa1pja1BYVjAwUmgyLWpPTGFMVjZaX3lVcThITnVydUFsUW1uNnUtMDdBS0dwY1F3Z2h1LXc?oc=5" target="_blank">Apple Aims To Beat Qualcomm In 5G Modem Performance, Developing Three Custom Variants; iPhone 18 Pro And iPad Pro To Support mmWave Versions</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Wccftech</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxOdmJibXctbjlDcnVoR3ZUNVNlcXNWbnZ6Yjhza28zOEtaTldiZ2JWVjZWbjU0WHpBOUxaUm5zeUpGXzdtZkd2bEh3LVM3elF1azBxWjRXQXhjNUhwMTA4TDlRMjhseGZkbThhVlc5bTFiUWtmbk9sYUszMlN1bXlMcEJ1eWFUUVhDN0E?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiigFBVV95cUxOdmJibXctbjlDcnVoR3ZUNVNlcXNWbnZ6Yjhza28zOEtaTldiZ2JWVjZWbjU0WHpBOUxaUm5zeUpGXzdtZkd2bEh3LVM3elF1azBxWjRXQXhjNUhwMTA4TDlRMjhseGZkbThhVlc5bTFiUWtmbk9sYUszMlN1bXlMcEJ1eWFUUVhDN0E?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:50:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[NASA finds Orion heatshield cracks won't cook Artemis II crew - The Register]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPZEJjZGIxZENoQmozQko2ejBDdG12VG4yZEhDVkF0dDdmM3h0ZGVTc2FvYzlhVG9majZ6eUVBTVhwNG5FT2xDeEdITHQ0QnVKS0JwSmVYNTE2T2Q0NlU1bXcwNkxPZ0R2MVhOcm91cTItRk5tcDRsdXRhcHJOUnhXWdIBhgFBVV95cUxNcTFXNURfS0llZlZCOTZielRJQVkzRWdOeEhPN2dvbTNraUkzYjlUeEpNSXlpdUxqbmlDNXhJakV6VlhnOHhiZlJQRXlnX3JLNzVIZXU3U3ZPeDl1aVlEMHdSLUR3eXR2RGNTOXVSNXVwaWdpZ3dUdk5VX21HZm95aWw5ekdZZw?oc=5" target="_blank">NASA finds Orion heatshield cracks won't cook Artemis II crew</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">The Register</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxPdlo0dHhyQzRxeU1NTnJtQm41WnlwT20tNlhPX1Iyd0J5R010YW54b0tCUDhVMDczZ1NUMXBfYXFoT2hnbTV3V1B6NG00Y3VLQmFRWFdhOFV6U3dpanoxaWt4R2Rmb2MwaFpMVjYxTWM5d3hXTmkxdy11U2M1MHVZaTc1OWJ5RVpZN01xZ1lOeEFsT0NT0gGLAUFVX3lxTE9Vb0Mzb3FhLVJmNTgtNmdFYUxTZnU4RFdZdnppblpJMFR6eGdSMGR6WmxkYnpSYnBydmphUk43eXpETW5ZTnJKRi1yTkZMMHc1Zi1KQjZUaU1YYks5ejRYZkVLd190TnVUTXd3SlQ5WW1VZVdxZ05wd283OTRLcHpCSXZUWHpnMC13NGs?oc=5" target="_blank">NASA delays first crewed flight to the moon in over 50 years</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">CNN</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipgFBVV95cUxOekVPeElXWTlBLVBJUU1DSkNUQllwZUk1bWdiT293T2xXSHVzc19MLWFMbzhTZmNtV044cGRKWEFIb3VyeWxaTEtBU2ptaktzSmlxRHFGWURCNlhuYllTUzdKMUZxRXhYal96Z0x0OHRmZHJIcENLUVh2NGFLZFdnTWN4amFGb1BwZGd1S0l0UU1hSzd2UFRkdXl6eldTM0R0b2ZwMUJR0gFWQVVfeXFMT3o5TGJGSTJpc0oyejBueU0yaHpvaXhqZlV6OTFYQW1haXBRTWd0bzBXUUtqY29RSFB0ZlFZb2NyUndleVpWZVJWWktCRlpHaFpLcjNXZkE?oc=5" target="_blank">NASA says moon mission is delayed, hopes to land astronauts before China</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NBC News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibEFVX3lxTE41NHFxb0h2YXBUZC1IM3VxQk1CWlFzeFIyZXFJd3I5QUxyMEo1OUUzVmhjZUxwZzlHN2ZqUms1WV80RDc1RzhOQnZaVXM4eHNuUy1sUHpXNXJMY214XzZEZWtrVGthTjEtLV9MZg?oc=5" target="_blank">Artemis II rescheduled for spring of 2026 as program decides on path forward</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">NASASpaceflight.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxQdlVSM3puUXE0M2MyYWxLNUF2VzlnUjBTeVBYVVJaV1FEUDhkV2hvd0FxWXJjVko2cmtNWUo1U3ZTY25MUGlFS2JpblJxVXlhZHdlX1BvWm53UVdfUTh2WWtDTXZWRTNoT3NXR2FGR2tkblkwa3pJd0w0X0M4Y0F0c1VlVzZod2gzZVZ3MDBJTmRfQXdFZm0xQ1JzR1NwVTM2SEhwMmMxUldBS2ZfMERJM2V3Q1g2OF81S1lmdjYxMGc3Vk1YUnlVcXJfcV8?oc=5" target="_blank">NASA delays Artemis 2 moon mission to 2026, Artemis 3 astronaut landing to mid-2027</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Space.com</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPZEJjZGIxZENoQmozQko2ejBDdG12VG4yZEhDVkF0dDdmM3h0ZGVTc2FvYzlhVG9majZ6eUVBTVhwNG5FT2xDeEdITHQ0QnVKS0JwSmVYNTE2T2Q0NlU1bXcwNkxPZ0R2MVhOcm91cTItRk5tcDRsdXRhcHJOUnhXWdIBhgFBVV95cUxNcTFXNURfS0llZlZCOTZielRJQVkzRWdOeEhPN2dvbTNraUkzYjlUeEpNSXlpdUxqbmlDNXhJakV6VlhnOHhiZlJQRXlnX3JLNzVIZXU3U3ZPeDl1aVlEMHdSLUR3eXR2RGNTOXVSNXVwaWdpZ3dUdk5VX21HZm95aWw5ekdZZw?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigAFBVV95cUxPZEJjZGIxZENoQmozQko2ejBDdG12VG4yZEhDVkF0dDdmM3h0ZGVTc2FvYzlhVG9majZ6eUVBTVhwNG5FT2xDeEdITHQ0QnVKS0JwSmVYNTE2T2Q0NlU1bXcwNkxPZ0R2MVhOcm91cTItRk5tcDRsdXRhcHJOUnhXWdIBhgFBVV95cUxNcTFXNURfS0llZlZCOTZielRJQVkzRWdOeEhPN2dvbTNraUkzYjlUeEpNSXlpdUxqbmlDNXhJakV6VlhnOHhiZlJQRXlnX3JLNzVIZXU3U3ZPeDl1aVlEMHdSLUR3eXR2RGNTOXVSNXVwaWdpZ3dUdk5VX21HZm95aWw5ekdZZw?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mars rover Perseverance sends home postcard from scenic 'Pico Turquino' (photo) - Space.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[<ol><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPR2h0cUpvSmp4LVJjclVOWklSOXFwU2xVZVpsdXptbVYtVUVTR0h2MFVPRExUZ0g5UnU4T1JjTnNsTEtxSXR2UjZNRExmWWhBYnhNT0p3OFlQYnI4LS1EMjlfOGlwSWpmbXAtTWJhNGxMOHJZalFEZWpnbThMZHZRSGFKcHpvYVNaTUhmVlVlcmNyZzBhZlVycjE1WXUwRml1Njd1Q3JhWUZpeXFXc3N6Vml0S1N0eURmUktuWU5BdnJaSHdKWXc?oc=5" target="_blank">Mars rover Perseverance sends home postcard from scenic 'Pico Turquino' (photo)</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Space.com</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxOSzI1eURGLTlKUERUb1lRMHJuOEhCNEdrc1d5Sm5EQWIxcVRWMzR0UXBJZ0JKdHcybS1VREtXLUdtbF9JLXZSYjg3bWl4ejZTc29HYUhIVGM3Vm1CYXREbFdCTE5qQ3I1Ui1uRHVCZnpmQktMWGQtcms1V2lJeDRyTHkzVktsTm9WcjBqVmtaUVU1WWdCc1d0dWxRc0k5VEpnMXZKTHJzbW9Xc1FzTUxtQkVRdTU?oc=5" target="_blank">Purdue scientist expecting new world to reveal itself to Mars rover</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Greenfield Daily Reporter</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxONkxpSEdlelZfZ1Zyc3lDVFdRTEN6VUJnWUFjRTJDSnJxcDNNeDY2LXVaMmFUa0FRQ2FRdEdiQm5NdGpHRy1Cd2RMWnNaZEh3MDdhNEZTZU80eXhIVk1PV2ZlRU90TGlPOThGM09FdHpaT0hMeHpDN3IwVm1uYVhTbkR0SEFWVXZmTGVqZ2RR?oc=5" target="_blank">Perseverance Looks Around The Landscape Of Mars</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Astrobiology News</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMibkFVX3lxTE85UmNHZXpkWjZQT0tESF9wQVRFWGhhVDBzQ0hITlFsZm0zekMzVkZYdUNkUl9CR2dGUnBwd25Bc0VkeEtLQlU5RV9wYm9jM3FUcmF3RVA0ZHpvNzVKbThLWk9QN1p3aGpNc2U0YmxB0gFsQVVfeXFMTjRZNGxaUlVOMUpNNlRjbFIySjB6dnNXcnJmNDBjSXA3NEw5YkxSRUxTcHM0djROSE1LSEtZcXpYQlRXcmJ5SWx5VHZuX1BjNkNJRXNmRnNKXzVvUmh6ME9LUmhIWUMtOW5tUHdG?oc=5" target="_blank">Perseverance now arriving at Pico Turquino</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">Phys.org</font></li><li><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxPeE50VWl5bFhyMUxXQ0o4MUs4ZUVUU2VrcVprOVpKNGNTVlJXWFJNVFJLLVE0cHFydlhpZ2dkQVhKVHAzckdDU1VQV2o0QXFHQ1J3UnBsejA4Z081LTZmbGMyUzF2Y1VuR3NjWFBwNzFrNzVrUWlJLXBLOWFWMUVQOGlWY1V1b2pSNUpfR3o0elk5eUpwSGZDR0szSzJ4U2MySFNueGpNd21HREJHMWJFa1hsYldqWjk4OVk4?oc=5" target="_blank">Artist Animation Of Water Flowing Into Ancient Mars Jezero Crater</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;<font color="#6f6f6f">MSN</font></li></ol>]]></description><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPR2h0cUpvSmp4LVJjclVOWklSOXFwU2xVZVpsdXptbVYtVUVTR0h2MFVPRExUZ0g5UnU4T1JjTnNsTEtxSXR2UjZNRExmWWhBYnhNT0p3OFlQYnI4LS1EMjlfOGlwSWpmbXAtTWJhNGxMOHJZalFEZWpnbThMZHZRSGFKcHpvYVNaTUhmVlVlcmNyZzBhZlVycjE1WXUwRml1Njd1Q3JhWUZpeXFXc3N6Vml0S1N0eURmUktuWU5BdnJaSHdKWXc?oc=5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPR2h0cUpvSmp4LVJjclVOWklSOXFwU2xVZVpsdXptbVYtVUVTR0h2MFVPRExUZ0g5UnU4T1JjTnNsTEtxSXR2UjZNRExmWWhBYnhNT0p3OFlQYnI4LS1EMjlfOGlwSWpmbXAtTWJhNGxMOHJZalFEZWpnbThMZHZRSGFKcHpvYVNaTUhmVlVlcmNyZzBhZlVycjE1WXUwRml1Njd1Q3JhWUZpeXFXc3N6Vml0S1N0eURmUktuWU5BdnJaSHdKWXc?oc=5</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Top Artificial Intelligence (AI) Stocks Ready for a Bull Run]]></title><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/5-top-artificial-intelligence-ai-105000235.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://finance.yahoo.com/news/5-top-artificial-intelligence-ai-105000235.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 10:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Italian startup iGenius and Nvidia to build major AI system]]></title><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/italian-startup-igenius-nvidia-build-140718448.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://finance.yahoo.com/news/italian-startup-igenius-nvidia-build-140718448.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 14:07:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Intel's Next-Generation Xe3 Celestial GPU Is Already 'Baked,' Says Intel Fellow]]></title><link>https://www.yahoo.com/tech/intels-next-generation-xe3-celestial-170228457.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.yahoo.com/tech/intels-next-generation-xe3-celestial-170228457.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 17:02:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US is closer to banning TikTok and these companies could benefit]]></title><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/video/us-closer-banning-tiktok-companies-173238971.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://finance.yahoo.com/video/us-closer-banning-tiktok-companies-173238971.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 17:32:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Intel names two chip industry veterans to its board amid CEO search]]></title><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/intel-names-two-chip-industry-162154721.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://finance.yahoo.com/news/intel-names-two-chip-industry-162154721.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 16:21:54 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>