<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 04:22:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 04:22:41 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for January 17: Win skins, bundles, diamonds, and more - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for January 17: Win skins, bundles, diamonds, and more</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250117040329_12bd8e3061aa30c9136889ddaa911392.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Garena Free Fire Max" title="Garena Free Fire Max" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Image representing Garena Free Fire Max</figcaption><p>The redeem codes offer players the chance to unlock a variety of in-game rewards, from stylish skins to diamonds, without the need for real money. Gamers can benefit from daily updated codes that enhance their gameplay experience.</p><ul><li>Daily redeem codes available for Free Fire MAX players.</li><li>Unlock skins, outfits, pets, and diamonds for free.</li><li>Game celebrated for its multiplayer battle royale experience.</li></ul><blockquote>“Every day, the developers of Garena Free Fire MAX release a fresh batch of redeem codes.”</blockquote><p>Overall, the redeem codes serve as a valuable resource for players looking to enhance their gaming experience in Free Fire MAX.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-january-17-win-skins-bundles-diamonds-and-more-article-12912839.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-january-17-win-skins-bundles-diamonds-and-more-article-12912839.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 04:04:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo’s new Switch 2 console will come out this year - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nintendo to Launch New Switch 2 Console This Year</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 17, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/y9z4oo/article69107345.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Nintendo-Switch_2_84792.jpg" alt="Nintendo Switch 2 Console" title="Nintendo Switch 2 Console"><figcaption>The announcement did not provide many details on the console or a specific release date [File] | Photo Credit: AP</figcaption><p>Nintendo has officially announced the upcoming release of its new console, the Nintendo Switch 2, much to the excitement of gamers worldwide. This console is set to play exclusive games as well as existing Nintendo Switch games.</p><ul><li>The Nintendo Switch 2 will be released in 2025.</li><li>The new console features larger design and redesigned Joy-Cons that attach to the main unit.</li><li>It will support a range of exclusive and existing games, although some may not be fully compatible.</li><li>Nintendo plans to reveal more details during an upcoming Nintendo Direct event in April.</li><li>There will be hands-on experience events in cities including Los Angeles, New York, London, and Paris starting in April.</li></ul><blockquote>"More information about the system will be available during the company’s April Nintendo Direct event."</blockquote><p>As anticipation builds, Nintendo fans await further details on the Switch 2, which promises to enhance their gaming experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/nintendos-new-switch-2-console-will-come-out-this-year/article69107343.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/nintendos-new-switch-2-console-will-come-out-this-year/article69107343.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crash Detection on Apple Watch helps save man after passing out while driving - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Watch Saves Life of 55-Year-Old Man After Car Crash</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 17, 2025</p><p><strong>Published By:</strong> Aman Rashid</p><p>A 55-year-old man from Easthampton, Massachusetts, was saved by his Apple Watch after passing out while driving and crashing into a swimming pool.</p><img src='image_url_here' alt='Apple Watch' /><figcaption>The Apple Watch played a crucial role in saving Brent Hill's life.</figcaption><p>Key Points:</p><ul><li>Brent Hill blacked out while driving and crashed into a neighbor's swimming pool.</li><li>The Apple Watch detected the crash and called emergency services.</li><li>Hill was trapped upside down in the car but was guided by the watch's voice until help arrived.</li><li>He sustained minor injuries but credited the watch with saving his life.</li><li>Neighbor Elizabeth Laprade-Appelquist was surprised by the effectiveness of the watch's crash detection.</li></ul><blockquote>“If emergency services had not contacted me through that watch and coached me through it, there’s no way I would’ve got out of there.” - Brent Hill</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the potential life-saving capabilities of technology during emergencies and encourages awareness about such features in smart devices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/crash-detection-on-apple-watch-helps-save-man-after-passing-out-while-driving-2666063-2025-01-17</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/crash-detection-on-apple-watch-helps-save-man-after-passing-out-while-driving-2666063-2025-01-17</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:51:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim may feature smaller battery compared to rest of the Galaxy S25 lineup - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim May Feature Smaller Battery Compared to Rest of the Galaxy S25 Lineup</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 17, 2025 | <strong>Published By:</strong> Nandini Yadav</p><div><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/samsung-galaxy-s25-slim-151337349-16x9_1.jpg?VersionId=z79zaCq7EDuy1XPI0tI_3.NZTp.30hMf&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim" title="Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim (Credit: X/@XiTOnline)" height="388"></div><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim (Credit: X/@XiTOnline)</figcaption><p>As Samsung's Galaxy Unpacked event approaches, leaks indicate that the Galaxy S25 Slim will have the smallest battery capacity in the new lineup, designed to be the thinnest model yet.</p><ul><li>The Galaxy S25 Slim's battery is rumored to be between 3,000mAh and 4,000mAh.</li><li>It measures just 6.4mm thick without the camera module, setting a new standard for smartphone slimness.</li><li>Despite its slimness, it boasts a large display between 6.7 to 6.8 inches.</li><li>The design includes a metal frame, glass back, and triple rear cameras.</li><li>Scheduled announcement is on January 22, 2025, during Samsung's Galaxy Unpacked event.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Slim is rumoured to be even thinner than the Galaxy S25 Ultra.”</blockquote><p>This model is anticipated to feature advanced hardware while maintaining a stylish, ultra-thin profile, surpassing previous models like the Galaxy A8.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/samsung-galaxy-s25-slim-may-feature-smaller-battery-compared-to-rest-of-the-galaxy-s25-lineup-2666056-2025-01-17</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/samsung-galaxy-s25-slim-may-feature-smaller-battery-compared-to-rest-of-the-galaxy-s25-lineup-2666056-2025-01-17</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 03:34:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple to halt AI-generated news alerts after errors - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Halts AI-Generated News Alerts Amid Criticism</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> [Your News Source]</p><p>Apple has decided to suspend its AI feature that generated news alerts after receiving complaints about the accuracy of the information it provided.</p><ul><li>The feature faced backlash for sending faulty news summaries, including misinformation regarding a criminal incident.</li><li>Major media organizations, including the BBC, criticized the accuracy of AI-generated alerts, citing issues with trust and misinformation.</li><li>Apple plans to work on improvements for the AI feature for a future software update.</li><li>The news alert feature has been disabled entirely for news and entertainment apps.</li><li>This decision follows the company's efforts to showcase its AI advancements amidst investor expectations.</li></ul><blockquote>“We're pleased that Apple has listened to our concerns and is pausing the summarization feature for news,” a BBC spokesperson stated.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Apple's decision reflects the challenges of implementing AI in sensitive areas like news dissemination and highlights the importance of accuracy in building trust with audiences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cq5ggew08eyo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cq5ggew08eyo</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:32:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Republic Day sale 2025: Get up to 35% off and more on top load washing machines with innovative technology | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/gadgets/amazon-republic-day-sale-2025-get-up-to-35-off-and-more-on-top-load-washing-machines-with-innovative-technology-11737028749441.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/gadgets/amazon-republic-day-sale-2025-get-up-to-35-off-and-more-on-top-load-washing-machines-with-innovative-technology-11737028749441.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:30:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Companies News Today Live Updates on January 17, 2025: After L&T 90 hours work week debate, Crunch Fitness CEO says employees must sacrifice for success, no work-life balance | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Crunch Fitness CEO Urges Employee Sacrifice for Success Amid L&T Work Week Debate</h1><p><strong>Published Date: </strong>17 Jan, 2025 | <strong>Source: </strong>LiveMint</p><figure><img src="https://images.livemint.com/img/2018/12/24/600x338/breaking_news_1545650155659.jpg" alt="Companies News Today Live Updates: After L&amp;T 90 hours work week debate, Crunch Fitness CEO says employees must sacrifice for success, no work-life balance" /><figcaption>Companies News Today Live Updates: After L&amp;T 90 hours work week debate, Crunch Fitness CEO says employees must sacrifice for success, no work-life balance</figcaption></figure><p>The debate surrounding L&T's 90-hour work week has spurred Crunch Fitness CEO Jim Rowley to claim that employees must be willing to sacrifice for success, dismissing the concept of work-life balance as a lack of commitment.</p><ul><li>Jim Rowley argues that the modern ethos of work-life balance reflects a lack of dedication.</li><li>He emphasizes that hard work is essential for success in the fitness industry.</li></ul><blockquote>“These new modern concepts are ‘illusions’ and we should focus on hard work instead,” Jim Rowley stated during the live update.</blockquote><p>This statement comes amid various corporate news updates that touch on significant financial and operational changes in multiple industries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/latest-company-news-today-on-january-17-2025-live-updates-11737054207943.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/latest-company-news-today-on-january-17-2025-live-updates-11737054207943.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stocks to buy: Ankush Bajaj recommends three stocks for today—17 January - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stocks-to-buy-recommendations-ankush-bajaj-stock-picks-17-january-sensex-nifty-50-nifty-bank-redington-bse-indus-towers-11737034695803.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stocks-to-buy-recommendations-ankush-bajaj-stock-picks-17-january-sensex-nifty-50-nifty-bank-redington-bse-indus-towers-11737034695803.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:30:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp Features: 4 New Fun Ways To Chat That You Must Know About - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/prakharkhanna/2025/01/16/whatsapp-features-4-new-fun-ways-to-chat-that-you-must-know-about/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/prakharkhanna/2025/01/16/whatsapp-features-4-new-fun-ways-to-chat-that-you-must-know-about/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 22:34:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[realme 14 pro series introduces world’s first cold-sensitive smartphones that change color - Designboom]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>realme 14 Pro Series Launches World's First Color-Changing Cold-Sensitive Smartphones</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] | <strong>Source:</strong> Designboom</p>
<img src="https://static.designboom.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/realme-14-pro-series-worlds-first-cold-sensitive-smartphones-change-color-designboom-01.jpg" alt="realme 14 pro smartphones" width="818" height="460">
<figcaption>realme 14 pro smartphones</figcaption>
<p>realme introduces its 14 Pro Series as the first smartphones that change color when exposed to cold, featuring a unique pearl white texture that transforms into marbled blue in low temperatures.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The smartphone starts changing color below 16 degrees Celsius.</li>
  <li>Designed in collaboration with Nordic industrial design studio Valeur Designers.</li>
  <li>Equipped with advanced cooling systems and AI eye protection algorithms.</li>
  <li>The smartphones have IP69 waterproof ratings, functioning after being submerged for 48 hours.</li>
  <li>Battery life supports up to 10 hours of gaming and rapid charging capabilities.</li>
  <li>Camera features include Sony OIS technology with up to 50 megapixels.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The devices can still work ‘just like before’ even after 48 hours under two meters of water.”</blockquote>
<p>This innovative smartphone not only emphasizes aesthetic appeal with its color-changing capabilities but also incorporates durable design elements suitable for active use.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.designboom.com/technology/realme-14-pro-series-worlds-first-cold-sensitive-smartphones-change-color-01-16-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.designboom.com/technology/realme-14-pro-series-worlds-first-cold-sensitive-smartphones-change-color-01-16-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 21:32:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple iPhone SE Exposed In New Leak - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/ewanspence/2025/01/16/apple-phone-se-dummy-unit-design-changes-leak-images/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/ewanspence/2025/01/16/apple-phone-se-dummy-unit-design-changes-leak-images/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 21:21:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Krafton’s rolls out BGMI 3.6 update with new gameplay elements and more - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Krafton Releases BGMI 3.6 Update with Exciting New Features</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Krafton News</p><p>The latest update for Battlegrounds Mobile India (BGMI) has been launched, introducing new gameplay elements and enhancements that aim to elevate the player experience.</p><ul><li>The 3.6 update includes several new modes and gameplay tweaks.</li><li>Players can now experience new maps and characters.</li><li>Enhanced graphics and gameplay mechanics have been introduced for a more immersive experience.</li><li>Various bug fixes and optimizations have been made based on user feedback.</li></ul><blockquote>“This update is committed to enhancing our players' experience and keeping them engaged with new features.” - Krafton Developer Team</blockquote><p>This update marks another step in Krafton's ongoing efforts to innovate and improve BGMI, further solidifying its position in the mobile gaming market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/kraftons-rolls-out-bgmi-3-6-update-with-new-gameplay-elements-and-more/articleshow/117308438.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/kraftons-rolls-out-bgmi-3-6-update-with-new-gameplay-elements-and-more/articleshow/117308438.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 17:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim leaks surface online: 6.4mm thick design and premium features tipped | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim leaks surface online: 6.4mm thick design and premium features tipped</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Samsung is set to unveil its Galaxy S25 series on January 22, with particular excitement surrounding the new Galaxy S25 Slim, rumored to be the slimmest smartphone from the brand.</p>
<img src="image-url-placeholder" alt="Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim" />
<figcaption>High-resolution renders of the Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim.</figcaption>
<p>The Galaxy S25 Slim aims to combine a sleek design with high-end features, measuring just 6.4mm thick. Here are the key details:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Expected thickness of 6.4mm (8.3mm with camera module).</li>
  <li>Features a spacious 6.7 to 6.8-inch display.</li>
  <li>Compact frame dimensions: 159 x 76 x 6.4mm.</li>
  <li>Premium design with a metal frame and glass back.</li>
  <li>Triple rear camera setup.</li>
  <li>Integration of a larger battery and advanced internals.</li>
  <li>Launch expected on January 22, with availability later in the year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Stay tuned for 22 January as Samsung unveils its most biggest smartphone lineup yet.”</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming Galaxy S25 Slim showcases Samsung's innovative approach to smartphone design, promising to attract attention in the competitive market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/samsung-galaxy-s25-slim-leaks-surface-online-6-4mm-thick-design-and-premium-features-tipped-11737041641253.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/samsung-galaxy-s25-slim-leaks-surface-online-6-4mm-thick-design-and-premium-features-tipped-11737041641253.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:41:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung S25 series key specs and new software features leaked online - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung S25 series key specs and new software features leaked online</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/01/001-Galaxy-Unpacked-2024-Galaxy-S24-Series-Press-Release-e1705568650139.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Galaxy S24" title="Galaxy S24" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Galaxy S24</figcaption><p>Samsung is set to launch its new Galaxy S25 series at the Galaxy Unpacked event on January 22, showcasing advanced AI features aimed at enhancing user experience.</p><ul><li>The Galaxy S25 is billed as a 'True AI Companion'.</li><li>Features like restaurant information and calendar management through a dedicated chatbot are introduced.</li><li>New 'Sketch to Image' functionality will allow users to sketch an object and transform it using AI.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/samsung-s25-series-key-specs-and-new-software-features-leaked-online-article-12912564.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/samsung-s25-series-key-specs-and-new-software-features-leaked-online-article-12912564.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:34:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung will now buy your Galaxy phone even if you don’t buy a new one - 9to5Google]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Introduces Year-Round Trade-In Program for Galaxy Phones</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> 9to5Google</p>
<img src="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2025/01/galaxy-trade-in-year-round.jpg?quality=82&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1500" alt="Galaxy Trade-In" width="1500" height="750">
<figcaption>Samsung's Year-Round Galaxy Trade-In Program</figcaption>
<p>Samsung has announced a new trade-in program allowing users to trade in their Galaxy devices at any time, regardless of whether they are purchasing a new phone.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The program is named the “Year-Round Galaxy Trade-In Program”.</li>
  <li>It allows trade-ins without the requirement of buying a new Samsung smartphone.</li>
  <li>The program currently operates in a pilot phase in Korea and France, with plans to expand throughout 2025.</li>
  <li>Eligible devices include recent models from the Galaxy S and Z series.</li>
  <li>Details about how the trade-in value is compensated remain unclear.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Samsung Electronics today announced a new Galaxy Trade-In Program, which allows trade-in of Samsung Galaxy devices at any time of the year…”</blockquote>
<p>This program highlights Samsung's commitment to offering value for its Galaxy devices while answering various consumer needs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://9to5google.com/2025/01/16/samsung-galaxy-trade-in-year-round-program-pilot/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://9to5google.com/2025/01/16/samsung-galaxy-trade-in-year-round-program-pilot/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Travelers discover vacationing in a ghost town can be grim | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/travelers-discover-vacationing-in-a-ghost-town-can-be-grim-11737039660933.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/travelers-discover-vacationing-in-a-ghost-town-can-be-grim-11737039660933.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 15:07:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart 9 First Look Suggests 24 Person Races Are Coming to the Nintendo Switch 2 Game - IGN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mario Kart 9 First Look Suggests 24 Person Races Are Coming to the Nintendo Switch 2 Game</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> N/A <strong>Source: </strong> IGN</p><p>Nintendo has officially revealed the Nintendo Switch 2 and Mario Kart 9 alongside it, which appears to confirm 24 person races for the first time in series history.</p><ul><li>Trailer unveiled alongside the Nintendo Switch 2 reveals Mario Kart 9.</li><li>24 starting positions were visible, suggesting a significant increase in racers.</li><li>The track appears wider to accommodate more racers.</li><li>Fans anticipate more details in the upcoming Nintendo Direct in April.</li></ul><blockquote>“Nintendo is deploying in Mario Kart 9.”</blockquote><p>The potential for 24-player races in Mario Kart 9 could revolutionize multiplayer experiences, building on Nintendo's history of increasing player counts with technological advancements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-9-first-look-suggests-24-person-races-are-coming-to-the-nintendo-switch-2-game</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-9-first-look-suggests-24-person-races-are-coming-to-the-nintendo-switch-2-game</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:52:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 16 Pro Max price drops by Rs 7,000 - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNUXJJN1RyM3FaUk45b2ViU2tGOVVwTjYxM0VXNGFMaUtYSlNVbTF4YTEtb0g2UkVScE1zdmhTMF80Mm9xOVh6RzZTTEppUExxdkNMVVkzQ2FJWXhTSnpwazFvdGM3WXNQZGRSN25fMlU0cm5kN1p4Ym5Ga005RDF2TU1UR01Xb0JmdTZqeWY5SkN1V2c0R0kxTEo3NmtvMFnSAZ8BQVVfeXFMTVFySTdUcjNxWlJOOW9lYlNrRjlVcE42MTNFVzRhTGlLWEpTVW0xeGExLW9INlJFUnBNc3ZoUzBfNDJvcTlYekc2U0xKaVBMcXZDTFVZM0NhSVl4U0p6cGsxb3RjN1lzUGRkUjduXzJVNHJuZDdaeGJuRmtNOUQxdk1NVEdNV29CZnU2anlmOUpDdVdnNEdJMUxKNzZrbzBZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxNUXJJN1RyM3FaUk45b2ViU2tGOVVwTjYxM0VXNGFMaUtYSlNVbTF4YTEtb0g2UkVScE1zdmhTMF80Mm9xOVh6RzZTTEppUExxdkNMVVkzQ2FJWXhTSnpwazFvdGM3WXNQZGRSN25fMlU0cm5kN1p4Ym5Ga005RDF2TU1UR01Xb0JmdTZqeWY5SkN1V2c0R0kxTEo3NmtvMFnSAZ8BQVVfeXFMTVFySTdUcjNxWlJOOW9lYlNrRjlVcE42MTNFVzRhTGlLWEpTVW0xeGExLW9INlJFUnBNc3ZoUzBfNDJvcTlYekc2U0xKaVBMcXZDTFVZM0NhSVl4U0p6cGsxb3RjN1lzUGRkUjduXzJVNHJuZDdaeGJuRmtNOUQxdk1NVEdNV29CZnU2anlmOUpDdVdnNEdJMUxKNzZrbzBZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:41:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Is Official: New Game Console Launches This Year - Hollywood Reporter]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/digital/nintendo-switch-2-console-coming-2025-1236110419/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/digital/nintendo-switch-2-console-coming-2025-1236110419/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:41:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech wrap Jan 16: Realme 14 Pro series, Samsung Galaxy S25, Google Chrome - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-wrap-jan-16-realme-14-pro-series-samsung-galaxy-s25-google-chrome-125011601022_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-wrap-jan-16-realme-14-pro-series-samsung-galaxy-s25-google-chrome-125011601022_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top Deals on Gaming Laptops Under Rs 1 Lakh to Consider During Amazon Great Republic Day Sale - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxPVDRkQ0VWbTlOQzlqVFRpaU9md2lNVVVyUS1vZDE5OVM1dXhaQ3liZVF3LUsyOU52a2syR1lGT2wweVBMbFlQWnlEakNmYUhtSlpSVVJBd1Vrb3RHZWZtTUhIY2VDenQxV2p5MW9UajlZbkh5MnRDSjNQN2FJWFNtekNRb1d1bmtES25JcEE2V1dFSEc5d0Fwc0VNM29vaVh2bEVaZ012MnNrb1pPaHlSanFCeHVEYTlzeVo5NUppbFlPbUhQSVBqVtIBzgFBVV95cUxORGNoN2NTNVNVbnRGTUdqRVhQdFBNckdVa0daamp1WERNb1JXajBmQU5PRGs2bkE0WDlQa1lJUmNkbDU1SHgwYUFhZGM2Vk1jaVNGamtoWGFHN3o5Sms2M0paeDVYMC1TVnh4OWFLWEtjYkVCeVB1Um5idGFIZEI5d2Q3LXJUS3R1dTNZV3hhTmZJMS1LcEp3UmgxWlVHQVZHaVRZLUhsN1pfdm9SRjEzdzZGLVZqZE9OODJGNUVraGlaa0hhNFRyYkxpSWUxdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxPVDRkQ0VWbTlOQzlqVFRpaU9md2lNVVVyUS1vZDE5OVM1dXhaQ3liZVF3LUsyOU52a2syR1lGT2wweVBMbFlQWnlEakNmYUhtSlpSVVJBd1Vrb3RHZWZtTUhIY2VDenQxV2p5MW9UajlZbkh5MnRDSjNQN2FJWFNtekNRb1d1bmtES25JcEE2V1dFSEc5d0Fwc0VNM29vaVh2bEVaZ012MnNrb1pPaHlSanFCeHVEYTlzeVo5NUppbFlPbUhQSVBqVtIBzgFBVV95cUxORGNoN2NTNVNVbnRGTUdqRVhQdFBNckdVa0daamp1WERNb1JXajBmQU5PRGs2bkE0WDlQa1lJUmNkbDU1SHgwYUFhZGM2Vk1jaVNGamtoWGFHN3o5Sms2M0paeDVYMC1TVnh4OWFLWEtjYkVCeVB1Um5idGFIZEI5d2Q3LXJUS3R1dTNZV3hhTmZJMS1LcEp3UmgxWlVHQVZHaVRZLUhsN1pfdm9SRjEzdzZGLVZqZE9OODJGNUVraGlaa0hhNFRyYkxpSWUxdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:32:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[32-inch smart TVs available at massive discount during Republic Day sale, starting from just Rs 7,000 - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Massive Discounts on 32-Inch Smart TVs During Republic Day Sale Starting at Rs 7,000</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/smart-tvs-at-discount-1737037823.webp" alt="Smart TVs at discount" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>Smart TVs at discount</figcaption>
<p>E-commerce giant Amazon is hosting a Republic Day sale with substantial discounts on various smart TVs, making it the perfect time to purchase a new one.</p>
<ul>
  <li>32-inch smart TVs are available starting from Rs 7,000.</li>
  <li>Discounts of up to 61% on select models, along with no-cost EMI options, bank offers, and exchange deals.</li>
  <li>The Xiaomi Smart TV A is discounted from Rs 24,999 to Rs 11,999, featuring a 20-watt sound output.</li>
  <li>The VW 32-inch Playwall is notably priced around Rs 6,000 to Rs 7,000 with a 59% discount.</li>
  <li>TCL's 32-inch model originally priced at Rs 21,990 is now available for Rs 10,990.</li>
  <li>Another VW model is discounted from Rs 22,999 to Rs 8,999 with a 61% discount.</li>
  <li>Acer's QLED TV is down from Rs 24,999 to Rs 12,499, featuring a 30-watt sound output.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This Republic Day Sale offers customers a chance to save significantly on popular brands like Samsung, TCL, Sony, Xiaomi, and more,” said an Amazon spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>The Republic Day Sale presents an excellent opportunity for television shoppers looking for budget-friendly options and great features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/32-inch-smart-tvs-available-at-massive-discount-during-republic-day-sale-starting-from-just-rs-7-000-2025-01-16-971633</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/32-inch-smart-tvs-available-at-massive-discount-during-republic-day-sale-starting-from-just-rs-7-000-2025-01-16-971633</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:31:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Sale 2025: Price drop deals on front load washing machines; Save up to 42% on LG, Samsung, Bosch, IFB and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-sale-2025-price-drop-deals-on-front-load-washing-machines-save-up-to-42-on-lg-samsung-bosch-ifb-and-more-101736927023111.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-sale-2025-price-drop-deals-on-front-load-washing-machines-save-up-to-42-on-lg-samsung-bosch-ifb-and-more-101736927023111.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:00:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Sale 2025: Price drop deals on front load washing machines; Save up to 42% on LG, Samsung, Bosch, IFB and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-sale-2025-price-drop-deals-on-front-load-washing-machines-save-up-to-42-on-lg-samsung-bosch-ifb-and-more-101736927023111.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/amazon-sale-2025-price-drop-deals-on-front-load-washing-machines-save-up-to-42-on-lg-samsung-bosch-ifb-and-more-101736927023111.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:00:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leica’s $5,300 SL3-S is its latest hybrid camera for stills and video - The Verge]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24343500/leica-sl3s-full-frame-mirrorless-hybrid-camera-price-specs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/16/24343500/leica-sl3s-full-frame-mirrorless-hybrid-camera-price-specs</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Android co-founder to Bill Gates: 'You're more responsible for Microsoft losing the $400 billion' - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQOHh4SkFsQkJDNnM4UkNHZUo0UXFsbXBfam5raWFWU1NMdnNzdUFYbWFOWTRndzYwMmFxY0ZWWWFlZHhaOW9leTJZcnlXNFlsWWNXb0dxNmtTdm1KYUwzM01kT1NxaE5QMmxVNjlRckg2M0F0NTBFa28wYXVxRlFfWGQzQ0Y5WTQ5UFJodTNfTWs4UW1KU05pbVIyekY5UHF1NTdNMDVGQTZGeXVlWmpYT1RqalB5bFp5LW5MZkJtZG9uN19tYXJwcUVleUpHQXQyRDJJbWNEVE1Ja2M1dGRhM3NR0gHnAUFVX3lxTE5JSVRuMnNoVEFVbVZ2emlObHRvOEF1cWtUalZzdFR0SXlJaHZfTGNtR0x5VWpyMnZiNGZ3VVlKa0hGcThZcFFEcjExUGdZeXJhZHBJdDcxZHg3WEJQb3J6MENIVElibHdmVS1HdVloNzY1YkpwSUFHV0ZVTmlQam4xLUJLUDE3NVVfNVZMOW8zdldwazBtejY4eGlTTmVhc3M4eklYRUYwRnZ1SEV5bTRQTE1teWRpMVlKN1NSRm5pN3NlUnhRZVpIM01GYXJOSnBkSlhYWXZ6dnloZ1hGTmx1aFk2TzZkTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQOHh4SkFsQkJDNnM4UkNHZUo0UXFsbXBfam5raWFWU1NMdnNzdUFYbWFOWTRndzYwMmFxY0ZWWWFlZHhaOW9leTJZcnlXNFlsWWNXb0dxNmtTdm1KYUwzM01kT1NxaE5QMmxVNjlRckg2M0F0NTBFa28wYXVxRlFfWGQzQ0Y5WTQ5UFJodTNfTWs4UW1KU05pbVIyekY5UHF1NTdNMDVGQTZGeXVlWmpYT1RqalB5bFp5LW5MZkJtZG9uN19tYXJwcUVleUpHQXQyRDJJbWNEVE1Ja2M1dGRhM3NR0gHnAUFVX3lxTE5JSVRuMnNoVEFVbVZ2emlObHRvOEF1cWtUalZzdFR0SXlJaHZfTGNtR0x5VWpyMnZiNGZ3VVlKa0hGcThZcFFEcjExUGdZeXJhZHBJdDcxZHg3WEJQb3J6MENIVElibHdmVS1HdVloNzY1YkpwSUFHV0ZVTmlQam4xLUJLUDE3NVVfNVZMOW8zdldwazBtejY4eGlTTmVhc3M4eklYRUYwRnZ1SEV5bTRQTE1teWRpMVlKN1NSRm5pN3NlUnhRZVpIM01GYXJOSnBkSlhYWXZ6dnloZ1hGTmx1aFk2TzZkTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:54:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 console revealed in first trailer: Here's all you need to know - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nintendo Switch 2 console revealed in first trailer: Here's all you need to know</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gaming News Online</p><p>The highly anticipated Nintendo Switch 2 has been officially revealed through its first trailer, sparking excitement among fans of the gaming community.</p><ul><li>The trailer showcases advanced graphics and new gaming features.</li><li>Pre-orders are expected to start next month.</li><li>It aims to compete with leading gaming consoles from Sony and Microsoft.</li><li>Nintendo promises a diverse library of launch titles.</li></ul><blockquote>“This new console is going to redefine portable gaming,” said Nintendo's CEO during the press event.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Nintendo Switch 2 is set to change the landscape of gaming once again, maintaining Nintendo's legacy of innovation in the gaming industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/nintendo-switch-2-console-revealed-in-first-trailer-heres-all-you-need-to-know/articleshow/117304082.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/nintendo-switch-2-console-revealed-in-first-trailer-heres-all-you-need-to-know/articleshow/117304082.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13 vs. OnePlus 13R: What's the best OnePlus phone in 2025? - Android Central]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 vs. OnePlus 13R: What's the best OnePlus phone in 2025?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date unavailable <strong>Source:</strong> Android Central</p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/A8HwsBkbJuMTnsiuiX6km4-1200-80.jpg" alt="OnePlus 13 render with extra space"><figcaption>(Image credit: Harish Jonnalagadda / Android Central)</figcaption><p>The article compares the OnePlus 13 and OnePlus 13R smartphones, highlighting their features, performance, design, and overall value in the context of the mobile market in 2025.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The OnePlus 13 boasts outstanding hardware, fantastic design, durable build, and impressive cameras.</li><li>The OnePlus 13R offers great value with similar performance but lacks in camera quality and design comfort.</li><li>Both models feature long-lasting batteries but differ in charging speeds and capabilities.</li><li>Software support is equal, with both devices set to receive multiple updates.</li></ul><blockquote>“The best OnePlus phone yet... one of the best flagships you can buy in 2025.” - Harish Jonnalagadda</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the OnePlus 13 is ideal for those seeking the best available technology, while the OnePlus 13R represents a smart choice for users looking for excellent performance without the higher price tag.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-vs-oneplus-13r</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.androidcentral.com/phones/oneplus-13-vs-oneplus-13r</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:52:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Connections Today: Answers and Hints for January 16, 2025 - Analytics Insight]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NYT Connections Today: Answers and Hints for January 16, 2025</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-16T13:49:32.162Z" title="2025-01-16 13:49">16 Jan 2025, 1:49 pm</time></p><p>Are the NYT 'Connections' puzzles leaving players scratching their heads? Thursday’s game is here to challenge and entertain, but if it feels like a brain teaser too tough to crack, help is at hand. Dive into the hints and solutions for NYT Connections #585 and unravel today’s puzzle with ease.</p><h3><strong>Hints for January 16 Categories</strong></h3><ul><li><strong>Economics and Trade</strong>: These words deal with buying, selling, and the exchange of goods or services. Think commerce and trade.</li><li><strong>Wall Fixtures</strong>: Items typically mounted or attached to walls or similar surfaces.</li><li><strong>Covert Operations</strong>: Words related to espionage and secret agents.</li><li><strong>Common Nouns Preceded by Words Ending in “Rat”</strong>: The challenge lies in identifying words that pairs with “rat” to form familiar terms.</li></ul><h3><strong>Full Solutions for NYT Connections #585</strong></h3><p>If the hints aren’t enough and curiosity wins, here are today’s answers:</p><ul><li><strong>Buying and Selling</strong>: Business, Commerce, Market, Trade</li><li><strong>Installed on a Wall</strong>: Baseboard, Outlet, Sconce, Switch</li><li><strong>Spy</strong>: Agent, Asset, Mole, Plant</li><li><strong>_____ Rat</strong>: Gym, Mall, Pack, Rug</li></ul><h3><strong>Category Breakdown</strong></h3><ol><li><strong>Buying and Selling</strong>: These words center on economics. They describe activities related to the exchange of goods and services.</li><li><strong>Installed on a Wall</strong>: This category focuses on objects commonly found mounted or fixed on walls.</li><li><strong>Spy</strong>: Words in this group evoke images of covert operations and espionage.</li><li><strong>_____ Rat</strong>: This playful category completes the phrase “_____ Rat” with familiar terms.</li></ol><h3><strong>Puzzle Popularity and Insights</strong></h3><p>The NYT ‘Connections’ game continues to grow in popularity. Its daily challenges strike a balance between fun and frustration.</p><h3><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h3><p>Today’s NYT Connections #585 offers a mix of challenges, ensuring a satisfying resolution for players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.analyticsinsight.net/gaming/nyt-connections-today-answers-and-hints-for-january-16-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.analyticsinsight.net/gaming/nyt-connections-today-answers-and-hints-for-january-16-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:49:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Realme 14 Pro, Pro Plus series launched in India - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Realme 14 Pro and Pro Plus Series Launched in India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 16 January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p><img src="https://images.deccanherald.com/deccanherald%2F2025-01-16%2F9pqsqu68%2FRealme-14-Pro-Plus.jpg?w=1200" alt="Realme 14 Pro."><figcaption>Realme 14 Pro. Credit: Realme</figcaption><p>This week, Realme unveiled its new line of premium mid-range smartphones, the Realme 14 Pro series, which includes the standard and Plus models boasting innovative features like color-changing technology.</p><ul><li>Launched the Realme 14 Pro and Pro Plus, featuring color-changing design when exposed to cold.</li><li>The standard model has a 6.7-inch AMOLED screen, 120Hz refresh rate, and a MediaTek Dimensity 7300 processor.</li><li>The Pro Plus offers a larger 6.83-inch AMOLED display, Snapdragon 7s Gen 3 chipset, and enhanced camera capabilities.</li><li>Both models are equipped with significant battery life, hefty RAM options, and advanced camera systems.</li><li>Realme also introduced the Realme Buds Wireless 5 ANC alongside the smartphone launch.</li></ul><blockquote>“Realme 14 Pro is touted to be the world's first cold-sensitive colour-changing phone.”</blockquote><p>The series is set to attract tech enthusiasts with its groundbreaking features, bolstering Realme's position in the competitive smartphone market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/technology/realme-14-pro-pro-plus-series-launched-in-india-3358488</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/technology/realme-14-pro-pro-plus-series-launched-in-india-3358488</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:43:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>