<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:22:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:22:29 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Arcade expands with 10 new games, including first official PGA Tour title - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Arcade Expands with 10 New Games, Including First Official PGA Tour Title</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117177671,imgsize-1866947,width-400,resizemode-4/117177671.jpg" alt="Apple Arcade expands with 10 new games, including first official PGA Tour title" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Apple Arcade expands with new games</figcaption>
<p>Apple Arcade is launching 10 new games in early 2025, headlined by the first officially licensed professional golf game, PGA TOUR Pro Golf.</p>
<ul>
  <li>PGA TOUR Pro Golf arrives on February 6, featuring authentic courses and tournament play.</li>
  <li>Seven new titles are released today; three more are scheduled for early February.</li>
  <li>Other games include Skate City: New York and a tower defense game, Gears &amp; Goo.</li>
  <li>Existing games are receiving updates, such as the Lunar New Year event in Hello Kitty Island Adventure.</li>
  <li>The subscription service costs INR 99 per month and allows access to over 200 games.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“All Arcade Originals are playable across Apple's device ecosystem, including the upcoming Vision Pro.”</blockquote>
<p>This expansion signifies Apple's commitment to enriching the gaming experience on its platforms, catering to diverse gaming preferences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxNaGt0ZGVJVzgzdzFtUFdHOWNXQjh1VnlqS2kwdTZNcXBiTWQxTU9ObFEzb1BEbW4zb2FSSGtkZHFadFMwNjBMdnI2SW11VG85eGYtUFV4WW41T202OG1aUy1lbXpJRnZmNmlTX05TMTBIc1dZSXpReDRrVmZ5TEFHSFJXNmROM0VXSjB4amg0TFI1QWc3OW15N0hvZU4tTmxTY0xTMzRfcjY5bUYyUnlCT3hOcXZ4TnZJX1d0WGZ2MldseUpsNjAtSWFKX0VQUllZRHZ5NHhRYlpsOERJWm5xekh6dFZVTERNTnB2RjNHd9IB9AFBVV95cUxOMG5oQmtVaG5mTXdNNEZPLXpNdWM2eXFocjN2cXJSNmpUUVBRNExaYUFyb1M2Qzl2bFlDNTBWVmtHM09qSEk3SXhoQktPUFV4R3RJaG1YOVRqdHhicHJaTDJfTm82U05VaE5hX1B1dmtVMjdpY0dRNUZ3ZTdJaWpvUEpYZlRrNzN0WWVXbmhfc21pdjNvZldsdEE4UlhFbUJfb0tkSlg0cjRuTS04RDdNTXNLVzVmbnZiSFpLREJQSmlaQk9LSXkxRzdNMk5GZmgxNTZyUEVzMEZEczNiYUJUZ0hROEZxRHM2RC00N2hDNG9peGpC?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxNaGt0ZGVJVzgzdzFtUFdHOWNXQjh1VnlqS2kwdTZNcXBiTWQxTU9ObFEzb1BEbW4zb2FSSGtkZHFadFMwNjBMdnI2SW11VG85eGYtUFV4WW41T202OG1aUy1lbXpJRnZmNmlTX05TMTBIc1dZSXpReDRrVmZ5TEFHSFJXNmROM0VXSjB4amg0TFI1QWc3OW15N0hvZU4tTmxTY0xTMzRfcjY5bUYyUnlCT3hOcXZ4TnZJX1d0WGZ2MldseUpsNjAtSWFKX0VQUllZRHZ5NHhRYlpsOERJWm5xekh6dFZVTERNTnB2RjNHd9IB9AFBVV95cUxOMG5oQmtVaG5mTXdNNEZPLXpNdWM2eXFocjN2cXJSNmpUUVBRNExaYUFyb1M2Qzl2bFlDNTBWVmtHM09qSEk3SXhoQktPUFV4R3RJaG1YOVRqdHhicHJaTDJfTm82U05VaE5hX1B1dmtVMjdpY0dRNUZ3ZTdJaWpvUEpYZlRrNzN0WWVXbmhfc21pdjNvZldsdEE4UlhFbUJfb0tkSlg0cjRuTS04RDdNTXNLVzVmbnZiSFpLREJQSmlaQk9LSXkxRzdNMk5GZmgxNTZyUEVzMEZEczNiYUJUZ0hROEZxRHM2RC00N2hDNG9peGpC?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What time is SpaceX's Starship Flight 7 launch test on Jan. 15? - Space.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What time is SpaceX's Starship Flight 7 launch test on Jan. 15?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Space.com</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/dNWQSWGN42Es8Y5fvPtuvk-320-80.jpg" alt="SpaceX's Starship Flight 7 Ship and Super Heavy seen assembled for flight." />
    <figcaption>SpaceX's Starship Flight 7 Ship and Super Heavy seen assembled for flight. (Image credit: SpaceX)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>SpaceX is preparing for the launch of its Starship Flight 7 on January 15, 2025. This launch will test a new version of the world's largest rocket with significant upgrades.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The launch is scheduled for <strong>5 p.m. EST (2200 GMT)</strong> from the Starbase facility in South Texas.</li>
    <li>SpaceX is targeting to catch the Super Heavy booster at the launch site, similar to a previous successful attempt.</li>
    <li>Viewers can watch the launch live on Space.com and other platforms starting 30 minutes before launch.</li>
    <li>If the weather or technical issues prevent the launch, backup days are available for January 14 and 15.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Excitement Guaranteed," says SpaceX regarding the launch.</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming Starship Flight 7 is pivotal as it showcases advancements in technology and aims for new records in space exploration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.space.com/space-exploration/launches-spacecraft/spacex-starship-flight-7-launch-what-time</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.space.com/space-exploration/launches-spacecraft/spacex-starship-flight-7-launch-what-time</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:43:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parliamentary panel reviews price spike of medicines | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Parliamentary panel reviews price spike of medicines</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 7 January | <strong>Source:</strong> Today News</p>
<p>The Parliamentary Standing Committee on Chemicals and Fertilizers met to discuss the rising prices of essential medicines, with a goal to potentially lower the cost of life-saving drugs.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The meeting was attended by officials from the Department of Pharmaceuticals (DoP).</li>
  <li>The primary focus was on essential medicines and their pricing strategies.</li>
  <li>The committee aims to address issues concerning price spikes in the pharmaceutical sector.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This move may lead to a lowering of prices of life-saving medicines.”</blockquote>
<p>In summary, the review of medicine prices by the parliamentary panel highlights a proactive approach towards ensuring affordable access to essential healthcare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/india/parliamentary-panel-reviews-price-spike-of-medicines-11736676507675.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/india/parliamentary-panel-reviews-price-spike-of-medicines-11736676507675.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:46:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 13 price drops on Flipkart - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iPhone 13 Price Drops on Flipkart</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: January 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: India Today</strong></p><img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2025/01/cropped-imageITG-1736692383025.png" alt="iPhone 13 Offer on Flipkart"><figcaption>iPhone 13 available for discounted price on Flipkart</figcaption><p>The iPhone 13 has received a significant price reduction on Flipkart, making it an attractive option for budget-conscious buyers. The device is now listed at approximately Rs 45,399 with possible further discounts through exchange and payment options.</p><ul><li>The iPhone 13 is available on Flipkart for around Rs 45,399.</li><li>The official retail price is Rs 49,900, offering a flat discount of Rs 4,501.</li><li>Additional discounts up to Rs 1,000 are available via UPI and bank card offers.</li><li>Exchange offers can reduce prices further, potentially providing up to Rs 28,500 off based on the age and condition of your old device.</li><li>The iPhone 13 is powered by the A15 Bionic chip, ensuring reliable performance.</li><li>It receives iOS updates regularly, enhancing its longevity and access to new features.</li><li>The dual-camera system offers impressive image quality for its price range.</li><li>It balances performance and usability for those seeking a premium smartphone experience.</li></ul><blockquote>“For those seeking a premium smartphone experience without breaking the bank, the iPhone 13 offers a good balance between performance, camera quality, and overall usability.”</blockquote><p>This price drop on the iPhone 13 at Flipkart presents a compelling opportunity for consumers looking to upgrade without exceeding their budgets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/iphone-13-price-drops-on-flipkart-201938-12-01-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/iphone-13-price-drops-on-flipkart-201938-12-01-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:34:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple iPhone SE 4 Might Boast OLED Display & Be Powered By A18 Chip - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple iPhone SE 4 Might Boast OLED Display & Be Powered By A18 Chip</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Tech News</p><p>The fourth-generation iPhone SE, possibly branded as iPhone 16e, is set to launch soon with a focus on affordability and updated specifications.</p><ul><li>Expected to feature a 6.06-inch full-HD+ LTPS OLED display with a 60Hz refresh rate.</li><li>Powered by Apple’s A18 Bionic chip.</li><li>Includes a 48-megapixel rear camera.</li><li>Face ID support and a durable, waterproof design are anticipated.</li><li>Pricing expected to be under $500.</li></ul><blockquote>“The device marks a significant step toward reducing Apple's reliance on third-party suppliers for cellular technology.” - Smart Pikachu</blockquote><p>With its budget-friendly approach and advanced specs, the iPhone SE 4 is poised to be a strong contender in the smartphone market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/apple-iphone-se-4-release-launch-date-display-processor-specifications-1743629</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/apple-iphone-se-4-release-launch-date-display-processor-specifications-1743629</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:31:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The OnePlus Open 2 tipped to be the thinnest foldable yet – with a new titanium build - TechRadar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The OnePlus Open 2 tipped to be the thinnest foldable yet – with a new titanium build</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert publication date] | <strong>Source:</strong> TechRadar</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/Awh6TceqdLmtNca2E89mem-320-80.jpg" alt="Honor Magic V3" loading="lazy">
  <figcaption>The Honor Magic V3 is currently the thinnest foldable (Image credit: Future)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The OnePlus Open 2 is set to launch soon, boasting a thinner and tougher design with a titanium build, aiming to be the slimmest foldable phone available.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The OnePlus Open 2 could be arriving imminently.</li>
  <li>A tougher, lighter, thinner build is rumored.</li>
  <li>The Honor Magic V3 is currently the thinnest foldable.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The OnePlus Open 2 will have to be less than the 9.2 mm thickness of the Honor Magic V3 when closed."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, anticipation builds around the OnePlus Open 2 as it promises significant advancements in design and capabilities compared to its predecessor.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techradar.com/phones/oneplus-phones/the-oneplus-open-2-tipped-to-be-the-thinnest-foldable-yet-with-a-new-titanium-build</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techradar.com/phones/oneplus-phones/the-oneplus-open-2-tipped-to-be-the-thinnest-foldable-yet-with-a-new-titanium-build</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows: Release date, platforms, editions and gameplay - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxPUGNQLVkzYmRQeEhVb0J0d1lkamRPTVpyTDZaa2VfN1N5U0xfUndMOFlrOWR1a1I3LTFVV0I4d2pvaXQwN2NqR2hkQnNXREhVNTM5Zi1aOVRLb1VyYTRXWlhxUXA2c2VBQmMzZkFpc0RXU192TGZTM0lFNThVa2o3YUt3MWFrc2RFcWttZVhDeUp5a0FUVmxjMTlyX3MxNjVmVWRucEMzSUpmVmpZVEU1RkxES0pjNVFfM002VXJZbGVDV0JrbEdUWVFEVnFpUVRiZFAtdlJ2WjRKSjR10gHiAUFVX3lxTE5FZGFubGtVZkNJTldyNURHcXNmQjlsSlNFWk05eVlJVDAwMTJtUjFDWXRpa2F0QUZLZm9TdjN5VWYwRlNxeDVienNvNTh6eWlIS0RPTnhxRjR2QzZEcThKTVVSVVZ6VWlEazlqMFJDeXNZVVZBMUdsOUJGSndRdDF0aXRPMzFRNXZ3SVY2Rk1kTThtSUdIYnJiV2pqZUlPa1lPTHA5SFpKVkQzOGNpSmp1c3lhRTh0bV9VdTA3R29WTnRIaTZ4X0JaaV9fX3RQWHpDQTNPb1VyR3lJMEg2T09Tb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxPUGNQLVkzYmRQeEhVb0J0d1lkamRPTVpyTDZaa2VfN1N5U0xfUndMOFlrOWR1a1I3LTFVV0I4d2pvaXQwN2NqR2hkQnNXREhVNTM5Zi1aOVRLb1VyYTRXWlhxUXA2c2VBQmMzZkFpc0RXU192TGZTM0lFNThVa2o3YUt3MWFrc2RFcWttZVhDeUp5a0FUVmxjMTlyX3MxNjVmVWRucEMzSUpmVmpZVEU1RkxES0pjNVFfM002VXJZbGVDV0JrbEdUWVFEVnFpUVRiZFAtdlJ2WjRKSjR10gHiAUFVX3lxTE5FZGFubGtVZkNJTldyNURHcXNmQjlsSlNFWk05eVlJVDAwMTJtUjFDWXRpa2F0QUZLZm9TdjN5VWYwRlNxeDVienNvNTh6eWlIS0RPTnhxRjR2QzZEcThKTVVSVVZ6VWlEazlqMFJDeXNZVVZBMUdsOUJGSndRdDF0aXRPMzFRNXZ3SVY2Rk1kTThtSUdIYnJiV2pqZUlPa1lPTHA5SFpKVkQzOGNpSmp1c3lhRTh0bV9VdTA3R29WTnRIaTZ4X0JaaV9fX3RQWHpDQTNPb1VyR3lJMEg2T09Tb2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:09:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 series launching soon with new colour options - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Series Launching Soon with New Colour Options</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2025/01/cropped-imageITG-1736494730826.png" alt="Samsung Galaxy S25" /><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S25 Series</figcaption><p>Samsung is set to unveil its flagship Galaxy S25 series on January 22, featuring various leaks revealing new color options and specifications.</p><ul><li>The S25 and S25+ will be available in Iceblue, Mint, Navy, and Silver Shadow.</li><li>The S25 Ultra will come in Titanium Black, Titanium Gray, Titanium Silver Blue, and Titanium White Silver.</li><li>All models are expected to feature flat frames and rounded edges.</li><li>The Galaxy S25 is rumored to include Snapdragon 8 Elite processors and up to 16GB of RAM in select markets.</li><li>Press coverage anticipates the S25 Ultra will boast advanced camera capabilities with a 200MP main sensor.</li><li>There may be a fourth model named Galaxy S25 Slim announced during the launch.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Galaxy S25 will be the most compact model, while the S25 Ultra is expected to offer the most powerful camera capabilities in the series."</blockquote><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 series is generating significant buzz, with enthusiasts eagerly awaiting its official launch and detailed features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-launching-soon-with-new-colour-options-201930-12-01-2025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-launching-soon-with-new-colour-options-201930-12-01-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:04:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NCLT Hearing Hack: A Wake-Up Call to Bolster Courts' Cybersecurity | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NCLT Hearing Hack: A Wake-Up Call to Bolster Courts' Cybersecurity</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Today News</p><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/subscription/onepagecheckout/lm/staging/extensivepaywall/computer.png" alt="NCLT Hearing Hack"/><figcaption>Image depicting cybersecurity concerns in courts.</figcaption><p>The National Company Law Tribunal (NCLT) in Mumbai has temporarily suspended virtual hearings, requiring lawyers to appear physically after its virtual hearing system was hacked on 12 and 17 December.</p><ul><li>Unidentified hackers disrupted proceedings by broadcasting pornographic content.</li><li>Legal and cyber law experts warn about the vulnerability of Indian courts to such cyberattacks.</li><li>There is a growing consensus on the need to strengthen digital infrastructure to ensure accessible justice.</li></ul><blockquote>"This incident highlights the critical need for enhanced cybersecurity measures in our legal system." - Cyber Law Expert</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the recent hack of the NCLT's virtual hearing system serves as a significant reminder of the vulnerabilities present in digital court systems and the urgent need for improved cybersecurity measures to protect the integrity of judicial proceedings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/india/nclt-hearing-hack-a-wake-up-call-to-bolster-courts-cybersecurity-11736666586781.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/india/nclt-hearing-hack-a-wake-up-call-to-bolster-courts-cybersecurity-11736666586781.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:01:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deals: OnePlus 13 launches, Poco X7 and X7 Pro arrive in Europe as well - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 Launches Globally Alongside Poco X7 and X7 Pro in Europe</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> GSM Arena</p><div><img src="https://fdn2.gsmarena.com/vv/bigpic/oneplus-13.jpg" alt="OnePlus 13" width="75" height="100"><figcaption>OnePlus 13</figcaption></div><p>The OnePlus 13 has officially launched with a pricing strategy aimed to attract previous OnePlus 12 buyers, while the Poco X7 series has also been introduced in the UK, featuring two models distinguished by performance and battery specifications.</p><ul><li>The OnePlus 13 comes with a €100 discount for the 16/512GB model, aligning its price with last year's OnePlus 12.</li><li>The Poco X7 and X7 Pro both feature 6.67” 120Hz OLED displays, with significant differences in battery capacity and performance chipsets.</li><li>The Poco X7 Pro is equipped with the Dimensity 8400 Ultra, while the standard X7 offers the Dimensity 7300 Ultra.</li><li>Batteries range from 5,110mAh in the standard model to 6,000mAh in the Pro, with HyperCharge support for fast charging.</li><li>Both models feature similar camera setups, though the recording capabilities differ due to chipset variations.</li></ul><blockquote>“We may get a commission from qualifying sales.”</blockquote><p>This new launch strategy by OnePlus and Xiaomi reflects their approach to enhancing market penetration in Europe by offering competitive pricing and technologically advanced features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gsmarena.com/deals_oneplus_13_launches_poco_x7_and_x7_pro_arrive_in_europe_as_well-news-66051.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gsmarena.com/deals_oneplus_13_launches_poco_x7_and_x7_pro_arrive_in_europe_as_well-news-66051.php</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:41:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Significant percentage of iPhone, Android users in India faced issues post software upgrade: Survey - BusinessLine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Significant percentage of iPhone, Android users in India faced issues post software upgrade: Survey</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu Business Line</p>
<img src="https://bl-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ot03tm/article69091994.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2025-01-02T151012Z_2075311777_RC28X9AA4WGK_RTRMADP_3_APPLE-SETTLEMENT-SIRI-PRIVACY.JPG" alt="Software Update Issues" />
<figcaption>Image depicting software update issues.</figcaption>
<p>A recent survey by LocalCircles has highlighted significant connectivity issues faced by iPhone and Android users in India following recent software upgrades.</p>
<ul>
  <li>60% of iPhone users report problems after upgrading to iOS 18 or higher.</li>
  <li>40% of Android users claim to experience issues post upgrade.</li>
  <li>iPhone users face call failures; Android users report app freezing.</li>
  <li>The survey received over 47,000 responses from users across 322 districts in India.</li>
  <li>Recent updates from Apple aim to fix existing issues, including freezing problems.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"6 in 10 apple iPhone users surveyed who have upgraded to iOS 18 or higher are having difficulties. 28 per cent of the respondents stated that most/some of voice and OTT calls don't connect or drop."</blockquote>
<p>This survey underscores the pressing issues users are facing with new software updates, prompting concerns over the reliability of recent operating system releases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/info-tech/significant-percentage-of-iphone-android-users-in-india-faced-issues-post-software-upgrade-survey/article69091984.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindubusinessline.com/info-tech/significant-percentage-of-iphone-android-users-in-india-faced-issues-post-software-upgrade-survey/article69091984.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:30:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Redmi Watch 5 in for review - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidkFVX3lxTE9jd19LcmpaTGpDS043bm5hWDd3NjI4RmNfSzR4Ry1FNl96YWo4NVNLWGNnc0FXOWVIMW5HOEoybW9LVWNRVGhVeDdkRmU0M2lMbFo2U3pXNWVTWGRaRENZc0lhZFY4RHJxQ3NJd21hYTFNcHJpdFHSAXJBVV95cUxORWtQSEhMZlU2R2xIWWEtM3RsQUM1SHNxaG9pcG1FbWtrYmgydkNNTzJmaHlYdTlXdTQyVG5nUlhRNUE4a1RUNnZVSGNkVlZycTJKUWs1Zy1OUTZrRjU4Y0lyWWNQb2s1UkM3SndTOUhVeVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidkFVX3lxTE9jd19LcmpaTGpDS043bm5hWDd3NjI4RmNfSzR4Ry1FNl96YWo4NVNLWGNnc0FXOWVIMW5HOEoybW9LVWNRVGhVeDdkRmU0M2lMbFo2U3pXNWVTWGRaRENZc0lhZFY4RHJxQ3NJd21hYTFNcHJpdFHSAXJBVV95cUxORWtQSEhMZlU2R2xIWWEtM3RsQUM1SHNxaG9pcG1FbWtrYmgydkNNTzJmaHlYdTlXdTQyVG5nUlhRNUE4a1RUNnZVSGNkVlZycTJKUWs1Zy1OUTZrRjU4Y0lyWWNQb2s1UkM3SndTOUhVeVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:12:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is PIA's MACE feature - TechRadar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What is PIA's MACE feature</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> TechRadar</p><figure><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/AJPCJ3YJJ4c8qVCqkUv4bZ-1200-80.png" alt="PIA running on a laptop"><figcaption><span>(Image credit: PIA)</span></figcaption></figure><p>The article explores MACE, a built-in ad blocker feature from Private Internet Access (PIA). MACE operates at the DNS level, blocking ads, trackers, and malware before they reach your device, providing enhanced privacy and resource efficiency.</p><ul><li>MACE is an integrated ad, tracker, and malware blocker from PIA.</li><li>It operates at the DNS level, blocking unwanted content proactively.</li><li>The feature is beneficial for privacy, reducing ads, and protecting against malware.</li><li>MACE is available on most PIA client apps, except for Android due to Google’s restrictions.</li><li>Enabling MACE is a straightforward process within the PIA app settings.</li></ul><blockquote><p>Remember, MACE isn’t a comprehensive malware solution on its own and can’t replace an anti-virus engine.</p></blockquote><p>MACE is a valuable addition to your security toolkit, working alongside other ad-blocking solutions, though it has limitations regarding its static blocklist and malware detection capabilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techradar.com/vpn/vpn-privacy-security/what-is-pias-mace-feature</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techradar.com/vpn/vpn-privacy-security/what-is-pias-mace-feature</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Critical Warning For 100 Million Apple Users—New Hack Attack Confirmed - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/daveywinder/2025/01/12/100-million-apple-users-warned-about-new-credential-stealing-hack-attack/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/daveywinder/2025/01/12/100-million-apple-users-warned-about-new-credential-stealing-hack-attack/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diaper maker Nobel Hygiene eyes up to ₹200 cr in funding led by Neo Group’s investment arm | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nobel Hygiene Seeks Up to ₹200 Crore in Funding</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>Nobel Hygiene, a manufacturer known for its diapers and maternity pads, is exploring a funding round aiming to raise ₹150-200 crore, primarily from new investors under the investment arm of Neo Asset Management.</p><ol><li>The company is in discussions for financing led by Neo Asset Management.</li><li>Funds will be utilized for company expansion, though specific valuation details remain undisclosed.</li><li>Existing investors are expected to join the funding round.</li></ol><blockquote>“The company plans to use the funds for expansion,” - Anonymous source</blockquote><p>This funding initiative highlights Nobel Hygiene's ambitions for growth in the healthcare and personal care sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/start-ups/nobel-hygiene-rs-150-200-crore-funding-round-neo-asset-management-neo-group-diapers-maternity-pads-11736658562573.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/start-ups/nobel-hygiene-rs-150-200-crore-funding-round-neo-asset-management-neo-group-diapers-maternity-pads-11736658562573.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:21:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Great Republic Day sale deal: Is iQOO 12 new OnePlus 13R killer? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amazon Great Republic Day sale deal: Is iQOO 12 new OnePlus 13R killer?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/oneplus-13-iqoo12.jpg?w=640" alt="OnePlus 13R vs iQOO 12" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Two affordable Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 powered phones. (Image credit: Amazon)</figcaption><p>The iQOO 12 is set to be available for Rs 45,999, with discounts bringing the price down to Rs 41,999, positioning it as a strong competitor against the OnePlus 13R.</p><ul><li>Both smartphones feature the Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 chip and target the affordable premium segment.</li><li>OnePlus 13R offers a superior software experience with OxygenOS 15 and longer support for updates.</li><li>iQOO 12 excels in hardware capabilities, with a better camera setup and higher refresh rate display.</li><li>Price comparisons show the OnePlus 13R is slightly cheaper after discounts.</li></ul><blockquote>“Both are fantastic devices on their own terms, and depending on your use case, pick either one, and you’ll be sorted for years.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the choice between the iQOO 12 and OnePlus 13R depends on user priorities: software experience vs. camera and gaming performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/iqoo-12-discount-oneplus13r-alternative-9774718/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/iqoo-12-discount-oneplus13r-alternative-9774718/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 09:50:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reliance Jio launches advanced 5.5G network in India - Telangana Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQdE13YVFJbE5yaS1kQnBSUFdPOW9YT1p6SzdjQ29udnNVbEZJSHl5SFhuWEx6cjlfMXJTUmxTd3JHZHY0NFJieVpIYTlibjBZNDMxNlY0ZGF4TTU4amhDU2hNeEJaNk5zRDd3TWYxbVdteFFZWjBDbWZFSklrR3FlOEhIa3ZjQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQdE13YVFJbE5yaS1kQnBSUFdPOW9YT1p6SzdjQ29udnNVbEZJSHl5SFhuWEx6cjlfMXJTUmxTd3JHZHY0NFJieVpIYTlibjBZNDMxNlY0ZGF4TTU4amhDU2hNeEJaNk5zRDd3TWYxbVdteFFZWjBDbWZFSklrR3FlOEhIa3ZjQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 09:41:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[For hassled homebuyers, an additional layer of protection from delays, hidden charges, substandard construction | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>For hassled homebuyers, an additional layer of protection from delays, hidden charges, substandard construction</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p>
<p>In response to concerns regarding construction delays, hidden charges, and substandard quality in apartment sales, India's consumer protection agency is stepping in to assist homebuyers.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Central Consumer Protection Authority (CCPA) is set to collaborate with the Real Estate Regulatory Authority (Rera).</li>
  <li>This partnership aims to help homebuyers file complaints and seek compensation.</li>
  <li>CCPA will assist in addressing unfair contracts with developers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The collaboration will empower consumers to fight against unfair practices in the real estate sector.”</blockquote>
<p>The initiative represents an important step in safeguarding consumer rights in the real estate market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/industry/homebuyers-ccpa-rera-consumer-rights-consumer-protection-real-estate-property-builders-developers-construction-delays-11736623089181.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/industry/homebuyers-ccpa-rera-consumer-rights-consumer-protection-real-estate-property-builders-developers-construction-delays-11736623089181.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 08:44:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why it’s time put personal style first | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why it’s time put personal style first</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified <strong>Source: </strong>Mint</p><p>In the evolving landscape of fashion, 'holistic dressing' emphasizes the importance of well-being and authenticity, urging consumers to focus on personal style amidst rapid industry changes.</p><ul><li>The fashion industry is witnessing significant shifts with new appointments at major houses.</li><li>Consumers are increasingly seeking authenticity in their fashion choices.</li><li>The trend of 'holistic dressing' is emerging as a response to the chaotic trends of recent years.</li></ul><blockquote>"It’s time for the consumer to put personal style first."</blockquote><p>This transformation in fashion indicates a deeper desire for meaningful consumption and individuality among consumers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/style/2025-fashion-trends-tarun-tahiliani-anti-algorithm-style-shein-cate-blanchett-alia-bhatt-11736491336235.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/style/2025-fashion-trends-tarun-tahiliani-anti-algorithm-style-shein-cate-blanchett-alia-bhatt-11736491336235.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 07:30:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flipkart puts all iPhones on sale: iPhone 16 at Rs 63,999, iPhone 14 at Rs 46,999 — top deals - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Flipkart Offers Major Discounts on iPhones in 2025 Republic Day Sale</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 14, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p>
<img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/South-Western-Railway-4.png?w=300" alt="South Western Railway" title="South Western Railway announces partial cancellation, diversion of trains for track maintenance">
<figcaption>South Western Railway announces partial cancellation, diversion of trains for track maintenance.</figcaption>
<p>Flipkart is set to launch its Republic Day Monumental sale on January 14, 2025, with early access for Plus and VIP members starting January 13. All iPhones will be discounted during this sale.</p>
<ul>
<li>The iPhone 16 will be available for Rs 63,999, down from Rs 79,900.</li>
<li>The iPhone 16 Plus will drop to Rs 73,999 from Rs 89,900.</li>
<li>Pro models will also see discounts: iPhone 16 Pro for Rs 1,02,900 (down from Rs 1,19,900) and iPhone 16 Pro Max for Rs 1,27,900 (down from Rs 1,44,900).</li>
<li>iPhone 15 prices will start at Rs 55,999 and iPhone 14 at Rs 46,999.</li>
<li>The sale runs until January 19, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Flipkart is promising the greatest deal on the iPhone 16.”</blockquote>
<p>This sale presents an opportunity for customers to purchase iPhones at significantly reduced prices, especially with additional bank offers and exchange bonuses available.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-flipkart-puts-all-iphones-on-sale-iphone-16-at-rs-63999-iphone-14-at-rs-46999-top-deals-3713015/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-flipkart-puts-all-iphones-on-sale-iphone-16-at-rs-63999-iphone-14-at-rs-46999-top-deals-3713015/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 07:20:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I've spent 10 years with Apple Watch, and after 10 minutes with the Galaxy Watch Ultra, I can't believe Samsung skipped this feature - TechRadar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>I've spent 10 years with Apple Watch, and after 10 minutes with the Galaxy Watch Ultra, I can't believe Samsung skipped…</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> TechRadar</p>
<img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/nr4XERCA9UNMhSavaDFiEP-1200-80.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy Watch Ultra">
<figcaption><span>(Image credit: Future)</span></figcaption>
<p>After years of using the Apple Watch and launching into the Android market with the Samsung Galaxy Watch Ultra, the author realizes the importance of features like the digital crown that are absent from the Samsung watch.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Extensive experience with Apple Watch since its 2014 launch.</li>
  <li>Amazed at the absence of the digital crown in the Galaxy Watch Ultra after trying it for just 10 minutes.</li>
  <li>Notes functionality differences between the Apple Watch and Samsung Galaxy Watch Ultra, particularly in outdoor and activity settings.</li>
  <li>Recommends that future versions of Samsung watches include a digital crown for improved user experience.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The lack of a digital crown has made me question everything I thought I knew about smartwatches."</blockquote>
<p>The Galaxy Watch Ultra is a strong contender in the smartwatch market but its missing digital crown poses a significant usability issue for those coming from Apple devices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techradar.com/health-fitness/smartwatches/ive-spent-10-years-with-apple-watch-and-after-10-minutes-with-the-galaxy-watch-ultra-i-cant-believe-samsung-skipped-this-feature</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techradar.com/health-fitness/smartwatches/ive-spent-10-years-with-apple-watch-and-after-10-minutes-with-the-galaxy-watch-ultra-i-cant-believe-samsung-skipped-this-feature</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 07:00:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Galaxy S25 Ultra: Everything we know so far about Samsung’s next flagship smartphone - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Galaxy S25 Ultra: Everything We Know So Far About Samsung’s Next Flagship Smartphone</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 19, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra.jpg" alt="Galaxy S25 Ultra"><figcaption>Galaxy S25 Ultra offers a 6.9-inch screen. (Image credit: Android Headlines)</figcaption><p>The Galaxy S25 Ultra is set to launch on January 22, 2025, and is rumored to feature incremental updates over its predecessor, including a new ultra-wide camera and a powerful processor.</p><ul><li>Maintains similar design with minor tweaks, including a boxier shape and improved brightness on a 6.9-inch display.</li><li>Quad-camera setup with upgraded 50 MP ultra-wide lens; retains 200 MP primary and 10 MP telephoto lenses.</li><li>Powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite, with options for up to 1 TB storage and 12 GB RAM.</li><li>Ships with Android 15-based OneUI 7 and promises seven years of updates.</li><li>Includes a 5,000 mAh battery with 45W fast charging.</li><li>Expected pricing between Rs 1,20,000 to Rs 1,30,000.</li></ul><blockquote>"Samsung seems to be playing it safe when it comes to battery and fast charging."</blockquote><p>The Galaxy S25 Ultra is poised to be a strong contender in the premium smartphone market, building on the solid foundation of its forerunners.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-features-specs-price-launch-9774373/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-features-specs-price-launch-9774373/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 06:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple MacBook users at risk: New malware threatens 100 million devices - how it spreads | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/apple-macbook-users-at-risk-new-malware-threatens-100-million-devices-how-it-spreads-11736653329432.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/apple-macbook-users-at-risk-new-malware-threatens-100-million-devices-how-it-spreads-11736653329432.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 05:37:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xiaomi Pad 7 with Snapdragon 7+ Gen 3 chipset, HyperOS 2 launched in India: Price, specs - Kalinga TV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Xiaomi Pad 7 with Snapdragon 7+ Gen 3 chipset, HyperOS 2 launched in India: Price, specs</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Kalinga TV</p><p>The Xiaomi Pad 7 has been launched in India at a starting price of Rs 27,999, featuring an 11.2-inch display, Snapdragon 7+ Gen 3 processor, and an 8,850mAh battery.</p><h4>Key Points:</h4><ul><li>Starting price is Rs 27,999 for 8GB + 128GB, Rs 30,999 for 12GB + 256GB.</li><li>The tablet features a 3.2K LCD with 144Hz refresh rate and HDR10 support.</li><li>Equipped with a Snapdragon 7+ Gen 3 chip and Android 15-based HyperOS 2.0.</li><li>Camera setup includes a 13MP rear and 8MP ultrawide front camera.</li><li>Available from January 13 via Amazon and Xiaomi stores.</li></ul><blockquote>“Customers can get a Rs 1,000 discount through ICICI Bank card holders.”</blockquote><p>The Xiaomi Pad 7 offers exciting specifications and competitive pricing, aiming to attract consumers looking for high-performance tablets in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://kalingatv.com/technology/xiaomi-pad-7-with-snapdragon-7-gen-3-chipset-hyperos-2-launched-in-india-price-specs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kalingatv.com/technology/xiaomi-pad-7-with-snapdragon-7-gen-3-chipset-hyperos-2-launched-in-india-price-specs/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 05:29:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX Redeem Codes for January 12: Unlock free crate, parachute and more - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX Redeem Codes for January 12: Unlock free crate, parachute and more</h1><p><strong>Date: January 12, 2025</strong><br><strong>Source: India TV News</strong></p><figure><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/free-fire-max-redeem-codes-1736658756.webp" alt="Free Fire Max" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Free Fire Max</figcaption></figure><p>New redeem codes for Garena Free Fire Max are now available, allowing players to acquire various in-game cosmetic items for free. Players should quickly utilize these codes as they are limited and specific to certain regions.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Redeem codes for January 12, 2025 include: MN3XK4TY9EP1, UPQ7X5NMJ64V, V44ZX8Y7GJ52, XN7TP5RM3K49, ZRW3J4N8VX56, TFX9J3Z2RP64, RD3TZK7WME65, F8YC4TN6VKQ9, WD4XJ7WQZ42A, HZ2RM8VW9TP7, JF6AT3ZREM45, KFN9Y6XW4Z89.</li><li>Players can redeem these codes for loot crates, diamond vouchers, and unique parachutes.</li><li>Instructions for redeeming codes include visiting the code redemption website and logging into your Free Fire account.</li><li>The original Free Fire was banned in India; however, Free Fire Max remains available.</li><li>Players are eagerly anticipating updates regarding the game's return in India.</li></ul><p><strong>Note:</strong> The redeem codes are valid only for a limited time and specific regions. Usage of expired or location-inappropriate codes may result in errors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-january-12-unlock-free-crate-parachute-and-more-2025-01-12-970850</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-january-12-unlock-free-crate-parachute-and-more-2025-01-12-970850</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 05:21:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for January 12, 2024: Win free gifts and rewards daily - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for January 12, 2024: Win free gifts and rewards daily</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250112045133_eb1df6b57997fec0c4ec81648e744db2.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Garena Free Fire Max" title="Garena Free Fire Max" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>Garena Free Fire Max</figcaption>
<p>Garena Free Fire MAX has quickly become a popular choice among gamers in India following the ban of its predecessor. Players can unlock special redeem codes daily for exclusive rewards including skins, weapons, and diamonds.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Game offers daily redeem codes for exclusive rewards.</li>
  <li>Redemption is limited to 500 players per day.</li>
  <li>Rewards are time-sensitive, typically available for 12 to 18 hours.</li>
  <li>Game known for its impressive visuals and engaging gameplay.</li>
  <li>Enhances the gaming experience for both new and seasoned players.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“With its time-sensitive rewards and captivating universe, Garena Free Fire MAX remains highly popular among gamers.”</blockquote>
<p>The daily redeem codes provide an exciting way for players to enhance their gameplay and keep the community engaged.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-january-12-2024-win-free-gifts-and-rewards-daily-article-12908208.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-january-12-2024-win-free-gifts-and-rewards-daily-article-12908208.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 04:52:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive! Gashmeer Mahajani says he is not 'desperate' to crack Hindi movies - TOI Etimes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Exclusive! Gashmeer Mahajani says he is not 'desperate' to crack Hindi movies</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117148488,imgsize-1390952,width-400,resizemode-4/117148488.jpg' alt='Gashmeer Mahajani' decoding='async' fetchpriority='high'><figcaption>Gashmeer Mahajani</figcaption><p>Gashmeer Mahajani, a popular Marathi actor, expresses that he is not in a rush to enter Bollywood. He is content with his existing audience in Maharashtra and is waiting for the right Hindi project.</p><ul><li>Gashmeer is focused on his work in Marathi films and OTT shows.</li><li>He emphasizes the importance of timing in his career decisions.</li><li>He does not view himself as a typical television actor and has limited his exposure.</li><li>While he remains open to television, he prefers longer commitments of 80 to 100 episodes.</li><li>He mentions a missed opportunity in the show Katha Ankahee, which he feels would have suited him well.</li></ul><blockquote>“You can’t rush into things; you have to wait for the right time.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Gashmeer Mahajani is taking a strategic approach to his career, prioritizing quality over quantity in his projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/gashmeer-mahajani-reflects-on-losing-katha-ankahee-role-i-could-have-nailed-it/articleshow/117148105.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/gashmeer-mahajani-reflects-on-losing-katha-ankahee-role-i-could-have-nailed-it/articleshow/117148105.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 04:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Unpacked 2025 on January 22: Galaxy S25 price is… - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Unpacked 2025 on January 22: Galaxy S25 Price Revealed</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 22, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<p>Samsung has officially announced its Galaxy Unpacked event, set to launch the Galaxy S25 series, which includes the Galaxy S25, S25+, and S25 Ultra, with potential new variants.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Galaxy S25</strong>: Starting at €964 for 128GB, with prices for 256GB and 512GB at €1,026 and €1,151, respectively.</li>
<li><strong>Galaxy S25+</strong>: Begins at €1,235 for 256GB and goes up to €1,359 for 512GB.</li>
<li><strong>Galaxy S25 Ultra</strong>: Expected to start at €1,557, with the 1TB variant potentially at €1,930.</li>
</ul>
<p>Storage options include 128GB, 256GB, and 512GB for Galaxy S25 models, with the Ultra variant possibly offering up to 1TB. Aesthetic choices range from icy blue to titanium finishes.</p>
<blockquote>“Pre-reservations for the Galaxy S25 series have commenced in India, offering early buyers exclusive benefits worth ₹5,000.”</blockquote>
<p>This event is highly anticipated as Samsung prepares to unveil its latest innovations and flagship devices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tech.hindustantimes.com/tech/news/samsung-unpacked-2025-on-january-22-galaxy-s25-price-is-71736655398975.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tech.hindustantimes.com/tech/news/samsung-unpacked-2025-on-january-22-galaxy-s25-price-is-71736655398975.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 04:26:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire Max redeem codes for January 12: Rewards for today are free diamonds, gun skins, and mor - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire Max redeem codes for January 12: Rewards for today are free diamonds, gun skins, and more</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Garena</p><p>Today’s redeem codes for Garena Free Fire Max provide players with a chance to earn free diamonds, exclusive gun skins, and additional in-game rewards. The available codes are limited and players are encouraged to redeem them quickly.</p><ul><li>Players can access the redeem codes by entering them in the rewards section.</li><li>The rewards include various in-game items that enhance gameplay.</li><li>Diamonds are a premium currency in the game and are highly sought after.</li></ul><blockquote>“These codes give players an opportunity to collect rare items that can significantly improve their gaming experience.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, players should make sure to redeem these codes promptly to enjoy the benefits of the rewards offered today.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-january-12-rewards-for-today-are-free-diamonds-gun-skins-and-more/articleshow/117165003.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-january-12-rewards-for-today-are-free-diamonds-gun-skins-and-more/articleshow/117165003.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 03:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus 13 vs iPhone 16 Plus: Which premium phone wins? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus 13 vs iPhone 16 Plus: Which premium phone wins?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<p>In this article, we compare the OnePlus 13 and the iPhone 16 Plus, focusing on key differences in design, display, software, camera capabilities, and performance to determine which premium smartphone may be the better choice for consumers.</p>
<ul>
<li>The iPhone 16 Plus features a more subtle design with frosted glass, while the OnePlus 13 offers a faux vegan leather option.</li>
<li>The OnePlus 13 boasts a 6.82-inch AMOLED display with a 120Hz refresh rate, compared to the iPhone 16 Plus’s 6.7-inch OLED display at 60Hz.</li>
<li>Both devices have IP ratings for water and dust resistance, but the OnePlus 13 has a higher IP69 rating.</li>
<li>Software-wise, iOS 18 offers extensive AI features compared to OxygenOS 15, though the latter allows app sideloading.</li>
<li>The camera setup on the OnePlus 13 includes a 50MP primary camera and a telephoto lens, while the iPhone 16 Plus sports a 48MP primary camera.</li>
<li>Battery performance favors the OnePlus 13 with a 6,000mAh capacity versus the iPhone 16 Plus’s smaller capacity and slower charging speed.</li>
<li>The OnePlus device is deemed superior in hardware specifications, including battery life and display smoothness.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>When comparing the hardware, the OnePlus 13 is the clear winner with its smoother screen, bigger battery, and more capable camera system.</blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, the choice between the OnePlus 13 and the iPhone 16 Plus depends on personal preference for operating systems and specific features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/oneplus-13-vs-apple-iphone-16-plus-design-display-camera-battery-9773523/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/oneplus-13-vs-apple-iphone-16-plus-design-display-camera-battery-9773523/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 03:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>