<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:31:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 13:31:07 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Huawei dethrones Apple as new king of the smartwatch market, report says - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Huawei surpasses Apple in smartwatch sales, capturing market leadership with advanced models</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p>
<img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/facetime.png?w=300" alt="Apple users report iMessage and FaceTime issues, issue now fixed" />
<figcaption>Apple unveils 2024 App Store awards: Here are the year’s best apps and games</figcaption>
<p>Till now, Apple had been ruling the technology market with its long list of products. However, recent reports reveal that Huawei has overtaken the smartwatch market, which was previously dominated by Apple.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Huawei has claimed the ‘best smartwatch’ award from Apple according to IDC.</li>
  <li>The company sold the most smartwatches during the first nine months of the year.</li>
  <li>New models like the GT5 and GT5 Pro feature advanced health-tracking capabilities.</li>
  <li>Huawei’s strategy includes catering to local markets across regions like Asia-Pacific and Latin America.</li>
  <li>China has seen a 20% increase in wrist-worn device shipments in 2024, indicating growing consumer interest.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Chinese consumers are quite interested in fitness bands and smartwatches, driven by stylish designs and health tracking features.”</blockquote>
<p>The market changes pose a significant challenge to traditional leaders like Apple, while other brands like Samsung and Xiaomi also expand their consumer bases with competitive products.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-huawei-dethrones-apple-as-new-king-of-the-smartwatch-market-report-saysnbsp-3695682/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-huawei-dethrones-apple-as-new-king-of-the-smartwatch-market-report-saysnbsp-3695682/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:50:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From CMF Phone 1 to Galaxy M15: Budget smartphones that made an impact in 2024 - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>From CMF Phone 1 to Galaxy M15: Noteworthy Budget Smartphones of 2024</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p> <img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/hmd-fusion-3.jpeg" alt="HMD Fusion review"> <figcaption>HMD Fusion is compatible with open source accessories. (Image credit: Anuj Bhatia/The Indian Express)</figcaption> <p>2024 has been remarkable for smartphone enthusiasts, particularly first-time buyers. Despite budget smartphones typically lacking innovation, this year has seen significant advancements, particularly in the Rs 15,000 price range.</p> <ul> <li>Demand for budget smartphones is rising alongside the interest in affordable 5G devices.</li> <li>Notable models include the <strong>CMF Phone 1</strong> for Rs 14,999, and the <strong>Samsung Galaxy M15 5G Prime Edition</strong> for Rs 11,999.</li> <li>Innovative designs and modular compatibility were highlighted, especially with the <strong>HMD Fusion</strong>.</li> <li>Most budget smartphones now offer at least 128 GB internal storage, and include expansions like microSD.</li> <li>Samsung stands out with its commitment to software updates: four major OS upgrades and five years of security updates.</li> </ul> <blockquote>"With more feature phone users upgrading to smartphones, it is important to have a strong lineup of budget smartphones."</blockquote> <p>The 2024 budget smartphone market offered a variety of choices, signaling shifting trends in affordability and technological capability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/best-budget-smartphones-of-2024-9734205/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/mobile-tabs/best-budget-smartphones-of-2024-9734205/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:22:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech News Today Live Updates on December 19, 2024: iPhone 16 now features Genmoji and Image Playground AI tools with iOS 18.2: How to get started | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tech News Today Live Updates on December 19, 2024: Elon Musk calls hashtags ‘Unnecessary and Ugly,’ here's how users react</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 19 Dec, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> LiveMint</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2024/12/19/600x338/USA-COURT-MUSK-SEC-0_1702211508903_1734612528656.JPG" alt="Tech News Today Live Updates: Elon Musk calls hashtags ‘Unnecessary and Ugly,’ here's how users react (AFP)">
  <figcaption>Tech News Today Live Updates: Elon Musk calls hashtags ‘Unnecessary and Ugly,’ here's how users react <strong>(AFP)</strong></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Elon Musk's recent comments labeling hashtags as 'unnecessary and ugly' have sparked diverse reactions across social media, highlighting the ongoing debate regarding their relevance and utility.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Musk's statement prompted a range of responses, with some users agreeing and others defending the role of hashtags in organizing content.</li>
  <li>The discussion touches upon broader themes of social media communication and user engagement.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Hashtags are both necessary and ugly. They help in organizing content but can clutter conversations." - User comment</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing debate reflects the evolving discourse surrounding social media and user interaction, emphasizing the different perspectives on how technology shapes communication.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/latest-technology-news-today-on-december-19-2024-live-updates-11734595067157.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/latest-technology-news-today-on-december-19-2024-live-updates-11734595067157.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:21:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sennheiser launches Profile Wireless, a wireless microphone system for creators - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sennheiser launches Profile Wireless, a wireless microphone system for creators</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Sennheiser-Profile-Wireless.png?w=640" alt="Sennheiser Profile Wireless will be available next year." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Sennheiser Profile Wireless will be available next year. (Image Source: Sennheiser)</figcaption><p>Sennheiser has introduced the Profile Wireless, a versatile wireless microphone system designed for creators and videographers, featuring multiple connectivity options.</p><ul><li>Profile Wireless can be used as a clip-on mic or in handheld and tabletop modes.</li><li>The two-channel system easily connects to mobile phones, computers, and cameras.</li><li>Includes a multifunctional charging bar that stores and charges pre-paired mics with an OLED display.</li><li>Offers a range of up to 245 meters with 16GB onboard storage for 30 hours of audio recording.</li><li>Backup Recording Mode automatically activates under weak Wi-Fi signals.</li><li>Launch price is Rs 29,900 and availability is set for next year.</li></ul><blockquote>“Profile Wireless connects using a 2.4GHz network and has an integrated handheld option with a battery life of 15 hours.”</blockquote><p>Sennheiser's Profile Wireless represents a significant development in wireless audio technology for content creators, providing innovative features for improved recording quality and functionality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/gadgets/sennheiser-profile-wireless-microphone-system-creators-videographers-9734360/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/gadgets/sennheiser-profile-wireless-microphone-system-creators-videographers-9734360/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 12:02:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sennheiser launches Profile Wireless 2.4 GHz microphone system for content creators: Details - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxOTUc0QXRRQmUzV01aUS0zclFxRTBMN0lwN0R2bmRNZjgwUktnbG1TOHREU2dCUkh0VXRXUmlVX29SOUdFX0ZVczVFSmRRMnE4c0Rqcmo3ZzlIOXQxMFRpaTgtZGJrc3BPdkJST3U0eENWek5ObmpFM2FWb2NhcHgwQncyZ1VPWmtjY1hGZjFWakVGTDl0NlJjTEJVT05OVVphUzNod2V4VnozbGh5MWJGWlJMbnVnMXU1dTlYNkJwTkJQbktnT2tBdldNRkxOR0RVZFplSWJDSC1CaUVLN2JsMGhmMNIB6gFBVV95cUxQelN1cWF6ekloeGVUc1I2MnhyVDZWTHdBeGNYRHJHeFprM3dSRUJidEJHR3BDblotNERFaGN3OXFUdW9JLVlmV3ZGcnBEOGxTNmd2MTYzUWpCZGdnS2xlck1UOVZvNTR3WV9tYTVQcHlDZUoxYnRtUDlBejlXVUhDWkRnSDZENDJSR3J2R3BMR3dmbGYxVjNGdVJjdWlDYWNVSW50cHlianJucW03SnRWcllxSkJibzFhNGUwT3RjR25tUTdWSlZHQm10YzRPVVhTMTNZVzEwc1MxVGRHbENCbzZBUTRBZFVfbVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4wFBVV95cUxOTUc0QXRRQmUzV01aUS0zclFxRTBMN0lwN0R2bmRNZjgwUktnbG1TOHREU2dCUkh0VXRXUmlVX29SOUdFX0ZVczVFSmRRMnE4c0Rqcmo3ZzlIOXQxMFRpaTgtZGJrc3BPdkJST3U0eENWek5ObmpFM2FWb2NhcHgwQncyZ1VPWmtjY1hGZjFWakVGTDl0NlJjTEJVT05OVVphUzNod2V4VnozbGh5MWJGWlJMbnVnMXU1dTlYNkJwTkJQbktnT2tBdldNRkxOR0RVZFplSWJDSC1CaUVLN2JsMGhmMNIB6gFBVV95cUxQelN1cWF6ekloeGVUc1I2MnhyVDZWTHdBeGNYRHJHeFprM3dSRUJidEJHR3BDblotNERFaGN3OXFUdW9JLVlmV3ZGcnBEOGxTNmd2MTYzUWpCZGdnS2xlck1UOVZvNTR3WV9tYTVQcHlDZUoxYnRtUDlBejlXVUhDWkRnSDZENDJSR3J2R3BMR3dmbGYxVjNGdVJjdWlDYWNVSW50cHlianJucW03SnRWcllxSkJibzFhNGUwT3RjR25tUTdWSlZHQm10YzRPVVhTMTNZVzEwc1MxVGRHbENCbzZBUTRBZFVfbVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:58:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Game changer’: Instagram influencer reveals secret to ‘automatic weight loss’ | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Game changer’: Instagram influencer reveals secret to ‘automatic weight loss’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Leana, an Instagram influencer, shares her weight loss journey and diet tips, focusing on replacing refined sugars with natural sugar options.</p><ul><li>Leana lost over 7 kg in 2 months by following a diet rich in natural sugar.</li><li>She emphasizes that reducing refined sugar can keep one full and decrease hunger pangs.</li><li>Leana encourages striving for “progress, not perfection” in dietary habits.</li><li>Switching to natural sugars can help break sugar addiction.</li><li>Focus on better eating will resolve many health issues.</li></ul><blockquote>“Replacing refined sugar with natural options like fruits is a game-changer and will help you lose weight right away.” - Leana</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Leana’s advice on dietary adjustments highlights the importance of mindful eating for effective weight loss.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/game-changer-instagram-influencer-shares-secret-to-automatic-weight-loss-diet-on-social-media-11734604785141.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/game-changer-instagram-influencer-shares-secret-to-automatic-weight-loss-diet-on-social-media-11734604785141.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:50:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 best gaming phones you can buy in India from iQOO, Realme, Apple, and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Best Gaming Phones You Can Buy in India from iQOO, Realme, Apple, and More</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/iqoo_13_price_in_india_1733121300333_1734608017683.png" alt="iQOO 13 is the cheapest Snapdragon 8 Elite-powered phone in India.(IQOO)" title="iQOO 13 is the cheapest Snapdragon 8 Elite-powered phone in India.(IQOO)">
<figcaption>iQOO 13 is the cheapest Snapdragon 8 Elite-powered phone in India.(IQOO)</figcaption>
<p>This article presents a curated list of the top gaming-centric smartphones available in India, showcasing options across various price points, ensuring a smooth gaming experience.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>iQOO 13:</strong> Priced at ₹55,000, featuring Snapdragon 8 Elite and 144Hz display.</li>
<li><strong>Realme GT7 Pro:</strong> Priced at ₹59,999, also powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite.</li>
<li><strong>iPhone 16 Pro:</strong> Features Apple A18 chip; excellent for AAA games.</li>
<li><strong>iPhone 16:</strong> Similar performance as 16 Pro at ₹79,900.</li>
<li><strong>Vivo X200:</strong> MediaTek Dimensity 9400 chip, priced around ₹65,000.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The iQOO 13 is the cheapest phone with the Snapdragon 8 Elite in India, making it great value for money.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, whether you're a hardcore gamer or someone looking for a versatile smartphone, this list offers impressive choices for every budget.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/5-best-gaming-phones-you-can-buy-in-india-from-iqoo-realme-apple-and-more-101734607919347.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/5-best-gaming-phones-you-can-buy-in-india-from-iqoo-realme-apple-and-more-101734607919347.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:41:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung's Galaxy S25 5G launch date revealed, set to debut in early 2025 - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung's Galaxy S25 5G Launch Date Revealed for Early 2025</h1><p><strong>Date: December 19, 2024 | Source: India TV News</strong></p><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-1-1734606625.webp" alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 5G" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S24 5G (Representational image)</figcaption><p>Exciting news for Samsung enthusiasts! The company is set to launch the Galaxy S25 5G Series, with significant updates regarding its debut date, which might be on January 22, 2025.</p><ul><li>The Samsung Galaxy S25 series is expected to include three models: Galaxy S25, Galaxy S25+, and Galaxy S25 Ultra.</li><li>Leaked information suggests the Samsung Galaxy Unpacked event is likely to occur in San Jose, California.</li><li>The base model's price might start around Rs 67,000, with the Galaxy S25+ at approximately Rs 84,300, and the Ultra variant expected to start at Rs 1,09,600.</li><li>Expected upgrades in the camera department promise enhanced photography experiences.</li></ul><blockquote>“If these leaks hold true, the event is likely to take place in San Jose, California.”</blockquote><p>The Galaxy S25 series is generating significant anticipation, and its potential innovations are likely to impact the smartphone market positively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/samsung-s-galaxy-s25-5g-launch-date-revealed-set-to-debut-in-early-2025-2024-12-19-967037</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/samsung-s-galaxy-s25-5g-launch-date-revealed-set-to-debut-in-early-2025-2024-12-19-967037</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:14:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Features To Look For In A Smartwatch - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Features To Look For In A Smartwatch</h1>
<p><strong>Published by: NDTV</strong></p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/gws/ms/7-features-to-look-for-in-a-smartwatch/assets/14.jpeg?1734605404" alt="Must-Have Pieces For Every Woman">
<figcaption>Image Credit: Pexels</figcaption>
<p>This article outlines essential features to consider when purchasing a smartwatch, focusing on health monitoring, activity tracking, and connectivity.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Heart Rate Monitor:</strong> Essential for fitness and wellness enthusiasts.</li>
<li><strong>Step Counter:</strong> Helps monitor daily activity.</li>
<li><strong>Sleep Tracker:</strong> Provides insights into sleep quality and patterns.</li>
<li><strong>Water Resistance:</strong> Important for durability in wet conditions.</li>
<li><strong>GPS Tracking:</strong> Aids in navigation during outdoor activities.</li>
<li><strong>Notification Alerts:</strong> Keeps you connected to calls and messages.</li>
<li><strong>Battery Life:</strong> Critical for maintaining usability over lengthy periods.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Click to invest in these fashion essentials and unlock a world of style possibilities"</blockquote>
<p>Choosing the right smartwatch involves evaluating various essential features to enhance the user experience and connectivity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/shopping/webstories/7-features-to-look-for-in-a-smartwatch-29380</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/shopping/webstories/7-features-to-look-for-in-a-smartwatch-29380</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:06:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI brings ChatGPT bot to WhatsApp - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OpenAI brings ChatGPT bot to WhatsApp</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 19 December 2024, 10:52 IST</p><p>After launching Sora AI video generator, OpenAI has announced that the ChatGPT bot will now be available on Meta's WhatsApp messenger app, but only for users in the US and Canada.</p><img src='https://www.deccanherald.com/image.jpg' alt='ChatGPT on WhatsApp'><figcaption>ChatGPT interface on WhatsApp</figcaption><p>The ChatGPT bot will allow users to interact for 15 minutes per month via a designated number. Conversations will be stored for safety measures, and the company reserves the right to block users for inappropriate behavior.</p><ul><li>The ChatGPT bot is currently available only in the US and Canada.</li><li>Users can access ChatGPT by messaging the number 1-800-242-8478.</li><li>Interaction is limited to text messages without image chatting capabilities.</li><li>OpenAI has also launched a new tool called Canvas AI aimed at software developers.</li></ul><blockquote>"Users can chat with ChatGPT on WhatsApp to access ChatGPT." - Kevin Wei, Chief Product Officer at OpenAI</blockquote><p>This integration offers a new way for users to experience AI interactions, although it is currently in a pilot phase with limited access.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/technology/openai-brings-chatgpt-bot-to-whatsapp-3324755</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/technology/openai-brings-chatgpt-bot-to-whatsapp-3324755</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 10:52:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google releases second developer preview of Android 16: Check new features - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/google-releases-second-developer-preview-of-android-16-check-new-features-124121900802_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/google-releases-second-developer-preview-of-android-16-check-new-features-124121900802_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 10:37:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Realme 14x 5G vs Poco M7 Pro 5G: Which smartphone to buy under Rs.15000 - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/realme-14x-5g-vs-poco-m7-pro-5g-which-smartphone-to-buy-under-rs15000-11734603623678.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/realme-14x-5g-vs-poco-m7-pro-5g-which-smartphone-to-buy-under-rs15000-11734603623678.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 10:24:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flipkart's new sale starts tonight with huge discounts on smartphones, including iPhones - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Flipkart's New Sale Tonight: Huge Discounts on Smartphones Including iPhones</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p> <p><strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p> <img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/flipkart-sale-1-1734603025.webp" alt="Flipkart sale" width="1200" height="675"> <figcaption>Flipkart sale</figcaption> <p>A new sale is set to kick off on Flipkart from tonight (December 20). During this year-end sale, shoppers can expect attractive discounts on smartphones including the iPhone, along with popular brands like Vivo, Nothing, and Realme. The sale runs until December 25.</p> <ul> <li>Discounts available on smartphones, gadgets, electronics, and home appliances.</li> <li>Smartwatches starting at just Rs 999.</li> <li>Up to 70% off on mobile accessories such as chargers and cables.</li> <li>Wishlist smartphones highlighted include iPhone 15 Plus, Nothing CMF Phone 1, Vivo T3 Pro 5G, and POCO M6 5G.</li> <li>Upcoming discounted offers on home appliances like refrigerators, geysers, and washing machines.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“This indicates that these devices will see the steepest discounts during the sale.”</blockquote> <p>Customers should prepare for exciting offers on a wide range of products.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/flipkart-s-new-sale-starts-tonight-with-huge-discounts-on-smartphones-including-iphones-2024-12-19-967023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/flipkart-s-new-sale-starts-tonight-with-huge-discounts-on-smartphones-including-iphones-2024-12-19-967023</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 10:11:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Realme 14 Pro+ showcased with a cold-sensitive color-changing panel - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxOVDNhV0d5dGVxVXM1aThFLWM1dVVycjAxUkRzQmx5MEhvNU1fTE1Jc3paOEdpenRRMndOSzRPRWJMUUFIdGlHbVlmOC04dzZhaHhXc1JIRG52eFdUcHl4REt4TldZT1lRQ2pMVFBTV21ZUDBoWlY5OGI0TjE2akZndTdPNEJlU2VYUTRWMS1vOW5hYXBwa1NxaHhqUUtEWWg2WXdqamM3Qi3SAaQBQVVfeXFMTlFBWllOeUlYUTNNNFZKRzJoakJDUXN5bDNocDZsOVFCdjUxN25DUXBCX3hPZFlRcWhWbUFuN1h5Mk9rWmpFMjA4dF9leW1XTFB2c2kwN3NLdDFEWXdYTlVPbFFYM2FZdWNzN1A3WHRHS1praktSRDBzMjRCak9XTXRodGtzZUkwRVl0RUlxYzVYMktTS3Z1X2pZbHFwSmxvakJBYTA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxOVDNhV0d5dGVxVXM1aThFLWM1dVVycjAxUkRzQmx5MEhvNU1fTE1Jc3paOEdpenRRMndOSzRPRWJMUUFIdGlHbVlmOC04dzZhaHhXc1JIRG52eFdUcHl4REt4TldZT1lRQ2pMVFBTV21ZUDBoWlY5OGI0TjE2akZndTdPNEJlU2VYUTRWMS1vOW5hYXBwa1NxaHhqUUtEWWg2WXdqamM3Qi3SAaQBQVVfeXFMTlFBWllOeUlYUTNNNFZKRzJoakJDUXN5bDNocDZsOVFCdjUxN25DUXBCX3hPZFlRcWhWbUFuN1h5Mk9rWmpFMjA4dF9leW1XTFB2c2kwN3NLdDFEWXdYTlVPbFFYM2FZdWNzN1A3WHRHS1praktSRDBzMjRCak9XTXRodGtzZUkwRVl0RUlxYzVYMktTS3Z1X2pZbHFwSmxvakJBYTA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 10:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sennheiser launches creators-focused Profile Wireless microphones in India - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/sennheiser-launches-creators-focused-profile-wireless-microphones-in-india-124121900645_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/sennheiser-launches-creators-focused-profile-wireless-microphones-in-india-124121900645_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 09:16:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple faults Meta for interoperability requests | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNdjE1Y3pDWEJIZEwtQzFOalZtS3QwM25rMFFoeDM5VHpvNmFLbW9tOFh1Y2QwT1lPR1ZiRTNiMnhvS3k0akdGVmN5TDBCaVRISXFucjRUeDU4SFlvTllmakd1STZwX191andFVUJ3YTJ0WW50YmttQ0prYUpkZkF4TzFDV25SWFFxLV9VYmV1QTh6aFM5UHRMQzdTS0ptSnUwUWJ4SlNaNm9MNVXSAbABQVVfeXFMUHFoOWZNeDVQNHRvbURwUHlEZVJIc1dPTFBTQVJ3SDR3Q01xTTlLSXRpaWhFZGlVVHhYQm85UERZcW5sN2ZXenJvWVFSWTNWMGZaTmJMRWJHOU9qVkZBcjlvemJvMEZlbHd0d1dXOXpCMmthb0g0NmliWlZtMmJ6NE1rWFc4aUttNHJsa0tNN1dmWVc0QVQxUWFCRXZtWEd4U2NrdDhvZFpKRmE1a1c3b2I?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqwFBVV95cUxNdjE1Y3pDWEJIZEwtQzFOalZtS3QwM25rMFFoeDM5VHpvNmFLbW9tOFh1Y2QwT1lPR1ZiRTNiMnhvS3k0akdGVmN5TDBCaVRISXFucjRUeDU4SFlvTllmakd1STZwX191andFVUJ3YTJ0WW50YmttQ0prYUpkZkF4TzFDV25SWFFxLV9VYmV1QTh6aFM5UHRMQzdTS0ptSnUwUWJ4SlNaNm9MNVXSAbABQVVfeXFMUHFoOWZNeDVQNHRvbURwUHlEZVJIc1dPTFBTQVJ3SDR3Q01xTTlLSXRpaWhFZGlVVHhYQm85UERZcW5sN2ZXenJvWVFSWTNWMGZaTmJMRWJHOU9qVkZBcjlvemJvMEZlbHd0d1dXOXpCMmthb0g0NmliWlZtMmJ6NE1rWFc4aUttNHJsa0tNN1dmWVc0QVQxUWFCRXZtWEd4U2NrdDhvZFpKRmE1a1c3b2I?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 09:12:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phone launches in upcoming weeks: OnePlus 13, Samsung Galaxy S25 series, more to look forward - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Phone launches in upcoming weeks: OnePlus 13, Samsung Galaxy S25 series, more to look forward</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 <strong>by:</strong> Aishwarya Panda</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/5_170806_1731403094958_1734598146786.jpg" alt="Check out the phone launches in the coming weeks from top smartphone brands. (HT Tech )" title="Check out the phone launches in the coming weeks from top smartphone brands. (HT Tech )">
<figcaption>Check out the phone launches in the coming weeks from top smartphone brands. (HT Tech )</figcaption>
<p>The smartphone market is buzzing with upcoming launches including the OnePlus 13 series and Samsung Galaxy S25 series. As 2025 approaches, consumers can expect major announcements from these brands regarding their next-generation models.</p>
<h2><strong>Key Points</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>OnePlus 13 series:</strong> Launching on January 7, 2025, with Snapdragon 8 Elite and Snapdragon 8 Gen 3 processors.</li>
<li><strong>Samsung Galaxy S25 series:</strong> Expected global debut on January 22, featuring three models powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite chip.</li>
<li><strong>Asus ROG Phone 9:</strong> Launched globally but debuting in India in 2025, also featuring Snapdragon 8 Elite.</li>
<li><strong>Xiaomi 15 series:</strong> Anticipated flagship series powered by Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>The upcoming weeks will see exciting launches in the smartphone market, providing great options for consumers looking to upgrade.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/phone-launches-in-upcoming-weeks-oneplus-13-samsung-galaxy-s25-series-more-to-look-forward-101734597926014.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/phone-launches-in-upcoming-weeks-oneplus-13-samsung-galaxy-s25-series-more-to-look-forward-101734597926014.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:53:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vivo X200, Vivo X200 Pro goes on sale in India: Check price, specs and more - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/vivo-x200-vivo-x200-pro-goes-on-sale-in-india-check-price-specs-and-more-article-12893887.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/vivo-x200-vivo-x200-pro-goes-on-sale-in-india-check-price-specs-and-more-article-12893887.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:48:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Veo 2 Unveiled: Google’s Cinematic Leap in AI Video Generation - YourStory]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxNb2VIaU8tUU44QXpBelpYZlJrbUF4N25LYXBlbG1xczljZmRDZXZDMFphLU9DcGFyZmFJM3RQbFIyZzc3a0JMOWliRWY2cXlPNEY3a24zNms2ZERqVkR1a3ByN0pVWm9mVXN4UzNrWjh2V08xUkJoT2tuWkh2aXF2N1BubmVsSlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxNb2VIaU8tUU44QXpBelpYZlJrbUF4N25LYXBlbG1xczljZmRDZXZDMFphLU9DcGFyZmFJM3RQbFIyZzc3a0JMOWliRWY2cXlPNEY3a24zNms2ZERqVkR1a3ByN0pVWm9mVXN4UzNrWjh2V08xUkJoT2tuWkh2aXF2N1BubmVsSlE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:07:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra price cut on Amazon—How to buy it with a ₹38,000 discount - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra price cut on Amazon—How to buy it with a ₹38,000 discount</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 19, 2024 | <strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/5_170806_1731403094958_1734594855228.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra has been discounted on Amazon India.(HT Tech)" title="Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra has been discounted on Amazon India.(HT Tech)"><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra has been discounted on Amazon India.(HT Tech)</figcaption><p>This article discusses the significant price drop of the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra, which is now available for ₹91,010, offering a discount of ₹38,989 from its original launch price.</p><ul><li>The Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra's price has dropped to ₹95,800 on Amazon India.</li><li>With an Amazon ICICI credit card, the effective price can be brought down to ₹91,010 after cashback.</li><li>Samsung phones typically do not see significant price drops post-launch of a new flagship.</li><li>The S24 Ultra retains value well, likely maintaining a price of around ₹70,000 to ₹80,000 in the future.</li></ul><blockquote>“Samsung phones rarely drop in price after a new flagship is launched.”</blockquote><p>In summary, the Samsung Galaxy S24 Ultra is currently a great buy for anyone looking for a flagship phone at a significantly reduced price as it continues to provide value even with the upcoming S25 series launch.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-price-cut-on-amazon-how-to-buy-it-with-a-rs-38-000-discount-101734594534763.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-price-cut-on-amazon-how-to-buy-it-with-a-rs-38-000-discount-101734594534763.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:06:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poco M7 Pro 5G Launched in India: Features, Specifications, and Price - The Quint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOY2ZxVEJyUW9Wcjd5TWN6c00yekp5UWJ3bE9OSmFLMHpQaExfTENJZC0xbXBRZmFpX2ZmMldnMURxYVNPYi1yRFZxQlBCa0p3ZFdHNDJ4Wk1tYlJpNmN0eDljUHc5R0FiZmlsZDV2c3BGemxWTnhkSUNRb3lpWW1ybXNDeHZUNHNCbS1GenlQY21IaDNoOUZWaGNvMFZKSlptTFpfaXVvRzNuakZ6eWFiRnVCSW5BUdIBwwFBVV95cUxQQXRndkpPV21Ca2ZadHJCRUFySFhaMVRTWkp3UEl6bjJNMjNDU0xJNDNGOWs4bW1pMW5iUk1MQ044QzBaY2J6Ml9nSlR6enpaNUszVHpmMVZfX3dqZXZJSUpCbFBNOW53TDlnbjU5R09ETjZnNmtvSk5Pd242RE5LNElILS1TNnR2b0NabXliUzdlT2U1c2pSb3dVMGFPRDN2dzNrcmI2dUYyYnpRcVE4bWp4U0Y5ZjhoX1ZhOHRVWGQ4czA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOY2ZxVEJyUW9Wcjd5TWN6c00yekp5UWJ3bE9OSmFLMHpQaExfTENJZC0xbXBRZmFpX2ZmMldnMURxYVNPYi1yRFZxQlBCa0p3ZFdHNDJ4Wk1tYlJpNmN0eDljUHc5R0FiZmlsZDV2c3BGemxWTnhkSUNRb3lpWW1ybXNDeHZUNHNCbS1GenlQY21IaDNoOUZWaGNvMFZKSlptTFpfaXVvRzNuakZ6eWFiRnVCSW5BUdIBwwFBVV95cUxQQXRndkpPV21Ca2ZadHJCRUFySFhaMVRTWkp3UEl6bjJNMjNDU0xJNDNGOWs4bW1pMW5iUk1MQ044QzBaY2J6Ml9nSlR6enpaNUszVHpmMVZfX3dqZXZJSUpCbFBNOW53TDlnbjU5R09ETjZnNmtvSk5Pd242RE5LNElILS1TNnR2b0NabXliUzdlT2U1c2pSb3dVMGFPRDN2dzNrcmI2dUYyYnpRcVE4bWp4U0Y5ZjhoX1ZhOHRVWGQ4czA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:06:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Group Corporation and Kadokawa Corporation to form strategic capital and business alliance - Gematsu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sony and Kadokawa Form Strategic Alliance</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 19, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Gematsu</p>
<p>Sony Group Corporation has signed a strategic capital and business alliance agreement with Kadokawa Corporation, becoming Kadokawa’s largest shareholder with a 10% stake through a significant share acquisition.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sony will acquire 12,054,100 new shares of Kadokawa Corporation for approximately 50 billion yen ($320 million) on January 7, 2025.</li>
  <li>This acquisition marks Sony as Kadokawa's largest shareholder.</li>
  <li>The two companies plan to enhance collaboration to maximize their intellectual property (IP) value globally.</li>
  <li>Joint initiatives may include adaptations of Kadokawa’s IP into live-action films and global distribution of anime.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We are very pleased to conclude this capital and business alliance agreement with Sony,” said Kadokawa CEO Takeshi Natsuno.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this partnership is poised to increase both companies' media mix options, enhancing their positions in the global content market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/sony-group-corporation-and-kadokawa-corporation-to-form-strategic-capital-and-business-alliance</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/sony-group-corporation-and-kadokawa-corporation-to-form-strategic-capital-and-business-alliance</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:06:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Introduces New Phone Number for ChatGPT, Lets Users Access Chatbot via Phone Calls and WhatsApp - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>You Can Now Call and Send WhatsApp Texts to ChatGPT</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Wednesday</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/eSNLVyaw_VM/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Play Video</figcaption><p>OpenAI has introduced an official phone number for ChatGPT, allowing users in eligible regions to call and interact with the chatbot verbally, while others can text on WhatsApp.</p><ul><li>New chatbot feature allows calls and WhatsApp texts.</li><li>Voice call time is limited to 15 minutes per month.</li><li>The phone number is toll-free and easy to remember: 1-800-ChatGPT.</li><li>Currently available only in Canada and the US.</li><li>WhatsApp users can only send text messages; no image generation or other features available.</li></ul><blockquote>“This move targets the rural demographic that either does not have a lot of data or has yet to experience the chatbot.”</blockquote><p>OpenAI's initiative aims to make ChatGPT more accessible to a wider audience, particularly those with limited internet access.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/ai/news/chatgpt-phone-number-call-whatsapp-text-messages-access-openai-7283656</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/ai/news/chatgpt-phone-number-call-whatsapp-text-messages-access-openai-7283656</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 07:43:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 15 Plus gets a huge discount on Flipkart - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iPhone 15 Plus gets a huge discount on Flipkart</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2024/12/cropped-imageITG-1734072500578.png" alt="iPhone 15 Plus"/><figcaption>iPhone 15 Plus on Discount</figcaption><p>Flipkart is offering the iPhone 15 Plus (128GB variant) at a discounted price of Rs 59,999, marking the lowest price of the year for the device.</p><ul><li>The iPhone 15 Plus is originally priced at Rs 63,999.</li><li>Additonal bank offers on Flipkart Axis Credit card and various other banks are also available.</li><li>Features a 6.7-inch Super Retina XDR display with ProMotion technology (120Hz refresh rate).</li><li>Powered by the A16 Bionic chip for high performance.</li><li>Camera system includes a 48MP main sensor alongside Ultra Wide and Telephoto cameras.</li><li>Additional features include a long-lasting battery, USB-C port, and under-display fingerprint sensor.</li><li>Available in five colors: pink, yellow, green, blue, and black.</li><li>Rated IP68 for water and dust resistance.</li><li>The offer is notable, considering the device is not eligible for Apple Intelligence but still priced attractively.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/iphone-15-plus-gets-a-huge-discount-on-flipkart-195675-19-12-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/iphone-15-plus-gets-a-huge-discount-on-flipkart-195675-19-12-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 07:30:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zupee Recognized Among India's Most Downloaded Apps in 2024 - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/content/specials/zupee-recognized-among-india-s-most-downloaded-apps-in-2024-124121801242_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/content/specials/zupee-recognized-among-india-s-most-downloaded-apps-in-2024-124121801242_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 07:24:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Three hotel stocks riding Santa’s wave: Is more cheer coming in 2025? | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Three hotel stocks riding Santa’s wave: Is more cheer coming in 2025?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Stock Market News</p>
<p>As Christmas approaches, Indian equities are caught between the festive cheer and market fluctuations. Despite a pullback, there may still be hidden opportunities in the market.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Nifty50 index has fallen from a peak of 24,700 to below 24,000 amidst market fluctuations.</li>
  <li>Analysts suggest that there might be stocks to watch as the festive season progresses.</li>
  <li>The article discusses potential recovery patterns for certain sectors heading into 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“But before you let your holiday cheer fade, a hidden gem in the market may be ready to surprise you.”</blockquote>
<p>This article emphasizes that even in a volatile market, opportunities can still arise, particularly as the holiday season enhances consumer spending.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/hotel-stocks-stock-markets-holiday-travel-nifty-50-sensex-techincal-charts-chalet-hotels-kamat-hotels-eih-hotels-11734589282744.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/hotel-stocks-stock-markets-holiday-travel-nifty-50-sensex-techincal-charts-chalet-hotels-kamat-hotels-eih-hotels-11734589282744.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 07:21:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus announces Ace 5 and Ace 5 Pro launch date - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxNc1M3c1k3WWF6NGtUYnFJcHVnZ3d6UXBlUmF3YUIzR0JaT3JVdXozbEw4UXJpb2ZLSmY0X1o2ak9mT2hVRVFKeWpJTk1LYl9vSDVmUGtrNHNEQldzRVhwWGIwcTVWRkhzci1iaDUwNUVUc2lfejJaV1Bpb2ZRUC1aeHhHMDdnWW5wNXU4Zjd1VU0wb03SAY8BQVVfeXFMTzVGWWNYb1FFeXEtYXZqQlB6UFZDZW1OSHJYM0ZfRFlTMk5WSGptT2l2dUFpbTBlaWFiVUdFR2V5V2t0LXlDVGZ4M1E3cjZFN2Y1M3FmT1I5eFhUVXY0cnNLWFZYSS10eVI2VTktc01adDhjXzNOcHRhR3M0cVJKbDVZS0FmeUNnSE54bDVyT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxNc1M3c1k3WWF6NGtUYnFJcHVnZ3d6UXBlUmF3YUIzR0JaT3JVdXozbEw4UXJpb2ZLSmY0X1o2ak9mT2hVRVFKeWpJTk1LYl9vSDVmUGtrNHNEQldzRVhwWGIwcTVWRkhzci1iaDUwNUVUc2lfejJaV1Bpb2ZRUC1aeHhHMDdnWW5wNXU4Zjd1VU0wb03SAY8BQVVfeXFMTzVGWWNYb1FFeXEtYXZqQlB6UFZDZW1OSHJYM0ZfRFlTMk5WSGptT2l2dUFpbTBlaWFiVUdFR2V5V2t0LXlDVGZ4M1E3cjZFN2Y1M3FmT1I5eFhUVXY0cnNLWFZYSS10eVI2VTktc01adDhjXzNOcHRhR3M0cVJKbDVZS0FmeUNnSE54bDVyT3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 07:09:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vivo X200 series goes on its first sale today: Check India price, offers, specs and more - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vivo X200 series goes on its first sale today: Check India price, offers, specs, and more</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><p>Vivo's latest flagship series, the Vivo X200 and X200 Pro, are now available for purchase in India, featuring cutting-edge specifications and exciting offers.</p><h3>Price, Offers and Availability</h3><ul><li>Vivo X200 starts at Rs 65,999 for 12GB + 256GB variant and Rs 71,999 for 16GB + 512GB variant.</li><li>Vivo X200 Pro priced at Rs 94,999 for 16GB + 512GB model.</li><li>Offers include easy EMI options, cashback with select banks, free 1-year extended warranty, and discounts on protection plans.</li></ul><h3>Specs and Features</h3><p>The Vivo X200 features a 6.67-inch OLED LTPS quad-curved display, a 5,800mAh battery with 90W fast charging, and a triple rear camera setup with a 50MP main sensor. The Pro model has advanced imaging features with a 200MP sensor and supports 4K HDR video recording.</p><p>Published By: Unnati Gusain</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/vivo-x200-series-goes-on-its-first-sale-today-check-india-price-offers-specs-and-more-2652217-2024-12-19</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/vivo-x200-series-goes-on-its-first-sale-today-check-india-price-offers-specs-and-more-2652217-2024-12-19</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 07:05:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI's ChatGPT is now on WhatsApp: How to start texting with AI chatbot - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/openai-s-chatgpt-is-now-on-whatsapp-how-to-start-texting-with-ai-chatbot-124121900441_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/openai-s-chatgpt-is-now-on-whatsapp-how-to-start-texting-with-ai-chatbot-124121900441_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 07:01:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[POCO M7 Pro 5G vs CMF Phone 1: Price, Specifications and Features Compared - MySmartPrice]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/mobiles/mobiles-features/poco-m7-pro-5g-vs-cmf-phone-1-compared/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/mobiles/mobiles-features/poco-m7-pro-5g-vs-cmf-phone-1-compared/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 07:00:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>