<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 19:21:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 19:21:18 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flipkart year-end sale: Grab iPhone 15 for ₹58,999 and iPhone 16 at … All details | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Flipkart Year-End Sale Offers Discounts on iPhones and More</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>As 2024 comes to a close, Flipkart is offering significant discounts on various premium and budget smartphones during its "Mobiles Year-End" sale.</p><ul><li>The iPhone 15 is now available for ₹58,999, down from ₹79,999 for the green variant, marking a saving of ₹21,000.</li><li>The iPhone 16 is priced at ₹74,900, with an additional ₹4,000 off for select bank card users.</li><li>Samsung's Galaxy S24 Plus has a discount bringing its price down to ₹64,999 from ₹99,999.</li><li>Motorola's Edge 50 Pro is available for ₹27,999, while the Moto G85 is listed at ₹17,999.</li><li>Other deals include the Nothing Phone (2a) for ₹22,499 and discounts on Vivo T3 Lite and Poco C61.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is an opportune moment for tech enthusiasts to grab their desired devices at competitive rates.”</blockquote><p>The sale presents a great opportunity for shoppers to take advantage of reduced prices on some of the latest smartphones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/flipkart-year-end-sale-grab-iphone-15-for-rs-58-999-and-iphone-16-at-all-details-11735666102371.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/tech-news/flipkart-year-end-sale-grab-iphone-15-for-rs-58-999-and-iphone-16-at-all-details-11735666102371.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 17:42:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US News Today highlights on December 31, 2024 : Sunita Williams to celebrate New Year 2025 16 times in space | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sunita Williams to Celebrate New Year 2025 16 Times in Space</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 31 Dec 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> LiveMint</p>
<img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2024/12/31/600x338/PTI12-25-2024-000011B-0_1735664639285_1735664650926.jpg" alt="Sunita Williams to celebrate New Year 2025 16 times in space" />
<figcaption>Sunita Williams to celebrate New Year 2025 16 times in space</figcaption>
<p>Astronaut Sunita Williams and the Expedition 72 crew will uniquely celebrate New Year’s by witnessing 16 sunrises and sunsets in just 24 hours while aboard the International Space Station (ISS).</p>
<ul>
    <li>Astronaut Sunita Williams and her crew are prepared to celebrate New Year’s Eve in a distinctive manner from space.</li>
    <li>The ISS crew will see 16 different sunrises and sunsets during the 24-hour period of New Year's Eve and New Year's Day.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Witnessing New Year 2025 from orbit is a truly unique experience!” - Sunita Williams</blockquote>
<p>This celebration marks a remarkable event in space exploration and draws attention to human achievements in science and technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/latest-us-news-today-on-december-31-2024-live-updates-11735584806259.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/latest-us-news-today-on-december-31-2024-live-updates-11735584806259.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 17:04:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Might Introduce 'ProMotion' Technology To iPhone 17 Series' Base Variants - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Might Introduce 'ProMotion' Technology To iPhone 17 Series' Base Variants</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> 9To5Google</p><p>Apple is reportedly planning to introduce its ProMotion display technology across the entire iPhone 17 lineup, potentially bringing higher refresh rates to all models and significantly enhancing user experience.</p><ul><li>ProMotion currently exclusive to Pro and Pro Max variants with up to 120Hz refresh rates.</li><li>Base models may feature refresh rates of up to 90Hz, closing the gap with Pro models.</li><li>This evolution reflects Apple's strategy to incorporate more advanced features into standard models.</li><li>The iPhone 17 series is expected to maintain distinctions between standard and Pro models, while still offering upgraded features.</li></ul><blockquote>“This upgrade for the standard models would still represent a significant improvement, narrowing the performance gap between the tiers.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Apple is set to enhance the iPhone 17 series with ProMotion technology for base models, signifying a continued trend towards feature convergence across its product line.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/apple-iphone-17-specifications-promotion-technology-vanilla-models-variants-1741009</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/apple-iphone-17-specifications-promotion-technology-vanilla-models-variants-1741009</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 16:39:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple TV+ Free Weekend Streaming Event: All you may want to know - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple TV+ Free Weekend Streaming Event: All You Need to Know</h1>
<p><strong>Last Updated: 31 December, 2024</strong> | <strong>The Feed</strong></p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-116836733,width-300,height-225,imgsize-3238,resizemode-75/lucky-what-we-know-about-apple-tv-shows-plot-and-production.jpg" alt="Lucky: What we know about Apple TV+ show’s plot and production" height="225" width="300">
  <figcaption>IANS</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Apple TV+ will allow users to stream its full catalog for free for three days in January 2025. The platform aims to attract new subscribers through this promotional offer.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Free streaming from January 3 to 5, 2025, for users with an Apple ID.</li>
  <li>No paid subscription is required to access content during the free period.</li>
  <li>The regular subscription cost of Apple TV+ is $9.99 per month or $99.99 per year.</li>
  <li>Popular titles available include 'Severance,' 'Ted Lasso,' and 'The Morning Show.'</li>
  <li>Users can stream from various devices by logging in with their Apple ID.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This initiative aims to encourage new users to subscribe to the service.”</blockquote>
<p>After January 5, a subscription will be required to continue accessing Apple TV+ content.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/apple-tv-free-weekend-streaming-event-all-you-may-want-to-know/articleshow/116836725.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/apple-tv-free-weekend-streaming-event-all-you-may-want-to-know/articleshow/116836725.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:28:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone SE 4 price leaked: All you need to know about Apple’s 2025 budget iPhone - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iPhone SE 4 Price Leak: All You Need to Know About Apple’s 2025 Budget iPhone</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p>
<img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/apple-resized-1-1_20241226184419.webp?w=300" alt="Apple TV+ teases exciting surprise event" width="198" height="110" />
<figcaption>Apple TV+ teases exciting surprise event on January 4-5: What to expect</figcaption>
<p>As we look ahead to 2025, Apple fans are buzzing about the anticipated iPhone SE (2025). Recent leaks suggest a price of $499, bringing excitement over whether the device will maintain its affordability.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The iPhone SE (2025) is anticipated to feature Apple’s latest A18 chipset, 8GB of RAM, and a 48 MP primary camera.</li>
  <li>The device is expected to include a 6.06-inch OLED display with a 60Hz refresh rate.</li>
  <li>A notable upgrade will be Face ID, adopting a design similar to the iPhone 14.</li>
  <li>Though not equipped with premium features like the iPhone 16, it offers high-end performance at a budget-friendly price.</li>
  <li>The launch is expected in the first half of 2025.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The price leak comes just as Apple fans were beginning to wonder whether the SE model would see a significant price bump or if it would remain relatively affordable."</blockquote>
<p>The expected pricing and features of the iPhone SE (2025) make it a compelling choice for budget-conscious consumers seeking advanced technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-iphone-se-4-price-leaked-all-you-need-to-know-about-apples-2025-budget-iphonenbsp-3704631/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-iphone-se-4-price-leaked-all-you-need-to-know-about-apples-2025-budget-iphonenbsp-3704631/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 14:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poco X7 5G Series Design Teased; Poco X7 Pro to Get MediaTek Dimensity 8400-Ultra SoC - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Poco X7 5G Series Design Teased; Poco X7 Pro Chipset Confirmed</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/V1xyrHMrIdQ/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video">
<figcaption>Poco X7 5G Series Launch Teaser</figcaption>
<p>Poco has revealed the design and specifications of the upcoming Poco X7 5G series in India, which will launch on January 9.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Poco X7 series will include a base model and a Pro variant, both available via Flipkart.</li>
  <li>The Pro variant will feature a MediaTek Dimensity 8400-Ultra chipset.</li>
  <li>The designs show distinct camera placements: a centered squircle for the base model and a pill-shaped island for the Pro.</li>
  <li>Both models are expected to have a 50-megapixel main camera, with the Pro variant getting a Sony IMX882 sensor.</li>
  <li>Battery capacities are anticipated to be 5,110mAh for the base and 6,000mAh for the Pro, with fast charging capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Poco X7 5G series handsets will get IP68-rated builds.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the Poco X7 5G series promises enhanced design and performance features, targeting tech enthusiasts in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/poco-x7-5g-series-pro-design-soc-features-launch-india-7371667</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/poco-x7-5g-series-pro-design-soc-features-launch-india-7371667</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 14:08:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OnePlus Watch 3 Could Offer ECG, 60-Second Checkup Features via OHealth App - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OnePlus Watch 3 Tipped to Debut With New Health Tracking Features</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not available <strong>Source:</strong> Not available</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/X5AGT4W5iSU/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video">
<figcaption>Upcoming features of OnePlus Watch 3.</figcaption>
<p>The OnePlus Watch 3 is rumored to launch alongside the OnePlus 13 and OnePlus 13R, featuring advanced health tracking capabilities.</p>
<ul>
<li>New ECG feature to detect health conditions like AFib and heart rate irregularities.</li>
<li>Wrist Temperature function requires baseline readings over several days.</li>
<li>60-second Checkup feature to monitor various health metrics.</li>
<li>Expected specifications include Snapdragon W5 Gen 1, 2GB RAM, and 32GB storage.</li>
<li>Potential Pro variant may be released.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The paired phone may need specific requirements to use some features, but many can be accessed directly on the watch.”</blockquote>
<p>The OnePlus Watch 3 aims to introduce robust health monitoring tools catering to user well-being.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/wearables/news/oneplus-watch-3-series-ohealth-app-apk-teardown-ecg-health-features-report-7371601</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/wearables/news/oneplus-watch-3-series-ohealth-app-apk-teardown-ecg-health-features-report-7371601</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 14:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Biggest Game Releases Of January 2025 - GameSpot]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Biggest Game Releases Of January 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> GameSpot</p><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4418292-january2025games.jpg" alt="January 2025 games release schedule"><figcaption>The upcoming game releases for January 2025.</figcaption><p>January 2025 brings a mix of remasters and new entries to various gaming platforms. Highlights include major releases such as Donkey Kong Country Returns HD and Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth.</p><ul><li>Remasters include Donkey Kong Country Returns and Star Wars: Jedi Power Battles.</li><li>PC gamers can look forward to Marvel's Spider-Man 2 and Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth.</li><li>Indie games making their debut include Hyper Light Breaker and Sniper Elite: Resistance.</li><li>February 2025 is expected to be packed with high-profile games.</li></ul><blockquote>“February 2025 will be the big month for new releases, as it's loaded with high-profile games.”</blockquote><p>In summary, January 2025 is shaping up to be an exciting month for gamers, although the major releases are slated for February.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-biggest-game-releases-of-january-2025/2900-6020/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-biggest-game-releases-of-january-2025/2900-6020/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vivo Said to Launch Mixed Reality Headset in 2025 to Compete With Apple Vision Pro - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vivo's Upcoming Mixed Reality Headset to Launch Next Year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Tuesday, Source: Gadgets360</p><p>Vivo has announced plans to launch a mixed reality (MR) headset next year, aiming to compete with models like the Apple Vision Pro and Samsung's Project Moohan. The first prototype is expected in 2025, with further details to follow.</p><ul><li>Vivo's mixed reality headset will launch next year.</li><li>The device is anticipated to compete with the Apple Vision Pro and Samsung's Project Moohan.</li><li>The first prototype will be available in September 2025.</li><li>The launch will depend on the readiness of the supporting content ecosystem.</li></ul><blockquote>“High-fidelity prototype experiences” will be conducted in several Chinese cities by the end of next year.</blockquote><p>The announcement signals Vivo's commitment to entering the mixed reality market, potentially affecting competition significantly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/wearables/news/vivo-mixed-reality-headset-apple-vision-pro-launch-weibo-7370713</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/wearables/news/vivo-mixed-reality-headset-apple-vision-pro-launch-weibo-7370713</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:57:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Flagship-Killer Smartphones of 2024 in India - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Best Flagship-Killer Smartphones of 2024 in India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Firstpost</p>
<img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/12/Flagship-Killers-2024-12-4b745671a4076d3befc895e183c7042a-1200x675.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Best Flagship-Killer Smartphones of 2024 in India" title="Best Flagship-Killer Smartphones of 2024 in India">
<figcaption>Composite Image</figcaption>
<p>This article showcases the top flagship-killer smartphones of 2024 in India, offering great features at more affordable prices.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>OnePlus 12:</strong> Features Snapdragon 8 Gen 3, excellent display, strong camera setup.</li>
  <li><strong>Xiaomi 14:</strong> Compact design, Leica cameras, impressive battery life.</li>
  <li><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 5G:</strong> Solid performance, excellent camera, long software support.</li>
  <li><strong>Realme GT 7 Pro:</strong> Powerful processor, robust design, great battery life.</li>
  <li><strong>Vivo X200 5G:</strong> Strong camera features, IP69 rating, durable battery.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These flagship-killers redefine value without compromising on quality.”</blockquote>
<p>The flagship-killer smartphones of 2024 prove that consumers can enjoy premium features without breaking the bank.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/tech/best-flagship-killer-smartphones-of-2024-in-india-13848969.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/tech/best-flagship-killer-smartphones-of-2024-in-india-13848969.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:54:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone SE 4 price leaked ahead of launch: Potential for budget-friendly Apple entry - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iPhone SE 4 Price Leaked Ahead of Launch: Potential for Budget-Friendly Apple Entry</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/iphone-se-3-1735649038.webp" alt="iPhone SE" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>iPhone SE</figcaption>
<p>The wait for the iPhone SE 4 will soon be over, as it's expected to launch in early 2025. This budget-friendly device from Apple is rumored to be unveiled in the first half of the year. Recent leaks have shed light on what to expect from this new model.</p>
<ul>
<li>The iPhone SE 4 is anticipated to incorporate advanced AI features driven by the new A18 Bionic chipset.</li>
<li>It may feature a 6.1-inch OLED display and a dual-camera setup for the first time.</li>
<li>Expected pricing is around KRW 800,000 (approximately Rs 46,000), with U.S. estimates between $449 and $549.</li>
<li>The price hike is attributed to rising component costs, alongside expected 5G support and a 48MP rear camera.</li>
<li>Additional features may include eSIM support, LPDDR5X RAM, and a USB Type-C port.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Market analysts suggest that the price hike for the upcoming iPhone SE 4 could be due to rising component costs.”</blockquote>
<p>Apple has also announced a ban on the sale of three iPhone models, affecting the iPhone 14, iPhone 14 Plus, and iPhone SE (3rd generation) in several European countries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/iphone-se-4-price-leaked-ahead-of-launch-potential-for-budget-friendly-apple-entry-2024-12-31-968842</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/iphone-se-4-price-leaked-ahead-of-launch-potential-for-budget-friendly-apple-entry-2024-12-31-968842</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:44:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple TV+ streaming for free first weekend; Top 5 series to watch - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple TV+ Streaming Available for Free This Weekend to Celebrate the New Year</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 3, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p>
<p>Apple has announced that its streaming service, Apple TV+, will be offered for free globally this weekend from January 3 to January 5, 2025. Users need just an Apple ID to access the service without any charges.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Free access to Apple TV+ from January 3 to January 5, 2025.</li>
  <li>No subscription required, but users must have an Apple ID.</li>
  <li>Current Apple device holders already possess an Apple ID.</li>
  <li>Top 5 popular shows highlighted for viewers.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Top 5 Popular Shows on Apple TV+</h2>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Severance:</strong> A psychological thriller exploring the separation of work and personal memories.</li>
  <li><strong>Silo:</strong> A dystopian drama set in a giant underground silo in a toxic world, renewed for additional seasons.</li>
  <li><strong>Ted Lasso:</strong> A heartwarming comedy about an American football coach managing a British soccer team.</li>
  <li><strong>Bad Sisters:</strong> A dark comedy-drama about sisterly bonds and secrets following a suspicious death.</li>
  <li><strong>Shrinking:</strong> A comedy series about a grieving therapist who breaks rules to share his honest opinions.</li>
</ul>
<p>This promotion is an excellent opportunity for viewers to experience Apple TV+ services and discover new shows.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/entertainment/apple-tv-streaming-for-free-first-weekend-top-5-series-to-watch-nc-124123100695_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/entertainment/apple-tv-streaming-for-free-first-weekend-top-5-series-to-watch-nc-124123100695_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:30:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Chrome 2FA Bypass Attacks Confirmed—Millions Of Users At Risk - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/daveywinder/2024/12/31/google-chrome-2fa-bypass-attack-confirmed-what-you-need-to-know/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/daveywinder/2024/12/31/google-chrome-2fa-bypass-attack-confirmed-what-you-need-to-know/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024 tough year for ad industry but the worst is behind us: EssenceMediacom's Navin Khemka | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/industry/advertising/2024-tough-year-for-ad-industry-but-the-worst-is-behind-us-essencemediacoms-navin-khemka-11735634283521.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/industry/advertising/2024-tough-year-for-ad-industry-but-the-worst-is-behind-us-essencemediacoms-navin-khemka-11735634283521.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:07:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 series might see a price hike due to use of Qualcomm chipset - 91mobiles]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Series Price Hike Due to Qualcomm Chipset</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> 91Mobiles</p><p><img src="https://www.91-cdn.com/hub/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Galaxy-S25-Plus-2.jpg?tr=w-781" alt="Samsung Galaxy S25 Plus"/></p><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S25 Plus</figcaption><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 series is set to debut on January 22nd at the 'Galaxy Unpacked' event, with all models powered by Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset due to low yields of the Exynos 2500, potentially leading to a price increase.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>Qualcomm charging approximately $190 per Snapdragon 8 Elite processor, impacting overall costs for Galaxy S25.</li><li>Manufacturing of Snapdragon using TSMC’s 3nm process could lead to further price hikes.</li><li>Shift from Exynos to Qualcomm is due to insufficient production yields of Samsung's chips.</li><li>Samsung's previous experience with low yields affected production timelines and strategies.</li></ul><blockquote>“Samsung reportedly faced a similar situation previously with the Snapdragon 8 Gen 1, leading to a shift in production.”</blockquote><p>This change in strategy might not only influence pricing for the Galaxy S25 series but may also reflect broader trends in the semiconductor supply chain.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-price-hike/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.91mobiles.com/hub/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-price-hike/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:06:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[realme 14x 5G Review: Durable, powerful, consistent - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>realme 14x 5G Review: Durable, powerful, consistent</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img alt="realme 14x 5G Review: Durable, powerful, consistent" title="realme 14x 5G Review: Durable, powerful, consistent" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360"><figcaption>Image of the realme 14x 5G smartphone</figcaption><p>The realme 14x 5G impresses with its durable design, long-lasting battery, and reliable performance, making it an excellent choice for those seeking value in the mid-range segment.</p><ul><li>IP69-certified design with military-grade protection.</li><li>Equipped with a MediaTek Dimensity 6300 ensuring smooth performance.</li><li>Features a robust 6,000 mAh battery for extensive usage.</li><li>6.67-inch IPS LCD display with a 120Hz refresh rate.</li><li>50MP primary camera and 8MP front camera with decent image quality.</li><li>Affordable pricing at ₹14,999.</li></ul><blockquote>“The realme 14x 5G is a game-changer in the mid-range smartphone market.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the realme 14x 5G stands out for its durability and performance at a competitive price, appealing to users who value resilience and battery life over premium features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/technology/realme-14x-5g-review-durable-powerful-consistent-19532495.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/technology/realme-14x-5g-review-durable-powerful-consistent-19532495.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 12:06:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Redmi Turbo 4 Battery, Build Details Revealed Ahead of January 2 Launch - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Redmi Turbo 4 Battery, Build Details Revealed Ahead of January 2 Launch</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<img src='https://img.youtube.com/vi/EYVfiGWKYUE/hqdefault.jpg' alt='Redmi Turbo 4 Video Preview'>
<figcaption>Play Video Preview of Redmi Turbo 4</figcaption>
<p>The Redmi Turbo 4 is set to launch in China on January 2. It is expected to be powered by MediaTek's new Dimensity 8400-Ultra chipset, featuring a powerful battery and impressive water resistance ratings.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Powered by a 6,550mAh battery.</li>
  <li>IP66, IP68, and IP69 ratings for dust and water resistance.</li>
  <li>Will have a 6.67-inch 1.5K OLED display with a 120Hz refresh rate.</li>
  <li>Expected to support up to 16GB of RAM and 512GB of storage with Android 15-based HyperOS 2.0.</li>
  <li>Features a dual rear camera with a 50MP primary sensor and a 20MP front camera.</li>
  <li>Could support 90W wired fast charging and an in-display fingerprint sensor.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The handset will arrive in a 'Lucky Cloud White' colour option.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the Redmi Turbo 4 is shaping up to be a powerful smartphone with exciting features that cater to tech-savvy users.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/redmi-turbo-4-battery-build-details-launch-features-expected-7370401</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/redmi-turbo-4-battery-build-details-launch-features-expected-7370401</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 11:26:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Machine learning can help blood tests have a separate ‘normal’ for each patient - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Machine Learning Tailors Blood Test Norms to Individual Patients</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Conversation</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/5x0p1a/article69046148.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_iStock-1827493426_2_1_8JDFP5E5.jpg" alt="Blood test image" title="Currently, blood test readings are based on one-size-fits-all reference intervals that don’t account for individual differences."><figcaption>Currently, blood test readings are based on one-size-fits-all reference intervals that don’t account for individual differences. | Photo Credit: Getty Images</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses recent advancements in using machine learning to personalize blood test readings, moving away from traditional one-size-fits-all reference intervals.</p>
<ul>
<li>Blood tests, particularly complete blood counts (CBC), are commonly used but often lack precision.</li>
<li>Current blood test analyses are based on population averages, which neglect individual patient specifics.</li>
<li>Research from the University of Washington and Harvard Medical School suggests machine learning can identify more accurate 'normal' ranges for individual patients.</li>
<li>Individual normal blood count ranges were found to be significantly narrower than population-based ones.</li>
<li>The study analyzed blood tests from over 50,000 patients, showing that personalized interpretations can improve disease diagnosis.</li>
<li>Future applications may lead to enhanced personalized medicine strategies that define health based on individual patient history.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The set points themselves were strong indicators for future risk of developing a disease.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, leveraging machine learning in clinical settings could revolutionize how blood test results are interpreted, enhancing the precision of diagnoses and personalized healthcare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/machine-learning-can-help-blood-tests-have-a-separate-normal-for-each-patient/article69046064.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/science/machine-learning-can-help-blood-tests-have-a-separate-normal-for-each-patient/article69046064.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 11:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy New Year 2025! Google Trends reveals OnePlus 13 as the hottest smartphone to watch this January - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxPZ2I2RndDdDhOVVdtQmFIZEpFS2VtSXc5R0tyWVpmZHBsRkUwZGhjeXY2dzc1cFF3N2RkWk1Ca1lYNUJrZUUwVHgtMnBlSTZqVkZ1M2Z6eGlLVS02clNzNlVfcjU3SFNxa0tZa2h0Y185eGdSdjloeDRkTjg5UFNhRlJYOEVsd2UwQWRyc2dCOHE2N0lNcDlLTkNTREFVcEtKeld5QTliWlVKWGhoUy1IdkVuNzdGdHhOWHpxdEdBX3BwZGkzQTBub2pqdF9VeDJuZ1pXTHdLRlB1UWE4RG9LcGkyYmZwazQzSEt1Y1dvd9IB9gFBVV95cUxQTWRxaEdEXzNHb0ZDRkVTenRicGZiYnRDUk56S3VwWEF3bzFYY0pGZG04Z2k5YkdOWlVINE1pLWdwZ0RtX01iUXEwTWFsVEwtVTM3OE1RXzkxMXk4aE9vWEVBaTVGZGhpNnpkN2lfSWFWQmxEVm9IT2FTcHM0X1FuMWhRT185YXVtd2NhbHNhU01OSGNvM3dndXQ3QV9DTHBBUGk4dFV3WGo1SlBQbGlSVlowMXZxY2cweXZHbkZ6MjBZVlFaN0YxV01SYy1ueHdBaFhyWEVuTkp3QWxKamhKb19BdXp0NXA0WGNfZjdrdGpEMnVJQ3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7wFBVV95cUxPZ2I2RndDdDhOVVdtQmFIZEpFS2VtSXc5R0tyWVpmZHBsRkUwZGhjeXY2dzc1cFF3N2RkWk1Ca1lYNUJrZUUwVHgtMnBlSTZqVkZ1M2Z6eGlLVS02clNzNlVfcjU3SFNxa0tZa2h0Y185eGdSdjloeDRkTjg5UFNhRlJYOEVsd2UwQWRyc2dCOHE2N0lNcDlLTkNTREFVcEtKeld5QTliWlVKWGhoUy1IdkVuNzdGdHhOWHpxdEdBX3BwZGkzQTBub2pqdF9VeDJuZ1pXTHdLRlB1UWE4RG9LcGkyYmZwazQzSEt1Y1dvd9IB9gFBVV95cUxQTWRxaEdEXzNHb0ZDRkVTenRicGZiYnRDUk56S3VwWEF3bzFYY0pGZG04Z2k5YkdOWlVINE1pLWdwZ0RtX01iUXEwTWFsVEwtVTM3OE1RXzkxMXk4aE9vWEVBaTVGZGhpNnpkN2lfSWFWQmxEVm9IT2FTcHM0X1FuMWhRT185YXVtd2NhbHNhU01OSGNvM3dndXQ3QV9DTHBBUGk4dFV3WGo1SlBQbGlSVlowMXZxY2cweXZHbkZ6MjBZVlFaN0YxV01SYy1ueHdBaFhyWEVuTkp3QWxKamhKb19BdXp0NXA0WGNfZjdrdGpEMnVJQ3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:19:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Benefits of Website Redesign - NASSCOM Community]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 Benefits of Website Redesign</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Date not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>In the always-changing digital world, your website serves as the foundation of your online presence. A outdated or poorly performing website hinders your brand growth and repels potential clients. Redesigning a website is not just about aesthetics; it is a smart step to improve functionality, user experience, and business output.</p>
<ul>
<li>Enhance User Experience (UX): Streamline navigation, improve accessibility, decrease bounce rates.</li>
<li>Better Mobile Responsiveness: Ensure mobile-friendly design for better engagement and conversion.</li>
<li>Increase in Search Engine Rankings (SEO): Align with best SEO practices to boost search visibility.</li>
<li>Faster Loads: Optimizing media, scripts, and coding standards to improve speed.</li>
<li>Stronger Branding and Visual Appeal: Reflect current brand identity and create a modern look.</li>
<li>Higher Conversion Rates: Improve calls-to-action and personalize user journeys.</li>
<li>Integration of Advanced Technologies: Incorporate chatbots, analytics, and e-commerce enhancements.</li>
<li>Better Security Features: Ensure compliance with latest security protocols with SSL, updated software, and regular backups.</li>
<li>Cost Savings Over Time: Reduce maintenance costs with modern infrastructure and easy updates.</li>
<li>Improved Analytics and Data Tracking: Utilize better tracking tools for data-driven decisions.</li>
</ul>
<p>A website redesign is a strategic move to improve your brand's digital presence and grow your business.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://community.nasscom.in/communities/mobile-web-development/10-benefits-website-redesign</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://community.nasscom.in/communities/mobile-web-development/10-benefits-website-redesign</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 09:07:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The entire iPhone 17 lineup could feature 120Hz refresh rate displays - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/the-entire-iphone-17-lineup-could-feature-120hz-refresh-rate-displays/articleshow/116825322.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/the-entire-iphone-17-lineup-could-feature-120hz-refresh-rate-displays/articleshow/116825322.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 09:03:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LG’s lightweight Gram laptops get new Intel chips and offline AI features - The Verge]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/31/24332438/lg-gram-pro-laptops-2025-ai-copilot</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/31/24332438/lg-gram-pro-laptops-2025-ai-copilot</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Series to Reportedly Offer Gemini Advanced Subscriptions for Free - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Series Might Offer Free Gemini Advanced Subscriptions</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/UVMrH-cGuss/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Video preview of the Samsung Galaxy S25 Series</figcaption><p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 series, set to launch on January 22, 2025, may include free Gemini Advanced subscriptions through a partnership with Google. The subscriptions could vary from three months to one year, enhancing the appeal of the new devices.</p><ul><li>The Galaxy S25 series might include various durations for free Gemini Advanced subscriptions.</li><li>Reportedly, the trial periods could be three, six, nine months, or one year depending on the device model.</li><li>Evidence for the offer was found in the APK teardown of the Google app.</li></ul><blockquote>“Your device gives you access to an {xxx}-month subscription to Gemini Advanced, with access to our most capable AI models, at no cost.”</blockquote><p>As of now, there has been no official confirmation from Google or Samsung about this offer, and more information is expected upon the launch of the Galaxy S25 series next month.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/ai/news/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-free-gemini-advanced-subscription-report-7369328</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/ai/news/samsung-galaxy-s25-series-free-gemini-advanced-subscription-report-7369328</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 08:38:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp Likely To Roll Out Reverse Image Search Feature For Web Users; Heres How To Use It - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxOejJscnZIb3F0QXNRMjVSNGdrRFhFeWpPb0dyc1E3THdZb2l1alhGSzVHYmdOSm1EVFVkaUVZN2ZBT1EyUE5LVEY5aW9xdlpsZm05SUJNUzhYS0thbUJlc2liN3VadmtPWjNpVmhiSzlSX1l5eF80ZF9SeS04Y2tTaV9CeU1oM2QzUk5ldlBPWTN2OXVYZmZXVkFHSktKeC1NRlN1RzZHQmZ1VHJpdnRjX3kweXpKWVhhMl9rWjlRVjZWbENVdVk3c1o5UzBqUEx6UjU5eGFvNA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxOejJscnZIb3F0QXNRMjVSNGdrRFhFeWpPb0dyc1E3THdZb2l1alhGSzVHYmdOSm1EVFVkaUVZN2ZBT1EyUE5LVEY5aW9xdlpsZm05SUJNUzhYS0thbUJlc2liN3VadmtPWjNpVmhiSzlSX1l5eF80ZF9SeS04Y2tTaV9CeU1oM2QzUk5ldlBPWTN2OXVYZmZXVkFHSktKeC1NRlN1RzZHQmZ1VHJpdnRjX3kweXpKWVhhMl9rWjlRVjZWbENVdVk3c1o5UzBqUEx6UjU5eGFvNA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 06:54:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 key takeaways from the PPFAS annual unitholders’ meeting | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 key takeaways from the PPFAS annual unitholders’ meeting</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p>
<p>PPFAS Asset Management Company recently conducted its annual unitholders' meeting, highlighting the success of their flagship Flexicap fund, which has seen a remarkable five-year CAGR of 26%. The fund management team addressed various investor inquiries, shedding light on their operations and strategies.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Flexicap fund has a five-year CAGR of 26%, demonstrating strong performance.</li>
  <li>Rajeev Thakkar, the chief investment officer, led discussions during the meeting.</li>
  <li>Investor questions covered stock choices, sector strategies, and overall fund management.</li>
  <li>The meeting addressed scrutiny surrounding the fund house despite its successes.</li>
  <li>Key takeaways include insights on investment strategy and market outlook.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Flexicap fund has registered a stellar five-year CAGR of 26%.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the annual meeting reaffirmed PPFAS's commitment to transparency and engagement with its investors while emphasizing its growth trajectory in the mutual fund market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/ppfas-annual-unitholders-meeting-rajiv-thakkar-investment-strategy-market-optimism-outsized-valuations-cash-holding-11735550200044.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/money/personal-finance/ppfas-annual-unitholders-meeting-rajiv-thakkar-investment-strategy-market-optimism-outsized-valuations-cash-holding-11735550200044.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 06:32:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new heavyweight joins the 2024 headphone party | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A new heavyweight joins the 2024 headphone party</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date not provided]<br><strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/subscription/onepagecheckout/lm/staging/extensivepaywall/headphone.png" alt="headphone"><figcaption>Headphones by Marshall</figcaption><p>The headphone market sees a new contender with the Marshall Monitor III joining premium noise-cancelling headphones, challenging established brands like Bose, Sennheiser, and Sony.</p><ul><li>Marshall introduces Monitor III priced at ₹29,999.</li><li>The headphone targets audiophiles, ensuring high-fidelity sound quality.</li><li>Marshall’s legacy in professional music gear adds value to its consumer audio products.</li><li>Questions remain about mainstream headphones' ability to deliver true audio quality.</li></ul><blockquote>“True audiophile-grade headphones typically use sophisticated sound drivers.”</blockquote><p>This new entry from Marshall into the headphone market showcases its commitment to quality and innovation, raising the standards for premium audio products.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/business-of-life/marshall-monitor-3-anc-review-11735625556366.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/business-of-life/marshall-monitor-3-anc-review-11735625556366.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 06:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MacBook Air price drops to lowest in India: All details here - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MacBook Air Price Drops to Lowest in India: All Details Here</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 31, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Ankita Garg</p><p>The price of the MacBook Air has hit an all-time low in India, thanks to Vijay Sales' Apple Days sale as part of their New Year celebration. Here are the details.</p><h3>MacBook Air Prices Drop in India</h3><p>The latest MacBook Air M3 model is now available for Rs 1,03,390. This is a discount of Rs 11,510 from its launch price of Rs 1,14,900. An additional Rs 10,000 discount is available for SBI and ICICI Bank credit card users, bringing the effective price down to Rs 93,390.</p><ul><li>MacBook Air M2 (8GB RAM + 512GB SSD): Rs 95,500.</li><li>MacBook Air M2 (16GB RAM + 256GB SSD): Rs 89,890.</li><li>MacBook Air M1 (8GB RAM + 256GB SSD): Rs 68,890.</li></ul><h3>MacBook Pro Discount Deals</h3><p>The 14-inch MacBook Pro with 16GB RAM and 512GB SSD is priced at Rs 1,52,900, with discounts bringing the final price down to Rs 1,47,900.</p><p>With these offers, it's a great time for buyers to pick up a MacBook at the lowest prices seen.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/macbook-air-price-drops-to-lowest-in-india-all-details-here-2657655-2024-12-31</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/macbook-air-price-drops-to-lowest-in-india-all-details-here-2657655-2024-12-31</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 05:56:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best phones launched in 2024 under ₹30,000: OnePlus Nord 4, Nothing Phone 2a Plus, and more - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Best Phones Launched in 2024 Under ₹30,000</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 31, 2024 11:23 AM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/31/550x309/phone_2a_1735624101157_1735624113129.png" alt="Know which smartphone you should buy under ₹30000.(Nothing)" title="Know which smartphone you should buy under ₹30000.(Nothing)">
<figcaption>Know which smartphone you should buy under ₹30000.(Nothing)</figcaption>
<p>This article highlights the best mid-range smartphones launched in 2024 priced under ₹30,000. It provides insights on their features and specifications to aid consumers in making informed choices.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Moto Edge 50 Neo:</strong> Features a vegan leather back, MediaTek Dimensity 7300 chipset, and a triple camera setup including a 50MP main camera.</li>
  <li><strong>Poco F6:</strong> Powered by Snapdragon 8s Gen 3 processor, offers competitive performance, ideal for multitasking and gaming.</li>
  <li><strong>Nothing Phone 2a Plus:</strong> Unique transparent design, MediaTek Dimensity 7350 Pro, and a promising dual camera setup.</li>
  <li><strong>OnePlus Nord 4:</strong> Metal design, Snapdragon 7+ Gen 3 processor, and excellent camera performance.</li>
  <li><strong>Vivo T3 Ultra:</strong> Premium design with MediaTek Dimensity 9200+ chipset, and a 50MP Sony IMX921 OIS rear camera.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Finding the right model could be a tedious job since the smartphone market is filled with various options from several different brands.”</blockquote>
<p>In summary, 2024's smartphone market under ₹30,000 is competitive, offering various options balancing aesthetics and performance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/best-phones-launched-in-2024-under-rs-30-000-oneplus-nord-4-nothing-phone-2a-plus-and-more-101735624024057.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/best-phones-launched-in-2024-under-rs-30-000-oneplus-nord-4-nothing-phone-2a-plus-and-more-101735624024057.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 05:52:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turning the page into the Gen Beta year: In charts | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/specials/olympics-chess-d-gukesh-stree-2-gen-beta-mukesh-ambani-gautam-adani-concerts-icc-trophy-2025-bollywood-films-box-office-11735619727575.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/specials/olympics-chess-d-gukesh-stree-2-gen-beta-mukesh-ambani-gautam-adani-concerts-icc-trophy-2025-bollywood-films-box-office-11735619727575.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 05:37:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 most anticipated game from 2025; garners 230 million views on trailer - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>GTA 6 Most Anticipated Game from 2025; Garners 230 Million Views on Trailer</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 5, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Sportskeeda</p><p>The Grand Theft Auto 6 trailer has shattered records with over 230 million views on YouTube ahead of its release in 2025, doubling the views of its predecessor's trailer.</p><ul><li>The trailer amassed 90 million views within 24 hours.</li><li>It set records for the most viewed and most liked video game trailer on YouTube in 24 hours.</li><li>The game is expected to return to Vice City and feature a new female protagonist, Lucia.</li><li>Release anticipated in fall 2025 for next-gen consoles.</li></ul><blockquote>"Most Viewed Video Game Reveal on YouTube in 24 Hours"</blockquote><p>The anticipation for GTA 6 showcases the game's strong fanbase and the excitement for new developments in the series.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/gta-6-most-anticipated-game-from-2025-garners-230-million-views-on-trailer-124123100208_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/gta-6-most-anticipated-game-from-2025-garners-230-million-views-on-trailer-124123100208_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 05:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>