<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:19:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 17:19:43 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pixel 10 reportedly using MediaTek modem as Google strives for better battery & heat - 9to5Google]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pixel 10 Reportedly Using MediaTek Modem for Improved Battery and Thermal Performance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 8, 2024 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> 9to5Google</p><img width="1600" height="800" src="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2024/11/Pixel-9-Wintergreen-2.jpg?quality=82&amp;strip=all&amp;w=1600" alt="Pixel 10" /><figcaption>Image of the Pixel 10 prototype.</figcaption><p>Google is set to enhance the performance of its upcoming Pixel 10 by incorporating a new MediaTek modem, departing from the previous Samsung modem which faced issues with heating and signal strength.</p><ul><li>The Pixel 10 will utilize the MediaTek T900 modem, based on the unreleased “M85” generation.</li><li>Previous Pixel models faced overheating issues stemming from the Samsung modem.</li><li>Google has acknowledged that modem performance has led to higher return rates for Pixel phones.</li><li>MediaTek’s modem is anticipated to improve efficiency and battery life, although performance comparisons to Qualcomm's modems are yet undisclosed.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tensor overheating problems have been the single biggest reason for people returning Pixel phones.”</blockquote><p>The shift to a MediaTek modem reflects Google's focus on improving user satisfaction by addressing performance shortcomings in the Pixel line.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://9to5google.com/2024/12/15/google-pixel-10-mediatek-modem-report/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://9to5google.com/2024/12/15/google-pixel-10-mediatek-modem-report/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 16:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xiaomi Redmi Buds 6 review: Bank for the buck - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/xiaomi-redmi-buds-6-review-bank-for-the-buck-article-12890381.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/xiaomi-redmi-buds-6-review-bank-for-the-buck-article-12890381.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 15:02:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OTT services see growth in AVoD as cost-sensitive audiences savour free content - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OTT services see growth in AVoD as cost-sensitive audiences savour free content</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p> <p>Video-streaming platforms utilizing hybrid models of subscription and advertising are witnessing substantial viewership for free content, accounting for 50% to 90% of total viewership.</p> <ul> <li>OTT platforms with hybrid models are thriving.</li> <li>Free content is highly popular, making up a large portion of viewership.</li> <li>Experts estimate free content viewership at 50% to 90%.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“Platforms are adapting to cost-sensitive audiences who prefer free content.”</blockquote> <p>This trend signifies a notable shift towards free viewing options among audiences, reaffirming the importance of accessibility in streaming media.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/industry/media/free-avod-content-remains-main-draw-on-ott-platforms-brings-in-50-90-of-viewership-11734248411785.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/industry/media/free-avod-content-remains-main-draw-on-ott-platforms-brings-in-50-90-of-viewership-11734248411785.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:51:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ITC Foods targets growth in north and west India amid shift to branded products | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>ITC Foods Targets Growth in North and West India Amid Shift to Branded Products</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Company Business News</p><p>ITC Ltd is set to expand its food brands and explore premium market opportunities as more consumers in India's poorer regions begin to seek branded products.</p><ul><li>ITC Ltd aims to scale its existing food brands and enter the premium segment.</li><li>Growing consumer class in regions like Bihar, Uttar Pradesh, and Rajasthan is increasing demand for branded foods.</li><li>The company is considering acquisitions to strengthen its brand portfolio.</li></ul><blockquote>“As more consumers enter the consuming class, we expect demand for branded products to grow significantly.” - Senior Company Official</blockquote><p>This strategic focus on brand growth comes in light of shifting consumer preferences toward packaged and branded food products in underserved regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/itc-foods-targets-growth-in-north-and-west-india-amid-shift-to-branded-products-11734083089065.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/itc-foods-targets-growth-in-north-and-west-india-amid-shift-to-branded-products-11734083089065.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:39:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Leaks: Upcoming Flagship Smartphone Might Lack Telephoto Camera & Feature Rounded Corners - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Leaks: Upcoming Flagship Smartphone Might Lack Telephoto Camera & Feature Rounded Corners</h1>
<p><strong>Published at:</strong> 15 Dec 2024 08:06 PM (IST) | <strong>Source:</strong> ABP Live</p>
<img src="https://feeds.abplive.com/onecms/images/uploaded-images/2024/12/15/bd0883fa92727b3c0764d43604b63d161734273294817555_original.png?impolicy=abp_cdn&amp;imwidth=1200&amp;height=675" alt="Samsung Galaxy S25 Leaks" />
<figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra might sport flatter frame with soft and rounded corners.</figcaption>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra is reportedly undergoing design changes and may lack a traditional telephoto camera, causing speculation about its innovation in camera technology.</p>
<ul>
<li>The S25 Ultra could feature a flatter design with rounded corners.</li>
<li>Leaks suggest the absence of a periscope telephoto lens, replacing it with ALoP (All Lenses on Prism) technology.</li>
<li>[There are rumors about a 50MP ultrawide sensor being introduced.]</li>
<li>Tech enthusiasts are eagerly awaiting the official unveiling of the Galaxy S25 series at a rumored event in January.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The upcoming Galaxy S25 Ultra might adopt a flatter frame with softer, rounded corners, marking a departure from the sharper look of earlier models."</blockquote>
<p>The leaks have generated considerable interest, but some skepticism remains regarding their authenticity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/samsung-galaxy-s25-leaks-release-launch-date-camera-design-display-battery-specifications-features-1737792</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/samsung-galaxy-s25-leaks-release-launch-date-camera-design-display-battery-specifications-features-1737792</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:36:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign: All you may want to know about upcoming co-op game - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQTFhvSkJKbjNoTG56TkZNVURNNUQxZ09GWGdIUnNMZndmSFJQZjRUS1FHZWNpa01tUXFSdGR4d0Y3VkZBaHhYLTF5SWNyY2hlMFBSLUg3WC1jRm5ua0RnNjkzN0x0S3dQekRza29LMERTSzJrQ2FJMklFVnJfLU5vRE80OHh1QURlNEN2MUN1V09WYmpfa1NZQlNtSnJMeGhkeHlOSHRTcWVrYk5ZSkVhVG5raGpFUXJ6OUZiTUVEcENwMDZKRjdtUnBkMGxQVUJvUnNYaGtuVkU5YmZxM3VmYXp30gHnAUFVX3lxTE0zRWxNQk04YUhDUkp3R1EwMkhubl9seUZpRUJkdFV6YTFQQi1mcEJzN2xWNGxFZ2lBaFd0dFBuSkhPV2ExUWhZNGJDdGxtQzM2MXJwUmg1eExtLXNBaXJDSWxNZjB5VDROSG40Q0NVdXJTSzQ4S1hfVkdrTDlYZmJiRXdJZGRPV3lTUWc5a3lHbUIzNTNUV3dhVlB2Xy1JeWpFanpNdUJ2Z3ZMbW1qZUd2NVQtV055TWZ5VV95d1E5d0FoS2JiZXBPd0kxNHpjR194QTRwVTRBRGcwZVdiUjFfSmdOUmdPTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxQTFhvSkJKbjNoTG56TkZNVURNNUQxZ09GWGdIUnNMZndmSFJQZjRUS1FHZWNpa01tUXFSdGR4d0Y3VkZBaHhYLTF5SWNyY2hlMFBSLUg3WC1jRm5ua0RnNjkzN0x0S3dQekRza29LMERTSzJrQ2FJMklFVnJfLU5vRE80OHh1QURlNEN2MUN1V09WYmpfa1NZQlNtSnJMeGhkeHlOSHRTcWVrYk5ZSkVhVG5raGpFUXJ6OUZiTUVEcENwMDZKRjdtUnBkMGxQVUJvUnNYaGtuVkU5YmZxM3VmYXp30gHnAUFVX3lxTE0zRWxNQk04YUhDUkp3R1EwMkhubl9seUZpRUJkdFV6YTFQQi1mcEJzN2xWNGxFZ2lBaFd0dFBuSkhPV2ExUWhZNGJDdGxtQzM2MXJwUmg1eExtLXNBaXJDSWxNZjB5VDROSG40Q0NVdXJTSzQ4S1hfVkdrTDlYZmJiRXdJZGRPV3lTUWc5a3lHbUIzNTNUV3dhVlB2Xy1JeWpFanpNdUJ2Z3ZMbW1qZUd2NVQtV055TWZ5VV95d1E5d0FoS2JiZXBPd0kxNHpjR194QTRwVTRBRGcwZVdiUjFfSmdOUmdPTQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 14:26:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI unveils Video Interaction features for ChatGPT users - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OpenAI Introduces Video Interaction Features for ChatGPT Users</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p><figure><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/chatgpt-logo-1734263023.webp" alt="ChatGPT" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>ChatGPT</figcaption></figure><p>OpenAI continues to elevate ChatGPT’s capabilities by introducing several new features that redefine user interaction with the AI. The platform now incorporates video recognition and real-time interaction, enhancing how users engage with the generative AI chatbot.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>ChatGPT can recognize objects via camera input and provide instant insights.</li><li>Features are rolling out for ChatGPT Plus and Pro users in December, with a later launch for enterprise and educational sectors expected by January 2025.</li><li>Sora Turbo allows users to create ultra-realistic videos from text prompts, available for Plus and Pro users worldwide.</li><li>Sora Turbo features include adjustable video length, various formats, customization options, and a community showcase for trending creations.</li><li>Regulatory constraints keep Sora Turbo from being available in the UK, EU, and Switzerland.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes:</h2><blockquote>“These updates are part of OpenAI’s 12-day product launch series, which aims to democratize access to advanced AI technologies.”</blockquote><h2>Conclusion:</h2><p>OpenAI’s latest features in ChatGPT enhance user interaction through significant advancements in video processing and creation, catering to a broader audience while aiming for future accessibility.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/openai-unveils-video-interaction-features-for-chatgpt-users-2024-12-15-966351</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/openai-unveils-video-interaction-features-for-chatgpt-users-2024-12-15-966351</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:02:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for December 15: Win in-game goodies and rewards - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for December 15: Win in-game goodies and rewards</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 15, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gaming News</p>
<p>The article discusses the redeem codes available for players of Garena Free Fire MAX on December 15, providing details on how players can win exclusive in-game goodies and rewards.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Introduction of redeem codes specific to December 15.</li>
    <li>Instructions on how to use these codes for in-game benefits.</li>
    <li>Benefits players can expect from redeeming the codes.</li>
    <li>Encouragement for players to redeem quickly as codes may be limited.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Don’t miss your chance to grab these limited-time rewards!”</blockquote>
<p>This update emphasizes community engagement and encourages players to stay active as new codes offer exciting benefits in the game.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-december-15-win-in-game-goodies-and-rewards/articleshow/116338869.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-for-december-15-win-in-game-goodies-and-rewards/articleshow/116338869.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp Brings Numeric Keypad for Calls to iOS - Gizchina.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp Introduces Numeric Keypad for Calls on iOS</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> GizChina</p><img src="https://www.gizchina.com/wp-content/uploads/images/2024/12/WA_CALL_A_PHONE_NUMBER_FEATURE_IOS.webp" alt="WhatsApp Dial Pad for iOS" width="1440" height="1118"><figcaption>WhatsApp's new virtual dial pad for iOS.</figcaption><p>WhatsApp is rolling out a new feature for its iOS users, allowing them to make calls using a virtual dial pad. This feature is already available on Android and simplifies calling someone by entering their phone number directly.</p><ul><li>The virtual dial pad can only call registered WhatsApp numbers, no need to save contacts.</li><li>Currently available only in the beta version via TestFlight.</li><li>Unlike Android's version, this dial pad lacks autocomplete capabilities.</li><li>This enhancement aims to improve the user experience on WhatsApp for iOS users.</li><li>WhatsApp is gradually evolving towards becoming a full-fledged communication platform.</li></ul><blockquote>“This development highlights WhatsApp’s ongoing efforts to enhance its calling features.”</blockquote><p>This new feature marks a positive step for WhatsApp, potentially making it a more user-friendly tool for iOS users looking for straightforward calling options.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gizchina.com/2024/12/15/whatsapp-brings-numeric-keypad-for-calls-to-ios/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gizchina.com/2024/12/15/whatsapp-brings-numeric-keypad-for-calls-to-ios/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:38:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple’s Siri gets smarter, iPhone 16 gets exclusive AI features in iOS 18.2 - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Enhances Siri and iPhone 16 with AI Features in iOS 18.2</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p><figure><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/siri-1734262549.webp" alt="Siri" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Siri</figcaption></figure><p>Apple has released the iOS 18.2 update, introducing advanced AI capabilities and exclusive features for iPhone 16 users, improving user experience significantly.</p><ul><li>Introduction of the standalone Image Playground app for creating animated images using generative AI.</li><li>Launch of the Image Wand feature for converting sketches into refined images.</li><li>Expansion of writing tools, including the new Describe Your Change feature for text editing.</li><li>Exclusive feature Visual Intelligence for the iPhone 16 series for real-time object recognition and text translation.</li><li>ChatGPT integration makes Siri smarter, enabling complex query responses and photo analysis.</li><li>iOS 18.2 is available for all iPhones supporting iOS 18.</li></ul><blockquote>“Siri can now answer complex queries, explain documents, and analyze photos, taking personal assistance to the next level.”</blockquote><p>The iOS 18.2 update marks another step forward in Apple’s commitment to enhancing user experience through innovative technologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/apple-s-siri-gets-smarter-iphone-16-gets-exclusive-ai-features-in-ios-18-2-2024-12-15-966349</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/apple-s-siri-gets-smarter-iphone-16-gets-exclusive-ai-features-in-ios-18-2-2024-12-15-966349</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:36:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple iPhone 17 Air Has Reportedly Gone Under Mass Production, Here's What We Know - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple iPhone 17 Air Enters Mass Production Phase</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Macrumors</p>
<h2><strong>Image with Caption:</strong></h2>
<p>No image available.</p>
<p>Apple's much talked about next iPhone, the iPhone 17 Air, has reportedly entered the New Product Introduction (NPI) phase at Foxconn. This model is expected to replace the 'Plus' variant in the iPhone 17 lineup and is set to be released in 2025.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The iPhone 17 Air is anticipated to be Apple's slimmest smartphone yet, with thickness ranging between 5mm and 6mm.</li>
  <li>Prototypes suggest the elimination of the physical SIM card tray in favor of eSIM technology.</li>
  <li>It may feature a centralized camera bump on the back, potentially with a single sensor instead of a dual-camera system.</li>
  <li>Rumors indicate a reduction in battery capacity due to the slimmer design.</li>
  <li>Audio setup may include only a single speaker in the earpiece.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The NPI phase takes a product from the concept stage to mass production.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while there are promising innovations with the iPhone 17 Air, there are also trade-offs regarding features and specifications compared to previous models.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/apple-iphone-17-air-specifications-features-launch-release-date-mass-production-begins-what-we-know-1737746</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/apple-iphone-17-air-specifications-features-launch-release-date-mass-production-begins-what-we-know-1737746</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 11:00:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Awards 2024: 11th Edition Crowns Winners—See The Full List Inside - Oneindia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Game Awards 2024: 11th Edition Crowns Winners—See The Full List Inside</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Sunday, December 15, 2024, 16:17 [IST] - <strong>Source:</strong> OneIndia News</p><img src="https://imagesvs.oneindia.com/img/2024/12/small-1734259628.jpg" alt="Game Awards 2024" width="600" height="338"><figcaption>Game Awards 2024</figcaption><p>The 11th annual Game Awards were held at the prestigious Peacock Theatre in Los Angeles, celebrating the most remarkable achievements in the gaming world.</p><ul><li>The Game of the Year 2024 was awarded to <strong>Astro Bot</strong> by Team Asobi.</li><li>Astro Bot also won multiple awards including Best Game Direction and Best Action/Adventure Game.</li><li>Exciting announcements included new titles like <strong>Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</strong> and <strong>Dispatch</strong>.</li><li>A special Innovation Award was presented to <strong>Fallout</strong> for Best Adaptation.</li><li>Notable winners included <strong>Metaphor: ReFantazio</strong> for Best Narrative and <strong>League of Legends</strong> for Best Esports Game.</li><li><strong>Grand Theft Auto VI</strong> was named the Most Anticipated Game of 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Game Awards 2024 celebrated gaming as an art form, blending technology, storytelling, and community.”</blockquote><p>The Game Awards showcased the ongoing evolution in gaming, with its ability to inspire and unite audiences worldwide.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oneindia.com/india/game-awards-2024-11th-edition-crowns-winners-see-the-full-list-inside-4016329.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oneindia.com/india/game-awards-2024-11th-edition-crowns-winners-see-the-full-list-inside-4016329.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:47:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 17 Air launch confirmed? Likely to replace iPhone 17 Plus - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iPhone 17 Air Launch Confirmed: What's New?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://cf-img-a-in.tosshub.com/sites/visualstory/wp/2024/11/cropped-iPhone-17-Air.png" alt="iPhone 17 Air" /><figcaption>Render of iPhone 17 Air</figcaption><p>The upcoming iPhone 17 Air is set to launch in 2025, expected to replace the iPhone 17 Plus model, as confirmed by supply chain reports.</p><ul><li>iPhone 17 Air has entered the New Product Introduction phase at Foxconn.</li><li>The device is reported to be approximately 2mm slimmer than the current iPhone 16 Pro.</li><li>Expected display size ranges between 6.55 and 6.65 inches.</li><li>Will feature a custom-designed 5G modem chip optimized for battery life.</li><li>New rear camera design anticipated with a single 48MP lens.</li><li>Debut alongside iPhone 17 series, which includes Pro and Pro Max models.</li></ul><blockquote>“The NPI process involves design validation, prototype testing, supplier qualification, manufacturing development, and pilot production before full-scale manufacturing.”</blockquote><p>The iPhone 17 Air promises exciting design changes and enhancements, marking a significant step in Apple’s smartphone evolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/iphone-17-air-launch-confirmed-likely-to-replace-iphone-17-plus-194602-15-12-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/visualstories/technology/iphone-17-air-launch-confirmed-likely-to-replace-iphone-17-plus-194602-15-12-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:36:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to plan the perfect serve for a house party | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How to plan the perfect serve for a house party</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/subscription/onepagecheckout/lm/staging/extensivepaywall/starpaper.png" alt="icons"><figcaption>Image related to preparing cocktails at home.</figcaption><p>In bartending lexicon, the perfect serve is the ultimate cocktail experience defined by various parameters such as ingredients, temperature, glassware, and technique.</p><ul><li>The classic Old Fashioned serves best in a rocks glass at 7-10 degrees Celsius.</li><li>Chill the glass with ice water and use large ice cubes to minimize dilution.</li><li>Neil Alexander, a beverage consultant, emphasizes the importance of garnishes like fresh orange peel for enhancing flavor.</li><li>Proper technique is crucial: shake cocktails with juices, stir spirit-forward drinks, and pour gently for layered drinks.</li></ul><blockquote>“Knowing that you should shake, not stir cocktails which have juices or creams in them and vice versa for the spirit-forward drinks; pouring gently over the back of a spoon to maintain distinct layers.” - Neil Alexander</blockquote><p>This article provides insights into how hobbyists can recreate the bar experience at home while emphasizing the importance of technique and presentation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/food/perfect-serve-recipe-house-party-2024-11734079163185.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/food/perfect-serve-recipe-house-party-2024-11734079163185.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 10:30:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YouTube lets you watch videos in preferred languages: Here's how - NewsBytes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>YouTube lets you watch videos in preferred languages: Here's how</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NewsBytesApp</p><img alt="YouTube lets you watch videos in preferred languages: Here's how" title="YouTube lets you watch videos in preferred languages: Here's how" src="https://i.cdn.newsbytesapp.com/images/l70020241215114346.jpeg"><figcaption>The feature only works for videos that provide audio in additional languages</figcaption><p>YouTube has introduced a new feature allowing users to watch select videos in their preferred languages, enhancing accessibility and user experience.</p><ul><li>YouTube automatically defaults to users' preferred language but allows manual changes.</li><li>To change language on the web, access 'Settings' in the video player and select 'Audio track.'</li><li>For mobile, navigate to 'Settings' -> 'Additional settings' -> 'Audio.'</li><li>The feature enhances multilingual video search and personalized recommendations.</li></ul><blockquote>“The service is aimed at enhancing user experience by catering to their linguistic preferences.”</blockquote><p>This new feature enhances accessibility and personalization on YouTube, making it easier for users to interact with content in their preferred languages.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/science/watch-youtube-videos-in-your-preferred-language/story</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/science/watch-youtube-videos-in-your-preferred-language/story</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 08:42:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Discover rolls out Material 3 redesign [U] - 9to5Google]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE1SZndjLWYzLTNqZHFHbUdGdE5ta3hBRi1TTThDWXpFQkdDTk04RWtEMld0OU1icWFNclc0V3FoeGdCY1lKVXVYLUJZb0ZtUm5CUTJlaUh0ZDdKMDBDODEyMHc4enJzbjE1TjJkTU9ycVBfUm5VVjdsbTlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE1SZndjLWYzLTNqZHFHbUdGdE5ta3hBRi1TTThDWXpFQkdDTk04RWtEMld0OU1icWFNclc0V3FoeGdCY1lKVXVYLUJZb0ZtUm5CUTJlaUh0ZDdKMDBDODEyMHc4enJzbjE1TjJkTU9ycVBfUm5VVjdsbTlB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 08:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Intelligences gets headline on ‘high-profile’ US murder wrong; BBC complains - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Intelligences Misreports High-Profile US Murder; BBC Issues Complaint</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> BBC News</p><p>This article reports on a significant error made by Apple Intelligences regarding a high-profile murder case in the US, which prompted a formal complaint from the BBC.</p><ul><li>Apple Intelligences incorrectly reported details surrounding a prominent murder case in the US.</li><li>This misinformation has raised concerns over the reliability of sources in high-stakes news reporting.</li><li>The BBC issued a complaint, seeking accountability for the error.</li></ul><blockquote>“An accurate representation of events is crucial, especially in sensitive cases.”</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the importance of accuracy in news reporting and the repercussions of misinformation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/apple-intelligences-gets-headline-on-high-profile-us-murder-wrong-bbc-complains/articleshow/116335166.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/apple-intelligences-gets-headline-on-high-profile-us-murder-wrong-bbc-complains/articleshow/116335166.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 08:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Introduces ‘Projects’ To Simplify Organising Chats and Files for ChatGPT Users - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxOT2Q5bVMzMlREVzFQNjlCZGJZS0c1T1JCRXZMT1FBNE1NaC1sMUxxRG9qQnAxSG9rbjJPM1JWM3FmSTlSeG9Eb2FCQUQ4NUJDMzB4cVRRWlYxaUs4OHljbEVzWlhOc3BmalZseGhKaVBNclplOGlxSC1pXzhOMDhqZzhlZXBjdzJ1VFRZSDJETlFwTGt4elFPZWQ5YzBlZVZ3OVczR1BVcy1CbUVBaG5mTzhiX2lRcGV0YVFJQk1vb2ozUjU0Z19MOXprTUxlamFDa3J0TzdJcmTSAd4BQVVfeXFMUHMzZXpoYzMzZWdJbmUxNE5US1J5NndxREFONU05VTMyYjM5bmdSZ09hYXlhRWM1dnoxd21LcU1BR3hieVhJVUw1b3hPc3BXd1FLMXVtQ0IzNHZOR3hpNnNyZ09WMElqZnJONF80M0xRaGY2QzJQbjhMa1F0bEFWN2VWWnNCeU1wOXRlcDJ0SnZuV1VpTzU5RGt5RGFWU2lFOFVsUzVtZDRCa3VteEZBa2JhQlJGVXlIbFZTOERzRWFRS2U3d0FWUzZ0d0J2WlFJUng4bTZXMGFvTXVwLUJ3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2AFBVV95cUxOT2Q5bVMzMlREVzFQNjlCZGJZS0c1T1JCRXZMT1FBNE1NaC1sMUxxRG9qQnAxSG9rbjJPM1JWM3FmSTlSeG9Eb2FCQUQ4NUJDMzB4cVRRWlYxaUs4OHljbEVzWlhOc3BmalZseGhKaVBNclplOGlxSC1pXzhOMDhqZzhlZXBjdzJ1VFRZSDJETlFwTGt4elFPZWQ5YzBlZVZ3OVczR1BVcy1CbUVBaG5mTzhiX2lRcGV0YVFJQk1vb2ozUjU0Z19MOXprTUxlamFDa3J0TzdJcmTSAd4BQVVfeXFMUHMzZXpoYzMzZWdJbmUxNE5US1J5NndxREFONU05VTMyYjM5bmdSZ09hYXlhRWM1dnoxd21LcU1BR3hieVhJVUw1b3hPc3BXd1FLMXVtQ0IzNHZOR3hpNnNyZ09WMElqZnJONF80M0xRaGY2QzJQbjhMa1F0bEFWN2VWWnNCeU1wOXRlcDJ0SnZuV1VpTzU5RGt5RGFWU2lFOFVsUzVtZDRCa3VteEZBa2JhQlJGVXlIbFZTOERzRWFRS2U3d0FWUzZ0d0J2WlFJUng4bTZXMGFvTXVwLUJ3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 08:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI brings Christmas celebrations to ChatGPT with new “Santa Mode”: Know what it is - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OpenAI brings Christmas celebrations to ChatGPT with new Santa Mode</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><p>OpenAI has unveiled a new feature called Santa Mode for ChatGPT, designed to enhance the user experience during the Christmas season.</p><ul><li>Introduces festive themes and responses.</li><li>Offers users engaging Christmas-related interactions.</li></ul><blockquote>No notable quotes found in the article.</blockquote><p>This new feature aims to make conversations more enjoyable and aligned with the holiday spirit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tech.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/openai-brings-christmas-celebrations-to-chatgpt-with-new-santa-mode-know-what-it-is-71734188012052.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tech.hindustantimes.com/web-stories/openai-brings-christmas-celebrations-to-chatgpt-with-new-santa-mode-know-what-it-is-71734188012052.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:30:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Realme 14x 5G to launch with 6000mAh battery, under Rs 15000: Launching on December 18 - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Realme 14x 5G to Launch with 6000mAh Battery, Under Rs 15000: Launching on December 18</h1><p><strong>Date: December 15, 2024 | Source: India TV News</strong></p><figure><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2024/12/elon-musk-reportedly-on-the-verge-of-raising-billions-for-his-ai-company-2024-12-15t124216-1734246650.webp" alt="Realme 14x 5G" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>Realme 14x 5G</figcaption></figure><p>Realme is preparing to launch its latest mid-range smartphone, the Realme 14x 5G, in India on December 18. This device is notable for its massive 6000mAh battery and an IP69 rating, targeting the budget smartphone segment.</p><ul><li>The launch date is set for December 18.</li><li>The smartphone features a flat-frame design with a diamond-cut gradient back panel.</li><li>It will come in three RAM variants, with the highest being 8GB RAM and 256GB storage.</li><li>The display is a 6.67-inch HD+ IPS LCD, ideal for streaming and gaming.</li><li>The device has an IP69 rating, making it water and dust resistant.</li><li>Expected price is under Rs 15,000, potentially making it the world's cheapest IP69-rated smartphone.</li></ul><blockquote>"The upcoming smartphone claims to last longer while being used for multitasking, backed by a 6000 mAh battery."</blockquote><p>The Realme 14x 5G is poised to make a significant impact in the budget smartphone market with its advanced features and affordability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/realme-14x-5g-to-launch-with-6000mah-battery-under-rs-15000-launching-on-december-18-2024-12-15-966308</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/news/realme-14x-5g-to-launch-with-6000mah-battery-under-rs-15000-launching-on-december-18-2024-12-15-966308</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:13:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Pixel 9a complete spec sheet & pricing revealed via carrier listing - gizmochina]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gizmochina.com/2024/12/15/google-pixel-9a-complete-spec-sheet-pricing-revealed/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gizmochina.com/2024/12/15/google-pixel-9a-complete-spec-sheet-pricing-revealed/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:30:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone SE 4 rumored upgrade sets the stage for a big Pixel 8a showdown - Tom's Guide]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPWVI2TWxhM2tCVHY1cDNLOXM1ekhMdXBiWjhRM3Q5Q01VUXhEdWJJRkZnM05qUmZHTWhaQmlqZUtiWlY5Vm0yM1VSOXZ1Y1UwT3pjbzZNMC01X05kY0JNUVlBM2x4YlZ3YWxvaWkyZnV6YTBueVk2Z0EtNUFOMjRMYmJrellueG5LalE2MmZ0bDJZazlHMi1NUkdxX1hmU1NfMFZ5SUFFZ3pXTTZ5dFNrb2RJNHVfVF8tMEtscA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxPWVI2TWxhM2tCVHY1cDNLOXM1ekhMdXBiWjhRM3Q5Q01VUXhEdWJJRkZnM05qUmZHTWhaQmlqZUtiWlY5Vm0yM1VSOXZ1Y1UwT3pjbzZNMC01X05kY0JNUVlBM2x4YlZ3YWxvaWkyZnV6YTBueVk2Z0EtNUFOMjRMYmJrellueG5LalE2MmZ0bDJZazlHMi1NUkdxX1hmU1NfMFZ5SUFFZ3pXTTZ5dFNrb2RJNHVfVF8tMEtscA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Weekly Tech News Wrap: Redmi Note 14, vivo X200, Samsung XR Headset, New Cancellation Charges By Flipkart and Myntra, and More - Smartprix]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.smartprix.com/bytes/weekly-tech-news-wrap-redmi-note-14-vivo-x200-samsung-xr-headset-new-cancellation-charges-by-flipkart-and-myntra-and-more/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.smartprix.com/bytes/weekly-tech-news-wrap-redmi-note-14-vivo-x200-samsung-xr-headset-new-cancellation-charges-by-flipkart-and-myntra-and-more/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:28:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Up to 50 480p videos per month! All about Sora video generator - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Up to 50 480p Videos Per Month: All About Sora Video Generator</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> etnownews.com</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/thumb/116331599.jpg?imgsize=17088&amp;width=420&amp;height=746&amp;resizemode=76" alt="Up to 50 480p Videos Per Month! All about Sora video generator">
<figcaption>Source: Shutterstock</figcaption>
<p>OpenAI has recently released its new AI video generator Sora, allowing users to create up to 50 low-resolution videos per month.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sora is available for premium ChatGPT users.</li>
<li>Users can create films up to 1080p resolution and 20 seconds long.</li>
<li>Sora does not incur additional costs for Plus account users, emphasizing affordability.</li>
<li>The Pro plan offers ten times the usage, sharper resolutions, and longer durations.</li>
<li>Sora-generated movies include C2PA metadata to ensure transparency.</li>
<li>Currently, only a limited number of testers can use Sora for videos of humans.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"OpenAI said it is blocking content with nudity and preventing the most harmful uses, including child sexual abuse material and sexual deepfakes."</blockquote>
<p>This release represents a significant advancement in AI-generated content, balancing accessibility and responsibility in content creation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/web-stories/up-to-50-480p-videos-per-month-all-about-sora-video-generator/photostory/116331585.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/web-stories/up-to-50-480p-videos-per-month-all-about-sora-video-generator/photostory/116331585.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:39:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 luxury hotels to celebrate the end of 2024 | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Luxury Hotels to Celebrate the End of 2024</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Not Available] | <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>As the holiday season approaches, consider indulging in luxurious stays at unique properties, offering a blend of comfort and cultural experiences, away from typical tourist spots.</p><ul><li>Explore luxury hotels that provide a distinctive experience.</li><li>Learn about unique ways to embrace local culture and cuisine.</li><li>Enjoy less crowded environments for a more intimate celebration.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/ideas/christmas-new-year-2025-travel-guide-holiday-season-11734012226880.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/ideas/christmas-new-year-2025-travel-guide-holiday-season-11734012226880.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:30:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 17 To iPhone 17 Pro Max: Launch Date, Price In India, Design, Cameras, Specs, Leaks, Everything We Know - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/gadgets/iphone-17-to-iphone-17-pro-max-launch-date-price-in-india-design-cameras-specs-leaks-everything-we-know-so-far-article-116331262</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/technology-science/gadgets/iphone-17-to-iphone-17-pro-max-launch-date-price-in-india-design-cameras-specs-leaks-everything-we-know-so-far-article-116331262</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 04:15:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[POCO X4 Pro 5G: Snapdragon Power Meets 108MP Brilliance - Udaipur Kiran]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>POCO X4 Pro 5G: Snapdragon Power Meets 108MP Brilliance</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Udaipur Kiran</p><img src="https://i0.wp.com/udaipurkiran.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/POCO-X4-Pro-5G.jpg?resize=840%2C473&amp;ssl=1" alt="POCO X4 Pro 5G" width="840" height="473"><figcaption>POCO X4 Pro 5G</figcaption><p>The POCO X4 Pro 5G offers a powerful combination of performance and camera capabilities, positioning itself as a strong contender in the mid-range smartphone market.</p><ul><li>Features a Snapdragon 695 chipset for balanced performance.</li><li>Includes a stunning 6.67-inch AMOLED display with a 120Hz refresh rate.</li><li>Equipped with a 108MP primary camera with good performance in well-lit conditions.</li><li>Offers a long-lasting 5000mAh battery with 67W fast charging.</li><li>Runs on MIUI 13, based on Android 11, with various customization options.</li></ul><blockquote>“For budget-conscious consumers looking for a feature-rich smartphone, the POCO X4 Pro 5G is a solid choice.”</blockquote><p>The POCO X4 Pro 5G successfully combines style and functionality, making it a significant player in the competitive mid-range smartphone market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://udaipurkiran.com/poco-x4-pro-5g-snapdragon-power-meets-108mp-brilliance/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://udaipurkiran.com/poco-x4-pro-5g-snapdragon-power-meets-108mp-brilliance/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 02:31:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 amla recipes to boost immunity in winters - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Amla Recipes to Boost Immunity in Winters</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116319148,imgsize-53794,width-400,resizemode-4/116319148.jpg" alt="5 amla recipes to boost immunity in winters" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>Amla - A Winter Superfood</figcaption><p>Amla or the Indian gooseberry is a powerhouse of vitamin C and antioxidants, ideal for boosting immunity during the winter months.</p><ul><li><strong>Amla Chutney:</strong> A tangy condiment made with green chilies, coriander, mint, garlic, and amla.</li><li><strong>Amla Candy:</strong> Sweet and tangy treats made by coating amla with jaggery or sugar.</li><li><strong>Amla Honey Shot:</strong> A drink made with fresh amla juice and honey to detoxify and boost immunity.</li><li><strong>Amla Murabba:</strong> A sweet tonic made with amla cooked in sugar syrup, flavored with cardamom and saffron.</li><li><strong>Amla Soup:</strong> A nutritious soup made with chopped amla, ginger, garlic, and spices.</li></ul><blockquote>Amla is rich in vitamin C, which strengthens white blood cells and enhances the body’s ability to fight infections.</blockquote><p>Incorporating these five recipes into your winter diet can enhance immunity while adding flavor and health benefits.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/food-news/boost-your-winter-immunity-5-delicious-amla-recipes/articleshow/116319179.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/food-news/boost-your-winter-immunity-5-delicious-amla-recipes/articleshow/116319179.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gadgets Weekly: Samsung Galaxy S24 Enterprise Edition and more - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gadgets Weekly: Samsung Galaxy S24 Enterprise Edition and more</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 15 December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p><img src="https://images.deccanherald.com/deccanherald%2F2024-12-13%2Fzxcroti5%2FSamsung-Galaxy-S24-24-Ultra-Enterprise-Edition-phones.jpg" alt="Samsung Galaxy S24, 24 Ultra Enterprise Edition phones."><figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S24, 24 Ultra Enterprise Edition phones. Credit: Samsung India</figcaption><p>This week's Gadgets Weekly features new technology launches from various companies including Samsung, Epson, and Portronics, summarizing key products and innovations in consumer electronics.</p><ul><li><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 Enterprise Edition:</strong> Offers Knox Suite for enhanced security and 7 years of firmware updates.</li><li><strong>Epson CW-C8050:</strong> High-speed label printer suitable for businesses, capable of printing up to 3,000 labels per day.</li><li><strong>Panasonic i-PRO AI Camera:</strong> Features AI-powered surveillance capabilities with options for high zoom and long-range performance.</li><li><strong>Portronics Vayu 5.0:</strong> A cordless tyre inflator designed for ease of use with various inflation modes.</li><li><strong>Blaupunkt BTW300 Moksha+:</strong> TWS earphones with Active Noise Cancellation and up to 50 hours of playtime.</li></ul><blockquote>“Generation Green embodies our commitment to the Government of India’s Net-Zero vision.” - Rakesh Bhardwaj, OPPO India</blockquote><p>This article provides a comprehensive look at the latest in technology and how these products cater to both consumer and business needs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/technology/gadgets/gadgets-weekly-samsung-galaxy-s24-enterprise-edition-and-more-3316762</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/technology/gadgets/gadgets-weekly-samsung-galaxy-s24-enterprise-edition-and-more-3316762</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Companies alert as along come AI web spiders - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQZUtmTmNhUHBpYUNZQ1h4dS1BUzFUanNqbFdQUHdoNUN2TGxodHRVQUJRQkExbElhMGx3MWJLY2dUQmR4Ykt0dkppeGF2U2tLRFJfdlZ5Z281Vmh4bzYtMl9wai1JN0VCckl1VlhMaDVMN3pUWXYzcGZsVkFhVURfa05IRWJKSldQQURzZWo2SDN4UlJCbWpLVEhOVFV0ZDA1SFJLU2tNdkVkNzR5VEhfR1RlOGxPS2JDSzVLNkJrZlpYa1pHZGfSAcsBQVVfeXFMT2hiODZSWWJzTWsyWGFCbWprX09BbHJwQ3pKUmk2TlFIVFlVb1F5VG5QelNaSHlvRWhSaklPVFFpUm5lUzI1anBKaEFVUXVJS3dDVnVCLXIxVlp4a3FrQV9fNl83RFJ1UnhtRzU5bG93VXNVTFBNZnlhY3cwSkp3NEllanJEM3NCMTFpZEZ5cXBtVHMyaS1XSWkxWm9Bdk1UTUJoM0F3NHdjajhFM1RTdkdpZ0tPcVNfMU90SzFyaS1pcm5VQUdCWmJBa28?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQZUtmTmNhUHBpYUNZQ1h4dS1BUzFUanNqbFdQUHdoNUN2TGxodHRVQUJRQkExbElhMGx3MWJLY2dUQmR4Ykt0dkppeGF2U2tLRFJfdlZ5Z281Vmh4bzYtMl9wai1JN0VCckl1VlhMaDVMN3pUWXYzcGZsVkFhVURfa05IRWJKSldQQURzZWo2SDN4UlJCbWpLVEhOVFV0ZDA1SFJLU2tNdkVkNzR5VEhfR1RlOGxPS2JDSzVLNkJrZlpYa1pHZGfSAcsBQVVfeXFMT2hiODZSWWJzTWsyWGFCbWprX09BbHJwQ3pKUmk2TlFIVFlVb1F5VG5QelNaSHlvRWhSaklPVFFpUm5lUzI1anBKaEFVUXVJS3dDVnVCLXIxVlp4a3FrQV9fNl83RFJ1UnhtRzU5bG93VXNVTFBNZnlhY3cwSkp3NEllanJEM3NCMTFpZEZ5cXBtVHMyaS1XSWkxWm9Bdk1UTUJoM0F3NHdjajhFM1RTdkdpZ0tPcVNfMU90SzFyaS1pcm5VQUdCWmJBa28?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>