<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:20:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 10:20:51 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best 2024 Phones Under Rs 20,000: CMF Phone 1, iQoo Z9x, OnePlus Nord CE4 Lite, More - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxQU1M2QUI4Z1NCRHpCNEUxZGRUb0lnbUpUTkF6S3RGV25yZkVINkxyQ1RrMUs0SXQ1WGdpTGlEVW5ZVjNscTFteUJsTWlvNTNzQ19GcHYtYzJFSkRrMHVSb3cyR2NtRHVFRmxKYVYzLVVEck1uZVZYTmxLdzhWY1B5LTZ0ZVU0ajIzUDU2aURvcTZfb1NZYjVXbk14dE9lUzk5WXlRVGZBendKSjVzVWU5MVVmTGxnQjFCcjJsSURlelYzUGxfRGNPaUVoQ04tdEhQTURDY01kVEd3MDBrZEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxQU1M2QUI4Z1NCRHpCNEUxZGRUb0lnbUpUTkF6S3RGV25yZkVINkxyQ1RrMUs0SXQ1WGdpTGlEVW5ZVjNscTFteUJsTWlvNTNzQ19GcHYtYzJFSkRrMHVSb3cyR2NtRHVFRmxKYVYzLVVEck1uZVZYTmxLdzhWY1B5LTZ0ZVU0ajIzUDU2aURvcTZfb1NZYjVXbk14dE9lUzk5WXlRVGZBendKSjVzVWU5MVVmTGxnQjFCcjJsSURlelYzUGxfRGNPaUVoQ04tdEhQTURDY01kVEd3MDBrZEE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:59:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung workers fired over leak of upcoming Galaxy S25 Ultra phones’ images: Report - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Workers Fired Over Leak of Upcoming Galaxy S25 Ultra Phones’ Images</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> March 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC-TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Samsung workers fired over leak of upcoming Galaxy S25 phones’ images: Report" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Samsung workers fired over leak of upcoming Galaxy S25 phones’ images: Report</figcaption><p>Several Samsung employees have been fired over the leak of images of the Samsung Galaxy S25+, according to a report by PhoneArena. The Galaxy S25 flagship lineup is expected to launch in January 2025, and amidst the hype, a prominent tipster leaked images leading to the firing of these employees.</p><ul><li>The leak was associated with a post by tipster @Jukanlosreve showing purported images of the Galaxy S25+.</li><li>Samsung used device identification numbers traced from the leaked images to identify the employees responsible.</li><li>Samsung is preparing for the Galaxy Unpacked event, expected to reveal the S25 lineup.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Samsung invite hints at four different models, with the new entrant being the highly anticipated Galaxy S25 Slim.”</blockquote><p>CNBC-TV18 has reached out to Samsung for comments regarding this development.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/technology/samsung-workers-fired-over-galaxy-s25-leak-report-19528441.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/technology/samsung-workers-fired-over-galaxy-s25-leak-report-19528441.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:58:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon offers on best laptops under ₹50,000: Grab up to 55% discount on brands like Apple, Lenovo, HP and more - Qrius]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxPQlVkbVA5T3RNVW95REd0RDhtTG9rTG9DYjNLTDBBVEFwWlF4TlFmaENTTEZvS3FMb3hqT2FtbWZCYU5acExjazJBTlRNTGp0cGx5aDd2UWdyb0hQVUVYbXk4U0hmZWNPOHlxVkVETl9LRDk1TXZjd0pmaUIwMEo1ZVpiNnZFODBOLUYwZ0tRQlBUNGZDRHkzN2ZzS2d0dGpYSXFCZUtUMFNKYml1TWFnWEE5RjQxS0ZGNlJrc1h4ZEJtRjFzb0EyTVYxMEs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizAFBVV95cUxPQlVkbVA5T3RNVW95REd0RDhtTG9rTG9DYjNLTDBBVEFwWlF4TlFmaENTTEZvS3FMb3hqT2FtbWZCYU5acExjazJBTlRNTGp0cGx5aDd2UWdyb0hQVUVYbXk4U0hmZWNPOHlxVkVETl9LRDk1TXZjd0pmaUIwMEo1ZVpiNnZFODBOLUYwZ0tRQlBUNGZDRHkzN2ZzS2d0dGpYSXFCZUtUMFNKYml1TWFnWEE5RjQxS0ZGNlJrc1h4ZEJtRjFzb0EyTVYxMEs?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:29:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple may bring AirDrop and AirPlay support to Android phones to comply with EU's new DMA draft - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple May Bring AirDrop and AirPlay Support to Android Phones Due to EU's DMA</h1><p><strong>Published: 23 December 2024, Source: Deccan Herald</strong></p><p>Cupertino-based technology major Apple is expected to expand the availability of two Apple-exclusive features to third-party devices next year following new EU regulations.</p><ul><li>Apple's AirDrop and AirPlay may soon be available on Android devices.</li><li>The European Union's new draft policy under the Digital Markets Act requires interoperability between devices.</li><li>This policy aims to decrease Apple’s exclusivity and enhance consumer choice.</li><li>Apple previously had to adopt a Type-C port for its devices and allowances for third-party app installations.</li></ul><blockquote>“It remains to be seen if Apple will comply with the EU's new DMA draft or take up any legal route to stall the new proposal.”</blockquote><p>This update signifies a major shift in Apple's approach towards integrating its technologies with other platforms, potentially leading to greater interoperability in the tech industry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/technology/gadgets/apple-may-bring-airdrop-and-airplay-support-to-android-phones-to-comply-with-eus-new-dma-draft-3329178</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/technology/gadgets/apple-may-bring-airdrop-and-airplay-support-to-android-phones-to-comply-with-eus-new-dma-draft-3329178</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 09:24:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple phasing out iPhone SE, iPhone 14, and iPhone 14 Plus in EU: Report - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Phasing Out iPhone SE, iPhone 14, and iPhone 14 Plus in the EU</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/g278r4/article69018248.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-09-09T211443Z_2082202891_RC28X9A9H7RQ_RTRMADP_3_APPLE-EVENT.JPG" alt="Apple-centric Lightning port" /><figcaption>These phone models come with an Apple-centric Lightning port [File] | Photo Credit: REUTERS</figcaption><p>Apple is phasing out several iPhone models, including the iPhone SE, iPhone 14, and iPhone 14 Plus, in the European Union in response to new regulations requiring USB-C ports for wired charging.</p><ul><li>The affected models were previously available on Apple’s online store in Switzerland.</li><li>This decision may expand to other EU countries soon.</li><li>Authorized resellers can continue selling their existing stock without disposal.</li><li>Apple often decommissions older models and ceases sales as part of its strategy.</li><li>India is also considering similar regulations for universal charging ports.</li></ul><blockquote>“Apple had warned this could affect local production numbers.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Apple's shift to phase out certain iPhone models aligns with EU regulations, signaling a significant change in the charging standard for future devices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/apple-phasing-out-iphone-se-iphone-14-and-iphone-14-plus-in-eu-report/article69018258.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/apple-phasing-out-iphone-se-iphone-14-and-iphone-14-plus-in-eu-report/article69018258.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech News Today Live Updates on December 23, 2024: Amazon offers on best laptops under ₹50,000: Grab up to 55% discount on brands like Apple, Lenovo, HP and more | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tech News Today Live Updates on December 23, 2024</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 23 Dec 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> LiveMint</p><figure><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2024/12/23/600x338/laptops_under_Rs_50000_1734938974653_1734938981179.jpg" alt="Tech News Today Live Updates: Amazon offers on best laptops under ₹50,000: Grab up to 55% discount on brands like Apple, Lenovo, HP and more"><figcaption>Tech News Today Live Updates: Amazon offers on best laptops under ₹50,000: Grab up to 55% discount on brands like Apple, Lenovo, HP and more</figcaption></figure><p>Amazon is offering significant discounts on laptops priced under ₹50,000, with discounts of up to 55% on popular brands such as Apple, Lenovo, and HP, making it an opportune time for consumers looking for budget-friendly tech gadgets.</p><ul><li>Heavy discounts available on laptops under ₹50,000.</li><li>Promising models from major brands at unprecedented prices.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is your chance to get promising models at unseen prices before."</blockquote><p>Stay updated for further developments in technology offerings and consumer electronics as Amazon leads the market with attractive deals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/latest-technology-news-today-on-december-23-2024-live-updates-11734912016099.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/latest-technology-news-today-on-december-23-2024-live-updates-11734912016099.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:52:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp is rolling out a new reaction emoji just in time for the New Year - BetaNews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp is rolling out a new reaction emoji just in time for the New Year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> BetaNews</p><img src="https://betanews.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/WhatsApp-reaction-emoji-640x411.png" alt="WhatsApp reaction emoji"><figcaption>WhatsApp reaction emoji</figcaption><p>WhatsApp is enhancing user interaction by introducing a new reaction emoji, increasing the total to seven. This feature allows quick responses, making messaging effortless, especially during busy times like the New Year.</p><ul><li>The new emoji is a party popper, perfect for celebrations.</li><li>Existing emoji include thumbs up, heart, crying with laughter, shocked, sad, and high five.</li><li>Additionally, sending certain emoji will trigger animated confetti in messages.</li><li>The update comes at a time when WhatsApp users are expected to communicate more frequently with friends and family.</li></ul><blockquote>"While certainly not a massive change to WhatsApp, it’s a nice bit of fun that has been delivered just time for one of the busiest periods for sending messages to friends and family."</blockquote><p>This update, while not groundbreaking, adds a fun element to messaging during the New Year celebrations and enhances the user experience on the platform.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://betanews.com/2024/12/23/whatsapp-is-rolling-out-a-new-reaction-emoji-just-in-time-for-the-new-year/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://betanews.com/2024/12/23/whatsapp-is-rolling-out-a-new-reaction-emoji-just-in-time-for-the-new-year/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:46:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 15 and iPhone 15 Pro are available with massive discounts - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iPhone 15 and iPhone 15 Pro are selling at amazing discount offers. Here are all the details of the deals.</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 23, 2024</p><p><strong>Published By:</strong> Aman Rashid</p><p>If you have been eyeing to buy the iPhone 15 and iPhone 15 Pro, now would be a great time. The latest offers on the iPhone 15 series are not part of any ongoing sale but are available across different channels.</p><ul><li><strong>iPhone 15:</strong> Available for Rs 58,499, with a discount of Rs 11,401.</li><li><strong>iPhone 15 Pro:</strong> Listed at Rs 97,690 after additional bank discounts, down from Rs 1,34,900.</li><li>EMI options available for both models starting at Rs 2,057 per month for iPhone 15 and Rs 4,955 per month for iPhone 15 Pro.</li></ul><blockquote>“The iPhone 15 Pro offers great value for money, especially for those looking to experience the iPhone Pro series without spending extra on the latest model.”</blockquote><p>Both models maintain strong performance and features, making them worthwhile purchases despite the release of the newer iPhone 16.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/iphone-15-and-iphone-15-pro-are-available-with-massive-discounts-2654034-2024-12-23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/iphone-15-and-iphone-15-pro-are-available-with-massive-discounts-2654034-2024-12-23</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:46:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What did India download on their iPhone? Most downloaded apps and games revealed - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What did India download on their iPhone? Most downloaded apps and games revealed</h1>
<p><strong>Published Date:</strong> 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Apple</p>
<p>As 2024 comes to an end, Apple has released data on the most downloaded games and applications in India from the App Store, highlighting popular trends among users.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Top Paid iPhone Games:</strong> Minecraft, Earn to Die 2, Hitman Sniper, among others.</li>
  <li><strong>Top Free iPhone Games:</strong> BATTLEGROUNDS MOBILE INDIA, Ludo King, Subway Surfers, and more.</li>
  <li><strong>Top Paid iPhone Apps:</strong> Forest, Money Manager, Procreate Pocket, etc.</li>
  <li><strong>Top Free iPhone Apps:</strong> WhatsApp, Instagram, YouTube, Google services, etc.</li>
  <li><strong>Shifts in Trends:</strong> An increase in the number of paid game purchases was noted.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, this data underscores user preferences and changing purchasing behaviors in the digital space.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/what-did-india-download-on-their-iphone-most-downloaded-apps-and-games-revealed/articleshow/116594651.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/magazines/panache/what-did-india-download-on-their-iphone-most-downloaded-apps-and-games-revealed/articleshow/116594651.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:40:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OPPO Reno13 Series: Design, display, and build detailed ahead of India launch - FoneArena]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>OPPO Reno13 Series: Design, display, and build detailed ahead of India launch</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Upcoming Launch, <strong>Source:</strong> FoneArena</p><p><img src="https://images.fonearena.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/OPPO-Reno13-Series-India-Teaser-1024x701.jpg" alt="OPPO Reno13 Series Teaser" width="840" height="575"></p><figcaption>Teaser for OPPO Reno13 Series</figcaption><p>OPPO India has announced the upcoming launch of the OPPO Reno13 series set for January 2025, highlighting its design and features ahead of the release.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>The Reno13 series exhibits a blend of matte and glossy finishes via laser direct writing technology for a dynamic look.</li><li>Exclusive color variants include Luminous Blue with a glowing camera module effect, and Mist Lavender with a calming tone.</li><li>The phones are built with an aerospace-grade aluminum frame, ultra-slim bezels, and are lightweight.</li><li>The IP66, IP68, and IP69 ratings indicate impressive water and dust resistance features.</li><li>Launch expected in the first week of January 2025, with pre-launch offers up to Rs. 8,000 exchange bonuses.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Reno13 series emphasizes ergonomic design and durable construction, showcasing OPPO's craftsmanship.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the OPPO Reno13 series promises a blend of aesthetic design and functional durability, aimed to capture the interest of consumers in its upcoming launch.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fonearena.com/blog/442776/oppo-reno-13-series-india-launch-teaser.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fonearena.com/blog/442776/oppo-reno-13-series-india-launch-teaser.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:39:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp To Stop Working On These Android Phones From January 2025: Full List - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp To Stop Working On These Android Phones From January 2025: Full List</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> December 23, 2024, 16:36 IST</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The start of 2025 will mean end of WhatsApp support for these Android users" title="The start of 2025 will mean end of WhatsApp support for these Android users"><figcaption>The start of 2025 will mean end of WhatsApp support for these Android users</figcaption></figure><p>WhatsApp is going to stop working on millions of Android phones running outdated versions of the operating system starting January 2025. The update is necessary as the Meta-owned platform continues to evolve, introducing new features that require modern hardware.</p><ul><li>The platform will no longer support devices running Android KitKat and older versions.</li><li>Users with affected devices should upgrade to new smartphones to continue using WhatsApp.</li><li>Popular brands affected include Samsung, LG, Sony, and HTC.</li></ul><p><strong>Affected Samsung Models:</strong> Galaxy S3, Note 2, Ace 3, S4 Mini.<br><strong>Affected HTC Models:</strong> One X, One X+, Desire 500, Desire 601.<br><strong>Affected Sony Models:</strong> Xperia Z, Xperia SP, Xperia T, Xperia V.<br><strong>Affected LG Models:</strong> Optimus G, Nexus 4, G2 Mini, L90.<br><strong>Affected Motorola Models:</strong> Moto G, Razr HD, Moto E 2014.</strong></p><blockquote>WhatsApp supports chat and data backup via Google Drive, urging users to back up their data before the end of support date.</blockquote><p>This shift highlights the increasing demand for modern specifications in messaging apps, pushing users to continuously upgrade their devices to stay connected.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/tech/whatsapp-to-stop-working-on-these-android-phones-from-january-2025-full-list-9165301.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/tech/whatsapp-to-stop-working-on-these-android-phones-from-january-2025-full-list-9165301.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:38:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Realme 14 Pro 5G Arriving Next Month in India: What to Expect? - The Quint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Realme 14 Pro 5G Arriving Next Month in India: What to Expect?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>December 19, 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>The Quint</p><p>The Realme 14 Pro 5G series is set to launch in India next month, showcasing a unique color-changing design and durable certifications.</p><ul><li>The series includes Realme 14 Pro and Realme 14 Pro+ models.</li><li>Features a color-changing back panel reacting to water, a first in smartphones.</li><li>Durability certifications: IP66, IP68, and IP69.</li><li>The circular camera module includes three sensors, enhanced by the 'MagicGlow' feature.</li><li>Globally launching in January 2025, amidst other major smartphone releases.</li></ul><blockquote>“The rear panel changes color when exposed to temperatures below 16 degrees Celsius.”</blockquote><p>This launch is eagerly anticipated given the innovative design features, particularly the cold-sensitive technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thequint.com/tech-and-auto/tech-news/realme-14-pro-5g-arriving-next-month-in-india-what-to-expect</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thequint.com/tech-and-auto/tech-news/realme-14-pro-5g-arriving-next-month-in-india-what-to-expect</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:26:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team Computers and Apple Join Forces to Revolutionize GCC Workplaces - Digital Terminal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Team Computers and Apple Join Forces to Revolutionize GCC Workplaces</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <time datetime="2024-12-23T08:23:18.469Z" title="2024-12-23 08:23">23 Dec 2024, 8:23 am</time></p><p>Team Computers, in collaboration with Apple, hosted an insightful event in Bengaluru on the theme “Empowering GCCs with Team Computers and Apple.” The session brought together over 25 IT decision-makers from prominent organizations to discuss how integrating Apple’s innovative solutions and Team Computers’ expertise can transform Global Capability Centers (GCCs).</p><p>The event delved into strategies to enhance productivity, streamline operations, and accelerate digital transformation within GCCs. Attendees explored Apple’s ecosystem of powerful devices and software solutions, paired with Team Computers' tailored IT services, to create smarter, more efficient workplaces.</p><blockquote>Ranjan Chopra, CEO of Team Computers, said, "Our partnership with Apple allows us to deliver cutting-edge technology and expertise to GCCs, enabling them to drive operational excellence and achieve greater success in their digital journeys."</blockquote><p>The interactive session featured live demonstrations, case studies, and collaborative discussions, showcasing the impact of Apple’s seamless ecosystem when combined with Team Computers' in-depth IT capabilities. The event underscored the importance of partnerships in addressing the evolving demands of GCCs and empowering them to stay ahead in an increasingly digital world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://digitalterminal.in/channel/team-computers-and-apple-join-forces-to-revolutionize-gcc-workplaces</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://digitalterminal.in/channel/team-computers-and-apple-join-forces-to-revolutionize-gcc-workplaces</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:23:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Developing Face ID-Enabled Smart Doorbell for 2025-2026 Launch - Mobile ID World]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Developing Face ID-Enabled Smart Doorbell for 2025-2026 Launch</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 22, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> TechCrunch, MacRumors, FoneArena, 9to5Mac, Business Insider</p><p>Apple is venturing into the smart home market with a new smart doorbell that integrates Face ID technology, expected to launch in late 2025 or 2026.</p><ul><li>Utilizes Face ID for facial recognition and wireless communication with smart locks.</li><li>Compatible with third-party HomeKit locks and possibly partnerships with specific lock manufacturers.</li><li>Focus on privacy and security with data protection and encrypted video storage.</li><li>Part of Apple's broader strategy to enhance its smart home device offerings amid a growing home security market.</li><li>Competitive landscape includes Amazon's Ring, with Apple's emphasis on privacy setting it apart.</li></ul><blockquote>“The home security market is expected to reach $81 billion, driven largely by smart lock adoption.”</blockquote><p>Apple's entry into the smart doorbell sector aims to provide a privacy-focused alternative in a market increasingly scrutinized for data security practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://mobileidworld.com/apple-developing-face-id-enabled-smart-doorbell-for-2025-2026-launch/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mobileidworld.com/apple-developing-face-id-enabled-smart-doorbell-for-2025-2026-launch/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:19:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zebronics Zeb-Axon 200 Portable Speaker Now on Amazon - SMEStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zebronics Zeb-Axon 200 Portable Speaker Now on Amazon</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>The Zebronics Zeb-Axon 200 is a powerful portable speaker designed for exceptional sound quality and versatile use. With innovative features like Z-Sync Mode and robust design, it caters to music lovers both indoors and outdoors.</p><ul><li>Features Z-Sync Mode for seamless pairing of over 100 speakers.</li><li>Pulsating 180W RMS output through 5 drivers and dual passive radiators.</li><li>IPX6 water resistance rating makes it suitable for outdoor use.</li><li>Easy-to-use controls and a long battery life of up to 10 hours.</li><li>Offers 3 EQ modes to customize sound output.</li><li>Available at an introductory price of Rs. 9,999/- on Amazon.</li></ul><blockquote>“Zebronics has pushed the boundaries of what a portable speaker can deliver with the Zeb-Axon 200. This is just not a speaker, it is a statement of how technology can transform how we relish music.” – Mr. Pradeep Doshi, Director & Co-Founder of Zebronics.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Zeb-Axon 200 aims to deliver premium sound experiences in a portable format, making it a noteworthy addition to Zebronics' product lineup.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://smestreet.in/technology/zebronics-zeb-axon-200-portable-speaker-now-on-amazon-8549859</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://smestreet.in/technology/zebronics-zeb-axon-200-portable-speaker-now-on-amazon-8549859</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:18:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Badminton Legend Prakash Padukone shares insights on crafting champions - People Matters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxPOWlabzdkdmhMZWxyTE53NDJnbjFhRWp6TGNkaGRoamFZMmJtUDBiZElOLU84MlVudmZkX1BBM0VLTVVxNEhvTWFMNHBBN0pFZmhZR2lzTlo2bC1ZVVR4Q0cwcEVUSzFuUXNlOURKNVpDckVlZXBSWXhnTmZpXzA1NGJrcWlzUG9VYjVZeUg5REFtQmNPUGNJbjdsSW1MbjdDOHlWX3dBVGFRSGhnTy1zY2F1UjM4TlRtTHhBeFR0MzBEUFHSAb4BQVVfeXFMTjVKR3g0U2cwZWZwMWVjaHh0Q0hYVEoxXzhSQ0RzOUdYZmhwRTJTbG0wYlh2LWoyQlh6TDZkQU9EZUMzY1B5dS1UMDZTZEhkZWRhZWlUSjM0YTI3eW9GUGQzbTZaZTI3WVI2MEZSQmtEY01JWmtyRU5qUVNyQURXdVV0Z0pHcXpOQlFGX29TZ2RZNzlvVlYyWTNnQ3N3Slk2dFhLTmtnTkhJRDVMWXFHa21jcGZleEdsVldjT2VoQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxPOWlabzdkdmhMZWxyTE53NDJnbjFhRWp6TGNkaGRoamFZMmJtUDBiZElOLU84MlVudmZkX1BBM0VLTVVxNEhvTWFMNHBBN0pFZmhZR2lzTlo2bC1ZVVR4Q0cwcEVUSzFuUXNlOURKNVpDckVlZXBSWXhnTmZpXzA1NGJrcWlzUG9VYjVZeUg5REFtQmNPUGNJbjdsSW1MbjdDOHlWX3dBVGFRSGhnTy1zY2F1UjM4TlRtTHhBeFR0MzBEUFHSAb4BQVVfeXFMTjVKR3g0U2cwZWZwMWVjaHh0Q0hYVEoxXzhSQ0RzOUdYZmhwRTJTbG0wYlh2LWoyQlh6TDZkQU9EZUMzY1B5dS1UMDZTZEhkZWRhZWlUSjM0YTI3eW9GUGQzbTZaZTI3WVI2MEZSQmtEY01JWmtyRU5qUVNyQURXdVV0Z0pHcXpOQlFGX29TZ2RZNzlvVlYyWTNnQ3N3Slk2dFhLTmtnTkhJRDVMWXFHa21jcGZleEdsVldjT2VoQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:18:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Year That Was: Revelations Made Possible By Artificial Intelligence - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPMTdKNUFuV2pZamFvSFNucWx3ZC02RjFQc0dJZzJwRXdMOTJ4Ym9WT0dVYzdWNFg0cGxCNHhuSzdBVDQ1S0d6UTVXQm9QUXNkdDBWY0F1OHNkZl9CYUJjdUlMWTlLUTJCR3VfUXdhRjdNc0Mwa2ttWnhGQjF2eG12TmlrTjJQMEtmV2hSZ0JmR2hCcm8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPMTdKNUFuV2pZamFvSFNucWx3ZC02RjFQc0dJZzJwRXdMOTJ4Ym9WT0dVYzdWNFg0cGxCNHhuSzdBVDQ1S0d6UTVXQm9QUXNkdDBWY0F1OHNkZl9CYUJjdUlMWTlLUTJCR3VfUXdhRjdNc0Mwa2ttWnhGQjF2eG12TmlrTjJQMEtmV2hSZ0JmR2hCcm8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:09:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OPPO confirms Reno 13 series launch for January 2025, shares design details - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/oppo-confirms-reno-13-series-launch-for-january-2025-shares-design-details-124122300387_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/oppo-confirms-reno-13-series-launch-for-january-2025-shares-design-details-124122300387_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:57:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung India Holiday Sale is here: Grab Galaxy S24 Ultra, Galaxy Z Fold6, and more at discounted prices - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxNX0l5VlNqakJ3X0NocFI0SWc4a0dJTDZJckNwRVRKd2t1Zk5La3FYUFhuNnVVaHZXd1VvcFNOVWduZmItdUk1bWg5enBvSnRVSWFiZFZiSkhsWVJuMnpDQ3B0QWQ5Skxsd3czYU9MVzFkTnFSOHV0T1RiSTNYLVBCbjAxUE0wSFZsa0xMc3hwZ3pJam1SdUhLSnJZOUxDc3NrdTY2dHAxQjFvSDhQQWN4Mm5TSGpWbkRYUENHMUdNNWtUWU5GODFrSjc0ZlRQS2psTlRLWGZ3dlZSWXhCZVJZNHZQS0xpSlhXN3cwTlFjQWVETDlpNEc3WdIB_gFBVV95cUxPODlQQzhqR0NkbzRoR1JoclAzTGNrNTdPUkg5c3RuSGR2cE9ucV96VGQtVmpQLU9uNjRKWlEzTk9tLUg1OUN0bExESnJqcmRfNUUwTHZZbWVERmNLd3FTNWlILTdPVEc5ZnV5YVQ4cWUtazlZY19PYllxTnpLXzdLT0M1OTFKbVVobXkwX0FYcWsyRnJlRjAyUG0teV9RT3hhaDZMZUx0aFg2MXcySGFkSjdDVnBiUjNMQUFnYnl4NmwzanFIc1pSalktYU1DR3FOaEJpQzRhRDkzVDZiNkE5eFczdGNlcEg0X3ZjZnNpbWJFSV9SNEFWWnhUSzhzdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxNX0l5VlNqakJ3X0NocFI0SWc4a0dJTDZJckNwRVRKd2t1Zk5La3FYUFhuNnVVaHZXd1VvcFNOVWduZmItdUk1bWg5enBvSnRVSWFiZFZiSkhsWVJuMnpDQ3B0QWQ5Skxsd3czYU9MVzFkTnFSOHV0T1RiSTNYLVBCbjAxUE0wSFZsa0xMc3hwZ3pJam1SdUhLSnJZOUxDc3NrdTY2dHAxQjFvSDhQQWN4Mm5TSGpWbkRYUENHMUdNNWtUWU5GODFrSjc0ZlRQS2psTlRLWGZ3dlZSWXhCZVJZNHZQS0xpSlhXN3cwTlFjQWVETDlpNEc3WdIB_gFBVV95cUxPODlQQzhqR0NkbzRoR1JoclAzTGNrNTdPUkg5c3RuSGR2cE9ucV96VGQtVmpQLU9uNjRKWlEzTk9tLUg1OUN0bExESnJqcmRfNUUwTHZZbWVERmNLd3FTNWlILTdPVEc5ZnV5YVQ4cWUtazlZY19PYllxTnpLXzdLT0M1OTFKbVVobXkwX0FYcWsyRnJlRjAyUG0teV9RT3hhaDZMZUx0aFg2MXcySGFkSjdDVnBiUjNMQUFnYnl4NmwzanFIc1pSalktYU1DR3FOaEJpQzRhRDkzVDZiNkE5eFczdGNlcEg0X3ZjZnNpbWJFSV9SNEFWWnhUSzhzdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:53:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Android 16 Developer Preview 2 Out Now: Here Are All The Details - Bizz Buzz]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxPdERzQXFDbjdqTVY0eWRfSG5VYW44STFLaTNpNjlUMzJhdXpBQUlVWU5IVXhVNWtTZEl3R3dJQlh4VllBVWZUWVdDZEswN2I0VDgzOEhMMUVJNzY0QzBrWEgzOWlMMGJjZzVWMzIyU3dVeGVGNUVOQjIwUlhtbGFWVFFCRFcxRVhGSjFWRTBCTU9Yc3dSaDhrVHdQckRlSXptMEI1bmpxd3hmQzBwcXp4NGtaMnJWQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxPdERzQXFDbjdqTVY0eWRfSG5VYW44STFLaTNpNjlUMzJhdXpBQUlVWU5IVXhVNWtTZEl3R3dJQlh4VllBVWZUWVdDZEswN2I0VDgzOEhMMUVJNzY0QzBrWEgzOWlMMGJjZzVWMzIyU3dVeGVGNUVOQjIwUlhtbGFWVFFCRFcxRVhGSjFWRTBCTU9Yc3dSaDhrVHdQckRlSXptMEI1bmpxd3hmQzBwcXp4NGtaMnJWQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:19:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 15 to OPPO Find X8: Five Best Flagship Deals from Flipkart Big Saving Days Sale - Gizbot]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iPhone 15 to OPPO Find X8: Five Best Flagship Deals from Flipkart Big Saving Days Sale</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> Monday, December 23, 2024, 12:45 [IST]</p><img src="https://images.gizbot.com/img/2024/12/iphone-151-1734938090.jpeg" alt="Five Best Flagship Deals from Flipkart Big Saving Days Sale 2024" width="600" height="338"><figcaption>Five Best Flagship Deals from Flipkart Big Saving Days Sale 2024</figcaption><p>Flipkart's Big Saving Days sale is ongoing, featuring significant discounts on popular smartphones just in time for Christmas and the New Year.</p><ul><li><strong>iPhone 15 and iPhone 15 Plus:</strong> iPhone 15 for Rs 55,574, down from Rs 69,900; iPhone 15 Plus for Rs 60,799, originally Rs 79,900.</li><li><strong>Samsung Galaxy S24 Plus:</strong> Discounted to Rs 61,749, from Rs 99,999.</li><li><strong>OPPO Find X8:</strong> Now at Rs 59,850, reduced from Rs 69,999.</li><li><strong>Infinix Zero Flip:</strong> Available at Rs 42,749 with discounts.</li><li><strong>Vivo V40:</strong> Priced at Rs 31,349, down from Rs 34,999.</li></ul><p>Many more premium smartphones are on sale at Flipkart, including options from Google and Samsung with substantial discounts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gizbot.com/deal-of-the-day/iphone-15-to-oppo-find-x8-five-best-flagship-deals-from-flipkart-big-saving-days-sale-107459.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gizbot.com/deal-of-the-day/iphone-15-to-oppo-find-x8-five-best-flagship-deals-from-flipkart-big-saving-days-sale-107459.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:15:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Novel solution for tackling pest menace in hostels | - UoH Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQUVlUcThNMkk2YjRlcWR1aHRPZ1hHNElieEQ3a28tREtZTzI5VmFCdEZUVk43Rk8xSEo3MEdsUUpSVjVyenFJUjkzcEtLRG5jYjl4SVRxWjVkbjlNaWlGV0hfUnRDc3hGbWZzVzlCMlJCVUQ1eDVIamo1Ymd4V2doWGVSN2Y?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxQUVlUcThNMkk2YjRlcWR1aHRPZ1hHNElieEQ3a28tREtZTzI5VmFCdEZUVk43Rk8xSEo3MEdsUUpSVjVyenFJUjkzcEtLRG5jYjl4SVRxWjVkbjlNaWlGV0hfUnRDc3hGbWZzVzlCMlJCVUQ1eDVIamo1Ymd4V2doWGVSN2Y?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 07:12:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iOS 19 Will Support iPhone SE 2020 and All Other Models Running iOS 18: Report - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>You Will Get iOS 19 Update If You Have Any of These iPhone Models</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/MdC4Er14Tvw/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Watch the trailer for more details.</figcaption><p>Apple is set to release the iOS 19 update, which will be compatible with all iPhones currently using iOS 18. The rollout is expected in late 2025, covering a wide range of devices.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>iOS 19 will support all iPhone models running iOS 18.</li><li>Latest models include the iPhone 16 series and older models like iPhone SE (2020).</li><li>iPadOS 19 may not support all iPad models, specifically iPad (7th generation).</li></ul><blockquote>"The update is slated for a late 2025 release."</blockquote><p>The compatibility list for iOS 19 shows extensive support, which is a significant benefit for existing Apple users.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/ios-19-iphone-compatibility-list-ipados-19-update-apple-report-7312237</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/ios-19-iphone-compatibility-list-ipados-19-update-apple-report-7312237</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:49:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp Will Stop Working on These Android Phones in 2025: Check Complete List - MySmartPrice]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp Will Stop Working on These Android Phones in 2025: Check Complete List</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> MySmartPrice</p>
<img src="https://assets.mspimages.in/gear/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/WhatsApp-featured-.jpg" width="400" height="210" alt="WhatsApp feature image"><figcaption>WhatsApp Will Stop Working on These Android Phones in 2025</figcaption>
<p>WhatsApp will stop working on select Android devices starting January 1, 2025, as part of its effort to update the platform. This change is necessary for the introduction of new features that require updated software.</p>
<ul>
  <li>WhatsApp will discontinue support for Android 4.4 KitKat and older versions.</li>
  <li>Users of affected phones need to upgrade by the end of the year to continue using the app.</li>
  <li>The latest supported versions are Android 5.0 and iOS 12.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If you own these vintage smartphones and use WhatsApp, you have until January 1 to upgrade!”</blockquote>
<p>This update aims to enhance user experience by ensuring that all supported devices can optimally function with the latest applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/internet/internet-news/whatsapp-drop-support-android-phones-2025-see-list/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/internet/internet-news/whatsapp-drop-support-android-phones-2025-see-list/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:35:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S24 series is available with big discount offers - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S24 series is available with big discount offers</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 | <strong>Published By:</strong> Aman Rashid</p><p>Samsung is offering significant discounts on the Galaxy S24 series and wearables, providing a great opportunity for customers during the holiday season.</p><ul><li>Big discounts on Galaxy S24 series and wearables as part of the holiday sale.</li><li>Galaxy S24 Ultra starts at Rs 1,09,999 with additional cashback offers.</li><li>Galaxy S24 Plus priced at Rs 64,999 and Galaxy S24 at Rs 62,999.</li><li>Galaxy Z Fold 6 and Z Flip 6 prices reduced significantly.</li><li>Galaxy S23 series also sees considerable price drops.</li><li>Wearables like Galaxy Watch Ultra and Galaxy Buds series have attractive offers.</li></ul><blockquote>“Samsung hasn’t stopped at just smartphone deals.”</blockquote><p>It's an opportune time for smartphone and wearable enthusiasts to take advantage of these discounts before the holiday season ends.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-is-available-with-big-discount-offers-2653956-2024-12-23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/samsung-galaxy-s24-series-is-available-with-big-discount-offers-2653956-2024-12-23</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:32:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Realme to invest Rs 100 crore in R&D of quad-curved display technology - ETTelecom]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Realme to invest Rs 100 crore in R&D of quad-curved display technology</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 23, 2024 at 12:02 PM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> ETTelecom</p><figure><img src="https://img.etb2bimg.com/files/cp/upload-1716881367-ettelecom-default.webp" alt="Realme quad curved display image"><figcaption>Realme quad curved display technology.</figcaption></figure><p>Realme has announced an investment of approximately Rs 100 crore aimed at further developing its innovative quad-curved display technology for smartphones on a global scale.</p><ul><li>The investment will focus on advanced display manufacturing techniques.</li><li>Realme aims to enhance user experiences with premium smartphones.</li><li>The Realme 14 Pro 5G series features a bezel-less design with slim 1.6mm bezels.</li></ul><blockquote>“This strategic investment will focus on the research and development of advanced display manufacturing techniques, ensuring realme stays ahead of the curve in delivering premium smartphone experiences,” the smartphone brand stated.</blockquote><p>Realme's vision is to redefine user experiences by setting new standards in innovation and design.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://telecom.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/devices/realme-to-invest-rs-100-crore-in-rd-of-quad-curved-display-technology/116590035</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://telecom.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/devices/realme-to-invest-rs-100-crore-in-rd-of-quad-curved-display-technology/116590035</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:32:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two larger sizes of Samsung Galaxy Ring leak ahead of launch - Sammy Fans]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxOc2ttN01WRDdoOUFidU1EeE9VZFF5dUpLd2t2SE56VDZPME9ibUhYaXdtZW1Ga2I3aVVvc2tzeDUwMC1xd1p0dWp0RjFPeHQ3aUxKXzB5VUVOcHVXekl2MHJzRGZsWHRyZ3FuUk9JSm5NVEI4dnE2X3QwRXExMXJ1Zm1fWFJ3ZDQ1enc5VlBibnJ1a3lnS0pUc042dzYtaWvSAaQBQVVfeXFMUDVFejl3RmR6X1YzSko4TVJNSkpndENjeEFCQlhJV0RoakdqOWVwZnp2WWdQcVpxd3Vzd2FLMjZXUC0yTVNFSkY1T3lzQ2RFM0NIdVZuNkNhZi14TDBvSUhmRFJ6Zjd5VllzLWV1X1NSNHhIRXotVW5RemswaVpBRHdlU3JXVjVzei1ST3FrYjk1UW9OSkQ3UmRvc2pVcDBrUjlnNTc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxOc2ttN01WRDdoOUFidU1EeE9VZFF5dUpLd2t2SE56VDZPME9ibUhYaXdtZW1Ga2I3aVVvc2tzeDUwMC1xd1p0dWp0RjFPeHQ3aUxKXzB5VUVOcHVXekl2MHJzRGZsWHRyZ3FuUk9JSm5NVEI4dnE2X3QwRXExMXJ1Zm1fWFJ3ZDQ1enc5VlBibnJ1a3lnS0pUc042dzYtaWvSAaQBQVVfeXFMUDVFejl3RmR6X1YzSko4TVJNSkpndENjeEFCQlhJV0RoakdqOWVwZnp2WWdQcVpxd3Vzd2FLMjZXUC0yTVNFSkY1T3lzQ2RFM0NIdVZuNkNhZi14TDBvSUhmRFJ6Zjd5VllzLWV1X1NSNHhIRXotVW5RemswaVpBRHdlU3JXVjVzei1ST3FrYjk1UW9OSkQ3UmRvc2pVcDBrUjlnNTc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:28:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vivo Y29 5G India price and specs leaked ahead of launch: All you need to know | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vivo Y29 5G India Price and Specs Leaked Ahead of Launch</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert date here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert source here]</p><p>Vivo is set to launch a new budget smartphone, the Vivo Y29 5G, with leaks revealing its pricing and specifications ahead of confirmation.</p><ul><li>Prices are expected to be ₹13,999 for 4GB RAM/128GB, ₹15,499 for 6GB RAM/128GB, ₹16,999 for 8GB RAM/128GB, and ₹18,999 for 8GB RAM/256GB.</li><li>The phone features a 6.68 inch display and MediaTek Dimensity 6300 processor.</li><li>It sports a 5,500mAh battery with 44W fast charging.</li><li>Camera specifications include a 50MP primary sensor and an 8MP front camera.</li><li>Additional features include IP64 dust and water resistance, military-grade shock resistance, and dimensions of 8.1mm thickness, weighing 198 grams.</li></ul><blockquote>“Vivo Y29 5G is said to come in Glacier Blue, Titanium Gold, and Diamond Black colors.”</blockquote><p>The Vivo Y29 5G promises to be a competitive option in the budget smartphone market with notable specifications and features.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/technology/gadgets/vivo-y29-5g-india-price-and-specs-leaked-ahead-of-launch-all-you-need-to-know-11734932723488.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/technology/gadgets/vivo-y29-5g-india-price-and-specs-leaked-ahead-of-launch-all-you-need-to-know-11734932723488.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:28:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xiaomi 15 Ultra Allegedly Receives BIS Certification, Hints at Possible India Launch - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Xiaomi 15 Ultra Allegedly Gets BIS Approval, India Launch May Be Imminent</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets360</p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/rHnAzKKS6Lc/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video"><figcaption>Xiaomi 15 Ultra Overview</figcaption><p>The Xiaomi 15 Ultra is expected to launch in India soon as it has been spotted on the Bureau of Indian Standards (BIS) website. It is anticipated to debut globally before arriving in India.</p><ul><li>The device is associated with the model number 25010PN30I.</li><li>Expected to feature Snapdragon 8 Elite flagship chipset.</li><li>Previous Xiaomi 14 Ultra launched internationally in February and in India in March.</li><li>Rumored features include 90W wired charging, a 2K display, and advanced camera specifications.</li></ul><blockquote>“The appearance of Xiaomi 15 Ultra on the BIS certification platform suggests that it could arrive in India soon.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the approval from BIS is a strong indicator that the Xiaomi 15 Ultra could soon make its way to the Indian market, garnering much anticipation among tech enthusiasts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/xiaomi-15-ultra-bis-listing-model-number-india-launch-imminent-specifications-report-7312210</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/xiaomi-15-ultra-bis-listing-model-number-india-launch-imminent-specifications-report-7312210</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:18:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honor Magic 7 RSR Porsche Design Camera Details Leaked; May Get 200-Megapixel Telephoto Lens - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Honor Magic 7 RSR Porsche Design Camera Details Leaked Ahead of Launch</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Today</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p>
<img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/597yDBFpTKc/hqdefault.jpg" alt="Play Video">
<figcaption>Video Preview of Honor Magic 7 RSR Porsche Design</figcaption>
<p>The Honor Magic 7 RSR Porsche Design is set to launch today in China, with leaked camera specifications revealing a 50-megapixel primary sensor and a telephoto lens with a remarkable zoom capability.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The phone features a 1/1.3-inch 50-megapixel OV50K primary sensor.</li>
  <li>It has a 50-megapixel ultra-wide angle shooter and a 200-megapixel telephoto sensor.</li>
  <li>Expect a dual electromagnetic motor and advanced focusing mechanisms.</li>
  <li>It will ship with Android 15-based MagicOS 9 and supports fast charging.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Honor Magic 7 RSR Porsche Design will get the industry's first periscope telephoto ultra-large aperture.”</blockquote>
<p>This device promises to deliver cutting-edge camera technology, solidifying Honor's position in the premium smartphone market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/honor-magic-7-rsr-porsche-design-camera-features-leak-launch-design-7311963</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/honor-magic-7-rsr-porsche-design-camera-features-leak-launch-design-7311963</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 06:13:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>