<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:28:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:28:31 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple discontinues iPhone SE and iPhone 14 as USB-C becomes mandatory charging standard in EU - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Discontinues iPhone SE and iPhone 14 as EU Mandates USB-C Charging Standard</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><h2>Introduction</h2><p>The European Union has implemented USB-C as the mandatory charging standard for electronic devices, pushing companies like Apple to discontinue older models such as the iPhone SE and iPhone 14 in the region.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>The EU's regulation aims to reduce e-waste and simplify charging for consumers.</li><li>Apple's iPhone SE (3rd generation) and iPhone 14 featured the outdated Lightning connector.</li><li>The discontinued models will still be available through third-party sellers until stock runs out.</li><li>A USB-C-equipped iPhone SE is planned for release in early 2025.</li><li>The regulation may influence global manufacturers to adopt USB-C.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics</h2><blockquote>This change meets the EU's regulatory requirements and responds to consumer demands for a more unified charging standard.</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>The EU's decision marks a significant change in the smartphone industry, potentially leading to a global standard for charging cables and devices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://tech.hindustantimes.com/mobile/news/apple-discontinues-iphone-se-and-iphone-14-as-usb-c-becomes-mandatory-charging-standard-in-eu-71735538422548.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tech.hindustantimes.com/mobile/news/apple-discontinues-iphone-se-and-iphone-14-as-usb-c-becomes-mandatory-charging-standard-in-eu-71735538422548.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:06:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Days Sale: Vijay Sales brings deals on iPhones, iPads, Macs, more - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Days Sale: Vijay Sales brings deals on iPhones, iPads, Macs, more</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> Dec 30 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Business Standard</p><img src="https://www.business-standard.com/assets/web-assets/images/Business_Standard_685x385.jpg" title="Vijay Sales Apple Days Sale" alt="Vijay Sales Apple Days Sale" width="826" height="465"><figcaption>Vijay Sales Apple Days Sale</figcaption><p>Vijay Sales has launched the "Apple Days Sale," offering significant discounts on various Apple products, including the latest iPhone models and MacBooks, from December 29, 2024, to January 5, 2025.</p><ul><li>Discounts of up to Rs 10,000 available with bank offers from ICICI, SBI, and Kotak Bank.</li><li>Trade-in deals for older devices with bonuses of up to Rs 10,000.</li><li>Offers on display units of select Apple products, such as the iPhone 13 starting at Rs 32,900.</li><li>Discounted prices on iPhone 16 series: effective prices range from Rs 57,490 to Rs 127,650.</li><li>MacBook discounts: Effective prices for MacBook Air start from Rs 63,890.</li></ul><blockquote>"During the Apple Days Sale, we aim to provide exciting offers and discounts to our customers on premium Apple products." - Vijay Sales spokesperson</blockquote><p>This sale presents an opportunity for Apple fans to purchase products at reduced prices, making high-quality technology more accessible.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/apple-days-sale-vijay-sales-brings-deals-on-iphones-ipads-macs-more-124123000256_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/apple-days-sale-vijay-sales-brings-deals-on-iphones-ipads-macs-more-124123000256_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 06:02:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 benefits of making lobia a staple in vegan, plant-based diet - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8 Benefits of Making Lobia a Staple in a Vegan, Plant-Based Diet</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/webstories/uploads/2024/12/cropped-lobia-benefits-8-2024-12-3edea898969ddeb34c3f1bdedf21380e.jpg' alt='Benefits of Lobia'><figcaption>Image illustrating the benefits of lobia.</figcaption><p>Black-eyed peas, or lobia, are a nutrient-dense food perfect for vegan and vegetarian diets, providing essential plant-based protein and fiber.</p><ul><li>Lobia is versatile, fitting various dishes like soups, salads, and curries.</li><li>It's a great source of calcium, essential for strong bones in dairy-free diets.</li><li>Helps stabilize blood sugar levels due to its low glycemic index.</li><li>Low in calories and high in fiber, aiding in weight management.</li><li>Rich in antioxidants, reducing oxidative stress and inflammation.</li><li>Packed with folate vital for cell growth and repair.</li><li>Contains non-heme iron, crucial for energy levels and preventing anemia.</li><li>Excellent source of plant-based protein, essential for muscle building.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/8-reasons-to-make-lobia-a-staple-in-your-vegan-plant-based-diet-visual-story-2721492.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/health-and-fitness/8-reasons-to-make-lobia-a-staple-in-your-vegan-plant-based-diet-visual-story-2721492.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:57:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astro Bot, Balatro, Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown and More: Gadgets 360's Best Games of 2024 - Gadgets 360]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Best Video Games of 2024: Our Top Picks</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Gadgets 360</p><img src="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/screen_ghost_1_1735311363598.png" alt="Animal Well Screenshot"><figcaption>Animal Well's intricate maze is full of animals and spirits</figcaption><p>This year has turned out to be unexpectedly fruitful for video games, featuring impressive titles across various platforms, from indie hits to large-scale releases.</p><ul><li>2024 saw standout multiplayer games like Helldivers 2 and Palworld.</li><li>Action-RPGs such as Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree and Black Myth: Wukong have captivated players.</li><li>Indie titles like Balatro received acclaim, with Balatro selling over 3.5 million copies and winning awards.</li><li>Remakes like Silent Hill 2 and Persona 3 Reload brought nostalgic games back to life.</li></ul><blockquote>“Astro Bot stood out in a year full of excellent action-adventure games, winning four trophies at The Game Awards 2024, including Game of the Year.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, 2024 has proven to be a vibrant year for the gaming industry, with a diverse array of captivating games that resonate with both casual and hardcore gamers alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gadgets360.com/games/guide/best-games-of-2024-astro-bot-prince-of-persia-balatro-animal-well-helldivers-2-senuas-saga-7345417</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gadgets360.com/games/guide/best-games-of-2024-astro-bot-prince-of-persia-balatro-animal-well-helldivers-2-senuas-saga-7345417</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:49:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech recap 2024: Samsung, Google lead advancements in gen-AI; Apple follows - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tech Recap 2024: Samsung and Google Lead AI Advancements While Apple Takes a Conservative Approach</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Tech News Daily</p><p>In 2024, the mobile technology landscape has notably shifted towards software advancements, primarily driven by Samsung and Google in the realm of artificial intelligence (AI) integration.</p><ul><li>Samsung has integrated advanced AI functionalities into its Galaxy S24 series, focusing on generative AI tools for image enhancement and real-time language translations.</li><li>Google has embedded AI deeply in the Android operating system, showcased by its Pixel 9 series with innovative features like Magic Eraser and AI-driven call screening.</li><li>Apple has taken a more conservative approach, opting for incremental improvements in its iPhone 16 series with a focus on privacy and on-device processing rather than aggressive AI strategies.</li><li>Samsung and Google are expected to continue their AI momentum into 2025, while Apple's long-term strategy may focus on privacy advantages.</li></ul><blockquote>“While Samsung and Google raced ahead with gen-AI, Apple remained relatively conservative.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the advancements in AI technologies by Samsung and Google set a high standard for the industry, while Apple’s measured approach may offer long-term advantages in security and user privacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-recap-2024-samsung-google-lead-advancements-in-gen-ai-apple-follows-124123000162_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/technology/tech-news/tech-recap-2024-samsung-google-lead-advancements-in-gen-ai-apple-follows-124123000162_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 04:39:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple discontinues iPhone SE and iPhone 14 as EU officially adopts USB-C as universal charging standard - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple Discontinues iPhone 14 and SE Following EU Adoption of USB-C Standard</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 30, 2024 <strong>by:</strong> Nandini Yadav</p><p>Apple has discontinued the iPhone 14 and iPhone SE in the EU as these models feature the outdated lightning port, while USB-C is now the official charging standard in the region, requiring all electronic devices sold in the EU to adopt this port.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>USB-C became the mandatory standard in the EU on December 28, 2024.</li><li>Apple's iPhone 14 and iPhone SE are discontinued in the EU to comply with the regulation.</li><li>Older models with lightning ports will still be available through third-party sellers until stocks last.</li><li>The regulation aims to reduce e-waste and simplify charging for consumers.</li><li>Apple is expected to launch a USB-C-equipped iPhone SE in early 2025.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quote</h2><blockquote>“Today’s the day! USB-C is officially the common standard for electronic devices in the EU!” - European Commission</blockquote><p>This regulation is seen as a significant step towards environmental sustainability and consumer convenience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/apple-discontinues-iphone-se-and-iphone-14-as-eu-officially-adopts-usb-c-as-universal-charging-standard-2657116-2024-12-30</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/apple-discontinues-iphone-se-and-iphone-14-as-eu-officially-adopts-usb-c-as-universal-charging-standard-2657116-2024-12-30</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 04:00:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for December 30, 2024: How to redeem codes and win exciting rewards - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes for December 30, 2024: How to redeem codes and win exciting rewards</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="TOI logo" width="300" height="24"><figcaption>Exciting rewards await you!</figcaption><p>This article provides the latest redeem codes for Garena Free Fire MAX as of December 30, 2024, along with a guide on how to use them to earn fantastic in-game rewards.</p><ul><li>Redeem codes can enhance your gaming experience by providing valuable in-game items.</li><li>Players are encouraged to redeem the codes promptly before they expire.</li><li>The article offers a step-by-step guide on how to redeem these codes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Unlock unique rewards and boost your gameplay with these latest codes!”</blockquote><p>Overall, this is a valuable resource for players looking to maximize their rewards in Garena Free Fire MAX.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-codes-for-december-30-2024-how-to-redeem-codes-and-win-exciting-rewards/articleshow/116784166.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/gaming/garena-free-fire-max-codes-for-december-30-2024-how-to-redeem-codes-and-win-exciting-rewards/articleshow/116784166.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024 Winners and losers: Motorola - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE1kRlRSUDJIYUtmR2Y0OFI1UEJkWVg4UVBwbzJsaE1SaF9lenhmc3NiNHNEZHIwNVZnbXJQR1hpUmlUS3BjZjhFLVdNSVBCVjZrZGxyanQ0TDcxZHVXQzVoY081aDZuS2tiZmEyZUoyM1hpZzlNdi12SnRESVfSAXhBVV95cUxOc2k0bC0yaDBuaTBCU2pxQlBOV0R3RmhDMnhFZWdvcEw5MlFZajJuUmhQYTk2WDRzS053MUpSVnNBMXVjNTliNWtaeEJKc1ZmSDV2MjZ5ekZfTl9FTWRrcGFtSVZ6YlJEYnlyUDFQNFlyY29aUUcxLTE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE1kRlRSUDJIYUtmR2Y0OFI1UEJkWVg4UVBwbzJsaE1SaF9lenhmc3NiNHNEZHIwNVZnbXJQR1hpUmlUS3BjZjhFLVdNSVBCVjZrZGxyanQ0TDcxZHVXQzVoY081aDZuS2tiZmEyZUoyM1hpZzlNdi12SnRESVfSAXhBVV95cUxOc2k0bC0yaDBuaTBCU2pxQlBOV0R3RmhDMnhFZWdvcEw5MlFZajJuUmhQYTk2WDRzS053MUpSVnNBMXVjNTliNWtaeEJKc1ZmSDV2MjZ5ekZfTl9FTWRrcGFtSVZ6YlJEYnlyUDFQNFlyY29aUUcxLTE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:34:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra camera specs leaked, but don’t get your hopes up - HT Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxPSGNsWmgtOEdjZUJxRk9XenZjMFlZUzU0X1BlbFVVYm1nSTE5NlVJNURvZllKLWZRcWFETkZJWG1FSjE5UkpfNXNkS1pTRWU4M0pILXhqOFE2czdpRHJSdDZrcDZyV0txVWZmVE9hWE5LdUJXWUgwdWZ1Q2xXOE5PUjB6UkN4TldVY3dJdjFoUFhTTTBidGRabG9OVGtaVWtvc1EwbFY1ZFlqX25YUTNjREpZUmRsYWk4cVJCeEp3Q045WnpUM2FRNlNKVDRXUU45QVHSAdcBQVVfeXFMT29GbWRNRWxmODdCbW9lb1VSSkhYaWFwUE1fdWVuRzF3cDdZTzhLeWtVdm50QTAxQzBYQWpzWWtjUGkzY2oySDJ0X1BITEdjMGdKT01aR1dfa0lOSFNlSk1jRHJfVEl1YW01eWhBXzFjWmJzd3Y4NkM1dHE2TWh3SEh4VlhENnQxRmtNT2xlTC1OUDYzSzcyemEtcWxqWDJjU3hlWGJuR0poWUxpUWhYS2tTTkVDVFhUck9kX1ppR0J1YzgtZEtqb3h5UTMtR3BpUk1FUjRORVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0gFBVV95cUxPSGNsWmgtOEdjZUJxRk9XenZjMFlZUzU0X1BlbFVVYm1nSTE5NlVJNURvZllKLWZRcWFETkZJWG1FSjE5UkpfNXNkS1pTRWU4M0pILXhqOFE2czdpRHJSdDZrcDZyV0txVWZmVE9hWE5LdUJXWUgwdWZ1Q2xXOE5PUjB6UkN4TldVY3dJdjFoUFhTTTBidGRabG9OVGtaVWtvc1EwbFY1ZFlqX25YUTNjREpZUmRsYWk4cVJCeEp3Q045WnpUM2FRNlNKVDRXUU45QVHSAdcBQVVfeXFMT29GbWRNRWxmODdCbW9lb1VSSkhYaWFwUE1fdWVuRzF3cDdZTzhLeWtVdm50QTAxQzBYQWpzWWtjUGkzY2oySDJ0X1BITEdjMGdKT01aR1dfa0lOSFNlSk1jRHJfVEl1YW01eWhBXzFjWmJzd3Y4NkM1dHE2TWh3SEh4VlhENnQxRmtNT2xlTC1OUDYzSzcyemEtcWxqWDJjU3hlWGJuR0poWUxpUWhYS2tTTkVDVFhUck9kX1ppR0J1YzgtZEtqb3h5UTMtR3BpUk1FUjRORVE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:33:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Massive Video Game Budgets: The Existential Threat We Saw A Decade Ago - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Massive Video Game Budgets: An Existential Threat We Saw A Decade Ago</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The New York Times</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://specials-images.forbesimg.com/imageserve/67720d8f2ab7d31558ba947e/Hands-with-handheld-game-controls-/960x0.jpg?cropX1=0&cropX2=1017&cropY1=52&cropY2=624" alt="Hands with handheld game controls." />
  <figcaption><small>Big budget games have nearly killed the gaming industry.</small></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The article discusses the challenges posed by exorbitant video game budgets, highlighting that the gaming industry is facing an unsustainable spending trend that has persisted for nearly a decade.</p>
<ul>
  <li>High-end graphics have led to a budgetary arms race in the gaming industry.</li>
  <li>Widespread layoffs in gaming are attributed to unsustainable budgets.</li>
  <li>Modern games have production cycles of 7-8 years, reflecting decisions made nearly a decade ago.</li>
  <li>The author criticizes the current publishing management for their misguided financial strategies.</li>
  <li>A call for a return to mid-tier games, which could revitalize the industry.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Laying off development staff to pay investors is like cutting off your legs while trying to escape from a rampaging lion."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the article warns that without significant changes, the gaming industry may face dire consequences as the current financial model continues to jeopardize its future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/olliebarder/2024/12/29/massive-video-game-budgets-the-existential-threat-we-saw-a-decade-ago/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/olliebarder/2024/12/29/massive-video-game-budgets-the-existential-threat-we-saw-a-decade-ago/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:21:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 slim expected to arrive later than the rest of the series - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AFBVV95cUxNQ3JiRTkzS2dPM212eUtLdmJTMHNQNmtwWkI3RUJkTDFLLUpPQ0RZZ2pUbU9leElEQUpBU29vdzRnMkk0SklSX0pBNFpPc05HdEV6R0d6R2p4czZPeUh3SG1nU3VieUJ2d3ppZUt4UlBzSDJKOXhFSlhMS2NYZ05Ma1AxOTFKQ2x2aHJnOFp4UXdETktiVEM0STB1OWZCOXRheDRDMlpQb040ZnhpTlB1aEJzRkhhdGRlXzhDcjJjNFJxckxIRkpCbWp2bUFHU2kxVkk3NVliYkktRm1lbU42OdIB4AFBVV95cUxNQ3JiRTkzS2dPM212eUtLdmJTMHNQNmtwWkI3RUJkTDFLLUpPQ0RZZ2pUbU9leElEQUpBU29vdzRnMkk0SklSX0pBNFpPc05HdEV6R0d6R2p4czZPeUh3SG1nU3VieUJ2d3ppZUt4UlBzSDJKOXhFSlhMS2NYZ05Ma1AxOTFKQ2x2aHJnOFp4UXdETktiVEM0STB1OWZCOXRheDRDMlpQb040ZnhpTlB1aEJzRkhhdGRlXzhDcjJjNFJxckxIRkpCbWp2bUFHU2kxVkk3NVliYkktRm1lbU42OQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4AFBVV95cUxNQ3JiRTkzS2dPM212eUtLdmJTMHNQNmtwWkI3RUJkTDFLLUpPQ0RZZ2pUbU9leElEQUpBU29vdzRnMkk0SklSX0pBNFpPc05HdEV6R0d6R2p4czZPeUh3SG1nU3VieUJ2d3ppZUt4UlBzSDJKOXhFSlhMS2NYZ05Ma1AxOTFKQ2x2aHJnOFp4UXdETktiVEM0STB1OWZCOXRheDRDMlpQb040ZnhpTlB1aEJzRkhhdGRlXzhDcjJjNFJxckxIRkpCbWp2bUFHU2kxVkk3NVliYkktRm1lbU42OdIB4AFBVV95cUxNQ3JiRTkzS2dPM212eUtLdmJTMHNQNmtwWkI3RUJkTDFLLUpPQ0RZZ2pUbU9leElEQUpBU29vdzRnMkk0SklSX0pBNFpPc05HdEV6R0d6R2p4czZPeUh3SG1nU3VieUJ2d3ppZUt4UlBzSDJKOXhFSlhMS2NYZ05Ma1AxOTFKQ2x2aHJnOFp4UXdETktiVEM0STB1OWZCOXRheDRDMlpQb040ZnhpTlB1aEJzRkhhdGRlXzhDcjJjNFJxckxIRkpCbWp2bUFHU2kxVkk3NVliYkktRm1lbU42OQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:16:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hackers Hijacked 16 Chrome Extensions to Inject Malicious Code - CybersecurityNews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid0FVX3lxTE1NY1NmT1VHMXVsWUNGaW9KYy1BYWl5WHRNZEtJZzJfMmw5dEJqcTNzYzZHWmFEVFU3SVZIU3pkWUtJT0dvVEU4TTdVNHFTNGRrcWsySmtZQjlBSlppV0NETHppVi1wRHoxdnBDOVJQcXktS29yVkdN0gF8QVVfeXFMTjJSUEVMLWZwV1NUTm1xaGlwbXhsRUMyWG41TDM5eVRoTkR4OGFySU5aQWQ2VnM3ZVd2YUJ6a283djVucUZBZmh0SWpUeWRuX2FBTzUwVEJGa2xTNmt1MDBHWXJhNWk3ZW0teXJSUkNmSm03QlZOR1J6Z1Q0SA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMid0FVX3lxTE1NY1NmT1VHMXVsWUNGaW9KYy1BYWl5WHRNZEtJZzJfMmw5dEJqcTNzYzZHWmFEVFU3SVZIU3pkWUtJT0dvVEU4TTdVNHFTNGRrcWsySmtZQjlBSlppV0NETHppVi1wRHoxdnBDOVJQcXktS29yVkdN0gF8QVVfeXFMTjJSUEVMLWZwV1NUTm1xaGlwbXhsRUMyWG41TDM5eVRoTkR4OGFySU5aQWQ2VnM3ZVd2YUJ6a283djVucUZBZmh0SWpUeWRuX2FBTzUwVEJGa2xTNmt1MDBHWXJhNWk3ZW0teXJSUkNmSm03QlZOR1J6Z1Q0SA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:06:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Redmi Turbo 4 to be announced on January 2 - FoneArena]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Redmi Turbo 4 to be announced on January 2</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> FoneArena</p>
<img src="https://images.fonearena.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Redmi-Turbo-4-white-1024x905.jpg" alt="Redmi Turbo 4" width="571" height="505">
<figcaption>Redmi Turbo 4 in Cloud White Color</figcaption>
<p>Xiaomi has confirmed the launch of the Redmi Turbo 4, the next mid-range phone in the Turbo series, set for January 2nd in China. The phone will showcase several new features and design elements.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Launch date: January 2, 2024, in China.</li>
  <li>First phone powered by MediaTek Dimensity 8400-Ultra processor.</li>
  <li>Promised flagship performance in gaming with high energy efficiency.</li>
  <li>Specifications include a 1.5K 120Hz LTPS screen, 50MP rear camera, and IP68 rating.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We should know more details in the coming days before the phone goes official later this week."</blockquote>
<p>The announcement of the Redmi Turbo 4 highlights Xiaomi's commitment to delivering advanced technology in mid-range smartphones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fonearena.com/blog/443040/redmi-turbo-4-launch-date.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fonearena.com/blog/443040/redmi-turbo-4-launch-date.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:06:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WhatsApp Is Ready To Help You Identify Fake Images Using Google: Here’s How - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WhatsApp Is Ready To Help You Identify Fake Images Using Google: Here’s How</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Google could make it easy to search for fake content and images." title="Google could make it easy to search for fake content and images."><figcaption>Google could make it easy to search for fake content and images.</figcaption><p>WhatsApp is leveraging Google's capabilities to tackle the spread of fake news and misinformation. The messaging app has begun testing reverse image search functionality for both Android and web versions.</p><ul><li>The new feature aims to help users identify fake content and find the original sources of images shared within chats.</li><li>This tool is particularly useful for those forwarding unchecked content, which may be dangerous.</li><li>Users can access the reverse image search via a three-dot menu after selecting an image.</li><li>The feature ensures that WhatsApp chats remain private, as only the selected content is uploaded to Google.</li><li>WhatsApp is gradually rolling out this feature and it is expected to reach more users soon.</li></ul><blockquote>"WhatsApp has already started beta testing the feature on Android, with plans to expand to web users soon."</blockquote><p>This new functionality underscores WhatsApp's commitment to ensuring user safety and combating misinformation in digital communication.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/tech/whatsapp-is-ready-to-help-you-identify-fake-images-using-google-heres-how-9172039.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/tech/whatsapp-is-ready-to-help-you-identify-fake-images-using-google-heres-how-9172039.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 03:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gaming in 2025: GTA 6, the Nintendo Switch 2 and what else to watch out for - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gaming in 2025: GTA 6, the Nintendo Switch 2 and what else to watch out for</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> BBC Newsbeat</p><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/b1d0/live/a8e16c60-c11e-11ef-b76e-9de78285d5f5.jpg.webp" alt="Rockstar Games" /><figcaption>Grand Theft Auto 6 is expected to be a record-breaking hit when it arrives</figcaption><p>2025 is anticipated to be a significant year for the gaming industry with major releases like Grand Theft Auto 6 and the new Nintendo Switch on the horizon.</p><ul><li>Grand Theft Auto 6 is expected to release in autumn 2025 and is poised for record-breaking sales and cultural impact.</li><li>The trailer for GTA 6 garnered 90 million views in just 24 hours.</li><li>The new Nintendo Switch console's details remain sparse, but it is confirmed to be backwards compatible with the existing game library.</li><li>Indie games like Balatro gained traction in 2024, hinting at a potential for breakout hits in 2025.</li><li>The inaugural Olympic Esports Games will be held in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, raising questions about esports' legitimacy in traditional sports.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's undoubtedly going to be one of, if not the biggest, game launches of all time.” - James Batchelor, editor-in-chief of GamesIndustry.biz</blockquote><p>The gaming landscape in 2025 appears vibrant, with potential shifts in console sales and industry dynamics driven by monumental game releases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c9dp0qqe48po</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c9dp0qqe48po</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:42:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LG pulls back the curtain on the most innovative monitor at CES - literally - XDA Developers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>LG pulls back the curtain on the most innovative monitor at CES - literally</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://static1.xdaimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/wm/2024/01/lg-signature-oled-t-06.jpg" alt="A wall of transparent LG OLED TVs showing a colorful forest with lights in the night sky"><figcaption>A wall of transparent LG OLED TVs showing a colorful forest with lights in the night sky</figcaption><p>With CES 2025 just around the corner, LG has revealed its award-winning UltraGear OLED Bendable Monitor, standing out even before the event begins.</p><ul><li>The UltraGear OLED Bendable Gaming Monitor (model 45GX990A) is the world's first 5K2K-resolution bendable OLED display.</li><li>This 45-inch monitor can transition from flat to a 900R curvature within seconds, enhancing user experience.</li><li>Features like upgraded Dual-Mode allow for easy switching between resolution and refresh rate presets.</li><li>It boasts an ultra-fast 0.03ms response time to ensure smooth gameplay.</li></ul><blockquote>“The LG UltraGear OLED Bendable Gaming Monitor is designed to provide incredible flexibility and more control over the gaming experience.”</blockquote><p>LG's latest monitor is set to redefine user flexibility and engagement in gaming, demonstrating their commitment to innovation in display technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.xda-developers.com/lg-most-innovative-monitor-ces/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.xda-developers.com/lg-most-innovative-monitor-ces/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LG pulls back the curtain on the most innovative monitor in CES - literally - XDA Developers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib0FVX3lxTE1HV0NEVTEyWFJoYUE0VmdjSnNqOE9ibEpkSXNqQnNNWEI4VFNMdGpCQzlOeHN5MVo3ZkNMWlZzbnJlNnpXSWtMWGNWNm50Q0YySi1jb091VVJkLXp6d2Fha0hPbFRRSkZOVVhuT19Waw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib0FVX3lxTE1HV0NEVTEyWFJoYUE0VmdjSnNqOE9ibEpkSXNqQnNNWEI4VFNMdGpCQzlOeHN5MVo3ZkNMWlZzbnJlNnpXSWtMWGNWNm50Q0YySi1jb091VVJkLXp6d2Fha0hPbFRRSkZOVVhuT19Waw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[25x in returns, ₹25 lakh for every ₹1 lakh: Can Varun Beverages do it again? | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxPSXpsN0g5VDBxbV9EOXVvSU9JSjJGQWJXM1VwU3Q1bFhlMU1WWjlTUy16b0hvd0VUSDhHV2JRSk1HTVNTQk5hekI1aUJnNm9ZRjNHWW1sSEk2VEpObmdaMng2R21WdDI4djQybXlqaS11d0xkUldkOWJMX0VOYWU1clhQWDBiU25CRXc4R25La3BLUmE5bk52NTE3T01jRng1aUYxVk12M2hySi03OGppdG9mcXpPZ3lYR09aUWJHSXJVVFZEb0FiSkRmR2E4aXJYM0hzQVpULUNoRWhQT0hLajlYb29LdzFIdjBnYktkaXR5RVFQ0gH6AUFVX3lxTE43ekJMSWRTVzltRHJ3M3RWYVdJOGdTZC1JRlJ6aGtqSExvSGNvc2JkVF9fRjZJd0xXTnRzRi0zRkcxVnhpOXVhTlQyeVRzdjhCdWVMOXY2aFR0UjNJcEVnRlVBSTRPVlJMS2xwdnVNenN5STVBSWU4RHk3Y2hoeThUTHd1QjJ2QXNsSVE5S0lpZ09kbmpfSV9WMzcxMXlEMUZ1Nkd6djZLdUZvaEpwM3hZY3RpZDlzdDYyX3o5andIb2tMTExpczhncld5MUxhNW0zcDdUZmJrRnM0SkIwQTRKa0ZVQmFTOUtCT3ptaUpjSzBTT2xFRHc1bHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxPSXpsN0g5VDBxbV9EOXVvSU9JSjJGQWJXM1VwU3Q1bFhlMU1WWjlTUy16b0hvd0VUSDhHV2JRSk1HTVNTQk5hekI1aUJnNm9ZRjNHWW1sSEk2VEpObmdaMng2R21WdDI4djQybXlqaS11d0xkUldkOWJMX0VOYWU1clhQWDBiU25CRXc4R25La3BLUmE5bk52NTE3T01jRng1aUYxVk12M2hySi03OGppdG9mcXpPZ3lYR09aUWJHSXJVVFZEb0FiSkRmR2E4aXJYM0hzQVpULUNoRWhQT0hLajlYb29LdzFIdjBnYktkaXR5RVFQ0gH6AUFVX3lxTE43ekJMSWRTVzltRHJ3M3RWYVdJOGdTZC1JRlJ6aGtqSExvSGNvc2JkVF9fRjZJd0xXTnRzRi0zRkcxVnhpOXVhTlQyeVRzdjhCdWVMOXY2aFR0UjNJcEVnRlVBSTRPVlJMS2xwdnVNenN5STVBSWU4RHk3Y2hoeThUTHd1QjJ2QXNsSVE5S0lpZ09kbmpfSV9WMzcxMXlEMUZ1Nkd6djZLdUZvaEpwM3hZY3RpZDlzdDYyX3o5andIb2tMTExpczhncld5MUxhNW0zcDdUZmJrRnM0SkIwQTRKa0ZVQmFTOUtCT3ptaUpjSzBTT2xFRHc1bHc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:30:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Platinum Guild rides double-digit surge as Young India seeks more than ‘Just Gold’ | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Platinum Guild rides double-digit surge as Young India seeks more than ‘Just Gold’</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p>
<p>India’s fascination with gold is legendary, but platinum is quickly carving out its own space, especially among young consumers who want jewellery to mean more than a mere “store of value.”</p>
<ul>
  <li>High levels of awareness and consideration for platinum among consumers.</li>
  <li>Sustained double-digit growth in platinum sales.</li>
  <li>Expansion of platinum marketing efforts into tier-2 and tier-3 towns.</li>
  <li>Consumer marketing director Sujala Martis discusses evolving consumer mindsets.</li>
  <li>Focus on the emotive aspects of platinum compared to gold.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Platinum is seen as a more meaningful choice among the younger generation, reflecting personal expression rather than just investment.”</blockquote>
<p>The growing trend of young consumers seeking more from their jewellery indicates a significant shift in marketing for the platinum industry aimed at emotional connections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/platinum-guild-rides-double-digit-surge-as-young-india-seeks-more-than-just-gold-consumers-nielsen-iq-precious-metals-11735314702189.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/platinum-guild-rides-double-digit-surge-as-young-india-seeks-more-than-just-gold-consumers-nielsen-iq-precious-metals-11735314702189.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:15:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Platinum Guild in double-digit surge as young India seeks more than ‘Just Gold' - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwJBVV95cUxQZm84eTQwbndXZ3hNSVZoTlVfSlNWd0tWZS1uaDBmUGk3MXRmeWh5LU1ZREZNUGhmN2lMaXRZblVlczMzcHA5RzhHcDVUN3ozX2prSGstN1BwWENTeGxwbE5WanpVa2hOWF9PcWN3OXRLdVZRTWNFNkdIblIzcVhmcGFEekNBMWJXLS0weTRGbm1IcmowS3BJTDVFbW5SMk8taFRLRHFfREE5ZnZTRXZxeHNoQnNiRjNwenFrUHFrT2FLcTlVQVlaRVRBVHU3a296WEViS1lIZm5rUElLRjBTaF91aEI5b1pUbTROMVpTWnlTTFczRlRLTXhfY2ZrNjJBYk12TkM3YTVhODg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwJBVV95cUxQZm84eTQwbndXZ3hNSVZoTlVfSlNWd0tWZS1uaDBmUGk3MXRmeWh5LU1ZREZNUGhmN2lMaXRZblVlczMzcHA5RzhHcDVUN3ozX2prSGstN1BwWENTeGxwbE5WanpVa2hOWF9PcWN3OXRLdVZRTWNFNkdIblIzcVhmcGFEekNBMWJXLS0weTRGbm1IcmowS3BJTDVFbW5SMk8taFRLRHFfREE5ZnZTRXZxeHNoQnNiRjNwenFrUHFrT2FLcTlVQVlaRVRBVHU3a296WEViS1lIZm5rUElLRjBTaF91aEI5b1pUbTROMVpTWnlTTFczRlRLTXhfY2ZrNjJBYk12TkM3YTVhODg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:15:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK study warns of perils in AI-driven 'intention economy' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UK Study Warns of Perils in AI-Driven 'Intention Economy'</h1><p><strong>Date: Dec 30, 2024</strong></p><p><strong>Source: Harvard Data Science Review</strong></p><figure><img src="https://images.hindustantimes.com/default/550x309.jpg" alt="HT Image" title="HT Image"><figcaption>HT Image</figcaption></figure><p>Researchers from the University of Cambridge have issued a warning about the dangers of a new marketplace they term the 'intention economy,' wherein conversational AI could influence user decision-making.</p><ul><li>The 'intention economy' could affect decisions ranging from buying movie tickets to voting.</li><li>Chatbots and AI agents could enable persuasive technologies that manipulate user behavior.</li><li>Unchecked AI could lead to 'social manipulation on an industrial scale.'</li><li>AI tools will be developed to collect and commodify human intentions.</li><li>Co-author Jonnie Penn emphasizes the need for regulation to prevent intentions from being treated as a currency.</li></ul><blockquote>“We should start to consider the likely impact such a marketplace would have on human aspirations...” - Jonnie Penn</blockquote><p>The study highlights the importance of public awareness to mitigate the risks associated with the intention economy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/uk-study-warns-of-perils-in-ai-driven-intention-economy-101735516936005.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/technology/uk-study-warns-of-perils-in-ai-driven-intention-economy-101735516936005.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:02:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Navigating the future: Real estate sector insights by Raja Venkatraman—30 December | Stock Market News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stocks-to-buy-raja-venkatraman-three-stocks-for-30-december-nifty-50-sensex-nifty-realty-prestige-ashiana-oberoi-realty-11735307286524.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/market/stock-market-news/stocks-to-buy-raja-venkatraman-three-stocks-for-30-december-nifty-50-sensex-nifty-realty-prestige-ashiana-oberoi-realty-11735307286524.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New rumor corroborates seamless update support on Galaxy S25 lineup - SamMobile - Samsung news]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New rumor corroborates seamless update support on Galaxy S25 lineup</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> SamMobile</p><p>Recent reports suggest that the Galaxy S25, S25+, and S25 Ultra will feature Android's seamless updates capability. Leaked files indicate that Samsung is set to implement this after eight years of the feature's introduction by Google.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>The Galaxy S25 lineup will be the first Samsung flagships to support seamless updates.</li><li>The seamless update process allows updates to occur in the background without interrupting user access.</li><li>The only current Samsung device with this feature is the Galaxy A55.</li><li>Implementation of two system partitions facilitates the seamless update process.</li></ul><blockquote>“The device then boots from that backup partition with the updated software upon restart.”</blockquote><p>This implementation marks a significant step forward for Samsung's flagship smartphones, enhancing user experience by eliminating downtime during updates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sammobile.com/news/samsung-galaxy-s25-seamless-updates-report/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sammobile.com/news/samsung-galaxy-s25-seamless-updates-report/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 23:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Specific launch date set for Xiaomi 15 Ultra and global Xiaomi 15 - Notebookcheck.net]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Specific Launch Date Set for Xiaomi 15 Ultra and Global Xiaomi 15</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Notebookcheck</p><img src="fileadmin/_processed_/0/2/csm_Xiaomi-15-Ultra-und-globales-Xiaomi-15-Konkreter-Launchtermin-steht_5fd143f027.jpg" loading="lazy" width="240" height="180" alt="Xiaomi has set a specific launch date for Xiaomi 15 Ultra and the global Xiaomi 15. (Image source: Xiaomi)"><figcaption>Xiaomi has set a specific launch date for Xiaomi 15 Ultra and the global Xiaomi 15. (Image source: Xiaomi)</figcaption><p>Xiaomi has officially announced a specific launch date for the Xiaomi 15 Ultra, coinciding with the Mobile World Congress in Barcelona in March 2025.</p><ul><li>The Xiaomi 15 Ultra will be unveiled during MWC, scheduled for March 3 to March 6, 2025.</li><li>March 2 is likely the target launch date for major announcements.</li><li>The global version of the Xiaomi 15 will also be announced on March 2.</li><li>Xiaomi fans will have to wait more than four months for the global version after its initial release in China.</li><li>Speculations suggest changes in camera features and battery capacity for the Xiaomi 15 Ultra.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Xiaomi 15 Ultra will be officially unveiled at the Mobile World Congress (MWC) in Barcelona.” - Lu Weibing, Xiaomi Group President</blockquote><p>This announcement marks an exciting development for Xiaomi fans as the highly anticipated devices approach their launch date.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.notebookcheck.net/Specific-launch-date-set-for-Xiaomi-15-Ultra-and-global-Xiaomi-15.938715.0.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.notebookcheck.net/Specific-launch-date-set-for-Xiaomi-15-Ultra-and-global-Xiaomi-15.938715.0.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 23:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why I Finally Switched to an iPad After Using an Android Tablet for Years - MUO - MakeUseOf]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why I Finally Switched to an iPad After Using an Android Tablet for Years</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> MakeUseOf</p>
<img src="https://static0.makeuseofimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/wm/2024/12/using-the-ipad-air-as-a-secondary-monitor-with-macbook-air.jpg" alt="Using the iPad Air as a secondary monitor with MacBook Air">
<figcaption>Using the iPad Air as a secondary monitor with MacBook Air</figcaption>
<p>The author discusses their transition from an Android tablet to an iPad, highlighting the benefits of seamless integration with other Apple devices, screen size, and suitable apps for light work.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Seamless integration with MacBook and iPhone simplifies multitasking.</li>
  <li>The large screen of the iPad Air provides valuable desktop real estate.</li>
  <li>The iPad Air offers necessary apps and accessories for efficient light work.</li>
  <li>Great for light work and professional photography tasks.</li>
  <li>Has all the essential apps needed for productivity.</li>
  <li>Accessories improve functionality, such as external drives and keyboards.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“While Samsung’s giant Galaxy Tab S10 Ultra is a tempting offer, I ultimately found better value in the 13-inch M2 iPad Air.”</blockquote>
<p>This article emphasizes the advantages the author found in switching to the iPad, suggesting it as a strong contender for those considering a change from Android tablets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.makeuseof.com/switch-to-ipad-after-using-android-for-years/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.makeuseof.com/switch-to-ipad-after-using-android-for-years/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YouTube is testing a floating ‘Play something’ button - The Verge]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>YouTube Tests New Floating 'Play Something' Button</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 26, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> 9to5Google</p><p>YouTube is introducing a new floating 'Play Something' button in its Android app that selects a video for users to watch.</p><ul><li>YouTube is currently testing a floating button that appears just above the bottom bar in the app.</li><li>The button auto-selects a video to play when tapped.</li><li>The feature utilizes the portrait-oriented YouTube Shorts player.</li><li>This initiative follows a similar feature by Netflix, which retired its own random video picker last year.</li></ul><blockquote>“Play Something” is reminiscent of a feature that Netflix offered, called “Surprise Me,” which launched in 2021.</blockquote><p>This latest feature reflects YouTube's attempt to enhance user engagement by offering randomized content suggestions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/29/24331622/youtube-play-something-floating-action-button-random-video</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/29/24331622/youtube-play-something-floating-action-button-random-video</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 21:58:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korean team develops ‘Iron Man’robot that helps paraplegics walk - Nagaland Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://nagalandpost.com/index.php/2024/12/30/south-korean-team-develops-iron-manrobot-that-helps-paraplegics-walk/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nagalandpost.com/index.php/2024/12/30/south-korean-team-develops-iron-manrobot-that-helps-paraplegics-walk/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 21:36:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple’s iPad in 2024: Highlights, Misses, and What to Expect in 2025 - NoMusica]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Apple’s iPad in 2024: Highlights, Misses, and What to Expect in 2025</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Apple News</p><p>Apple had a busy year in 2024, introducing several new iPads, particularly enhancing the iPad Pro, iPad Air, and iPad mini.</p><h3>The Highs of 2024</h3><ul><li>The iPad Pro featured the powerful M4 chip and a Tandem OLED display, appealing to creative professionals.</li><li>The iPad Air showcased a new 13-inch version at an affordable price, retaining the older M2 chip.</li><li>Introduction of the Apple Pencil Pro with haptic feedback made drawing and note-taking more intuitive.</li><li>The iPad mini was upgraded with the A17 Pro chip, enhancing performance and supporting Apple Intelligence.</li></ul><h3>The Lows of 2024</h3><ul><li>Entry-level iPads (9th and 10th generations) did not receive upgrades, disappointing many users.</li><li>iPadOS 18 offered some improvements but still lacked a desktop-class experience.</li><li>Multitasking capabilities and Apple device integration require further enhancements.</li></ul><h3>What to Expect in 2025</h3><p>Anticipated updates for the entry-level iPad include the 11th generation, featuring a design similar to the iPad Air and a faster chip.</p><p>New iPadOS 19 is expected to focus on improved multitasking and Apple ecosystem integration, with potential surprises for users.</p><p>Overall, 2024 saw significant advancements but left some areas for improvement. 2025 presents an opportunity for Apple to refine its offerings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://nomusica.com/apple-ipad-in-2024-highlights/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nomusica.com/apple-ipad-in-2024-highlights/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 21:35:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Law of diminishing returns hits gaming - Fudzilla]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxORWxYQ1YtdHRncXJYVzJMbFZ4VXl5dktMdWhLTU5mQTdTS0NwdkpDbEVLODV3MHlZaUlIQTFTYmxfMnd6VjZ3d09keERWRDZRUzVmeVVEQjdJakVLREktM2dCZjJyTnpRYXFJRW5pVEVEMWFGQllqZ3dtakhQa0NGQUppdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxORWxYQ1YtdHRncXJYVzJMbFZ4VXl5dktMdWhLTU5mQTdTS0NwdkpDbEVLODV3MHlZaUlIQTFTYmxfMnd6VjZ3d09keERWRDZRUzVmeVVEQjdJakVLREktM2dCZjJyTnpRYXFJRW5pVEVEMWFGQllqZ3dtakhQa0NGQUppdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 19:50:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oppo confirms bi-annual release events for Find X and N series - Android Headlines]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Oppo Confirms Bi-Annual Release Events for Find X and N Series</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Android Headlines</p><img src="https://www.androidheadlines.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/oppo-bi-annual-release-find-x.webp" alt="Oppo bi-annual release find x" width="786" height="646"><figcaption>Oppo plans to host bi-annual events for its flagship Find series.</figcaption><p>Oppo will hold bi-annual release events for its Find X and Find N series phones, introducing new models in spring and autumn each year. This shift aims to allow consumers easier access to the latest technology.</p><ul><li>The company is set to unveil flagship phones in spring and autumn.</li><li>Products expected in spring 2025 include Find N5, Find X8 Ultra, Find X8 Mini, and Find X8s.</li><li>The autumn event will likely feature Find X9 and Find X9 Pro.</li><li>The Find N5 could include a periscope lens and satellite communication features.</li><li>Improved innovation and faster production timeline expected as a result of this new scheduling.</li></ul><blockquote>“With two events a year, customers won’t have to wait too long for the next big thing.” - Zhou Yibao</blockquote><p>This new strategy by Oppo aims to keep consumers engaged and enhance the pace of innovation in their smartphone lineup.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.androidheadlines.com/2024/12/oppo-confirms-bi-annual-release-events-for-find-x-and-n-series.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.androidheadlines.com/2024/12/oppo-confirms-bi-annual-release-events-for-find-x-and-n-series.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 18:40:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>