<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Technology Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 13:22:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/Technology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 13:22:37 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forget Apple Intelligence – I want the next iPhone SE to be a bastion of privacy - TechRadar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Next iPhone SE: A Privacy-Focused Alternative</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> TechRadar</p>
<img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/TQ8CNTrWeNxdErYuUsBugQ-320-80.jpg" alt="A dummy unit of the iPhone SE 4 acquired by Japanese Apple blog Mac Otakara.">
<figcaption><span itemprop="copyrightHolder">(Image credit: Mac Otakara)</span></figcaption>
<p>Recent discussions suggest that the upcoming iPhone SE 4 could prioritize privacy over artificial intelligence features, allowing users to maintain control over their personal data in an increasingly AI-driven market.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gareth Beavis argues that Apple can capitalize on budget iPhones while enhancing privacy features.</li>
  <li>The article raises concerns about AI's potential privacy invasions on smartphones.</li>
  <li>Calls for a phone that serves core functionalities without advanced AI features.</li>
  <li>Speculation that Apple may position the iPhone SE 4 as an entry point into Apple Intelligence despite privacy concerns.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I think there could be a real refreshed market for phones that avoid all the fancy AI bits and simply work as a phone, camera, web browser and casual games machine."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, there’s a significant demand for privacy-focused smartphones as consumers seek to mitigate data tracking and AI integrations in favor of straightforward device functionality.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techradar.com/phones/iphone/forget-apple-intelligence-i-want-the-next-iphone-se-to-be-a-bastion-of-privacy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techradar.com/phones/iphone/forget-apple-intelligence-i-want-the-next-iphone-se-to-be-a-bastion-of-privacy</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nazi ties to Credit Suisse ran deeper than was known, hidden files reveal - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nazi ties to Credit Suisse ran deeper than was known, hidden files reveal</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> Company Business News</p>
<p>Newly discovered documents indicate that Switzerland's past with Nazi collaborators may have been obscured, revealing deeper connections of Credit Suisse with the Nazi regime than previously acknowledged.</p>
<ul>
<li>A cache of client files labeled 'American blacklist' was uncovered, indicating potential financing or trading with Nazis.</li>
<li>The findings contradict prior assumptions that Swiss banks had resolved their past involvement with Nazi-related activities.</li>
<li>This new information came to light as independent investigators examined Credit Suisse's operations, now part of UBS.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Switzerland thought it came to terms with its Nazi-assisting past… Documents unearthed… show it might have been at least in part a whitewash."</blockquote>
<p>This revelation may prompt a reevaluation of Swiss banks' roles during WWII and their implications for historical accountability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/nazi-ties-to-credit-suisse-ran-deeper-than-was-known-hidden-files-reveal-11735987564596.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/nazi-ties-to-credit-suisse-ran-deeper-than-was-known-hidden-files-reveal-11735987564596.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 10:59:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra leak shows off the phone's super-thin bezels - TechRadar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra Leak Reveals Super-Thin Bezels</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> TechRadar</p><p>Recent leaks of the Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra highlight its ultra-thin bezels and more rounded corners. These design features align with previous renders, suggesting an exciting new look for the flagship device.</p><ul><li>A photo of the Galaxy S25 Ultra has leaked.</li><li>Thinner bezels and more rounded corners are evident.</li><li>The design matches previously leaked renders.</li></ul><blockquote>"The tiny bezels could potentially be thinner than those on many rival phones."</blockquote><p>The Galaxy S25 Ultra is set to be unveiled soon, with anticipation building around its design and upgraded internals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.techradar.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-phones/new-samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leak-shows-off-the-phones-super-thin-bezels</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techradar.com/phones/samsung-galaxy-phones/new-samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leak-shows-off-the-phones-super-thin-bezels</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oppo Find X8 Pro | Finger clicking good - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Finally there's a smartphone that's fit to fire your DSLR</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/reporter/202209/SPICE-logo-1200x768.jpg?VersionId=e74UY321t4HbYLnOdejvOJssmtlPvGG2&size=50:50" alt="Oppo Find X8 Pro" loading="lazy"><p>We’ve been using the Oppo Find X8 Pro for some time, and it’s safe to say this phone wants a seat at the big kids’ table. Priced at a cool Rs 99,999, it’s challenging Apple, Samsung, and Google for flagship supremacy.</p><ul><li>Oppo Find X8 Pro priced at Rs 99,999.</li><li>Positioned as a competitor to flagship phones from Apple, Samsung, and Google.</li><li>Offers high-end features suitable for professional photography.</li></ul><blockquote>This phone wants a seat at the big kids’ table.</blockquote><p>The Oppo Find X8 Pro stands as a serious contender in the flagship smartphone market, offering features that challenge established players.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/magazine/supplement/story/20250113-oppo-find-x8-pro-finger-clicking-good-2658604-2025-01-04</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/magazine/supplement/story/20250113-oppo-find-x8-pro-finger-clicking-good-2658604-2025-01-04</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 10:25:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oppo Reno 13 AI: New phone with powerful display and underwater photography feature to launch on THIS day - ET Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Oppo Reno 13 AI: Launch Details and Features Unveiled</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 4, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> ET Now News</p>
<img src="https://etstatic.tnn.in/photo/msid-95598012,width-200,height-200,resizemode-75/95598012.jpg" alt="Oppo Reno 13 Series" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Oppo Reno 13 series is set to launch on January 9 in India.</figcaption>
<p>The Oppo Reno 13 series is set for an official launch in India on January 9, featuring powerful specifications and innovative photography capabilities.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Launch Date: January 9 at 5 PM IST, streaming on Flipkart and Oppo’s platforms.</li>
  <li>Expected to feature OLED panels, aerospace-grade aluminum frame, and Gorilla Glass 7i.</li>
  <li>Powered by MediaTek Dimensity 8350 processor with options up to 12GB RAM and 512GB storage.</li>
  <li>IP68 and IP69 ratings for water and dust resistance.</li>
  <li>Includes AI features like AI LivePhoto and AI Unblur Photo.</li>
  <li>Reno 13 Pro features a telephoto super zoom camera with up to 120x digital zoom.</li>
  <li>Expected price for Reno 13 starts at Rs 32,999; Reno 13 Pro around Rs 40,000.</li>
  <li>Battery life: Reno 13 Pro with 5,800mAh and 80W SuperVOOC charging, standard Reno 13 with 5,600mAh.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Reno 13 Pro will feature a 3.5x telephoto super zoom camera with a significant upgrade for photography enthusiasts.”</blockquote>
<p>This launch marks another significant addition to Oppo's Reno series, showcasing advanced technology and smart features tailored for photography lovers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.etnownews.com/technology/oppo-reno-13-ai-new-phone-with-powerful-display-and-underwater-photography-feature-to-launch-on-this-day-article-116938011</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.etnownews.com/technology/oppo-reno-13-ai-new-phone-with-powerful-display-and-underwater-photography-feature-to-launch-on-this-day-article-116938011</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 10:03:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra Leaks: Upcoming Flagship Smartphone Might Be Powered By Snapdragon 8 Elite Chipset - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra Leaks: Upcoming Flagship Smartphone Might Be Powered By Snapdragon 8 Elite Chipset</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 22, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> ABP News</p>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra is poised to be unveiled at the upcoming Galaxy Unpacked event. This model is anticipated to be the premium offering in the S25 series, which may also include the S25 Slim, launching later.</p>
<ul>
<li>The S25 Ultra is expected to feature Qualcomm's Snapdragon 8 Elite chipset.</li>
<li>Rumored introduction of a 16GB RAM variant for improved performance.</li>
<li>Expected upgrades to display durability through second-generation Corning Gorilla Glass Armor.</li>
<li>A new 50MP ultra-wide camera sensor to enhance mobile photography.</li>
<li>Launch with One UI 7, offering design enhancements and new features.</li>
<li>Redesigned flat-frame structure with rounded corners, retaining the S Pen feature.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The camera system promises to maintain its position as a leader in mobile photography."</blockquote>
<p>In summary, the Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra introduces significant upgrades that promise to elevate user experience and performance in the flagship smartphone market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leaks-rumour-roundup-processor-snapdragon-8-elite-camera-price-specifications-1741804</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.abplive.com/technology/gadgets/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-leaks-rumour-roundup-processor-snapdragon-8-elite-camera-price-specifications-1741804</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 10:03:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 16 Pro Max Price Cut: Apple’s Top Premium Smartphone Available at Over INR 14,000 Discounted Price on Indian E-Commence Website; Check Details - LatestLY]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>iPhone 16 Pro Max Price Cut: Apple’s Top Premium Smartphone Available at Over INR 14,000 Discounted Price on Indian E-Commerce Website; Check Details</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 04, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> LatestLY</p><p>The iPhone 16 Pro Max, which is known for its enhanced camera performance and advanced features, is available at a significant discount of over INR 14,000 on various Indian e-commerce platforms.</p><ul><li>Original price: INR 1,44,900; discounted price: INR 1,30,650 on Vijay Sales.</li><li>Price on Amazon and Flipkart is INR 1,37,900.</li><li>Offers include up to INR 3,000 off on selected bank cards and no-cost EMI options.</li><li>Significant upgrades from the previous model, iPhone 15 Pro Max, including the A18 Pro chip and advanced camera capabilities.</li><li>Available in multiple color options including Black Titanium and White Titanium.</li></ul><blockquote>"Apple's latest smartphone came with significant improvements compared to its predecessor, the iPhone 15 Pro Max."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the iPhone 16 Pro Max's price cut presents a lucrative opportunity for customers looking for a high-end smartphone with advanced features at a lower price point.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.latestly.com/technology/iphone-16-pro-max-price-cut-apples-top-premium-smartphone-available-at-over-inr-14000-discounted-price-on-indian-e-commence-website-check-details-6539882.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.latestly.com/technology/iphone-16-pro-max-price-cut-apples-top-premium-smartphone-available-at-over-inr-14000-discounted-price-on-indian-e-commence-website-check-details-6539882.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:54:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Apple MacBook Air series with M4 chipset set to launch in early 2025 - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxNX2VvYWpKa3hhMmJxd1JSbmN6YTdqckJuREU3ZHBvVlptYTlLMmFKSTJxbFUwNmdYX2lUclNKS2V6YTgyWVYtdzRfcVExaGV2WTNmZldJdU5MS202OFZIc25pcjJVWElFMVlvOFhtUDVIN3M3bFRJT21pN1VzYWoxVmo4RERCeDRCMUJXR0huWE9PVWZLa2pKZlpqSzhXWnphVTJFeWFRbzN0Z21TTUNUQVdKUkd4QkdxWm9BQjZKT3BLOG01Z2xZTzFEbDVYUFXSAdQBQVVfeXFMTWJkZjlKbDhTRHB1Z09fd201eElKOWN0am9Eamg3LXBUSnJONks1VjNCMDFTYWpHSk53Ql9rOTYwSzhTSE9DdVd3dzhaUldacElHeUF1Qkx4RUVpSmtBa2x4VHMtc2Z0QkVQNXdPRi1JcUY0dS10dGFJNVRrczR4VXRKYVM0V0ZSZGEyY1BvREtfdTU0elIyWTJqU1Bsdm9iN1F4YVZLc3ZuV1hZaTZ6VGt5R1BOT2tublFHWm5pajdnM2NqWW03NThIRmsySTlseXFLaG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxNX2VvYWpKa3hhMmJxd1JSbmN6YTdqckJuREU3ZHBvVlptYTlLMmFKSTJxbFUwNmdYX2lUclNKS2V6YTgyWVYtdzRfcVExaGV2WTNmZldJdU5MS202OFZIc25pcjJVWElFMVlvOFhtUDVIN3M3bFRJT21pN1VzYWoxVmo4RERCeDRCMUJXR0huWE9PVWZLa2pKZlpqSzhXWnphVTJFeWFRbzN0Z21TTUNUQVdKUkd4QkdxWm9BQjZKT3BLOG01Z2xZTzFEbDVYUFXSAdQBQVVfeXFMTWJkZjlKbDhTRHB1Z09fd201eElKOWN0am9Eamg3LXBUSnJONks1VjNCMDFTYWpHSk53Ql9rOTYwSzhTSE9DdVd3dzhaUldacElHeUF1Qkx4RUVpSmtBa2x4VHMtc2Z0QkVQNXdPRi1JcUY0dS10dGFJNVRrczR4VXRKYVM0V0ZSZGEyY1BvREtfdTU0elIyWTJqU1Bsdm9iN1F4YVZLc3ZuV1hZaTZ6VGt5R1BOT2tublFHWm5pajdnM2NqWW03NThIRmsySTlseXFLaG8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 08:51:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My top 5 phones of 2024 - Sagar - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE9XczhhellvT1A5Z0NOYmppaU1leVc2ZFlIaHUzV3cyeXlOaVdUTnBEOExDOEVUb05pVHNTX2dDMzNJZl9TNE16aGR1ZHhzSjhtanZQMnJFMmFfbUxWTFpoZ29vM0xHUFVRZUFfZUpLSjJ3R21LTGc2M9IBdEFVX3lxTE9XemZ5THMzemJCU1pYcTRibmdDUVc2R1lTZDZCMlhWTWRWbl91LWcyZkRQcTlWejF5YVRMelZyQ2sybHhORzVWVXhQbW5EZm9aTXl0TVZkNFJPOXNQLUZJUzlwZF9TUUZ3bE4xWklMUEY3NmEt?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMieEFVX3lxTE9XczhhellvT1A5Z0NOYmppaU1leVc2ZFlIaHUzV3cyeXlOaVdUTnBEOExDOEVUb05pVHNTX2dDMzNJZl9TNE16aGR1ZHhzSjhtanZQMnJFMmFfbUxWTFpoZ29vM0xHUFVRZUFfZUpLSjJ3R21LTGc2M9IBdEFVX3lxTE9XemZ5THMzemJCU1pYcTRibmdDUVc2R1lTZDZCMlhWTWRWbl91LWcyZkRQcTlWejF5YVRMelZyQ2sybHhORzVWVXhQbW5EZm9aTXl0TVZkNFJPOXNQLUZJUzlwZF9TUUZ3bE4xWklMUEY3NmEt?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 07:48:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sheet masks are perfect for today's busy lifestyle, says Jung Ji-woo | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jung Ji-woo's Neaf Neaf: A New Arrival in India’s K-Beauty Scene</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>South Korean beauty entrepreneur Jung Ji-woo launches her brand Neaf Neaf in India, aiming to cater to the growing K-beauty market among Indian consumers.</p><ul><li>Neaf Neaf was launched at the Kosmos festival in Delhi.</li><li>The brand focuses on plant-derived ingredients and will feature a PDRN product range.</li><li>Jung Ji-woo discusses her motivations and insights into the Indian beauty market.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Korean beauty industry is trying to expand its presence in India."</blockquote><p>This initiative is part of a broader trend of increasing K-beauty influence in India, meeting local consumer demands.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/style/bts-j-hope-jung-ji-woo-k-beauty-korean-skincare-neaf-neaf-11735972730283.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/style/bts-j-hope-jung-ji-woo-k-beauty-korean-skincare-neaf-neaf-11735972730283.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 07:44:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sheet masks are perfect for today's busy lifestyle, says Jung Ji-woo - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jung Ji-woo's Neaf Neaf: A New Arrival in India’s K-Beauty Scene</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>South Korean beauty entrepreneur Jung Ji-woo launches her brand Neaf Neaf in India, aiming to cater to the growing K-beauty market among Indian consumers.</p><ul><li>Neaf Neaf was launched at the Kosmos festival in Delhi.</li><li>The brand focuses on plant-derived ingredients and will feature a PDRN product range.</li><li>Jung Ji-woo discusses her motivations and insights into the Indian beauty market.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Korean beauty industry is trying to expand its presence in India."</blockquote><p>This initiative is part of a broader trend of increasing K-beauty influence in India, meeting local consumer demands.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/style/bts-j-hope-jung-ji-woo-k-beauty-korean-skincare-neaf-neaf-11735972730283.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/mint-lounge/style/bts-j-hope-jung-ji-woo-k-beauty-korean-skincare-neaf-neaf-11735972730283.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 07:44:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra gets huge price drop once again, now available for just Rs 2,692 per month - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra gets huge price drop once again, now available for just Rs 2,692 per month</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p>
<img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/samsung-galaxy-s23-ultra-2-1735971491.webp" alt="Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra</figcaption>
<p>Samsung has significantly reduced the price of its Galaxy S23 Ultra during the New Year Sale on Flipkart. The phone is now available for Rs 40,000 less, though it's still above its lowest price.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Galaxy S23 Ultra is now priced at Rs 76,560, down from Rs 1,49,999.</li>
<li>Offers available include bank discounts, no-cost EMI, and additional savings for trade-ins.</li>
<li>Features a 200MP camera, 12GB RAM, 256GB storage, and a 6.81-inch Dynamic AMOLED display.</li>
<li>Includes advanced features like S-Pen functionality, 5000mAh battery, and 45W charging.</li>
<li>Quad-camera system and 12MP front camera for photography enthusiasts.</li>
<li>Flipkart is offering 5% cashback with specific credit cards.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The phone supports S-Pen functionality and packs a robust 5000mAh battery.”</blockquote>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy S23 Ultra's price drop makes it an appealing option for consumers seeking premium features at a reduced cost.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/samsung-galaxy-s23-ultra-gets-huge-price-drop-once-again-now-available-for-just-rs-2-692-per-month-2025-01-04-969458</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/samsung-galaxy-s23-ultra-gets-huge-price-drop-once-again-now-available-for-just-rs-2-692-per-month-2025-01-04-969458</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 06:20:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes, January 4, 2025, edition: Unlock rewards and level up your gameplay - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Garena Free Fire MAX redeem codes, January 4, 2025 edition: Unlock rewards and level up your gameplay</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 4, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p>
<img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/RELIANCE-JIO-NEW2-REUTERS1.jpg?w=300" alt="Jio is promoting the Rs 601 voucher as a 'gift' for seamless connectivity on its MyJio app"><figcaption>Jio is promoting the Rs 601 voucher as a 'gift' for seamless connectivity on its MyJio app</figcaption>
<p>Garena Free Fire MAX, a popular battle royale game, offers daily redeem codes that allow players to unlock exclusive rewards. These codes have become a key feature driving the game's popularity, especially following the ban of the original Free Fire due to privacy concerns.</p>
<ul>
<li>Frequent updates and challenges keep players engaged.</li>
<li>Redeem codes unlock items such as skins, diamonds, and gear without additional costs.</li>
<li>Each code is valid for just 24 hours, creating urgency among players to redeem them quickly.</li>
<li>The game competes effectively with other popular battle royale games like PUBG Mobile.</li>
<li>Redeeming codes involves logging into the Garena website and entering the provided code.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>The listed redeem codes for January 4, 2025:</p>
<p>XF4SWKCH6KY4, FVTCQK2MFNSK, FFWX9TSY2QK7, FFWST4NYM6XB, PFS5Y7NQFV9S, FFNYX2HQWCVK, YF6WN9QSFTHX, FF4MTXQPFDZ9, RDNAFV2KX2CQ, FV4SF2CQFY9M, HQK6FX2YT9GG, FFXT7SW9KG2M, FFWCY6TSX2QZ, FFXMTK9QFFX9</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Players are encouraged to continuously check for new codes to maximize their in-game performance and enjoy an enhanced gaming experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-january-4-2025-edition-unlock-rewards-and-level-up-your-gameplay-3707108/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/life/technology-garena-free-fire-max-redeem-codes-january-4-2025-edition-unlock-rewards-and-level-up-your-gameplay-3707108/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 05:44:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spotify’s Content Gaps: What Pornographic Search Results Reveal - MediaNama.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNMEQtNFlLSHQwUm9GT2Y0TW1mRHVmQzlqVjNuTnNqSDlPWG0xNG9GR1pHamhpOElzOFpORE1uTHUxSUVIRkpFODZIUVVsZjEwWndOVzdKbVFxeUwzNzlsTm9rcHlFNGdDZnNJLTlkNHFxNHpwd2lyTS1DeGxxYXVrcWhQTTNnZVZONEtrMHFxVlpnNG5UX0djdTd1el9EZEZFaXRVNVJoc21MT0tNZDdwbEdVVmU0UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNMEQtNFlLSHQwUm9GT2Y0TW1mRHVmQzlqVjNuTnNqSDlPWG0xNG9GR1pHamhpOElzOFpORE1uTHUxSUVIRkpFODZIUVVsZjEwWndOVzdKbVFxeUwzNzlsTm9rcHlFNGdDZnNJLTlkNHFxNHpwd2lyTS1DeGxxYXVrcWhQTTNnZVZONEtrMHFxVlpnNG5UX0djdTd1el9EZEZFaXRVNVJoc21MT0tNZDdwbEdVVmU0UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 05:41:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet Eclipsa Audio, the free-to-use Dolby Atmos alternative made by Google and Samsung - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Meet Eclipsa Audio, the free-to-use Dolby Atmos alternative made by Google and Samsung</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Eclipsa-Audio.png?w=640' alt='Eclipsa Audio will be supported by Samsung TVs, soundbars and YouTube.' width='640' height='360'><figcaption>Eclipsa Audio will be supported by Samsung TVs, soundbars and YouTube. (Image Source: Samsung)</figcaption><p>Google and Samsung recently unveiled Eclipsa Audio, a new 3D audio format that will be featured on Samsung made TVs and smartbars launched in 2025.</p><ul><li>Eclipsa Audio allows creators to adjust audio data for an immersive 3D experience.</li><li>The new format will be available on Samsung's Crystal UHD series to premium Neo QLED 8K models.</li><li>It is a free and open-source alternative to Dolby Atmos.</li><li>Available on YouTube, but requires adoption by streaming services.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are excited to see how the creator community uses it to create new and innovative audio experiences.” - Google Chrome executive</blockquote><p>Eclipsa Audio presents a notable challenge in terms of adoption despite being free, as the ecosystem for supported devices remains small compared to Dolby Atmos.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/tech-news-technology/eclipsa-audio-3d-audio-format-dolby-atmos-google-samsung-9759400/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/technology/tech-news-technology/eclipsa-audio-3d-audio-format-dolby-atmos-google-samsung-9759400/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 05:28:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 16 Plus now available for only Rs 39,750, here's how to avail this offer - India TV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Massive Discount on iPhone 16 Plus: Now Available for Rs 39,750</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> India TV News</p><img src="https://resize.indiatvnews.com/en/centered/newbucket/1200_675/2025/01/iphone-16-representational-image-1735967623.webp" alt="iPhone 16 discount" width="1200" height="675"><figcaption>iPhone 16 discount</figcaption><p>The new year has brought excellent discounts on smartphones, particularly on the iPhone 16 series. The iPhone 16 Plus is now available for Rs 39,750 through various offers and discounts.</p><ul><li>The iPhone 16 Plus has a listed price of Rs 89,900 but has dropped to Rs 84,900 due to a 5% discount.</li><li>Add an instant discount of Rs 4,000 with specific credit card payments, reducing the price further to Rs 80,900.</li><li>By trading in an old smartphone, customers can receive an additional exchange value of Rs 41,150.</li><li>Overall, with all offers applied, the iPhone 16 Plus can be purchased for just Rs 39,750.</li><li>The smartphone features a 6.7-inch Super AMOLED display, IP68 certification, and runs on iOS 18.</li><li>It is powered by the Apple A18 Bionic chipset and offers up to 8GB RAM and 512GB storage.</li></ul><blockquote>“If you make the most of these offers, you could walk away with the iPhone 16 Plus for just Rs 39,750.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, this is a great opportunity for customers looking to invest in an iPhone this new year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/iphone-16-plus-now-available-for-only-rs-39-750-here-s-how-to-avail-this-offer-2025-01-04-969445</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatvnews.com/technology/gadgets/iphone-16-plus-now-available-for-only-rs-39-750-here-s-how-to-avail-this-offer-2025-01-04-969445</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 05:15:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Garena Free Fire Max Codes For January 4: Score Street Savvy Bundle, Diamonds, Criminal Ring & More. Here's How - ABP Live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxNNHhzck1jenFMMzFPWmdOREw4cUtxSHREbUFOSE1ucC1MVVFUM2ppWmRDdFA5MWc1VUNvcTg5LWhrZ1NLY1plVkhib2g5RmU1ZzVNRFFyanVQLTM2dUZMREMzdjZuS2hRbkRTV2VTQXdBeTFJazNVdlcxeUJhN1VqcU9MSVlrZi1UcXRQTkNDcEpKUlZBOTR0YmduY1oyNk0wLXpmSlZISTJka2l1R29KM05jS2hDb05zaGtHdHl6R1cwSG9tWXUtcmFMQkxjQTF1LXlXQUFCWTFaTjVmcEh1R01vUVU0T0pxdExiWmdES0FmWmhSS2lQdE9vT1pFUW5xLUHSAYcCQVVfeXFMTW9hNjh0TFplTkxEMWJfbkRwZ2EyUUhyYWR0Tm1PZkgzTTVzdTlldnNyZlBQM3JlX2tmc08yeVk3RFExUWdKMDliNHp0TzlRSF9SX3pUcEVoZHdqLUJ0bThpaHBhc2tRc1NKdVNxd29ONm5IYkdmZ2ZKTFRpcE1DQ2NOdzJCemlMWlpVclJ6QWEzYzZxUGRMS2FHSEg5R2dvVWFubGNPUHRZYkd3X2dpUGsycGoyeTM2OHVMSGpub0owdkZJTHdtWHZQVTlDblZaQlU3Wnd1Ykdzb1JxRmVDUGlBOWNtQmhPWTEzVnZFNFRvVlFSVmJZTDZiakpJaG10UVFlNFJkZ2s?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxNNHhzck1jenFMMzFPWmdOREw4cUtxSHREbUFOSE1ucC1MVVFUM2ppWmRDdFA5MWc1VUNvcTg5LWhrZ1NLY1plVkhib2g5RmU1ZzVNRFFyanVQLTM2dUZMREMzdjZuS2hRbkRTV2VTQXdBeTFJazNVdlcxeUJhN1VqcU9MSVlrZi1UcXRQTkNDcEpKUlZBOTR0YmduY1oyNk0wLXpmSlZISTJka2l1R29KM05jS2hDb05zaGtHdHl6R1cwSG9tWXUtcmFMQkxjQTF1LXlXQUFCWTFaTjVmcEh1R01vUVU0T0pxdExiWmdES0FmWmhSS2lQdE9vT1pFUW5xLUHSAYcCQVVfeXFMTW9hNjh0TFplTkxEMWJfbkRwZ2EyUUhyYWR0Tm1PZkgzTTVzdTlldnNyZlBQM3JlX2tmc08yeVk3RFExUWdKMDliNHp0TzlRSF9SX3pUcEVoZHdqLUJ0bThpaHBhc2tRc1NKdVNxd29ONm5IYkdmZ2ZKTFRpcE1DQ2NOdzJCemlMWlpVclJ6QWEzYzZxUGRMS2FHSEg5R2dvVWFubGNPUHRZYkd3X2dpUGsycGoyeTM2OHVMSGpub0owdkZJTHdtWHZQVTlDblZaQlU3Wnd1Ykdzb1JxRmVDUGlBOWNtQmhPWTEzVnZFNFRvVlFSVmJZTDZiakpJaG10UVFlNFJkZ2s?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 05:01:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung India unveils ‘Big TV Days’ with premium AI-Powered TVs and exclusive offers - MediaNews4U]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung India Launches 'Big TV Days' with Premium AI-Powered TVs and Exclusive Offers</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Medianews4U</p><img src='https://www.medianews4u.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Samsng.jpg' alt='Samsung India unveils ‘Big TV Days’ with premium AI-Powered TVs and exclusive offers'><figcaption>Samsung India unveils ‘Big TV Days’ with premium AI-Powered TVs and exclusive offers</figcaption><p>Samsung, India’s leading consumer electronics brand, has launched its ‘Big TV Days’ campaign featuring exciting deals on premium big-screen TVs. From January 3 to January 31, 2025, customers can enjoy exclusive discounts, cashback offers, and bundled freebies.</p><ul><li>The campaign offers up to 20% cashback, zero down payment, and flexible EMI options for up to 30 months.</li><li>Select purchases come with free Samsung TVs worth up to ₹204,990 and soundbars worth up to ₹99,990.</li><li>Samsungs's lineup includes Neo QLED, OLED, and 4K UHD TVs, utilizing AI for enhanced viewing experience.</li></ul><blockquote>“At Samsung, we are redefining home entertainment with our ‘Big TV Days’ campaign...next-level viewing experiences to consumers across India with added benefits in the New Year,” said Viplesh Dang, Senior Director, Visual Display Business, Samsung India.</blockquote><p>Samsung aims to democratize advanced technologies and provide premium TVs to a broader audience, with diverse screen sizes and exceptional value.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.medianews4u.com/samsung-india-unveils-big-tv-days-with-premium-ai-powered-tvs-and-exclusive-offers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.medianews4u.com/samsung-india-unveils-big-tv-days-with-premium-ai-powered-tvs-and-exclusive-offers/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 04:54:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[POCO X7 Series Roundup: What to Expect From the POCO Launch Event Next Week - MySmartPrice]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>POCO X7 Series Roundup: What to Expect From the POCO Launch Event Next Week</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> MySmartPrice</p><img src="https://assets.mspimages.in/gear/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Poco-X7-series.jpg" alt="POCO X7 Series" width="400" height="210"><figcaption>POCO X7 Series Launch Announcement</figcaption><p>POCO is set to launch the POCO X7 series in India next week, including the POCO X7 and POCO X7 Pro, scheduled for January 9th.</p><ul><li>The launch event will be live-streamed on YouTube at 5:30 pm IST.</li><li>POCO X7 Pro to start at under Rs. 26,000 on Flipkart.</li><li>Expect improvements in processing power with the MediaTek Dimensity 8400 Ultra SoC in the X7 Pro.</li><li>POCO X7 Pro features a 6,550mAh battery with 90W fast charging.</li><li>POCO X7 is expected to carry a MediaTek Dimensity 7300 Ultra SoC.</li></ul><blockquote>“POCO promises 3 years of Android updates and 4 years of security patches.”</blockquote><p>Stay tuned for further announcements as the POCO X7 series promises to deliver powerful features and cutting-edge technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/mobiles/mobiles-features/poco-x7-series-roundup/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mysmartprice.com/gear/mobiles/mobiles-features/poco-x7-series-roundup/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 04:30:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung may have a ‘plan’ to beat Sony's iPhone camera ‘dominance’ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Samsung Plans Strategy to Challenge Sony's iPhone Camera Dominance</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Specified] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/109343604.cms" alt="Samsung Camera Technology" />
<figcaption>Samsung is preparing to counter Sony's lead in smartphone camera technology.</figcaption>
<p>Samsung is reportedly devising a plan to enhance its camera technology in order to compete with Sony's dominance in the smartphone camera market.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Samsung aims to improve user experience with innovative camera features.</li>
  <li>The company is investing in advanced imaging technologies.</li>
  <li>The competition is driven by the increasing demand for high-quality smartphone photography.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Our goal is to ensure that our users have the best photography experience possible." - Samsung Executive</blockquote>
<p>This latest development highlights the ongoing competition between major smartphone manufacturers and the significance of camera quality in attracting consumers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/mobiles-tabs/samsung-may-have-a-plan-to-beat-sonys-iphone-camera-dominance/articleshow/116931209.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/mobiles-tabs/samsung-may-have-a-plan-to-beat-sonys-iphone-camera-dominance/articleshow/116931209.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 03:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SpaceX's Starship to deploy mock satellites in next test - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SpaceX's Starship to Deploy Mock Satellites in Upcoming Test Flight</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 04 January 2025, 00:50 IST</p><p>Elon Musk's SpaceX is preparing for a crucial test of its Starship rocket, which will attempt to deploy payloads in space by releasing 10 model Starlink satellites. This marks a significant step in Starship's development as a satellite launch vehicle.</p><ul><li>The Starship flight will take place from Boca Chica, Texas, later this month.</li><li>This will be the first exercise of a satellite deployment mission, showcasing Starship's capabilities.</li><li>October's test saw the 'Super Heavy' booster successfully returning to its launch pad.</li><li>The rocket aims to support future satellite launches and SpaceX's plans to colonize Mars.</li></ul><blockquote>"Starship is the centerpiece of SpaceX's future satellite launch business."</blockquote><p>With its powerful design, Starship is set to expand SpaceX's Starlink internet network and support NASA's plans to return astronauts to the moon.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/spacexs-starship-to-deploy-mock-satellites-in-next-test-3341239</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/spacexs-starship-to-deploy-mock-satellites-in-next-test-3341239</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:50:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NPCI moving to give netbanking a UPI-like makeover | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NPCI Aims to Transform Netbanking with UPI-Style Integration</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Mint</p><p>Mumbai: A pilot project by the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) could resolve the common issue of missing banks in netbanking options during mobile payments on e-commerce sites.</p><ul><li>The problem arises from the way merchants collaborate with payment gateways, leading to difficulties in bank visibility for consumers.</li><li>The NPCI initiative aims to streamline integrations and improve user experience by using a UPI-like model for netbanking.</li><li>This transformation seeks to enhance payment efficiency and accessibility for a larger number of consumers.</li></ul><blockquote>“This stumbling block faced by many consumers may be fixed if a pilot rolled out by the National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) last month works out.”</blockquote><p>This development promises to increase convenience for users and could signify a major shift in how online payments are processed in India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/industry/banking/npci-netbanking-upi-axis-bank-payu-razorpay-amazon-flipkart-cc-avenue-nbbl-bhim-ntt-data-payment-services-qr-code-11735912037858.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/industry/banking/npci-netbanking-upi-axis-bank-payu-razorpay-amazon-flipkart-cc-avenue-nbbl-bhim-ntt-data-payment-services-qr-code-11735912037858.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 17 Air, Samsung Galaxy S25 Slim price range and thickness leak - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNMlMtOVZBS3hhSGlHQ3k5cGpXVHkwR1pFRWl2aFRsNzRHMjZOWHhaWXluc1h1WHF1b1NIaFRzaS1xNnZrX1RtZUxuQzJvOWdsbEljNTN2eko2a2FaRzV1ODlnbHpuTWIxMGJhWlI2eDk2Q2V0U3FNdEFmSTlreWUtMVhPaVMwQnk3ZmpnTVJmU2M1ZFJQUHVSTDVzNUlFTmEzelMwa1NjZ3hJNGFn0gGoAUFVX3lxTFBTcmhPaGZuQThrWlpqZnpTcTliSmdEV2Q1Rjl1em1xQU1WdkNLcE5fZ1JXODFFUmY4S2RFWGR3YkRadGplTkVvWVE2SnFacFRRNXI4WE5IZzQ0Wk53cklmZXA5U1FZLTA1dzFjY2NHOFpWZmVmOEo2cVRoSmlUYksxRk1UYkRoay1lRmVWc0dMR0pTT05PS09QRWpKWk45bVZMcGF1dWVJVA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxNMlMtOVZBS3hhSGlHQ3k5cGpXVHkwR1pFRWl2aFRsNzRHMjZOWHhaWXluc1h1WHF1b1NIaFRzaS1xNnZrX1RtZUxuQzJvOWdsbEljNTN2eko2a2FaRzV1ODlnbHpuTWIxMGJhWlI2eDk2Q2V0U3FNdEFmSTlreWUtMVhPaVMwQnk3ZmpnTVJmU2M1ZFJQUHVSTDVzNUlFTmEzelMwa1NjZ3hJNGFn0gGoAUFVX3lxTFBTcmhPaGZuQThrWlpqZnpTcTliSmdEV2Q1Rjl1em1xQU1WdkNLcE5fZ1JXODFFUmY4S2RFWGR3YkRadGplTkVvWVE2SnFacFRRNXI4WE5IZzQ0Wk53cklmZXA5U1FZLTA1dzFjY2NHOFpWZmVmOEo2cVRoSmlUYksxRk1UYkRoay1lRmVWc0dMR0pTT05PS09QRWpKWk45bVZMcGF1dWVJVA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 22:59:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mercedes CLE Cabriolet Review - Drop-top motoring is a civilised affair - Driven]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mercedes CLE Cabriolet Review - A Civilized Drop-top Driving Experience</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24<br><strong>Source:</strong> Driven</p><img src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/612f4f7e00611a662fb50b92/79662247-0583-46bc-85d7-042df2299596/Mercedes+CLE+Cabriolet+%284%29.jpg" alt="Mercedes CLE Cabriolet" width="6000" height="4000"><figcaption>Mercedes CLE Cabriolet</figcaption><p>The Mercedes CLE Cabriolet merges the qualities of the C-Class and E-Class convertibles into a stylish and tech-savvy vehicle that offers a civilized open-top motoring experience.</p><ul><li>The CLE Cabriolet replaces both the C-Class Cabriolet and E-Class Cabriolet.</li><li>Offers various engine options, including the powerful AMG models.</li><li>Interior space is improved compared to predecessors, comfortably seating four.</li><li>Notable features include the Airscarf warm air system for neck comfort and an effective wind deflector.</li><li>Base price for the CLE 300 starts at £53,030, with the top model at £70,320.</li><li>Handling is geared towards comfort rather than sportiness, making it ideal for relaxed cruising.</li></ul><blockquote>“When it comes to cruising along in a glamorous-looking car, they don’t get much better than this.”</blockquote><p>The Mercedes CLE Cabriolet stands out with its sleek design, advanced features, and a focus on comfort, making it an excellent option for luxury open-top driving enthusiasts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://driven.site/words/mercedes-cle-cabriolet-review</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://driven.site/words/mercedes-cle-cabriolet-review</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 21:54:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Windows Insider Program Rings in the New Year with New Canary and Beta Builds - Thurrott.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Windows Insider Program Rings in the New Year with New Canary and Beta Builds</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 03, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Thurrott</p><p><img src="https://thurrott-assets.nyc3.digitaloceanspaces.com/web/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/01/magnifier-new-buttons.jpg" alt="Windows 11 Magnifier with two new buttons" width="1066" height="600"><figcaption>Windows 11 Magnifier with two new buttons</figcaption></p><p>The winter break is over: Microsoft has issued minor new Windows 11 Insider Preview builds to the Canary and Beta channels.</p><ul><li>Canary channel users can download Windows 11 Insider Preview build 27766, which includes general improvements and bug fixes.</li><li>The Beta build, KB5048808, updates the OS to Windows 11 23H2 build 22635.4660, introducing minor features and fixes.</li><li>New features include labels for commands in context menus and two new buttons in the Magnifier tool.</li></ul><blockquote>“Happy New Year. Or something.” - Paul Thurrott</blockquote><p>This update, while minor, continues the ongoing development of Windows 11, reflecting Microsoft’s commitment to improving the user experience.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thurrott.com/windows/windows-11/315247/windows-insider-program-rings-in-the-new-year-with-new-canary-and-beta-builds</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thurrott.com/windows/windows-11/315247/windows-insider-program-rings-in-the-new-year-with-new-canary-and-beta-builds</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 21:05:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Loop: iPhone SE Price Leaks, iOS 18.2.1 Details, 2025’s MacBook Air Plans - Forbes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/ewanspence/2025/01/03/apple-news-headlines-iphone-se-price-ios-18-macbook-air-release-date/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/ewanspence/2025/01/03/apple-news-headlines-iphone-se-price-ios-18-macbook-air-release-date/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 21:00:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Fitness+ adds Strava integration and a ton of new content - GSMArena.com news - GSMArena.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxNQlQwWVNfM1N2Q0ljOEVSY25JbGVJSlJHM2tlWjhVbUNvSS1Rd1FfUTExN2RPcnVvWTlIajdOSl9vdS0yOXl6aEtXLThkMnFQMlExOVBsS1JjZU5nb2tWVWhBQzN5VkpRR00xTnRoZTBoZDlHT2dVQmRIRnJtZGJFNWpJREoxd0NySGs5TmRVSTBCV0FCRDVUUTVrNF9UNUhqbXdKYdIBoAFBVV95cUxPZExjdzIwTG5TMTUyaERERnNuQmVxZnF2N3JabDN4VWdoR3ZtVzFzTWdkRWQ2U1ZJYkZoaTBvZjBWSk5tX0FOUG9KUGxDOS1IUnBIZ21HUUZtX2E1TE52aV9GUzFTTGo2Yk5RQmlvdG5pTWI0OUQtNzNqVzNBc3h5X3ZvbG01ajFQM0F2RENVT09ITEZqaGxJSFppTVR1M3RN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMipAFBVV95cUxNQlQwWVNfM1N2Q0ljOEVSY25JbGVJSlJHM2tlWjhVbUNvSS1Rd1FfUTExN2RPcnVvWTlIajdOSl9vdS0yOXl6aEtXLThkMnFQMlExOVBsS1JjZU5nb2tWVWhBQzN5VkpRR00xTnRoZTBoZDlHT2dVQmRIRnJtZGJFNWpJREoxd0NySGs5TmRVSTBCV0FCRDVUUTVrNF9UNUhqbXdKYdIBoAFBVV95cUxPZExjdzIwTG5TMTUyaERERnNuQmVxZnF2N3JabDN4VWdoR3ZtVzFzTWdkRWQ2U1ZJYkZoaTBvZjBWSk5tX0FOUG9KUGxDOS1IUnBIZ21HUUZtX2E1TE52aV9GUzFTTGo2Yk5RQmlvdG5pTWI0OUQtNzNqVzNBc3h5X3ZvbG01ajFQM0F2RENVT09ITEZqaGxJSFppTVR1M3RN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 20:01:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Value in Smartphone.AI, volume at the 5G end for 2025 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/cons-products/electronics/value-in-smartphone-ai-volume-at-the-5g-end-for-2025/articleshow/116925278.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/cons-products/electronics/value-in-smartphone-ai-volume-at-the-5g-end-for-2025/articleshow/116925278.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 19:05:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to play Red Light, Green Light in Black Ops 6 Multiplayer: New Squid Game 2 LTM explained - Sportskeeda]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How to Play Red Light, Green Light in Black Ops 6 Multiplayer: New Squid Game 2 LTM Explained</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> <span>Published on October 2023, Source: Sportskeeda</span></p>
<figure><img src="https://staticg.sportskeeda.com/editor/2025/01/bdbde-17359259784570-1920.jpg?w=640" alt="Young-hee in Red Light Green Light game mode in Black Ops 6 (Image via Activision)"><figcaption>Young-hee in Red Light Green Light game mode in Black Ops 6 (Image via Activision)</figcaption></figure>
<p>This article discusses the new limited-time mode (LTM) Red Light, Green Light in Black Ops 6, part of the Call of Duty X Squid Games Season 2 crossover event. Players engage in a multiplayer adaptation of the classic game.</p>
<ul>
<li>The mode takes place at the Red Card Stadium and features the iconic Young-hee doll.</li>
<li>Players must freeze while Young-hee says "Red Light" and move when she says "Green Light".</li>
<li>There are three rounds, each lasting two minutes.</li>
<li>Power-ups such as Piggy Bank and Ddakji are available to boost scores.</li>
<li>In later rounds, players can pick up weapons and engage in combat.</li>
<li>Top three survivors win the game.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"That covers everything you need to know about the Red Light, Green Light in Black Ops 6."</blockquote>
<p>This limited-time mode incorporates elements from the popular Squid Games series, generating excitement among players looking for new gameplay experiences.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sportskeeda.com/call-of-duty-game/how-play-red-light-green-light-black-ops-6-multiplayer-new-squid-game-2-ltm-explained</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sportskeeda.com/call-of-duty-game/how-play-red-light-green-light-black-ops-6-multiplayer-new-squid-game-2-ltm-explained</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 18:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Looking to buy a smartphone in 2025? Here are the top 10 most anticipated ones, is the one you are looking - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAJBVV95cUxPVjVnMnd4ZUJ5NU1fQ05kODFySDBUak1ZZjJWRUtjLWNUbmNPRWhoelVoUUpBenVvbDlNU1Y4dC1HUHVLVDh3QWMyc2hNRGlScFZobmZhTGVHd3ZpLW5CRlI2VW9OWEhzOGhIbnpKQ3N3OWJKU082TXMycjZlaWJ4cDBwQld0cnVDUUdxTUs5cHFHdHhzcHQ3R2F4MjVCckZWdTJsYXZxN1V1NW5pZ3NPUjN0dERtMEhQd3lpTVM1WFRWZDl3ZElyUS10RTBJajlkNHI2eUtfVWs3T0U3ZnNPOGRrdzVvbkJ3anp3Q2g3Nk9UXzlZTkE5dDljcENDRWxoSlpwUDNObi0xdkcxd09yN2E5TTNjQWpubUloddIBogJBVV95cUxNdlVnRlNoV0hGYnoyRTJwTlhYbUQ0Mkp6OXMwLUhHRThXN1lyQXZPY1JuNnd6ZlFrZkE5V05qWjdZcmlwMmJGWHR0Y19qS0E4SWZtNm9YS3E5WjZxSnV1d2lRUWdEaG03Wm56RTZBX0M4ZTk3SzlVWTliSjVJRGE0RHNFUDBjNHgtRDZoZkY4bzRzeHc2OHFzSDRpMG9WT2pjbU1aazZJVWhrbFVSMWE5aGJFZS1YTS1xblFwU1MwaFFDcUItd0hCS1JtdzM1MDVYN1FTVS12QzVzUDI5UV9nb2RCVGgxYkZ5NVVKeHcxekdsVXRMMHpvOTBWWW90SVp1aVZ2amUtTk00NXR5bzVRZG1FZFUzYVZ4T2xkaElVOEZyUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAJBVV95cUxPVjVnMnd4ZUJ5NU1fQ05kODFySDBUak1ZZjJWRUtjLWNUbmNPRWhoelVoUUpBenVvbDlNU1Y4dC1HUHVLVDh3QWMyc2hNRGlScFZobmZhTGVHd3ZpLW5CRlI2VW9OWEhzOGhIbnpKQ3N3OWJKU082TXMycjZlaWJ4cDBwQld0cnVDUUdxTUs5cHFHdHhzcHQ3R2F4MjVCckZWdTJsYXZxN1V1NW5pZ3NPUjN0dERtMEhQd3lpTVM1WFRWZDl3ZElyUS10RTBJajlkNHI2eUtfVWs3T0U3ZnNPOGRrdzVvbkJ3anp3Q2g3Nk9UXzlZTkE5dDljcENDRWxoSlpwUDNObi0xdkcxd09yN2E5TTNjQWpubUloddIBogJBVV95cUxNdlVnRlNoV0hGYnoyRTJwTlhYbUQ0Mkp6OXMwLUhHRThXN1lyQXZPY1JuNnd6ZlFrZkE5V05qWjdZcmlwMmJGWHR0Y19qS0E4SWZtNm9YS3E5WjZxSnV1d2lRUWdEaG03Wm56RTZBX0M4ZTk3SzlVWTliSjVJRGE0RHNFUDBjNHgtRDZoZkY4bzRzeHc2OHFzSDRpMG9WT2pjbU1aazZJVWhrbFVSMWE5aGJFZS1YTS1xblFwU1MwaFFDcUItd0hCS1JtdzM1MDVYN1FTVS12QzVzUDI5UV9nb2RCVGgxYkZ5NVVKeHcxekdsVXRMMHpvOTBWWW90SVp1aVZ2amUtTk00NXR5bzVRZG1FZFUzYVZ4T2xkaElVOEZyUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 18:10:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>