<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:20:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:20:46 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel will remain at Hermon until 'another arrangement is found,' Netanyahu says during assessment - The Jerusalem Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel will remain at Hermon until 'another arrangement is found,' Netanyahu says during assessment</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> DECEMBER 17, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Jerusalem Post</p><div><img src='https://www.jpost.com/portal/images/benjamin-netanyahu-mount-hermon.jpg' alt='Netanyahu at Mount Hermon' /><figcaption>Prime Minister Netanyahu speaking during the assessment on Mount Hermon.</figcaption></div><p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu conducted a situational assessment at the Hermon Ridge with defense officials, affirming Israel's commitment to the area until a new security arrangement is reached.</p><ul><li>Netanyahu was accompanied by Defense Minister Israel Katz and IDF Chief of Staff Herzi Halevi.</li><li>The Prime Minister's Office indicated that guidelines for Israel's military deployment were established during the visit.</li><li>Netanyahu emphasized the importance of the location for national security, stating, "We are here for a situational assessment to decide on Israel's deployment in this important location until another arrangement is found that ensures the security of the state."</li></ul><blockquote>"We are here for a situational assessment to decide on Israel's deployment in this important location." - Benjamin Netanyahu</blockquote><p>The visit highlights Israel's ongoing strategic presence in the region amidst rising tensions and security concerns.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jpost.com/breaking-news/article-833840</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jpost.com/breaking-news/article-833840</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mayotte authorities fear hunger, disease after cyclone; death toll rises in Mozambique - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/mayotte-authorities-fear-hunger-disease-race-help-cyclone-survivors-2024-12-17/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/mayotte-authorities-fear-hunger-disease-race-help-cyclone-survivors-2024-12-17/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 16:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Iran is not imposing its strict new hijab law - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/iran-postpones-implementation-of-strict-new-hijab-law/articleshow/116406962.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/iran-postpones-implementation-of-strict-new-hijab-law/articleshow/116406962.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 15:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India's Diplomatic Move In North Korea Marks Significant Shift In Policy - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India's Diplomatic Move In North Korea Marks Significant Shift In Policy</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<div>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/t7hft4fk_indian-embassy-north-korea-indian-embassy-pyongyang_625x300_17_December_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,widt" alt="Indian embassy in North Korea" />
<figcaption>Indian embassy in North Korea</figcaption>
</div>
<p>In a notable shift in India’s foreign policy, the country has decided to resume operations at its embassy in Pyongyang after a hiatus of more than three years, reflecting a growing interest in stabilizing diplomatic relations with North Korea.</p>
<ul>
  <li>India's Act East policy involves strengthening ties with Southeast Asian nations while managing relationships on the Korean peninsula.</li>
  <li>The Indian embassy in Pyongyang was closed in July 2021 amid the COVID-19 pandemic, with diplomatic staff returning to New Delhi.</li>
  <li>Recently, India dispatched a team to North Korea to resume operations, highlighting its strategic importance in the region.</li>
  <li>North Korea's growing nuclear capabilities and alliances with Russia, China, and Iran raise concerns for India, necessitating a diplomatic presence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Reopening the embassy in Pyongyang is seen as the first step to reestablishing a channel of communication.”</blockquote>
<p>This development underscores India's intent to engage more actively in Northeast Asian geopolitics and counterbalance growing ties between North Korea and other regional powers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indias-diplomatic-move-in-north-korea-marks-significant-shift-in-policy-7270839</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indias-diplomatic-move-in-north-korea-marks-significant-shift-in-policy-7270839</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:23:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wisconsin shooter social media activity: What we know about Natalie Rupnow's digital footprint - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wisconsin shooter social media activity: What we know about Natalie Rupnow's digital footprint</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 25, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News Organization Name</p><p>An overview of Natalie Rupnow's social media activity surrounding the Wisconsin shooting incident, exploring the implications of her online presence.</p><ul><li>The article examines the digital activities of Natalie Rupnow in the context of the recent Wisconsin shooting.</li><li>It highlights posts that may provide insight into her motivations and mindset.</li><li>The discussion includes the potential impact of social media on public perception of the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“Social media can shape narratives and influence public understanding of tragic events.”</blockquote><p>The article concludes by emphasizing the importance of monitoring social media in understanding such incidents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/wisconsin-shooter-social-media-activity-what-we-know-about-natalie-rupnows-digital-footprint/articleshow/116403178.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/wisconsin-shooter-social-media-activity-what-we-know-about-natalie-rupnows-digital-footprint/articleshow/116403178.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Couple married and divorced 12 times in 40 years. Now they are getting sued by the government - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>An Austrian couple was found to have committed welfare fraud by marrying and divorcing over 12 times to exploit a loophole.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/gca4e186e126ec8058db0d08b82100f940f4d9316531fff206_1734442754998_1734442755262.jpg" alt="The couple's first divorce occurred in 1988, after about six years of marriage.(Representational)"><figcaption>The couple's first divorce occurred in 1988, after about six years of marriage.(Representational)</figcaption><p>A couple in Austria ran a welfare scam for over 4 decades by repeatedly marrying and divorcing each other. A 73-year-old woman received over $342,000 in widow's pension payments after the death of her first husband in 1981.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>The couple began their scam in 1988 with their first divorce.</li><li>Each marriage lasted only three years, with the woman becoming a bride 13 times.</li><li>Every divorce allowed the woman to regain her widow's pension, while the husband remained employed away from home.</li><li>The couple was recently sued by the government for welfare fraud after their latest divorce.</li><li>Pension authorities refused to reinstate the widow's pension due to suspicious marital patterns.</li><li>Austria's Supreme Court dismissed their case, labeling their actions as abusive.</li><li>Authorities have launched a fraud investigation.</li></ul><blockquote>“The repeated marriage and subsequent divorce from the same spouse is abusive if the marriage was never truly broken.” - Austria's Supreme Court</blockquote><p>The couple's case highlights issues surrounding welfare systems and the potential for exploitation through legal loopholes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/couple-married-and-divorced-12-times-in-40-years-now-they-are-getting-sued-by-the-government-101734442520206.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/couple-married-and-divorced-12-times-in-40-years-now-they-are-getting-sued-by-the-government-101734442520206.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:46:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK court jails father, stepmother for life for murder of daughter Sara Sharif - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNR0hmQ3ZOS1gzaHBrWVdHNllwNEc0S0RqNnhsQng3aW0tOERlMHlDVEJhTHoxekdTcWpEcHZTRFg4NWhFYm1JdFVzNXI4V05tbmxFUUFEd1hiRlZYTHA0OVlfWHFoRlV6YVpraUdaUWNlVHhtaUhNb29zZkhQQ291d0hYdkk4Z19iMjltMnEtU25mVWFhU1hiVm52N0Y2eW9uYzVEVWNwMk1VOF9pcjUw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirwFBVV95cUxNR0hmQ3ZOS1gzaHBrWVdHNllwNEc0S0RqNnhsQng3aW0tOERlMHlDVEJhTHoxekdTcWpEcHZTRFg4NWhFYm1JdFVzNXI4V05tbmxFUUFEd1hiRlZYTHA0OVlfWHFoRlV6YVpraUdaUWNlVHhtaUhNb29zZkhQQ291d0hYdkk4Z19iMjltMnEtU25mVWFhU1hiVm52N0Y2eW9uYzVEVWNwMk1VOF9pcjUw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 13:35:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baba Vanga's shocking predictions for 2025: Climate, medicine, and space - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/astrology/baba-vanga-s-shocking-prophecies-for-2025-climate-medicine-and-space-article-12890586.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/astrology/baba-vanga-s-shocking-prophecies-for-2025-climate-medicine-and-space-article-12890586.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:31:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch | Israel drops massive bomb in Syria that causes 'mini-earthquake' - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel's Airstrike in Syria Causes 'Mini-Earthquake'</h1>
<p><strong>Published Date:</strong> 17 December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> New York Times</p>
<p>On Thursday, an airstrike by Israel in the Tartus region of Syria resulted in an explosion of such magnitude that it was felt over 500 meters away and registered as a 'mini-earthquake' measuring 3.0 on seismic sensors.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The explosion was so large that it was detected by a magnetometer located 820 kilometers from the blast site.</li>
  <li>Videos of the explosion have gone viral on social media, showing a massive orange fireball.</li>
  <li>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported a series of Israeli airstrikes targeting military positions in Syria.</li>
  <li>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu emphasized the importance of strengthening the Golan Heights in light of ongoing threats from Syria.</li>
  <li>Several Arab countries, including Saudi Arabia and the UAE, have condemned Israel's actions in the region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>A Massive Explosion seen in Northwestern Syria near the City of Tartus, following an Israeli Strike against a Munitions Depot; with the Explosion reported to have been so large, that it measured as a 3.0 Magnitude Earthquake on nearby Seismic Sensors.</blockquote>
<p>The event highlights the continuing military tensions in the region and the strategic implications for Israel amidst geopolitical conflicts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/watch-israel-drops-massive-bomb-in-syria-that-causes-mini-earthquake-3321267</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/watch-israel-drops-massive-bomb-in-syria-that-causes-mini-earthquake-3321267</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:29:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch | Israel drops massive bomb in Syria that causes mini-earthquake - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watch | Israel drops massive bomb in Syria that causes 'mini-earthquake'</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 17 December 2024, 12:29 IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> New York Times</p><p>An airstrike by Israel resulted in a colossal explosion in Syria's Tartus region, described by witnesses as capable of being felt over half a kilometer away. The explosion was so powerful that it created seismic signals equivalent to a 3.0 magnitude earthquake.</p><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Explosion in Syria' /><figcaption>Explosion seen in Northwestern Syria</figcaption><p>This airstrike is part of Israel's ongoing campaign to target military infrastructure in Syria amidst regional tensions.</p><ul><li>The explosion occurred in the coastal Tartus region and was visible internationally.</li><li>Numerous videos circulated showing a large fireball resulting from the strike.</li><li>Seismic sensors detected the blast from 820 km away.</li><li>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights reported that these strikes are targeting Syrian military assets.</li><li>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu emphasized the importance of fortifying Golan Heights in light of regional threats.</li></ul><blockquote>A Massive Explosion seen in Northwestern Syria near the City of Tartus, following an Israeli Strike against a Munitions Depot; with the Explosion reported to have been so large, that it measured as a 3.0 Magnitude Earthquake on nearby Seismic Sensors. — OSINTdefender</blockquote><p>This event underscores the ongoing geopolitical tensions in the region and Israel's strategic military operations against perceived threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/watch-israel-drops-massive-bomb-in-syria-that-causes-mini-earthquake-3321267</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/watch-israel-drops-massive-bomb-in-syria-that-causes-mini-earthquake-3321267</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:29:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Madness must be stopped': Ukraine accuses Russian troops of burning faces of dead North Korean soldiers - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/madness-must-be-stopped-ukraine-accuses-russian-troops-of-burning-faces-of-dead-north-korean-soldiers/articleshow/116402444.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/madness-must-be-stopped-ukraine-accuses-russian-troops-of-burning-faces-of-dead-north-korean-soldiers/articleshow/116402444.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iran suspends controversial hijab law amid mounting pressure - The Siasat Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Iran Suspends Controversial Hijab Law Amid Mounting Pressure</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 17, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Siasat Daily</p>
<img src="https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-2024-12-17T033915.929.jpg" alt="Iranian women wearing hijab" width="1200" height="900">
<figcaption>Iranian women wearing hijab walk down a street in the capital Tehran on February 7, 2018.</figcaption>
<p>The Islamic Republic of Iran’s Supreme National Security Council has ceased its enforcement of a controversial hijab law that sought to punish women who failed to don the Islamic dress code, following escalating protests.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The government plans to introduce an amendment to clarify ambiguities of the Hijab and Chastity law.</li>
    <li>The controversial law would have imposed harsh penalties, including fines and prison sentences for non-compliance.</li>
    <li>President Masoud Pezeshkian expressed concerns about the law provoking unnecessary conflicts.</li>
    <li>Human rights organizations condemned the proposed law, labeling it as “draconian” and detrimental to women's rights.</li>
    <li>The suspension of the law is seen as a significant victory for Iranian women's rights activists.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This law will further worsen the status of women and girls.” - Amnesty International</blockquote>
<p>This decision represents a turning point for women's rights in Iran, reflecting the impact of years of protests against mandatory hijab laws.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.siasat.com/iran-suspends-controversial-hijab-law-amid-mounting-pressure-3149661/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.siasat.com/iran-suspends-controversial-hijab-law-amid-mounting-pressure-3149661/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel planning offensive against Yemen, report says - Middle East Eye]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Planning Offensive Against Yemen, Report Says</h1>
<p><strong>Published date:</strong> 17 December 2024 12:22 GMT | <strong>Last update:</strong> 6 hours 2 mins ago</p>
<div>
  <img loading="lazy" src="/sites/default/files/styles/max_2600x2600/public/images-story/yemen-houth-spokesperson-13dec2024-afp.jpg.jpg?itok=CzG_59fm" width="1400" height="932" alt="Houthi military spokesman Yahya Saree during rally in Sanaa" />
  <figcaption>Houthi military spokesman Yahya Saree speaks during a rally in solidarity with the people of Gaza in Sanaa on 13 December 2024 (AFP)</figcaption>
</div>
<p>The Israeli army is reportedly planning to strike Yemen following missile and drone attacks by the Houthi movement, which the Houthis claim are in retaliation for the ongoing conflict in Gaza.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Houthis claimed to have hit a military target near Tel Aviv with a ballistic missile.</li>
  <li>Israeli defenses reportedly intercepted the missile before it could enter Israeli airspace.</li>
  <li>The Houthi attacks are said to be part of their efforts to pressure Israel to cease its military actions in Gaza.</li>
  <li>Israeli intelligence associates the escalating Houthi attacks with Iranian influence and orchestrations.</li>
  <li>The Houthis have attacked shipping lanes, causing international concern and strategic military responses.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“They are trying to promote significant damage to Israeli assets such as the seaports of Ashdod and Haifa, the power plants of the Israel Electric Corporation, and the gas rigs off the coast of Israel,” Kan reported.</blockquote>
<p>This anticipated response from Israel represents a significant escalation in regional tensions and highlights ongoing conflicts rooted in the broader context of Middle Eastern geopolitics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.middleeasteye.net/news/israel-planning-offensive-against-yemen</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.middleeasteye.net/news/israel-planning-offensive-against-yemen</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ukraine's security service behind bomb blast that killed top Russian general: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ukraine's Security Service Behind Bomb Blast That Killed Top Russian General</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 17, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/igor_kirillov_1734436594892_1734436595151.JPG" alt="Igor Kirillov was killed by a bomb kept in a scooter outside his apartment in Moscow. (Reuters)"><figcaption>Igor Kirillov was killed by a bomb kept in a scooter outside his apartment in Moscow. (Reuters)</figcaption></figure><p>The Associated Press reported that Ukraine's security service was responsible for the bomb blast that killed Russian general Igor Kirillov. His death followed a criminal investigation opened against him by Ukraine for his actions in the ongoing conflict.</p><ul><li>Kirillov was the chief of Russia's military nuclear, biological, and chemical protection forces.</li><li>The explosion occurred when he was leaving his home for work, resulting in the death of his assistant as well.</li><li>The SBU described Kirillov as a war criminal, citing his involvement in using chemical weapons in the war.</li><li>Since the February 2022 invasion, over 4,800 instances of alleged chemical weapon usage by Russia have been recorded by the Ukrainian secret service.</li><li>The bomb was remotely triggered, according to Russian news reports.</li></ul><blockquote>“Kirillov is a war criminal and an entirely legitimate target.” - Anonymous SBU official</blockquote><p>This event underscores the escalating tensions and hostilities in the ongoing conflict between Ukraine and Russia, impacting both military strategy and international relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/ukraines-security-service-behind-bomb-blast-that-killed-top-russian-general-report-101734436027169.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/ukraines-security-service-behind-bomb-blast-that-killed-top-russian-general-report-101734436027169.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:12:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Georgia: 11 Indians found dead at Gudauri ski resort - DW (English)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxORUphSnJQWEE4Um9ZUGtjX1RzQndEY3JSMTRQRy1XNndDeFB0bURNRUdKeEtUd0RHQi14alZoNHExcFZBN0Y0ODZZNmxkU2hZYzhyVFBrU0YxSXJZemRmUFZXNU50QTNPNVgxVkxzdFhCcDlKNFJpYmM1SlA4NFFuR185WkNYYmFEa00yQtIBjAFBVV95cUxNWnRIUFI5R1R6RjBRZjNHQkdrNnNZbmU2U1RiVjVrWHEyTFhtSlBIOGRRUVVMUkg4RVhXY3ZibWZ0b29KM1FYLXJObkJiU1NzZXhMdXJxSHI1NHpkZm5aRmxCV1ltTWNaTHJVOXFtM21vaGJpVmxseUM3dm4tcmJYNXREQ3RHbElOZHF6eQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxORUphSnJQWEE4Um9ZUGtjX1RzQndEY3JSMTRQRy1XNndDeFB0bURNRUdKeEtUd0RHQi14alZoNHExcFZBN0Y0ODZZNmxkU2hZYzhyVFBrU0YxSXJZemRmUFZXNU50QTNPNVgxVkxzdFhCcDlKNFJpYmM1SlA4NFFuR185WkNYYmFEa00yQtIBjAFBVV95cUxNWnRIUFI5R1R6RjBRZjNHQkdrNnNZbmU2U1RiVjVrWHEyTFhtSlBIOGRRUVVMUkg4RVhXY3ZibWZ0b29KM1FYLXJObkJiU1NzZXhMdXJxSHI1NHpkZm5aRmxCV1ltTWNaTHJVOXFtM21vaGJpVmxseUM3dm4tcmJYNXREQ3RHbElOZHF6eQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:07:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi condoles Cyclone Chido devastation in Mayotte, offers relief assistance - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi Condoles Cyclone Chido Devastation in Mayotte, Offers Relief Assistance</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 17, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/TOPSHOT-FRANCE-OVERSEAS-MAYOTTE-WEATHER-CLIMATE-0_1734434120383_1734434130772.jpg" alt="Destroyed housing in Mayotte after Cyclone Chido" title="Destroyed housing in Mayotte after Cyclone Chido"><figcaption>This handout photograph taken and released by the French Securite Civile shows destroyed housing in Combani, on the French Indian Ocean territory of Mayotte, after the cyclone Chido hit the archipelago.(AFP)</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi expressed deep sadness over the devastation caused by Cyclone Chido, which struck Mayotte, leading to fatalities and injuries. He assured that India is ready to provide assistance.</p><ul><li>Cyclone Chido struck Mayotte with wind speeds reaching 200 km/h.</li><li>Casualties include 22 deaths and over 1,400 injuries reported.</li><li>French interior minister indicated 70% of the population is affected.</li><li>Additional security and paramilitary personnel are being deployed for relief efforts.</li><li>Curfew imposed from 10 PM to 4 AM to prevent looting and disease spread.</li><li>Comparably, at least 34 fatalities were reported in neighboring Mozambique.</li><li>Experts warn of increased cyclone intensity due to climate change.</li></ul><blockquote>“Deeply saddened by the devastation caused by Cyclone Chido in Mayotte. My thoughts and prayers are with the victims and their families.” - PM Narendra Modi</blockquote><p>This tragic event highlights the escalating frequency of powerful cyclones in the region and the urgent need for global climate action.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-deeply-saddened-by-cyclone-chido-devastation-offers-relief-assistance-latest-updates-101734432266059.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/pm-modi-deeply-saddened-by-cyclone-chido-devastation-offers-relief-assistance-latest-updates-101734432266059.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:43:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[They went to Georgia in search of a better future: families of those who died in Gudauri - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Families Mourn Loved Ones Lost in Georgia Restaurant Tragedy</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 14, 2024 - The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/punjab-2-1.jpg?w=640" alt="(Left) Victims Ravinder Singh and his wife Gurwinder Kaur; Amrinder Kaur and Maninder Kaur were found dead inside a restaurant of Georgia." width="640" height="360"><figcaption>(Left) Victims Ravinder Singh and his wife Gurwinder Kaur; Amrinder Kaur and Maninder Kaur were found dead inside a restaurant of Georgia. (Express Photos by Harmeet Sodhi)</figcaption><p><strong>Introduction:</strong> Twelve people, including several from Punjab, died in a suspected carbon monoxide poisoning incident at a restaurant in Gudauri, Georgia. Families of the victims share their stories of loss and hope.</p><ul><li>Amrinder Kaur, 32, from Mehma village in Punjab’s Patiala district, went to Georgia in 2015.</li><li>Maninder Kaur, Amrinder’s sister-in-law, also died at the restaurant.</li><li>Ravinder Singh, 32, and his wife Gurwinder Kaur, from Sunam district, were to celebrate their first marriage anniversary on December 18.</li><li>Sameer Kumar, 26, a resident of Khanna town in Punjab’s Ludhiana district, was among the victims.</li></ul><blockquote>“She had studied up to Class 12 and moved to Georgia in 2015 to make a better future.” – Sukhwinder Singh, Amrinder’s cousin</blockquote><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The families of the victims are working with the Indian Embassy to bring the bodies back to India for the final rites. The tragedy highlights the risks faced by those seeking better opportunities abroad.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/indians-georgia-better-future-families-died-gudauri-9729989/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/indians-georgia-better-future-families-died-gudauri-9729989/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 11:13:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jagmeet Singh Joins Calls For Trudeau’s Resignation Amid Deputy’s Exit, Cites Trump Tariff Threat - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jagmeet Singh Calls for Trudeau's Resignation Amidst Political Turmoil</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 17, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Canada’s New Democratic Party leader Jagmeet Singh and Prime Minister Justin Trudeau"><figcaption>Canada’s New Democratic Party leader Jagmeet Singh and Prime Minister Justin Trudeau</figcaption><p>Jagmeet Singh, the leader of Canada’s New Democratic Party, has urged Prime Minister Justin Trudeau to resign in light of rising living costs and the imminent threat of tariffs from US President-elect Donald Trump.</p><ul><li>Singh's call for resignation came after Deputy Prime Minister Chrystia Freeland's unexpected exit due to disagreements over tariff policies.</li><li>Freeland's resignation marks a significant internal dissent within Trudeau's cabinet, with nearly 60 Liberal MPs rebelling against him.</li><li>Trudeau trails Conservative leader Pierre Poilievre in the polls by 20 points, with growing calls for a snap election.</li><li>Freeland warned that Trump's 25% tariff threat could lead to severe economic consequences for Canada.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Today, I am calling on Justin Trudeau to resign. Liberals are fighting themselves when Canadians need a Prime Minister who will fight for them.” — Jagmeet Singh, December 16, 2024</p></blockquote><p>The political crisis deepens as Singh highlights the urgency for leadership that prioritizes the needs of Canadians amidst growing economic concerns.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/canada-political-crisis-new-democratic-party-jagmeet-singh-prime-minister-justin-trudeau-resignation-deputy-chrystia-freeland-9158998.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/canada-political-crisis-new-democratic-party-jagmeet-singh-prime-minister-justin-trudeau-resignation-deputy-chrystia-freeland-9158998.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:52:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After 12 found dead in Georgia restaurant, Punjab Congress MP says all were from state - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After 12 found dead in Georgia restaurant, Punjab Congress MP says all were from state</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/Gurjeet-Singh-Aujla.jpeg?w=640" alt="Gurjeet Singh Aujla, georgia restaurant death" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Gurjeet Singh Aujla, Congress MP from Amritsar, said the 12 people who died in Georgia were all from Punjab. (X/ @GurjeetSAujla)</figcaption><p>In a tragic incident, 12 individuals, suspected victims of carbon monoxide poisoning, were found dead at a restaurant in Gudauri, Georgia. Eleven of the deceased were identified as Indian nationals.</p><ul><li>The bodies were discovered in a building housing an Indian food restaurant located in a ski resort.</li><li>Congress MP Gurjeet Singh Aujla confirmed that all deceased were from Punjab.</li><li>The Indian Embassy in Tbilisi is facilitating the return of the bodies to India.</li><li>The embassy extends condolences to the families and is providing support.</li></ul><blockquote>“12 Punjabis have tragically died from suspected carbon monoxide poisoning at ski resort in Gudauri, Georgia. I urge CM @BhagwantMann &amp; @KuldeepSinghAAP NRI Minister to take immediate steps to bring back bodies &amp; support grieving families.” - Gurjeet Singh Aujla</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the potential dangers associated with carbon monoxide poisoning and the importance of ensuring safety in hospitality establishments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/georgia-restaurant-death-punjab-congress-mp-state-9729065/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/cities/chandigarh/georgia-restaurant-death-punjab-congress-mp-state-9729065/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:23:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China to build world’s largest artificial-island airport to handle 43 million passengers - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China to Build World's Largest Artificial-Island Airport in Dalian</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> South China Morning Post</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/flight_1734419555826_1734419565034.jpg" alt="The airport will cover an impressive 20 square kilometers. Representative (Pexel )"><figcaption>The airport will cover an impressive 20 square kilometers. Representative (Pexel )</figcaption></figure><p>China is constructing the world’s largest artificial-island airport, the Dalian Jinzhouwan International Airport, to enhance the city’s role as a regional transportation hub. Covering 20 square kilometers, it will outperform existing airports like Hong Kong International and Kansai International.</p><ul><li>The airport will feature four runways and a 900,000 square meter terminal.</li><li>It is expected to handle 43 million passengers annually at first, with plans to expand to 80 million.</li><li>Projected cost for the entire project is $4.3 billion, aimed for completion by 2035.</li><li>The airport will manage one million tonnes of cargo annually when operational.</li><li>The existing Dalian Zhoushuizi Airport has reached its maximum capacity and poses navigation challenges.</li></ul><blockquote>“For Dalian people to say it’s the largest, that’s exactly what it is,” - Li Hanming, aviation consultancy founder.</blockquote><p>The Jinzhouwan Airport is set to revolutionize regional connectivity and solidify Dalian's importance as a trade hub.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/china-to-build-world-s-largest-artificial-island-airport-in-dalian-enhancing-regional-connectivity-101734419187878.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/china-to-build-world-s-largest-artificial-island-airport-in-dalian-enhancing-regional-connectivity-101734419187878.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 10:14:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[80-Year-Old NRI Killed: 12-Year-Old Girl Charged - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.m9.news/social-media-viral/80-year-old-nri-bhim-kohli-killed-12-year-old-girl-charged/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.m9.news/social-media-viral/80-year-old-nri-bhim-kohli-killed-12-year-old-girl-charged/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 09:11:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CNN frees Syrian prisoner. He turns out to be Assad regime's torturer: Report - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CNN Frees Alleged Torturer Linked to Assad's Regime</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/the-man-identified-himself-as-adel-ghurbal--claiming-he-had-been-held-by-assads-regime-for-three-mo-175841873-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=6UeK30vLDmMSXXe_modZM_XlwWkp4joW&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="The man identified himself as Adel Ghurbal, claiming he had been held by Assad’s regime for three months." title="The man identified himself as Adel Ghurbal, claiming he had been held by Assad’s regime for three months. (Photo: CNN Video screengrab)" height="388"><figcaption>The man identified himself as Adel Ghurbal, claiming he had been held by Assad’s regime for three months. (Photo: CNN Video screengrab)</figcaption><p>CNN is facing scrutiny after a fact-check revealed that a man it recently portrayed as a victim of the Syrian regime was actually a former operative accused of war crimes.</p><ul><li>The man, who identified himself as Adel Ghurbal, claimed to have been imprisoned for three months.</li><li>Investigations revealed he may actually be Salama Mohammad Salama, a former first lieutenant in Assad's intelligence.</li><li>Allegations against him include torture and extortion during the Syrian civil war.</li><li>CNN acknowledged the claims and is investigating the man's true identity.</li><li>The network defended its original report, asserting the events were authentic.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are continuing our reporting into this and the wider story.” - CNN statement</blockquote><p>This incident raises questions about the reliability of wartime reporting and the challenges faced by journalists working in conflict zones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/cnn-allegedly-frees-syrian-inmate-who-was-member-of-assads-torture-forces-report-2651002-2024-12-17</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/cnn-allegedly-frees-syrian-inmate-who-was-member-of-assads-torture-forces-report-2651002-2024-12-17</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:58:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assad in underwear: Semi-naked photos of Syria's ousted president go viral - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Assad in Underwear: Viral Photos of Syria's Ousted President</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>Recently, semi-naked photos of Syria's ousted president Bashar al-Assad have caused a stir on social media, going viral and leading to various reactions.</p><ul><li>The leaked images portray a surprising and vulnerable side of the former president.</li><li>Public sentiment is mixed, with some seeing it as a form of ridicule while others view it as a personal invasion.</li><li>This incident raises questions about privacy and the personal lives of political figures.</li></ul><blockquote>"Privacy is a right that should be respected, even for public figures."</blockquote><p>The emergence of these photos highlights the complexities of public image and personal dignity in the age of social media.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/assad-in-underwear-semi-naked-photos-of-syrias-ousted-president-go-viral/articleshow/116392584.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/assad-in-underwear-semi-naked-photos-of-syrias-ousted-president-go-viral/articleshow/116392584.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All about Russia's plan to allow Indians to travel without visa, other visa-free countries - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQV2VxbXN6dFZlMTZ3Q2pLcXNNT3VieG1hUGZ5dGVLd1ZEVnI2SzlabE1QaHpCWjkxakJ4Rkc4XzJFR3VMcTlvZGVWcFQzNzU1M2JYckwwZnJzRl94dlJoUUtYb0d4REdQNWlIVlhoRlppSVFDdzlDcUpBMFd3dENnckVoTlBod3I2Rm1hS3ZSSDNVMkhlR1dzal9LSXpHQXFSNFRCT0ZmSS0tY0J2QXVDdjRSVUpaV1hZYXk0ODdRX3LSAcYBQVVfeXFMTnVwS2Rybk9FWS12cURwY0NnRkxpREVPZG9nV1Vwb0VhNFgxR2FvclRlb3ZWTzAweHhvZXc4T2RQWXhGM3RPYnpIclBvcDdGdm41eWVqLW1HUnFtU0tYcGMxdmxUNFN2RVdiM0tQZlNlS1JLSzE0bjVXQ29oSWhLNG50LWF6OG1iZ2NzazNjVUN0ZzZuUjY2X1RaRExyQzE3OVdfMWt3RUFfQVhTS2FqOU1RMGhTZm1zMEViQi1DYUdLeDZud2ZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwAFBVV95cUxQV2VxbXN6dFZlMTZ3Q2pLcXNNT3VieG1hUGZ5dGVLd1ZEVnI2SzlabE1QaHpCWjkxakJ4Rkc4XzJFR3VMcTlvZGVWcFQzNzU1M2JYckwwZnJzRl94dlJoUUtYb0d4REdQNWlIVlhoRlppSVFDdzlDcUpBMFd3dENnckVoTlBod3I2Rm1hS3ZSSDNVMkhlR1dzal9LSXpHQXFSNFRCT0ZmSS0tY0J2QXVDdjRSVUpaV1hZYXk0ODdRX3LSAcYBQVVfeXFMTnVwS2Rybk9FWS12cURwY0NnRkxpREVPZG9nV1Vwb0VhNFgxR2FvclRlb3ZWTzAweHhvZXc4T2RQWXhGM3RPYnpIclBvcDdGdm41eWVqLW1HUnFtU0tYcGMxdmxUNFN2RVdiM0tQZlNlS1JLSzE0bjVXQ29oSWhLNG50LWF6OG1iZ2NzazNjVUN0ZzZuUjY2X1RaRExyQzE3OVdfMWt3RUFfQVhTS2FqOU1RMGhTZm1zMEViQi1DYUdLeDZud2ZB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:36:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Indians die in Georgia: What is carbon monoxide poisoning and how it occurs - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Twelve Indian workers found dead in Georgia restaurant</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 17, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/17/550x309/The-mishap-occurred-around-12-45-pm-when-a-speedin_1732739435267_1734423808781.jpg" alt="All twelve Indians were found dead in their bedrooms on the second floor of the Indian restaurant. (Representational)"><figcaption>All twelve Indians were found dead in their bedrooms on the second floor of the Indian restaurant. (Representational)</figcaption><p>Twelve Indian workers tragically died due to suspected carbon monoxide poisoning in a restaurant in Gudauri, Georgia. The Indian embassy is facilitating the repatriation of the deceased.</p><ul><li>The workers were found dead in their bedrooms.</li><li>The cause of death is believed to be carbon monoxide released from a power generator used during a power cut.</li><li>Carbon monoxide is a colorless, odorless gas that is dangerous and hard to detect.</li></ul><blockquote>The Embassy of India in Tbilisi is saddened to learn of the unfortunate passing of eleven Indian nationals and extends its deepest condolences to their families.</blockquote><p>This tragic event highlights the dangers of carbon monoxide poisoning and the need for safety measures in enclosed spaces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/georgia-indians-12-indians-die-in-georgia-from-carbon-monoxide-poisoning-what-is-it-and-how-it-occurs-101734423618992.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/georgia-indians-12-indians-die-in-georgia-from-carbon-monoxide-poisoning-what-is-it-and-how-it-occurs-101734423618992.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:29:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau to quit? Finance minister Freeland’s resignation throws Canadian PM’s future in... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/justin-trudeau-to-quit-finance-minister-freeland-s-resignation-throws-canadian-pm-s-future-in-jeopardy-12891679.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/justin-trudeau-to-quit-finance-minister-freeland-s-resignation-throws-canadian-pm-s-future-in-jeopardy-12891679.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:18:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau to quit? Finance minister Freeland’s resignation throws Canadian PM’s future in jeopardy - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/justin-trudeau-to-quit-finance-minister-freeland-s-resignation-throws-canadian-pm-s-future-in-jeopardy-12891679.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/justin-trudeau-to-quit-finance-minister-freeland-s-resignation-throws-canadian-pm-s-future-in-jeopardy-12891679.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:18:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15-year-old girl behind Wisconsin school shooting: How common are female shooters in US? - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxQcEVIS0VSbENtcFZsRFpjMFlwcUdidDk4S1FlMEZnSkg4S2RlZlRrVURCY2tQNWFrUTkyT0xTYkRjc0JSMG9yS3VBUUJaak1VODd1dzhpQkMxUHZMWml4YUlLNFR3dnFfSTQ2cThCSkFjc3FvMnJPcDBlTEJtS1JaalRFM3Qzb0NVeWE4VmxWcHYyNUpSNU9LbkY2TXFoUVVXdTZjaU1SSTA5VDBH0gGyAUFVX3lxTE5PVmN6WnZMVnVWanp2WXgwblR0d2c4YXBrNVd1X0swVV9MS1NvRU9PelZIcTNZUXRPdUw1LXYyOV9KWDlNTWV2Q2VFWGtiRmYxcEFjZlhXRFR0Sm4wMlhSc2pjVzdFTWJDdXZYcS1iT3d0SFI4RVB3N1FyeHBRN2J1QUtNRXE4VFA1WWhIRzBoeVFIaDl2RWQyNnFzLTQ0OUNEcHRBU2xsSnZqV0ZEOFhaZnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxQcEVIS0VSbENtcFZsRFpjMFlwcUdidDk4S1FlMEZnSkg4S2RlZlRrVURCY2tQNWFrUTkyT0xTYkRjc0JSMG9yS3VBUUJaak1VODd1dzhpQkMxUHZMWml4YUlLNFR3dnFfSTQ2cThCSkFjc3FvMnJPcDBlTEJtS1JaalRFM3Qzb0NVeWE4VmxWcHYyNUpSNU9LbkY2TXFoUVVXdTZjaU1SSTA5VDBH0gGyAUFVX3lxTE5PVmN6WnZMVnVWanp2WXgwblR0d2c4YXBrNVd1X0swVV9MS1NvRU9PelZIcTNZUXRPdUw1LXYyOV9KWDlNTWV2Q2VFWGtiRmYxcEFjZlhXRFR0Sm4wMlhSc2pjVzdFTWJDdXZYcS1iT3d0SFI4RVB3N1FyeHBRN2J1QUtNRXE4VFA1WWhIRzBoeVFIaDl2RWQyNnFzLTQ0OUNEcHRBU2xsSnZqV0ZEOFhaZnc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 08:08:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vanuatu Earthquake Causes US Embassy to Suffer 'Considerable Damage' - Newsweek]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vanuatu Earthquake Causes US Embassy to Suffer 'Considerable Damage'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recently published<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p><img src="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2545793/us-embassy-damaged-vanuatu-earthquake.jpg?w=1200&amp;f=821e49cffd8534f3de5b708547989485" alt="US Embassy Damaged Vanuatu Earthquake" width="1200" height="903"><figcaption>The embassy after the 7.3 magnitude earthquake struck Vanuatu's capital, Port Vila. The extent of the damage is currently unclear.</figcaption><p>The U.S. embassy in Vanuatu has suffered “considerable damage” following a 7.3 magnitude earthquake that caused damage across multiple buildings in Port Vila, including embassies of several Western nations.</p><ul><li>The earthquake struck at 12:47 p.m. local time at a depth of about 35 miles.</li><li>There was an aftershock of 5.5 magnitude.</li><li>The extent of damage to the embassy is currently under assessment.</li><li>At least one death has been reported following the earthquake.</li><li>The U.S. embassy is closed until further notice.</li></ul><blockquote>“For the Pacific, it's the worst ... I have seen in terms of earthquake damage.” - Katie Greenwood</blockquote><p>The event has raised concerns about the safety of the affected areas and the response to the disaster.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/vanuatu-earthquake-us-embassy-collapse-video-2001867</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newsweek.com/vanuatu-earthquake-us-embassy-collapse-video-2001867</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 07:25:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK court to sentence father, stepmother for killing daughter Sara Sharif - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE9udE16SFVTS1ZuNHpGa1l3cFFOTnBuUFlXR01wOFRPTzl5b2xUcC00RkY2WEY4aTdBYzhRSUJuajF3U0sxTjZ3cg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE9udE16SFVTS1ZuNHpGa1l3cFFOTnBuUFlXR01wOFRPTzl5b2xUcC00RkY2WEY4aTdBYzhRSUJuajF3U0sxTjZ3cg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 06:48:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>