<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:17:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 05:17:45 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea Plane Crash Live Updates: Pilot in Jeju Air plane crash mentioned bird strike, says Transport ministry official - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Plane Crash Live Updates</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>December 29, 2024 <strong>Source: </strong>The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/South-Korea-plane-crash-AP-2.jpg?w=640" alt="South Korea Plane Crash Live" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>South Korea Plane Crash Live: Rescue team carry the body of a passenger at the site of a plane fire at Muan International Airport in Muan, South Korea, Sunday, Dec. 29, 2024. (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>The pilot of the Jeju Air Flight 7C 2216 reported a bird strike and declared a mayday call shortly before crashing into a wall at Muan International Airport, resulting in the death of 179 individuals.</p><ul><li>The aircraft veered off the runway and exploded during landing.</li><li>South Korea’s acting President declared a national mourning period until January 4.</li><li>The flight carried 175 passengers, including two Thai nationals.</li></ul><blockquote>“The government would like to offer its sincere condolences to the bereaved families...” - Choi Sang-mok, acting President.</blockquote><p>This devastating crash has prompted rescue operations and an investigation into its causes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 04:09:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jimmy Carter's India connection: Haryana village was named 'Carterpuri' in his honour - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jimmy Carter's India connection: Haryana village named 'Carterpuri' in his honour</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p><p>In a unique tribute, a village in Haryana, India has been named 'Carterpuri' in honor of former US President Jimmy Carter, celebrating his humanitarian efforts and connection to the region.</p><ul><li>The village's name change recognizes Carter's contributions and goodwill.</li><li>This gesture signifies the longstanding friendship between the US and India.</li><li>Local officials and residents expressed their appreciation for Carter's values of peace and service.</li></ul><blockquote>“Carter has always been a beacon of hope and compassion,” said a local leader.</blockquote><p>This gesture not only honors Jimmy Carter but also aims to strengthen the cultural ties between India and the United States.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/jimmy-carters-india-connection-haryana-village-was-named-carterpuri-in-his-honor/articleshow/116781942.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/jimmy-carters-india-connection-haryana-village-was-named-carterpuri-in-his-honor/articleshow/116781942.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 02:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jimmy Carter, 39th U.S. President, dies at 100 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jimmy Carter, 39th U.S. President, dies at 100</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Carter Center</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/j316qs/article68706554.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/Jimmy_Carter_100th_Birthday_06901.jpg" alt="Jimmy Carter" style="width: 100%;"><figcaption>Jimmy Carter, celebrating his 100th birthday.</figcaption><p>Jimmy Carter, the former U.S. President known for his humanitarian work and modest lifestyle, has passed away at the age of 100 after a period in hospice care.</p><ul><li>Carter served as the 39th President of the United States from 1977 to 1981.</li><li>He died in Plains, Georgia, where he and his wife lived most of their lives.</li><li>President Biden praised Carter as an exemplary leader and humanitarian.</li><li>Carter’s legacy includes efforts in disease eradication, civil rights advocacy, and international peace-making.</li><li>He was the longest-lived American President, entering hospice care 22 months before his death.</li></ul><blockquote>“I’m perfectly at ease with whatever comes... I’ve had a wonderful life.”</blockquote><p>Carter's life and work set a standard for humanitarian efforts in and out of politics, and he is remembered both for his presidency and his extensive post-presidential advocacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/jimmy-carter-39th-us-president-dies-at-100/article69041899.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/jimmy-carter-39th-us-president-dies-at-100/article69041899.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea Plane Crash Live Updates: Biden offers US assistance to South Korea after plane crash - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Plane Crash Live Updates</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 24, 2024, Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/expressintro-9.jpg?w=640" alt="South Korea plane crash" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>South Korea Plane Crash Live: The accident happened around 9 am (local time) when the Jeju Air flight was landing at Muan International Airport in South Jeolla Province, about 288 km away from capital Seoul. (X/Yonhanp news agency)</figcaption><p>In an emergency meeting on Sunday, South Korea’s acting President Choi Sang-mok declared a national mourning period until January 4 following the deadly plane crash at Muan International Airport that killed 179. All on board except two crew members are feared dead as a plane carrying 181 passengers and six crew on a flight from Bangkok crashed and burst into flames early Sunday.</p><p>The crash site has been declared a special disaster zone.</p><ul><li>A Jeju Air flight veered off the runway while landing and exploded into flames.</li><li>The airline is gathering information regarding the casualties and causes of the accident.</li><li>Two Thai nationals were among the 175 passengers, with the rest believed to be South Koreans.</li></ul><blockquote>“The government would like to offer its sincere condolences to the bereaved families and will do its best to recover from this accident and prevent a recurrence.” - Choi Sang-mok</blockquote><p>Furthermore, South Korean authorities are continuing rescue efforts as they assess the situation and provide support for the affected families.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 01:08:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Pilot declared mayday’: What caused the Jeju Air plane crash in South Korea? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Pilot declared mayday’: What caused the Jeju Air plane crash in South Korea?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 30, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/30/550x309/SKOERA-AVIATION-ACCIDENT-6_1735520106505_1735520126457.jpg" alt="Firefighters and recovery teams work at the scene where a Jeju Air Boeing 737-800 series aircraft crashed and burst into flames at Muan International Airport on December 30. (AFP)" title="Firefighters and recovery teams work at the scene where a Jeju Air Boeing 737-800 series aircraft crashed and burst into flames at Muan International Airport on December 30. (AFP)"><figcaption>Firefighters and recovery teams work at the scene where a Jeju Air Boeing 737-800 series aircraft crashed and burst into flames at Muan International Airport on December 30. (AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>A Jeju Air flight from Bangkok to South Korea crashed during landing, resulting in 179 deaths and only two survivors being rescued.</p><ul><li>The plane was warned of a bird strike during its first landing attempt.</li><li>The pilot declared a “mayday” and attempted a belly landing.</li><li>All 175 passengers and four crew members died; only two flight attendants survived.</li><li>Investigations are examining a potential bird strike and adverse weather as causes.</li><li>Both flight data and cockpit voice recorders have been recovered.</li></ul><blockquote>“It really has to be a series of catastrophic events that led to such a high loss of life,” - Philip Butterworth-Hayes, aviation consultant.</blockquote><p>This tragic incident has brought to light the aviation safety measures and the potential hazards involved in flight operations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/pilot-declared-mayday-what-led-to-the-jeju-air-plane-crash-in-south-korea-101735518908010.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/pilot-declared-mayday-what-led-to-the-jeju-air-plane-crash-in-south-korea-101735518908010.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:59:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Should I Say My Last Words’: Jeju Air Flyer's Final Message To Family Moments Before Plane Crash - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/south-korea-jeju-air-plane-crash-flyers-last-message-to-family-eyewitness-video-latest-updates-9171756.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/south-korea-jeju-air-plane-crash-flyers-last-message-to-family-eyewitness-video-latest-updates-9171756.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 21:42:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former US president Jimmy Carter passes away at 100 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Former US President Jimmy Carter Passes Away at 100</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The New York Times</p>
<p>Jimmy Carter, the 39th President of the United States, has passed away at the age of 100. Known for his humanitarian efforts post-presidency, he leaves behind a legacy of social justice and peacebuilding.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Carter served from 1977 to 1981 and is remembered for significant achievements like the Camp David Accords.</li>
  <li>He dedicated much of his later life to charity work through the Carter Center.</li>
  <li>His commitment to democracy and human rights earned him the Nobel Peace Prize in 2002.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Jimmy Carter showed us that a life dedicated to the service of others can change the world.”</blockquote>
<p>Carter’s influence extends beyond his time in office, making him a revered figure in both national and global contexts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/former-us-president-jimmy-carter-passes-at-100-39th-president/articleshow/116777236.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/former-us-president-jimmy-carter-passes-at-100-39th-president/articleshow/116777236.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 21:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Missing Kerala student found dead in Scotland - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Missing Kerala student found dead in Scotland</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p><p>Authorities have confirmed the tragic discovery of the body of a missing student from Kerala in Scotland, raising concerns among the local community and the student's family.</p><ul><li>The student was reported missing earlier this month, prompting a search operation.</li><li>The body was found near a popular recreational area.</li><li>Officials are investigating the circumstances surrounding the student's death.</li><li>The incident has highlighted issues related to student safety abroad.</li></ul><blockquote>"This tragedy has shocked us all, and we are working closely with the family to provide support during this difficult time." - Local official</blockquote><p>The discovery of the student's body serves as a somber reminder of the potential risks faced by international students and the need for vigilance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/missing-kerala-student-found-dead-in-scotland/articleshow/116775954.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/missing-kerala-student-found-dead-in-scotland/articleshow/116775954.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 19:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Shadow swimming just beyond’: First ever live footage of roughskin dog fish shark captured | Watch | Mint - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>First Ever Live Footage of Roughskin Dog Fish Shark Captured</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent, <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>The roughskin dog fish shark has been spotted alive for the first time in the depths of the Cayman Islands, providing crucial insights into this elusive species.</p>
<img src='image_url_if_available' alt='Roughskin Dog Fish Shark' />
<figcaption>First live footage of the roughskin dog fish shark.</figcaption>
<p>Key Points:</p>
<ul>
  <li>The shark was filmed at a depth of 1,045 meters using a baited remote underwater video system (BRUVS).</li>
  <li>This discovery marks the first live observation of the shark species, previously only known from dead specimens.</li>
  <li>Researchers hope these findings will promote conservation efforts in the Cayman Islands.</li>
  <li>Video-based research methods minimize ecological disturbance compared to traditional fishing methods.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Shadow swimming just beyond the (camera’s) detection window,” described by scientists during the first sighting.</blockquote>
<p>This groundbreaking discovery not only adds to our understanding of marine biodiversity but also emphasizes the need for conservation strategies in protecting such elusive species.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/science/news/shadow-swimming-just-beyond-first-ever-live-footage-of-roughskin-dog-fish-shark-captured-watch-11735492678424.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/science/news/shadow-swimming-just-beyond-first-ever-live-footage-of-roughskin-dog-fish-shark-captured-watch-11735492678424.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 17:48:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-Footballer Mikheil Kavelashvili Becomes Georgia's New President Amid Political Crisis - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ex-Footballer Mikheil Kavelashvili Becomes Georgia's New President Amid Political Crisis</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Mikheil Kavelashvili, a far-right leader known for his anti-LGBTQ views, has been sworn in as the President of Georgia. (AFP)">
<figcaption>Mikheil Kavelashvili, a far-right leader known for his anti-LGBTQ views, has been sworn in as the President of Georgia. (AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Georgia inaugurated a ruling party loyalist as president amidst a political showdown, with protests against the ruling party's legitimacy.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kavelashvili's inauguration is expected to escalate pro-EU protests in Georgia.</li>
  <li>Protesters claim the ruling Georgian Dream party rigged the October elections.</li>
  <li>The outgoing president, Salome Zurabishvili, has been declared “illegitimate” by protesters.</li>
  <li>Kavelashvili, known for his far-right views, emphasized Georgian traditions after his swearing-in.</li>
  <li>Mass protests are ongoing against the government's decision to delay EU membership talks.</li>
  <li>Reports of police brutality during protests have led to international condemnation and sanctions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I remain the only legitimate president,” said Zurabishvili during a protest.</blockquote>
<p>The political situation in Georgia continues to be volatile as protests demand a reevaluation of recent elections amid accusations against the ruling party.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/ex-footballer-mikhail-kavelashvili-becomes-georgias-new-president-amid-intense-protests-9171801.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/ex-footballer-mikhail-kavelashvili-becomes-georgias-new-president-amid-intense-protests-9171801.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 17:48:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experts question ‘bird strike’ as reason behind South Korea plane crash that killed 179 | Top updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Experts question ‘bird strike’ as reason behind South Korea plane crash that killed 179</h1>
<p><strong>Date: December 29, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/TOPSHOT-SKOREA-AVIATION-ACCIDENT-5_1735492056838_1735492077341.jpg" alt="Firefighters and rescue personnel work near the wreckage of a Jeju Air Boeing 737-800 series aircraft after the plane crashed and burst into flames at Muan International Airport in South Jeolla Province, some 288 kilometres southwest of Seoul on December 29, 2024.(AFP)">
<figcaption>Firefighters and rescue personnel work near the wreckage of a Jeju Air Boeing 737-800 series aircraft after the plane crashed and burst into flames at Muan International Airport in South Jeolla Province, some 288 kilometres southwest of Seoul on December 29, 2024.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>The tragic Jeju Air flight 7C2216 crash has raised significant questions regarding the actual cause, with experts disputing the likelihood of a bird strike leading to the aircraft's malfunction.</p>
<ul>
<li>The plane was landing at Muan International Airport when it crashed, resulting in the death of 179 people.</li>
<li>Experts argue that a bird strike could not have solely caused the malfunctioning of the landing gear.</li>
<li>Survivors of the crash are stable and conscious but the majority of passengers have not been identified.</li>
<li>The South Korean government declared a period of national mourning following the incident.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“At this point there are a lot more questions than we have answers.” - Gregory Alegi, aviation expert</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing investigation into the crash continues as authorities examine the factors that contributed to this tragic event.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/experts-question-bird-strike-as-reason-behind-south-korea-plane-crash-that-killed-179-top-updates-101735489167236.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/experts-question-bird-strike-as-reason-behind-south-korea-plane-crash-that-killed-179-top-updates-101735489167236.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 17:20:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Afghanistan-Pakistan Border War: What Is The “Hypothetical” Durand Line That Taliban Claims Crossing & Seizing Pak Army Posts - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Afghanistan-Pakistan Border War: What Is The “Hypothetical” Durand Line That Taliban Claims Crossing & Seizing Pak Army Posts</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Eurasian Times</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Su-57-1290-x-650-px-5.png" alt="" width="1290" height="650">
<figcaption>Pakistan airstrikes inside Afghanistan. Image Credits Platform X.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Recent military confrontations along the Durand Line have resulted in significant casualties for both Afghan and Pakistani forces. Following airstrikes by Pakistan in Afghanistan, Afghan forces launched counterstrikes across the border, leading to escalating tensions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>19 Pakistani soldiers were reported killed as Afghan forces crossed the contested Durand Line.</li>
  <li>The Afghan attacks were in retaliation for previous Pakistani airstrikes that killed 46 Afghan civilians, predominantly women and children.</li>
  <li>Afghan Defense Minister claims that the operations targeted areas used to launch attacks on Afghanistan.</li>
  <li>Both nations have acknowledged ongoing clashes and casualties on their sides, indicating a significant rise in border tensions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We do not consider it to be the territory of Pakistan… but it was on the other side of the hypothetical line.” - Enayatullah Khowarazmi, Afghan Ministry of Defense</blockquote>
<p>The escalating situation illustrates the persistent instability and the historical complexities surrounding the Durand Line, which has never been officially recognized by Afghanistan. The conflict reflects broader geopolitical dynamics in South Asia.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/afghan-surgical-strikes-in-pak-taliban-crosses/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/afghan-surgical-strikes-in-pak-taliban-crosses/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 16:25:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Panamanian President gives major reality check to Trump over China operates Panama Canal claim: ‘Whole world is free…' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Panamanian President José Raúl Mulino gives major reality check to Trump over China operates Panama Canal claim: ‘Whole world is free…'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/Untitled_1734932675342_1735486349895.jpg" alt="Panama president José Raúl Mulino reacts after Donald Trump threatens to take control of Panama Canal (AP Photo/Pamela Smith, photo by JOSH EDELSON / AFP)" title="Panama president José Raúl Mulino reacts after Donald Trump threatens to take control of Panama Canal (AP Photo/Pamela Smith, photo by JOSH EDELSON / AFP)">
<figcaption>Panama president José Raúl Mulino reacts after Donald Trump threatens to take control of Panama Canal (AP Photo/Pamela Smith, photo by JOSH EDELSON / AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Panamanian President José Raúl Mulino dismissed US President-elect Donald Trump's accusation of Chinese troops operating the Panama Canal as unfounded.</p>
<ul>
<li>President Mulino called Trump's claims "nonsense" and stressed that there is currently no Chinese presence in the canal.</li>
<li>Mulino emphasized the canal's Panamanian ownership and independence, stating it is not up for negotiation.</li>
<li>He highlighted the respectful diplomatic relationship between Panama and China established after severing ties with Taiwan in 2017.</li>
<li>Trump's comments were made during a social media post and at a conference where he expressed grievances over Panama's fees.</li>
<li>Mulino asserted the sovereignty of Panama, countering Trump’s threats to seize control of the canal.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There is not a single Chinese soldier in the canal. For the love of God, you are free, the whole world is free, to visit the canal if you please.” - José Raúl Mulino</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights ongoing tensions in U.S.-Latin America relations, particularly concerning U.S. accusations regarding China's involvement in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/panamanian-president-gives-major-reality-check-to-trump-over-china-operates-panama-canal-claim-whole-world-is-free-101735484247030.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/panamanian-president-gives-major-reality-check-to-trump-over-china-operates-panama-canal-claim-whole-world-is-free-101735484247030.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:37:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China unveils prototype of world's fastest train, capable of reaching 450 km/h - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Unveils Prototype of World's Fastest Train, Capable of Reaching 450 km/h</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Fastest Train Prototype" width="600" />
<figcaption>The prototype of China's fastest train.</figcaption>
<p>China has introduced a new prototype train that can reach speeds of up to 450 km/h, setting a new benchmark for high-speed rail technology.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The prototype showcases advanced aerodynamics and lightweight materials.</li>
  <li>It aims to enhance transportation efficiency across the country.</li>
  <li>The innovation is part of China's broader plan to lead in high-speed rail technology.</li>
  <li>Officials emphasize the train's potential for economic growth and tourism.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This innovation is not just about speed but improving convenience and connectivity for travelers,” said a spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>This development positions China at the forefront of the high-speed rail industry and could influence global transportation trends.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/china-unveils-protoype-of-worlds-fastest-train-capable-of-reaching-450-km/h/articleshow/116772040.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/china-unveils-protoype-of-worlds-fastest-train-capable-of-reaching-450-km/h/articleshow/116772040.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MAGA fury over H-1B scorches even Indian-American Republicans - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MAGA fury over H-1B scorches even Indian-American Republicans</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Article Image"><figcaption>Image related to the article</figcaption><p>The article discusses the rising tensions within MAGA circles regarding H-1B visas, even affecting Indian-American Republicans. It highlights how some far-right voices have intensified their critiques against the H-1B visa program.</p><ul><li>Far-right influencers are vocal against H-1B visa holders.</li><li>Criticism is also directed towards the candidates defending the program.</li><li>The topic has created a rift within the Republican party, particularly among Indian-American members.</li></ul><blockquote>“Why should they come here and take our jobs?” - Comment from a prominent MAGA supporter.</blockquote><p>The H-1B visa debate reflects broader conflicts within the GOP about immigration and job competition, raising questions about future candidacies among Indian-Americans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/maga-fury-over-h-1b-scorches-even-indian-american-republicans/articleshow/116771147.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/maga-fury-over-h-1b-scorches-even-indian-american-republicans/articleshow/116771147.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 14:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea plane crash live: Only 65 victims of plane crash identified - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Plane Crash: 65 Victims Identified Amid National Mourning</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/SKOERA-AVIATION-ACCIDENT-0_1735472836685_1735472851854.jpg" alt="Firefighters and rescue personnel carry the body of a victim near the scene" title="Firefighters and rescue personnel carry the body of a victim near the scene"><figcaption>Firefighters and rescue personnel carry the body of a victim near the scene.</figcaption><p>The Jeju Air flight 7C2216 crashed during landing in Muan, resulting in the deaths of 179 out of 181 passengers. Only two flight attendants survived the horrific accident.</p><ul><li>The plane was returning from Bangkok with 175 passengers and six crew members.</li><li>The South Korean government has declared seven days of national mourning for the victims.</li><li>Widespread condolences have been offered from international leaders, including Pope Francis and the German Chancellor.</li><li>Five of the deceased were children under ten, with the youngest being just three years old.</li><li>The crash is the deadliest air disaster in South Korean history since 1997.</li></ul><blockquote>“I believe no words of consolation would suffice for the bereaved families who have suffered this tragedy,” - South Korea's acting President Choi Sang-mok.</blockquote><p>This tragic event is a somber reminder of the vulnerabilities involved in air travel, prompting a thorough investigation into the causes to prevent future incidents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-jeju-air-muan-boeing-death-toll-101735437972261.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-jeju-air-muan-boeing-death-toll-101735437972261.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 14:23:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump says he has ‘always liked’ H-1B visas: How the programme did under his last term - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/trump-h-1b-visas-how-programme-did-under-his-last-term-9750378/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/trump-h-1b-visas-how-programme-did-under-his-last-term-9750378/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 13:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump backs Elon Musk and H-1B visas amid MAGA meltdown - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump backs Elon Musk and H-1B visas amid MAGA meltdown</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='TOI logo' width='300' height='24'><figcaption>Donald Trump expresses support for H-1B visas.</figcaption><p>The article discusses Donald Trump's recent endorsement of Elon Musk and support for H-1B visas amidst backlash from his base regarding his tech appointments.</p><ul><li>Trump backs Musk's stance on H-1B visas</li><li>Controversy arises among MAGA supporters</li><li>Impact on immigration policy discussed</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a significant step for tech and innovation,” said Trump, highlighting the importance of skilled worker visas.</blockquote><p>The situation underscores the tension within Trump’s supporter base regarding immigration and tech leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-backs-elon-musk-and-h-1b-visas-amid-maga-meltdown/articleshow/116769297.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-backs-elon-musk-and-h-1b-visas-amid-maga-meltdown/articleshow/116769297.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan accuses Russia of trying to hide causes of plane crash; says the plane was shot from Russia - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Azerbaijan accuses Russia of trying to hide causes of plane crash; says the plane was shot from Russia</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/5ueo2b/article69040073.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-29T121219Z_1883412839_RC2L3BAXKGEP_RTRMADP_3_KAZAKHSTAN-CRASH-RUSSIA.JPG" alt="Azerbaijan’s President Ilham Aliyev said the Azerbaijan Airlines jet that crashed this week was shot at from Russia and called for Moscow to admit “guilt” in the disaster. File" /><figcaption>Azerbaijan’s President Ilham Aliyev speaking about the incident.</figcaption><p>Azerbaijan’s President Ilham Aliyev stated that the Azerbaijan Airlines jet that crashed was shot at from Russia, calling for Moscow to acknowledge its responsibility for the tragedy.</p><ul><li>The crash resulted in the death of 38 people out of 67 onboard.</li><li>Aliyev claimed the plane was struck “by accident” from Russian territory.</li><li>Russian President Vladimir Putin has apologized but did not confirm that the jet was hit by Russian fire.</li><li>Aliyev blamed Russian electronic warfare systems for compromising the plane's control.</li><li>He criticized Russia for suggesting theories that attempt to cover up the event.</li></ul><blockquote>“Of course, our plane was hit by accident. Of course, there can be no talk of a deliberate act of terror here.” - President Ilham Aliyev</blockquote><p>In light of the circumstances, Aliyev urged timely admission of guilt from Russia, highlighting the importance of transparent communication regarding the incident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/azerbaijan-accuses-russia-of-trying-to-hide-causes-of-plane-crash-says-the-plane-was-shot-from-russia/article69040088.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/azerbaijan-accuses-russia-of-trying-to-hide-causes-of-plane-crash-says-the-plane-was-shot-from-russia/article69040088.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UAE: 2 killed in plane crash off the coast of Ras Al Khaimah - Gulf News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UAE: 2 killed in plane crash off the coast of Ras Al Khaimah</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>The tragic crash of a light aircraft belonging to Jazirah Aviation Club off the coast of Ras Al Khaimah resulted in the deaths of both the pilot and co-pilot.</p><ul><li>A light aircraft crashed into the sea near Ras Al Khaimah.</li><li>The incident resulted in two fatalities: the pilot and his co-pilot.</li><li>The General Civil Aviation Authority is investigating the cause of the crash.</li><li>The GCAA has offered condolences to the victims' families.</li></ul><blockquote>The GCAA extends its sincere condolences and sympathy to the families and relatives of the two victims.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the ongoing need for safety in aviation and thorough investigations into aviation accidents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://gulfnews.com/uae/emergencies/uae-2-killed-in-plane-crash-off-the-coast-of-ras-al-khaimah-1.500008464</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gulfnews.com/uae/emergencies/uae-2-killed-in-plane-crash-off-the-coast-of-ras-al-khaimah-1.500008464</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:48:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UAE: 26-year-old doctor among 2 killed in Ras Al Khaimah aircraft crash - Khaleej Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxPR1hiSkJPQzBmRjVfYkM4OUZWV3hRLVA0X2NfWmItYjVUYnRWcmtQTl8yOENldFhmLVdvNVROckNvM3JyWV9DUHFFVkdtcGJjS0dpWFFGWi1hRmN2M1pBOUtmOHZMR0o3RDlzLW94WTJHYnNrU3RXa3BDMnBpUzZvZU5n0gGKAUFVX3lxTE92N2JXRDdLRGtaQlJFdDZVZS1KWERzZ0FSbGtLdzJTamd1ektsRXdHVkNlN2xhQ0psYWd4WVhQWVlXZ1p1Wjh5NGxtVFZhT2NVOWlBNl9rWVVFS0k3RlhtQUx3VXJJS2tWczcwdVFFQzczc1VFZE5rX01GM1JuOVRueVk2Z0s5Mkl2QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxPR1hiSkJPQzBmRjVfYkM4OUZWV3hRLVA0X2NfWmItYjVUYnRWcmtQTl8yOENldFhmLVdvNVROckNvM3JyWV9DUHFFVkdtcGJjS0dpWFFGWi1hRmN2M1pBOUtmOHZMR0o3RDlzLW94WTJHYnNrU3RXa3BDMnBpUzZvZU5n0gGKAUFVX3lxTE92N2JXRDdLRGtaQlJFdDZVZS1KWERzZ0FSbGtLdzJTamd1ektsRXdHVkNlN2xhQ0psYWd4WVhQWVlXZ1p1Wjh5NGxtVFZhT2NVOWlBNl9rWVVFS0k3RlhtQUx3VXJJS2tWczcwdVFFQzczc1VFZE5rX01GM1JuOVRueVk2Z0s5Mkl2QQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:39:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan president claims plane that crashed was shot at from Russian soil - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Azerbaijan President Claims Plane Crashed Due to Shots from Russian Soil</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/FILE-PHOTO--A-drone-view-shows-emergency-specialis_1735475564281_1735475577455.jpg" alt="Emergency specialists working at the crash site of the plane crash(HT_PRINT)">
<figcaption>Emergency specialists working at the crash site of the plane crash(HT_PRINT)</figcaption>
<p>Azerbaijan's President Ilham Aliyev announced that the passenger plane which crashed in Kazakhstan, resulting in the death of 38 people, was reportedly hit by shots fired from Russian territory. He accused certain elements in Russia of attempting to obscure the reality of the incident.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Aliyev emphasized the need for Russia to admit responsibility and apologize to Azerbaijan.</li>
  <li>The crash occurred on Wednesday near Aktau, with initial assumptions of a bird strike or fog.</li>
  <li>Putin expressed his regrets over the tragic incident during their discussions.</li>
  <li>The U.S. and UK governments suggested the airliner might have been downed by Russian anti-aircraft systems and called for an independent investigation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Admitting guilt, apologising in a timely manner to Azerbaijan, which is considered a friendly country, and informing the public about this -- all these were measures and steps that should have been taken.” – Ilham Aliyev</blockquote>
<p>This incident has raised serious issues in Azerbaijan-Russia relations, highlighting the complexities surrounding airspace safety and international protocols.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/azerbaijan-president-claims-plane-that-crashed-was-shot-at-from-russian-soil-101735471996660.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/azerbaijan-president-claims-plane-that-crashed-was-shot-at-from-russian-soil-101735471996660.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:37:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea Plane Crash Live Updates: Seven day national mourning declared till Jan 4 - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Plane Crash Live Updates</h1><p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> December 24, 2024, Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/expressintro-9.jpg?w=640" alt="South Korea plane crash" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>South Korea Plane Crash Live: The accident happened around 9 am (local time) when the Jeju Air flight was landing at Muan International Airport in South Jeolla Province, about 288 km away from capital Seoul. (X/Yonhanp news agency)</figcaption><p>In an emergency meeting on Sunday, South Korea’s acting President Choi Sang-mok declared a national mourning period until January 4 following the deadly plane crash at Muan International Airport that killed 179. All on board except two crew members are feared dead as a plane carrying 181 passengers and six crew on a flight from Bangkok crashed and burst into flames early Sunday.</p><p>The crash site has been declared a special disaster zone.</p><ul><li>A Jeju Air flight veered off the runway while landing and exploded into flames.</li><li>The airline is gathering information regarding the casualties and causes of the accident.</li><li>Two Thai nationals were among the 175 passengers, with the rest believed to be South Koreans.</li></ul><blockquote>“The government would like to offer its sincere condolences to the bereaved families and will do its best to recover from this accident and prevent a recurrence.” - Choi Sang-mok</blockquote><p>This tragic incident has raised significant concerns regarding aviation safety measures in South Korea.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:22:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jolani's latest stance on Iran, constitution, Russia - Mehr News Agency - English Version]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxPUDBvMkk5ZDk4aS1tcFJsdFl2STQ4MDR5Ui1TUXJMQzZCMHVhUEZFVUhuNUs1YnU0MkdIWWVNcHBvY3FEMzFiVGNEX2g2eGhHbWxqc3ZZWDhjM21QeUZNVFdmTDhHbktHemJpS01GVG5ncEVHLU5jdW5DaW9xT002MEN3VktuRUZrN3lfelVGY9IBS0FVX3lxTE4yMUtVQlQxekl5UW5CbzVQOEZTVmpQTDQ1cUE5X056VGZ2YjBTRmlycV9uV0Q1UFUzeHJEamZfLVBZeGNCa2VYb0wxdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxPUDBvMkk5ZDk4aS1tcFJsdFl2STQ4MDR5Ui1TUXJMQzZCMHVhUEZFVUhuNUs1YnU0MkdIWWVNcHBvY3FEMzFiVGNEX2g2eGhHbWxqc3ZZWDhjM21QeUZNVFdmTDhHbktHemJpS01GVG5ncEVHLU5jdW5DaW9xT002MEN3VktuRUZrN3lfelVGY9IBS0FVX3lxTE4yMUtVQlQxekl5UW5CbzVQOEZTVmpQTDQ1cUE5X056VGZ2YjBTRmlycV9uV0Q1UFUzeHJEamZfLVBZeGNCa2VYb0wxdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan president says Russia shot the plane that crashed in Kazakhstan killing 38 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Azerbaijan President Claims Russian Forces Shot Down Plane in Kazakhstan, Resulting in 38 Deaths</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>Azerbaijan's President has alleged that Russian forces shot down a plane that crashed in Kazakhstan, leading to the tragic death of 38 individuals. This assertion raises serious questions about the responsibilities and actions of military powers in the region.</p><ul><li>The incident involved a plane crash in Kazakhstan.</li><li>38 individuals lost their lives as a result of the crash.</li><li>Azerbaijan's President directly attributed the incident to Russian forces.</li><li>This claim could increase tensions between Azerbaijan and Russia.</li></ul><blockquote>“The evidence clearly indicates that the plane was shot down by Russian military forces,” said the Azerbaijan President.</blockquote><p>This incident has drawn significant attention and could have far-reaching implications for diplomatic relations in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/azerbaijan-president-says-russia-shot-the-plane-that-crashed-in-kazakhstan-killing-38/articleshow/116768318.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/azerbaijan-president-says-russia-shot-the-plane-that-crashed-in-kazakhstan-killing-38/articleshow/116768318.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan President Says Plane That Crashed Was Shot At From Russia - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Azerbaijan President Claims Plane Crash Caused by Gunfire from Russia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Azerbaijan State Television</p><p>The Azerbaijan Airlines plane crash in Kazakhstan, which killed 38 people, was allegedly caused by gunfire from Russian territory, according to Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev. He has called for Russia to acknowledge its role in the incident.</p><h3>Key Points:</h3><ul><li>The plane was shot at from the ground in Russia, damaging it and leading to its crash.</li><li>President Aliyev accused Russia of trying to conceal the truth about the crash.</li><li>Putin offered an apology but did not confirm that Russian fire was responsible.</li><li>Azerbaijan has demanded accountability and an investigation into the crash.</li><li>Survivors reported hearing three blast sounds before the crash.</li></ul><blockquote>“Therefore, admitting the guilt, apologizing in a timely manner to Azerbaijan, which is considered a friendly country, and informing the public about this - all these were measures and steps that should have been taken.” - Ilham Aliyev</blockquote><p>This incident has raised significant tensions between Azerbaijan and Russia, with implications for their diplomatic relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/azerbaijan-president-says-plane-that-crashed-was-shot-at-from-russia-7357112</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/azerbaijan-president-says-plane-that-crashed-was-shot-at-from-russia-7357112</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:56:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hamas rejects Israeli media report on Haniyeh assassination - Mehr News Agency - English Version]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxOZEZhaGs3ZXBmbkpZWkdPZDJleU9NWmxicThkZVM1Q3l6Skp5SnYzSE5tUkx3SFEwTUdsTnp5em1JUzZLYmhTbXRuNThsS0lyUWJKQXZhWncteUl2ak1uRTJLV0lUQ2t0dkszbE1pWGtDSzN5ckJtOGhwZU02MlR1NExORjJQZU5MWU8wT1FvVjVtX1hjSDJlTXpnTdIBS0FVX3lxTE51Vm9vTTBDVzlTX1llMjJzaDdxdXZOcnpoNjZIMWFHaHIwSkhiUWZJcV9wTHN6RkJZTC1VendJVEdjRGYtNEJ4UzBiYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxOZEZhaGs3ZXBmbkpZWkdPZDJleU9NWmxicThkZVM1Q3l6Skp5SnYzSE5tUkx3SFEwTUdsTnp5em1JUzZLYmhTbXRuNThsS0lyUWJKQXZhWncteUl2ak1uRTJLV0lUQ2t0dkszbE1pWGtDSzN5ckJtOGhwZU02MlR1NExORjJQZU5MWU8wT1FvVjVtX1hjSDJlTXpnTdIBS0FVX3lxTE51Vm9vTTBDVzlTX1llMjJzaDdxdXZOcnpoNjZIMWFHaHIwSkhiUWZJcV9wTHN6RkJZTC1VendJVEdjRGYtNEJ4UzBiYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 11:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Peru Hit By Massive 13-Foot-High Waves, Leaving Scores Of Ports Closed - Free Press Journal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/world/peru-hit-by-massive-13-foot-high-waves-leaving-scores-of-ports-closed</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.freepressjournal.in/world/peru-hit-by-massive-13-foot-high-waves-leaving-scores-of-ports-closed</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:18:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea Plane Crash Live Updates: All except 2 presumed dead, say authorities after plane veers off runway at South Korea airport - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Plane Crash Live Updates</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Early Sunday<br><strong>Source: </strong>Reuters</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/expressintro-9.jpg?w=640" alt="South Korea plane crash" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>South Korea Plane Crash Live: The accident occurred when a Jeju Air flight was landing at Muan International Airport.</figcaption><p>Authorities report that all except two crew members are feared dead after a plane carrying 175 passengers crashed and erupted into flames while landing.</p><ul><li>The accident happened around 9 am local time at Muan International Airport, South Jeolla Province.</li><li>The flight was a Jeju Air Boeing 737-800, operating from Bangkok to South Korea.</li><li>120 bodies have been recovered so far, and the incident is noted as the worst air accident involving a South Korean airline in nearly three decades.</li><li>The aircraft failed to land correctly and crashed into a wall, leading to an explosion.</li><li>Recovery efforts are underway, as the acting President ordered all-out rescue operations.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is the worst air accident involving a South Korean airline in nearly three decades and it is on track to become the country’s deadliest ever.”</blockquote><p>As recovery efforts continue, the focus remains on identifying the casualties and understanding the cause of this tragic incident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-9749485/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 09:51:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea plane crash live: 176 passengers confirmed dead out of 181 - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Plane Crash: 177 Confirmed Dead Out of 181 Passengers</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 29, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/SOUTHKOREA-CRASH--7_1735439197070_1735439220072.JPG" alt="Firefighters carry out extinguishing operations on an aircraft which drove off runaway at Muan International Airport." />
<figcaption>Firefighters carry out extinguishing operations on an aircraft which drove off runaway at Muan International Airport in Muan, South Jeolla Province, South Korea.</figcaption>
<p>A Jeju Air plane returning from Bangkok veered off the runway and caught fire at Muan International Airport, resulting in the tragic loss of life with 177 confirmed dead out of 181 passengers on board.</p>
<ul>
<li>The flight, Jeju Air 7C2216, was landing when it collided with a fence and caught fire.</li>
<li>179 passengers were initially feared dead, but authorities have confirmed 177 deaths.</li>
<li>Two crew members were rescued from the wreckage.</li>
<li>The incident has been marked as one of the worst air disasters in South Korean history.</li>
<li>Eyewitness accounts noted flames in the engine and loud explosions before the crash.</li>
<li>Condolences have poured in from international leaders, including the German Chancellor and South Korea's acting president.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Passengers were ejected from the aircraft after it collided with the barrier, leaving little chance of survival.” - Fire Department Official</blockquote>
<p>This devastating crash underscores the importance of aviation safety protocols and the impact such tragedies have on the victims' families and communities both locally and internationally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-jeju-air-muan-boeing-death-toll-101735437972261.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/south-korea-plane-crash-live-updates-jeju-air-muan-boeing-death-toll-101735437972261.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 09:45:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>