<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:15:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:15:38 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Burgers at $2: Canada's Dairy Queen celebrates Justin Trudeau's resignation with special offer - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Burgers at $2: Canada's Dairy Queen celebrates Justin Trudeau's resignation with special offer</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Dairy Queen Offer" /><figcaption>Dairy Queen promotes their special offer.</figcaption><p>This article discusses how Canada's Dairy Queen is celebrating the resignation of Prime Minister Justin Trudeau by offering burgers for only $2 as a promotional gimmick.</p><ul><li>Dairy Queen introduces a special promotion in response to Trudeau's resignation.</li><li>Burgers are priced at an unusually low $2.</li><li>The offer is part of a broader campaign to engage customers during the political transition.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is a time to create community spirit and celebrate change," said a Dairy Queen representative.</blockquote><p>The Dairy Queen promotion is seen as a lighthearted response to a significant political event, highlighting how brands capitalize on current events to connect with their customers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/burgers-at-2-canadas-dairy-queen-celebrates-justin-trudeaus-resignation-with-special-offer/articleshow/117012991.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/burgers-at-2-canadas-dairy-queen-celebrates-justin-trudeaus-resignation-with-special-offer/articleshow/117012991.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Asks If US Should "Liberate" UK From "Tyrannical Government" - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk Questions if US Should 'Liberate' UK from 'Tyrannical Government'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> X Platform</p>
<blockquote><img src='image_link_here' alt='Elon Musk'></blockquote>
<figcaption>Elon Musk's recent poll on whether Americans should 'liberate' the British.</figcaption>
<p>Elon Musk, the world's richest man, initiated a poll on his social media platform asking if Americans should 'liberate' Britons from their government, amidst his ongoing feud with the UK's Labour Party over child abuse case handling.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The poll was created on January 6 and received nearly two million votes.</li>
  <li>Suggestions from users included making the UK a US state, echoing Donald Trump's earlier remarks.</li>
  <li>Errol Musk urged the public to ignore his son's comments.</li>
  <li>The poll followed UK Minister Jess Phillips rejecting a government inquiry into child exploitation.</li>
  <li>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer criticized those spreading misinformation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“America should liberate the people of Britain from their tyrannical government” — Elon Musk</blockquote>
<p>This situation highlights tensions around child exploitation cases in the UK, an issue that has resurfaced in public discourse.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-asks-if-us-should-liberate-uk-from-tyrannical-government-7418223</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-asks-if-us-should-liberate-uk-from-tyrannical-government-7418223</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:46:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SBI’s collateral-free education loan for studying abroad: All you need to know - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>SBI Launches Collateral-Free Education Loans for Studying Abroad</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/branch-kolkata-phones-front-checks-state-mobile_6dd36522-b53b-11ea-b3b3-7b919605787e_1736155500283.jpg" alt="SBI’s collateral-free education loan for studying abroad: With flexible repayment terms and coverage for major expenses, this scheme reduces financial hurdles and helps students focus on achieving their academic goals.(REUTERS)" title="SBI’s collateral-free education loan for studying abroad: With flexible repayment terms and coverage for major expenses, this scheme reduces financial hurdles and helps students focus on achieving their academic goals.(REUTERS)"><figcaption>SBI’s collateral-free education loan for studying abroad: With flexible repayment terms and coverage for major expenses, this scheme reduces financial hurdles and helps students focus on achieving their academic goals.(REUTERS)</figcaption></figure><p>The State Bank of India (SBI) has increased the limit for collateral-free education loans for students aiming to study abroad, offering loans up to ₹50 lakh without requiring collateral.</p><ul><li>SBI Global Ed-Vantage is designed for full-time courses at foreign colleges.</li><li>Loans offered without collateral for selected institutions.</li><li>Repayment period up to 15 years with Easy Monthly Installments (EMIs).</li><li>Loans cover various expenses including tuition, travel, and living costs.</li><li>Tax benefits available under Section 80(E) of the Income Tax Act.</li></ul><blockquote>Ankit Mehra, CEO of GyanDhan, stated, "This initiative significantly eases access to education financing for meritorious students."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, SBI’s collateral-free education loan presents a valuable opportunity for students planning to study abroad, making education financing more accessible.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/education/study-abroad/sbis-collateral-free-education-loan-for-studying-abroad-all-you-need-to-know-101736149397998.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/education/study-abroad/sbis-collateral-free-education-loan-for-studying-abroad-all-you-need-to-know-101736149397998.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 07:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yellen raises ‘serious concern’ to China after US Treasury cyberattack - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE5FVGxNRnpFUm5RWjRDYnlXNmEyeFduLWRBRnlVTlJQallLemVzN1NqYUpuLUI2VVJ0c3QwRjJPUWZ4VU01cVo5ag?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE5FVGxNRnpFUm5RWjRDYnlXNmEyeFduLWRBRnlVTlJQallLemVzN1NqYUpuLUI2VVJ0c3QwRjJPUWZ4VU01cVo5ag?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 06:57:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk a 'monster': Giorgia Meloni slams labelling, says because he chose the side considered 'wrong' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAJBVV95cUxNZDktd1dIM3ZmYWJuZW9SOHNNWi1aUzIxbzhIUExGYmRQX2ItUkRORW5rT0JXSVd2SmZ4c243OGJfMWphS3NfZ1FqaEx4WmtMeGw3NkU1cXlROWpjYkpNTkVlT1FaTkVqVnZEZ0ZRMzIxdF9vak13YS1yUlhLWUsyWm5fc3ZFVl9OeENQNXV4UU9GU081djRoZEJwNkNRY0g3dXVaZXE4Rlh0b0J2T1ZGSGdQMVNwMHM4RDVQUlZ6VkdLcnpxbFdBcTNLbFV0U1Y2TUx1TExkUFFGYUtzbnZqN2hYMG9XenM0S21IVEZRcWhiU1hlelVyazRkYWFNbDcwYkNPSDN1STdrVElIUkFGM0phMUU1MHF5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAJBVV95cUxNZDktd1dIM3ZmYWJuZW9SOHNNWi1aUzIxbzhIUExGYmRQX2ItUkRORW5rT0JXSVd2SmZ4c243OGJfMWphS3NfZ1FqaEx4WmtMeGw3NkU1cXlROWpjYkpNTkVlT1FaTkVqVnZEZ0ZRMzIxdF9vak13YS1yUlhLWUsyWm5fc3ZFVl9OeENQNXV4UU9GU081djRoZEJwNkNRY0g3dXVaZXE4Rlh0b0J2T1ZGSGdQMVNwMHM4RDVQUlZ6VkdLcnpxbFdBcTNLbFV0U1Y2TUx1TExkUFFGYUtzbnZqN2hYMG9XenM0S21IVEZRcWhiU1hlelVyazRkYWFNbDcwYkNPSDN1STdrVElIUkFGM0phMUU1MHF5?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 05:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden slaps tight Donald Trump with this 72-year-old act just days before leaving - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Protects 625 Million Acres of Offshore Areas from Drilling Ahead of Trump's Presidency</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/President-Joe-Biden-meets-with-President-elect-Don_1731598109806_1736220223498.jpg" alt="President Joe Biden meets with President-elect Donald Trump in the Oval Office of the White House, on Wednesday. (AP)" title="President Joe Biden meets with President-elect Donald Trump in the Oval Office of the White House, on Wednesday. (AP)"> <figcaption>President Joe Biden meets with President-elect Donald Trump in the Oval Office of the White House, on Wednesday. (AP)</figcaption> <p>In a significant move, President Joe Biden announced the protection of 625 million acres of offshore areas from oil and gas drilling, complicating plans for the incoming Donald Trump administration.</p> <ul> <li>Biden utilizes the 1953 Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to prevent future drilling in these areas.</li> <li>The protected areas span the East and West coasts, Eastern Gulf of Mexico, and Alaska’s North Bering Sea.</li> <li>Trump may require Congressional approval to reverse this decision due to the limitations of the OCSLA.</li> <li>Biden asserts that drilling could cause irreversible damage and is unnecessary for national energy needs, especially amidst the climate crisis.</li> <li>Incoming press secretary Karoline Leavitt criticized the decision as politically motivated, while industry leaders argue for the reversal of the protections to support energy production.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“Drilling in the areas I’m seeking to protect could cause irreversible damage... is not worth the risks.” - Joe Biden</blockquote> <p>This decision signals a strong stance on environmental protection as the Biden administration prepares to transition out while raising challenging questions for Trump's upcoming plans for energy expansion.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/joe-biden-slaps-tight-donald-trump-with-this-72-year-old-act-just-days-before-leaving-101736217788002.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/joe-biden-slaps-tight-donald-trump-with-this-72-year-old-act-just-days-before-leaving-101736217788002.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:48:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why flying is different for the world’s tallest woman. She reveals in intriguing video - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why flying is different for the world’s tallest woman</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/World_Tallest_woman_Rumeysa_Gelgi_Viral_Plane_1736221450430_1736221456796.jpg" alt="The world’s tallest woman, Rumeysa Gelgi, explains how it feels to travel in flight. (Instagram/@guinnessworldrecords)" title="The world’s tallest woman, Rumeysa Gelgi, explains how it feels to travel in flight. (Instagram/@guinnessworldrecords)">
<figcaption>The world’s tallest woman, Rumeysa Gelgi, explains how it feels to travel in flight. (Instagram/@guinnessworldrecords)</figcaption>
<p>Rumeysa Gelgi, the world’s tallest woman, shared her unique flying experience on Instagram, revealing how she needs to lie on a stretcher during flights due to her spinal condition.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gelgi recently travelled to the US and UK with Turkish Airlines.</li>
  <li>She has scoliosis and two rods and thirty screws in her spine, necessitating her lying down to keep her back straight.</li>
  <li>She expressed excitement about her travel in the Instagram video, stating, “I am literally so excited, my heart beats fast.”</li>
  <li>Social media users reacted positively, praising both Gelgi and Turkish Airlines for their support.</li>
  <li>Gelgi holds five Guinness World Records titles and advocates for awareness of her condition.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Flying on a stretcher is the safest - and only - option for me to travel by air.” - Rumeysa Gelgi</blockquote>
<p>Rumeysa Gelgi's story highlights the impact of unique physical challenges and the kindness of airline staff in accommodating her needs.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/why-flying-is-different-for-the-world-s-tallest-woman-she-reveals-in-intriguing-video-101736221260367.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/why-flying-is-different-for-the-world-s-tallest-woman-she-reveals-in-intriguing-video-101736221260367.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:46:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['A plan for self-defence': North Korea's Kim Jong Un says new hypersonic missile will deter rivals - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/a-plan-for-self-defence-north-koreas-kim-jong-un-says-new-hypersonic-missile-will-deter-rivals/articleshow/117007766.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/a-plan-for-self-defence-north-koreas-kim-jong-un-says-new-hypersonic-missile-will-deter-rivals/articleshow/117007766.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump renews his offer of making Canada 51st state of U.S. after Trudeau resigns - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Proposes Canada as 51st State Following Trudeau's Resignation</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> January 07, 2025 08:38 am IST</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/z7juv4/article69070862.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/Canada_Cabinet_Shuffle_95138.jpg" alt="File picture of U.S. President-elect Donald Trump with Canada’s Prime Minister Justin Trudeau"><figcaption>File picture of U.S. President-elect Donald Trump with Canada’s Prime Minister Justin Trudeau | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>In a surprising move, U.S. President-elect Donald Trump renewed his proposal to make Canada the 51st state shortly after Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau announced his resignation amid declining popularity.</p><ul><li>Trudeau announced his resignation as his party pushed him out, pending a leadership election.</li><li>Trump has suggested that Canada could benefit from merging with the U.S. through lower taxes and greater security.</li><li>He claims many Canadians support the idea, citing public sentiment on social media.</li></ul><blockquote>“Many people in Canada LOVE being the 51st State... Together, what a great Nation it would be!!!” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>Despite Trump's assertions, there has been little response from Canadian officials regarding the proposal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-renews-his-offer-of-making-canada-51st-state-of-us-after-trudeau-resigns/article69070879.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-renews-his-offer-of-making-canada-51st-state-of-us-after-trudeau-resigns/article69070879.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 03:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7.1 magnitude earthquake hits Kathmandu, epicentre at China; tremors felt in Bihar - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7.1 Magnitude Earthquake Hits Kathmandu, Epicentre at China; Tremors Felt in Bihar</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Press Trust of India</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/mymls4/article69070885.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2023-02-15T142926Z_1200355584_RC2QBZ9VHHM6_RTRMADP_3_ROMANIA-QUAKE.jpeg" alt="Representational file image of a seismograph recording an earthquake." /><figcaption>Representational file image of a seismograph recording an earthquake. | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>A strong earthquake jolted Kathmandu early morning on Tuesday, measuring 7.1 on the Richter scale at 6:50 a.m. The epicentre was located in Dinggye, China, with tremors felt in Nepal and parts of India, particularly in Bihar’s Madhubani district.</p><ul><li>The National Earthquake Measurement Centre recorded the earthquake.</li><li>People evacuated homes in panic in Kathmandu and surrounding districts.</li><li>No damage reports have surfaced as of yet.</li><li>A related 6.8 magnitude earthquake struck Western China with at least nine fatalities.</li></ul><blockquote>“It shook quite strongly here, everyone is awake, but we don’t know about any damages yet,” said Jagat Prasad Bhusal, a government official in Nepal's Namche region.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the earthquake has prompted a significant emergency response while raising concerns for ongoing seismic activity in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/earthquake-hits-kathmandu-epicentre-at-china/article69070877.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/earthquake-hits-kathmandu-epicentre-at-china/article69070877.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 02:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winter storm: Polar Vortex freezes much of US; over 9,000 flights disrupted - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Winter Storm: Polar Vortex Freezes Much of the US, Disrupting Over 9,000 Flights</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Major News Outlets</p><p>The polar vortex has brought severe winter weather, causing significant disruptions across the United States. Over 9,000 flights have been cancelled or delayed as regions face extreme cold and heavy snowfall.</p><ul><li>Polar vortex causes extreme cold across much of the US.</li><li>Over 9,000 flights disrupted due to weather conditions.</li><li>Road travel impacted; safety warnings issued.</li><li>Authorities working to address power outages.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is one of the coldest winters we've seen in a decade." - Meteorologist</blockquote><p>This winter storm highlights the increasing impact of severe weather patterns and their effects on transportation and public safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/winter-storm-polar-vortex-freezes-much-of-us-over-9000-flights-disrupted/articleshow/117007013.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/winter-storm-polar-vortex-freezes-much-of-us-over-9000-flights-disrupted/articleshow/117007013.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 02:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau resigns: How allegations against India sparked his downfall - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Trudeau resigns: How allegations against India sparked his downfall</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/TOPSHOT-CANADA-POLITICS-GOVERNMENT-TRUDEAU-1_1736214065627_1736214075106.jpg" alt="Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau speaks during a news conference at Rideau Cottage in Ottawa, where he announced his resignation.(AFP)" title="Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau speaks during a news conference at Rideau Cottage in Ottawa, where he announced his resignation.(AFP)">
<figcaption>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau speaks during a news conference at Rideau Cottage in Ottawa, where he announced his resignation.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>In response to escalating discontent over the leadership, Canadian prime minister Justin Trudeau announced his resignation as prime minister after months of political crisis.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trudeau claimed that India was sponsoring criminal activities on Canadian soil, a claim denied by New Delhi.</li>
  <li>His resignation follows serious internal divisions and slumping polls within his party.</li>
  <li>Allegations against India started in September 2023 regarding the killing of Khalistani militant Hardeep Singh Nijjar.</li>
  <li>Relations between India and Canada deteriorated following Trudeau's accusations, resulting in expelled diplomats and heightened tensions.</li>
  <li>Increased pro-Khalistani sentiments and attacks on temples in Canada were significant factors leading to Trudeau's political downfall.</li>
  <li>Trudeau's administration failed to provide evidence for his allegations despite international pressure, raising questions about their validity.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The diplomatic fallout from Trudeau's claims was severe for his leadership in Canada, which has a significant Indian population.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Trudeau's resignation underscores the significant impact of political allegations on international relations and internal party dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/justin-trudeau-resigns-how-his-allegations-against-india-led-to-his-fall-as-canadian-pm-101736213773384.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/justin-trudeau-resigns-how-his-allegations-against-india-led-to-his-fall-as-canadian-pm-101736213773384.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 02:30:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earthquake hits Tibet’s Shigatse city, tremors felt in Nepal’s Kathmandu - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/7/earthquake-hits-tibets-shigatse-city-tremors-felt-in-nepals-kathmandu</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/7/earthquake-hits-tibets-shigatse-city-tremors-felt-in-nepals-kathmandu</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 02:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nepal earthquake today: 7.1 magnitude quake hits Kathmandu, tremors felt in Delhi-NCR - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7.1 Magnitude Earthquake Hits Nepal, Tremors Felt in North India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/-p-Minor-earthquake-strikes-Sonbhadra---p-_1717352392857_1736215836562.jpg" alt="Tremors from a 7.1 magnitude earthquake in Nepal felt in Delhi-NCR and North India." title="Tremors from a 7.1 magnitude earthquake in Nepal felt in Delhi-NCR and North India."><figcaption>Tremors from a 7.1 magnitude earthquake in Nepal felt in Delhi-NCR and North India.</figcaption><p>A 7.1 magnitude earthquake struck Nepal today, with tremors felt strongly in Delhi and surrounding regions. Emergency services are on alert for any aftershocks.</p><ul><li>The earthquake occurred at 6:35 AM IST, 93 km northeast of Lobuche.</li><li>Tremors were felt across Delhi-NCR and as far as Bihar.</li><li>No damage to property has been reported as of yet.</li><li>Emergency response teams are monitoring the situation closely.</li><li>The quake is part of a seismically active zone where the Indian and Eurasian plates meet.</li></ul><blockquote>"EQ of M: 7.1, On: 07/01/2025 06:35:18 IST, lat: 28.86 N, long: 87.51 E, Depth: 10 Km, Location: Xizang." - National Centre for Seismology</blockquote><p>Emergency officials have advised residents to remain calm and prepare for potential aftershocks as the region is known for seismic activity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/71-magnitude-earthquake-in-nepal-tremors-felt-in-delhincr-101736214432196.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/71-magnitude-earthquake-in-nepal-tremors-felt-in-delhincr-101736214432196.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:56:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earthquake of 7.1 magnitude strikes Nepal, tremors felt in Delhi-NCR - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7.1 Magnitude Earthquake Hits Nepal, Tremors Felt in North India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/-p-Minor-earthquake-strikes-Sonbhadra---p-_1717352392857_1736215836562.jpg" alt="Tremors from a 7.1 magnitude earthquake in Nepal felt in Delhi-NCR and North India." title="Tremors from a 7.1 magnitude earthquake in Nepal felt in Delhi-NCR and North India."><figcaption>Tremors from a 7.1 magnitude earthquake in Nepal felt in Delhi-NCR and North India.</figcaption><p>A 7.1 magnitude earthquake struck Nepal today, with tremors felt strongly in Delhi and surrounding regions. Emergency services are on alert for any aftershocks.</p><ul><li>The earthquake occurred at 6:35 AM IST, 93 km northeast of Lobuche.</li><li>Tremors were felt across Delhi-NCR and as far as Bihar.</li><li>No damage to property has been reported as of yet.</li><li>Emergency response teams are monitoring the situation closely.</li><li>The quake is part of a seismically active zone where the Indian and Eurasian plates meet.</li></ul><blockquote>"EQ of M: 7.1, On: 07/01/2025 06:35:18 IST, lat: 28.86 N, long: 87.51 E, Depth: 10 Km, Location: Xizang." - National Centre for Seismology</blockquote><p>Emergency officials have advised residents to remain calm and prepare for potential aftershocks as the region is known for seismic activity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/71-magnitude-earthquake-in-nepal-tremors-felt-in-delhincr-101736214432196.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/71-magnitude-earthquake-in-nepal-tremors-felt-in-delhincr-101736214432196.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:56:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump renews offer to make Canada the 51st state after Justin Trudeau’s resignation - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Proposes Canada as the 51st State Following Trudeau's Resignation</h1> <p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/files-us-canada-trade-tariff-politics_7c5a9308-d86e-11ea-8122-d3bbe1b049d5_1736214138432.jpg" alt="File photo of US Presidnt Donald Trump and Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau at the White House in Washington, DC.(AFP File)" title="File photo of US Presidnt Donald Trump and Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau at the White House in Washington, DC.(AFP File)"> <figcaption>File photo of US Presidnt Donald Trump and Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau at the White House in Washington, DC.(AFP File)</figcaption> <p>Following the resignation of Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, US President-elect Donald Trump renewed his long-standing proposition to make Canada the 51st state, criticizing the nation's trade practices.</p> <ul> <li>Trump criticized Canada's trade practices, claiming they exploit the US.</li> <li>He suggested that merging Canada with the US would eliminate tariffs and improve security against foreign threats.</li> <li>Trudeau resigned amid declining popularity and pressure from his party.</li> <li>Trump has mocked Trudeau, referring to him as Canada’s “governor.”</li> </ul> <blockquote>“Many people in Canada LOVE being the 51st State. The United States can no longer suffer the massive Trade Deficits and Subsidies that Canada needs to stay afloat.” - Donald Trump</blockquote> <p>Trump's statehood proposal has garnered minimal reaction from Canada, as he continues to leverage public opinion against Trudeau's administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/donald-trump-renews-offer-to-make-canada-the-51st-state-after-justin-trudeau-s-resignation-101736212637114.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/donald-trump-renews-offer-to-make-canada-the-51st-state-after-justin-trudeau-s-resignation-101736212637114.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:42:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Macron, European leaders hit back in Elon Musk meddling row - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Macron, European leaders hit back in Elon Musk meddling row</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/6y2vno/article69070806.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_France_s_President_E_2_1_QBAJD42J.jpg" alt="File picture of France’s President Emmanuel Macron and billionaire Elon Musk" title="File picture of France’s President Emmanuel Macron and billionaire Elon Musk">
<figcaption>File picture of France’s President Emmanuel Macron and billionaire Elon Musk | Photo Credit: via Reuters</figcaption>
<p>European leaders expressed their frustration with Elon Musk as a major controversy escalated involving misinformation online, historical sex offences, and the interference of a tech billionaire in European politics.</p>
<ul>
<li>U.K. Prime Minister Keir Starmer criticized Musk for spreading misinformation regarding sex offences in northern England.</li>
<li>Musk accused Starmer of being complicit in mass rapes due to his previous role as chief state prosecutor.</li>
<li>French President Emmanuel Macron condemned Musk for interfering in elections, particularly in Germany.</li>
<li>Other European leaders, including Norway's Prime Minister Jonas Gahr Store, expressed concern about Musk's wealth and influence in politics.</li>
<li>The ongoing discourse touches on historical grooming gang scandals in Britain related to systemic abuse.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Those that are spreading lies and misinformation as far and as wide as possible, they're not interested in victims, they're interested in themselves." - Keir Starmer</blockquote>
<p>This controversy highlights the complex dynamics between tech influence and politics in Europe, prompting calls for accountability and further inquiries into past failures in handling abuse cases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/macron-european-leaders-hit-back-in-elon-musk-meddling-row/article69070803.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/macron-european-leaders-hit-back-in-elon-musk-meddling-row/article69070803.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Massive earthquake of 7.1 magnitude strikes Tibet-Nepal border; at least 30 killed - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Death toll from earthquake in Tibet-Nepal jumps to 95, over 100 injured</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>An earthquake near the Tibet-Nepal border has caused significant casualties, with the death toll reaching 95 and over 100 individuals injured as rescue efforts continue.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The earthquake struck an area frequented by tourists, heightening concerns about safety.</li>
  <li>Rescue operations are underway, but difficult terrain is complicating efforts.</li>
  <li>This event has raised alarm over geological stability in the region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The need for immediate international aid is crucial to support the affected communities." - Local official</blockquote>
<p>The earthquake's impact underscores the vulnerability of the region to natural disasters and the need for improved infrastructure and preparedness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/earthquake-of-magnitude-7-1-strikes-nepal-tremors-felt-in-parts-of-india-bihar-delhi-ncr/articleshow/117007173.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/earthquake-of-magnitude-7-1-strikes-nepal-tremors-felt-in-parts-of-india-bihar-delhi-ncr/articleshow/117007173.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earthquake Of Magnitude 7.1 Hits Tibet, Tremors Felt In Parts Of India - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>95 Dead In Huge Quake Near Mount Everest, Tremors Also Felt In Parts Of India</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> AFP, Xinhua</p><p>The article reports a devastating earthquake of magnitude 7.1 that struck near Mount Everest, resulting in 95 fatalities and tremors felt across parts of India.</p><ul><li>The epicenter was located in Tingri county, Shigatse city, Tibet, approximately 400 km southwest of Lhasa.</li><li>The earthquake occurred at 6:35 am local time, followed by two additional tremors of magnitudes 4.7 and 4.9.</li><li>Tremors were reported in Indian states such as Bihar, Assam, and West Bengal, with no immediate reports of property damage.</li><li>This region is known for its geological activity due to the collision of the Indian and Eurasian tectonic plates.</li><li>The 2015 earthquake in Nepal resulted in nearly 9,000 deaths, highlighting the area's vulnerability to such natural disasters.</li></ul><blockquote>“The tremors were seen particularly in Bihar where people were outside their homes.”</blockquote><p>This incident underscores the ongoing threat of earthquakes in the Himalayan region, emphasizing the need for preparedness and safety measures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earthquake-of-magnitude-7-1-hits-nepal-tremors-felt-in-parts-of-india-7416291</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earthquake-of-magnitude-7-1-hits-nepal-tremors-felt-in-parts-of-india-7416291</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:33:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Multiple earthquakes strike Tibet, tremors felt in several parts of India - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOZFNucVg0NkZPMEo0T2ZIOUdmT0lja0hkWXp0a3c1X3N4UHIxUDFDRmRvZzZ4WnZPQllRUEMxRi1PeEE1dUVGQnNGOV9UanIzZnNTbThLZm5XdEFneGVnR2JwNmx3Y0lmNzBkd3U1YUR1bnJPV3FCNHlsa0JXV0x3ZUQ0MXB6aUtBYkROWGJFZ2U2eU80c1JNNk5fT0lsbXFVYUhXenVEay04bnJFVG5BSFhwVHAtUdIBuwFBVV95cUxPM1BwQ21WN0M2UWx0MXJ4N05mUGVGb19VNEZzMF9icDd1a1E1V1hua0w2ZzE2aC1tUVFVTTB2VGdFNlpMcXhkNjNFRG82SzVlSE1kVlhNNFlYXzZvdm53OEF2dTdqMFhoWDBGS2tJc2hhQjg5OHFiQjU2eWdoZW9Ib3FWRC1kM0VSSHRNRnRkQ1htbF9WTEJreWlOLWJSREJ1cjg5QkljcjVaTjN6RnBRTEtzXzA0c2h5TmZ3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxOZFNucVg0NkZPMEo0T2ZIOUdmT0lja0hkWXp0a3c1X3N4UHIxUDFDRmRvZzZ4WnZPQllRUEMxRi1PeEE1dUVGQnNGOV9UanIzZnNTbThLZm5XdEFneGVnR2JwNmx3Y0lmNzBkd3U1YUR1bnJPV3FCNHlsa0JXV0x3ZUQ0MXB6aUtBYkROWGJFZ2U2eU80c1JNNk5fT0lsbXFVYUhXenVEay04bnJFVG5BSFhwVHAtUdIBuwFBVV95cUxPM1BwQ21WN0M2UWx0MXJ4N05mUGVGb19VNEZzMF9icDd1a1E1V1hua0w2ZzE2aC1tUVFVTTB2VGdFNlpMcXhkNjNFRG82SzVlSE1kVlhNNFlYXzZvdm53OEF2dTdqMFhoWDBGS2tJc2hhQjg5OHFiQjU2eWdoZW9Ib3FWRC1kM0VSSHRNRnRkQ1htbF9WTEJreWlOLWJSREJ1cjg5QkljcjVaTjN6RnBRTEtzXzA0c2h5TmZ3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:22:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Series of earthquakes hit Tibet near Nepal border; tremors felt in parts of north India - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Series of earthquakes hit Tibet near Nepal border; tremors felt in parts of north India</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Early Tuesday morning</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/earthquake.jpg?w=640" alt="earthquake, delhi ncr, nepal" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>An earthquake of 7.1 magnitude hit Nepal on early Tuesday morning.</figcaption><p>A series of earthquakes, including a significant 7.1 magnitude quake, occurred near the Tibet-Nepal border, affecting northern India. Reports indicate fatalities in the impacted towns.</p><ul><li>The 7.1 magnitude earthquake was followed by at least seven aftershocks, each around 5.0 in magnitude.</li><li>The quake originated approximately 10 km below the Earth's surface, indicating high destructive potential.</li><li>This region is known for seismic activity due to the collision of tectonic plates forming the Himalayas.</li><li>The April 2015 Nepal earthquake, which killed about 10,000 people, remains a significant historical reference for similar events.</li></ul><blockquote>“A magnitude 7 earthquake is about 1,000 times more devastating than an earthquake of magnitude 5.”</blockquote><p>The recent earthquakes highlight the vulnerability of the Himalayan region and the potential for substantial destruction due to shallow seismic activity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/nepal-earthquake-tremors-north-india-delhi-ncr-live-updates-9763903/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/nepal-earthquake-tremors-north-india-delhi-ncr-live-updates-9763903/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five dead as winter storm Blair wreaks havoc across US - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Winter Storm Blair Causes Disruption and Fatalities Across the US</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025 &nbsp;|&nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/US_winter_storm_1736211123660_1736211123936.jpg" alt="Crews clearing snow at the U.S. Capitol" title="Crews work before dawn to clear snow East Front Plaza of the U.S. Capitol as a winter storm slams into the nation's capital on January 06, 2025 in Washington, DC.(AFP)">
<figcaption>Crews work before dawn to clear snow East Front Plaza of the U.S. Capitol as a winter storm slams into the nation's capital on January 06, 2025 in Washington, DC.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Winter Storm Blair has led to severe weather conditions across major parts of the central and eastern US, resulting in five fatalities and widespread travel disruptions.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Five dead due to accidents related to the winter storm.</li>
  <li>Freezing temperatures caused mass flight cancellations and disrupted rail and road travel.</li>
  <li>Seven states declared a state of emergency.</li>
  <li>Record snowfall reported at Cincinnati/Northern Kentucky International Airport.</li>
  <li>Over 250,000 people left without power due to downed power lines from the storm.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The weather was a major reason” - West Virginia police regarding storm-related fatalities.</blockquote>
<p>Storm Blair exemplifies the impact of extreme winter weather, highlighting the vulnerabilities in infrastructure and the need for emergency preparedness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/five-dead-as-winter-storm-blair-wreaks-havoc-across-us-101736208433370.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/five-dead-as-winter-storm-blair-wreaks-havoc-across-us-101736208433370.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 01:06:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brazil announces Indonesia's full membership in BRICS - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Brazil Welcomes Indonesia as Newest Member of BRICS</h1><p><strong>Jan 07, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Prime-Minister-Narendra-Modi-with-other-world-lead_1729709633275_1736209900883.jpg" alt="Brazil announces Indonesia's admission as a full BRICS member. (ANI FILE PHOTO)" title="Brazil announces Indonesia's admission as a full BRICS member. (ANI FILE PHOTO)"><figcaption>Brazil announces Indonesia's admission as a full BRICS member. (ANI FILE PHOTO)</figcaption><p>Brazil has announced that Indonesia has become a full member of the BRICS bloc, confirming Indonesia's candidacy was approved in August 2023.</p><ul><li>Indonesia is the world’s fourth-most populous country and has the largest economy in Southeast Asia.</li><li>The decision to join followed the formation of Indonesia's newly elected government in 2024.</li><li>The Brazilian government emphasized the shared commitment to reforming global governance.</li><li>The BRICS group was established in 2009 and has expanded to include several nations, with further applications from Turkey, Azerbaijan, and Malaysia.</li><li>Concerns persist regarding alternative currencies to the US dollar among some BRICS members.</li></ul><blockquote>“With the largest population and economy in Southeast Asia, Indonesia shares with other members a commitment to reforming global governance institutions.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Indonesia's membership in BRICS signifies a growing collaboration among key developing economies and may influence global economic dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/brazil-announces-indonesias-full-membership-in-brics-101736209207295.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/brazil-announces-indonesias-full-membership-in-brics-101736209207295.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:38:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What happens now that Justin Trudeau is resigning as Canada's prime minister? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What happens now that Justin Trudeau is resigning as Canada's prime minister?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Monday, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/CANADA-TRUDEAU-5_1736201867207_1736201893024.jpg" alt="Justin Trudeau, Canada's prime minister, arrives for a news conference at Rideau Cottage in Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, on Monday,(Bloomberg)" title="Justin Trudeau, Canada's prime minister, arrives for a news conference at Rideau Cottage in Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, on Monday,(Bloomberg)"><figcaption>Justin Trudeau, Canada's prime minister, arrives for a news conference at Rideau Cottage in Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, on Monday,(Bloomberg)</figcaption></figure><p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau announced he will step down in the coming months after nine years in power due to worsening pre-election polling for his Liberal Party. He will remain in his position until a new leader is chosen.</p><ul><li>Trudeau will not leave office immediately; he will stay on until the Liberal Party elects a new leader.</li><li>No immediate election is expected as parliament is prorogued until March 24, delaying any non-confidence motions.</li><li>The Liberal Party is anticipated to implement a shortened leadership selection process to choose a successor quickly.</li><li>Polls indicate a significant defeat for the Liberals in the upcoming election, regardless of the new leader.</li><li>Potential candidates to succeed Trudeau include top ministers like Francois-Philippe Champagne and Anita Anand.</li></ul><blockquote>“The governor general won't dismiss a prime minister who still holds the confidence of the Commons.” - Philippe Lagasse, constitutional expert</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Trudeau's resignation will trigger a crucial period of transition within the Liberal Party, with significant implications for the next election.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/what-happens-now-that-justin-trudeau-is-resigning-as-canadas-prime-minister-101736201197503.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/what-happens-now-that-justin-trudeau-is-resigning-as-canadas-prime-minister-101736201197503.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 22:20:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump loses bid to delay sentencing in hush money case as he appeals - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Loses Bid to Delay Sentencing in Hush Money Case</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 06 January 2025, 22:07 IST</p><p>US President-elect Donald Trump has lost his attempt to postpone sentencing related to his criminal conviction over hush money payments made to a porn star.</p><ul><li>Trump's lawyers argued for a delay citing presidential immunity and the incoming inauguration.</li><li>Judge Juan Merchan declined the request, stating Trump's motion was largely repetitive of previous arguments.</li><li>The sentencing is scheduled for January 10, and the judge indicated that jail time was unlikely.</li><li>Prosecutors highlighted the public interest in moving forward with the case.</li><li>The matter stems from a $130,000 payment made to Stormy Daniels during the 2016 election campaign.</li><li>This case marks Trump as the first sitting or former U.S. president to be charged with a crime.</li></ul><blockquote>“The balance of equities weighs heavily in the People's favor given the strong public interest in prompt prosecution and the finality of criminal proceedings.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the court's decision to maintain the sentencing schedule underscores the ongoing legal challenges Trump faces as he prepares for his inauguration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/us-president-elect-donald-trump-loses-bid-to-delay-sentencing-in-hush-money-case-as-he-appeals-3343953</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/us-president-elect-donald-trump-loses-bid-to-delay-sentencing-in-hush-money-case-as-he-appeals-3343953</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 22:07:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is the inauguration 2025: Date, how to watch Trump's victory rally and what's different - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Inauguration 2025: Date, Viewing Options, and Key Differences for Trump's Ceremony</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 07, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/conference-in-president-trump-holds-washington-new_1736155220854_1736155221241.jpg" alt="Trump's inauguration Day proceedings will broadcast on ABC, CBS, CNN, CSPAN, NBC, Fox News and PBS.(REUTERS PHOTO.)"><figcaption>Trump's inauguration Day proceedings will broadcast on ABC, CBS, CNN, CSPAN, NBC, Fox News and PBS.(REUTERS PHOTO.)</figcaption></figure><p>Donald Trump will be inaugurated as the 47th president of the United States on January 20, 2025, at noon ET on the steps of the Capitol in Washington, D.C. His inauguration will have significant themes and occur just after the certification of his electoral victory.</p><ul><li>Trump's inauguration is scheduled for January 20, 2025, at noon ET.</li><li>He received 312 Electoral College votes, surpassing the 270 needed to win.</li><li>The theme for the inauguration is “Our Enduring Democracy: A Constitutional Promise.”</li><li>A victory rally is planned for January 19, 2025, at Capital One Arena.</li><li>Flags will be flown at half-staff in remembrance of former President Jimmy Carter.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Democrats are all 'giddy' about our magnificent American Flag potentially being at 'half mast' during my Inauguration.” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>The inauguration represents a pivotal moment in U.S. politics, particularly following the events surrounding the Capitol riot in 2021.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trumps-inauguration-date-how-to-watch-maga-victory-rally-and-whats-different-101736153151386.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trumps-inauguration-date-how-to-watch-maga-victory-rally-and-whats-different-101736153151386.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 20:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indonesia is admitted to the BRICS bloc of developing nations, Brazil announces - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indonesia is admitted to the BRICS bloc of developing nations, Brazil announces</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/wtcef8/article69069945.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/AFP_36T83KT.jpg" alt="(FILES) Handout picture released by the Brazilian Presidency showing Brazil’s President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva (L) posing for a picture with Indonesia’s President Prabowo Subianto before the launch of the Global Alliance against Hunger and Poverty and the first session of the G20 Leaders’ Meeting in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, on November 18, 2024. Brazil on January 6, 2025, announced that Indonesia had become a full member of BRICS, a bloc of developing economies increasingly seen as a counterweight to the West. Brazil, which holds the rotating presidency of the grouping in 2025, said Indonesia’s bid to join the bloc had been approved during a summit in 2023 in Johannesburg." />
<figcaption>Photo Credit: AFP</figcaption>
<p>Indonesia has officially joined the BRICS bloc, a significant move in the geopolitical landscape of developing economies.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Indonesia’s candidacy was approved by BRICS leaders in August 2023.</li>
  <li>The announcement was made by Brazil, which holds the presidency of BRICS for 2024.</li>
  <li>Indonesia is the world's fourth-most populous nation and the largest economy in Southeast Asia.</li>
  <li>The inclusion of Indonesia aims to enhance South-South cooperation and reform global governance.</li>
  <li>BRICS was initially formed by Brazil, Russia, India, and China in 2009, adding South Africa in 2010.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The Brazilian government welcomes Indonesia’s entry into BRICS, emphasizing its role in fostering cooperation among developing nations.</blockquote>
<p>This membership marks a pivotal moment for Indonesia and the BRICS bloc, establishing stronger ties among developing nations and enhancing their collective influence on global governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/indonesia-is-admitted-to-the-brics-bloc-of-developing-nations-brazil-announces/article69069943.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/indonesia-is-admitted-to-the-brics-bloc-of-developing-nations-brazil-announces/article69069943.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 20:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump reacts to Justin Trudeau's resignation: 'If Canada merges with US... ' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump reacts to Justin Trudeau's resignation: 'If Canada merges with US... '</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><img src='https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/GETTY_IMAGES/SKP/1171659600__e8MxbVQW.jpg' alt='Image related to the article'><figcaption>Image related to Trump's remarks on Trudeau's resignation.</figcaption><p>In this article, Donald Trump responds to the resignation of Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, suggesting the potential for Canada to merge with the United States.</p><ul><li>Trump's comments were made during a public appearance.</li><li>The reaction involved a mix of humor and political commentary.</li><li>Trudeau's resignation has sparked discussions regarding Canada's political future.</li></ul><blockquote>“If Canada merges with the US, it could be a great opportunity for both nations,” said Trump.</blockquote><p>This interaction underscores the ongoing political dynamics between the US and Canada, especially following Trudeau's controversial leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-reacts-to-justin-trudeaus-resignation-if-canada-merges-with-us-/articleshow/117002677.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-reacts-to-justin-trudeaus-resignation-if-canada-merges-with-us-/articleshow/117002677.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US VP Kamala Harris certifies her defeat to Donald Trump four years post Capitol riots - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kamala Harris Certifies Trump's Victory Four Years Post Capitol Riots</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/06/550x309/Congress-Electoral-College-Republicans-0_1736190564114_1736190598316.jpg" alt="Kamala Harris and Donald Trump" title="Kamala Harris and Donald Trump"><figcaption>FILE - Republican presidential nominee former President Donald Trump, left, and Democratic presidential nominee Vice President Kamala Harris shake hands before the start of an ABC News presidential debate,(AP)</figcaption><p>On January 6, 2025, Vice President Kamala Harris presided over the ceremonial certification of her electoral defeat to Donald Trump, marking a significant moment in the aftermath of the Capitol riots.</p><ul><li>Kamala Harris held a ceremonial role in certifying the election results.</li><li>She expressed the importance of a peaceful transfer of power, calling it a “sacred obligation.”</li><li>Harris's certification comes four years after the violent interruption of the certification process by Trump supporters.</li><li>Notably, no other vice president had certified their loss while the incoming president had not conceded a previous defeat.</li><li>Harris was evacuated from a nearby location during the January 6 riots.</li><li>Trump faced criminal charges connected to his attempts to overturn the 2020 election results.</li></ul><blockquote>“A fundamental principle of American democracy is that when we lose an election, we accept the results,” said Kamala Harris.</blockquote><p>This moment underscores the resilience of democratic processes even in the face of past turmoil.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/us-vp-kamala-harris-certifies-her-defeat-to-donald-trump-four-years-post-capitol-riots-101736190328757.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/us-vp-kamala-harris-certifies-her-defeat-to-donald-trump-four-years-post-capitol-riots-101736190328757.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:13:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. Congress certifies Trump election victory for January 20 inauguration - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>U.S. Congress Certifies Trump Election Victory for January 20 Inauguration</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ova6tp/article69069921.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Congress_Electoral_College_66696.jpg" alt="Vice President Kamala Harris reads the results as House Speaker Mike Johnson listens during a joint session of Congress to confirm the Electoral College votes, affirming President-elect Donald Trump’s victory in the presidential election, on January 6, 2025, at the U.S. Capitol in Washington." />
<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris reads the results as House Speaker Mike Johnson listens during a joint session of Congress to confirm the Electoral College votes, affirming President-elect Donald Trump’s victory in the presidential election, on January 6, 2025, at the U.S. Capitol in Washington. | Photo Credit: AP</figcaption>
<p>The U.S. Congress formally certified Republican President-elect Donald Trump's election victory over Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris, allowing him to take office on January 20, 2025.</p>
<ul>
<li>The joint session of Congress took place on January 6, 2025, presided over by Vice President Harris.</li>
<li>Mr. Trump won 312 Electoral College votes to Ms. Harris’s 226.</li>
<li>No attempts were made by Democrats to block the certification.</li>
<li>Security was heightened around the Capitol during the certification process due to past events.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Congress certifies our great election victory today - a big moment in history. MAGA!" - Donald Trump</blockquote>
<p>The certification underscores the transition of power amidst heavy security, reflecting lessons learned from previous Capitol events. With Republicans controlling both the White House and Congress, Trump's administration is expected to pursue significant policy changes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/us-congress-certifies-trump-election-victory-for-january-20-inauguration/article69069919.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/us-congress-certifies-trump-election-victory-for-january-20-inauguration/article69069919.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>