<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:23:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:23:32 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires live: 3 out of 6 active fires in Los Angeles 100% contained, Palisades continues to burn - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires: Major Fires in Los Angeles Contained Amid Devastation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-79_1736720709551_1736720732338.jpg" alt="A fire fighting helicopter drops water as the Palisades fire grows" title="A fire fighting helicopter drops water as the Palisades fire grows"><figcaption>A fire fighting helicopter drops water as the Palisades fire grows.</figcaption><p>The California wildfires have wreaked havoc, with at least 16 confirmed deaths and over 12,000 structures damaged. As of now, three of the six active fires in Los Angeles have been contained, but the Palisades fire continues to burn.</p><strong>Key Points:</strong><ul><li>The Palisades Fire spread to an additional 1,000 acres, prompting ongoing firefighting efforts.</li><li>Evacuation orders affect approximately 153,000 residents, with many additional residents warned to prepare for evacuation.</li><li>Governor Gavin Newsom announced significant containment progress for several fires, with different percentages confirmed.</li><li>President Biden has been coordinating relief efforts and addressing state officials regarding the crisis.</li><li>International aid is on the way, with offers from Canada and Ukraine for firefighting assistance.</li></ul><blockquote>“The fires are still raging in L.A. This is one of the worst catastrophes in the history of our Country.” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical with adverse weather predicted, and officials continue to emphasize the importance of safety and evacuation compliance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 22:28:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Kamala Harris' LA home be affected by wildfires? This is the house where... - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Will Kamala Harris' LA Home Be Affected by Wildfires?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Current Date, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="LA Home" /><figcaption>Kamala Harris' residence in Los Angeles</figcaption><p>The article discusses the potential threat of wildfires to Kamala Harris' home in Los Angeles, along with the broader implications of increasing wildfire risks in the area.</p><ul><li>The wildfires in California are intensifying.</li><li>Utility companies have warned of potential power outages due to the fires.</li><li>Kamala Harris' residence is located in one of the areas prone to wildfires.</li></ul><blockquote>“Wildfires are becoming more frequent and severe due to climate change,” highlighting the urgency for better fire management strategies.</blockquote><p>This highlights the urgent need for preventive measures and awareness regarding climate change impacts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/will-kamala-harris-la-home-be-affected-by-wildfires-this-is-the-house-where-/articleshow/117182055.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/will-kamala-harris-la-home-be-affected-by-wildfires-this-is-the-house-where-/articleshow/117182055.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 20:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis unveils advanced drone manufacturing facility in Nagpur - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Devendra Fadnavis unveils advanced drone manufacturing facility in Nagpur</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 13, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/devendra-fadnavis-113146150-16x9.jpg?VersionId=7.PojJCghLc7XT0OW59vaJooeT9AGxdF&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Devendra Fadnavis" title="The new drones facility in Nagpur was unveiled by Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis." height="388">
<figcaption>The new drones facility in Nagpur was unveiled by Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis.</figcaption>
<p>In a significant boost to India's defence manufacturing capabilities, the new drone facility established by Economic Explosives Limited in Nagpur aims to strengthen indigenous production of drones and unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs).</p>
<ul>
<li>The facility was inaugurated by Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis.</li>
<li>It will focus on producing loiter munitions, counter-drone systems, and military drone technologies.</li>
<li>The Nagastra-1, India's first indigenous loiter munition, has been introduced into the Indian Army.</li>
<li>Solar Industries aims to innovate and enhance India's self-reliance in defence technology.</li>
<li>The facility aligns with global trends recognizing drones as essential in modern warfare.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Solar Industries Chairman Satyanarayan Nuwal emphasized his vision of transforming Nagpur into a hub for the development of advanced weaponized drones.</blockquote>
<p>The launch of this facility marks a pivotal step in advancing India's defence manufacturing capabilities and confirms India's growing expertise in military technologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/maharashtra-chief-minister-devendra-fadnavis-unveils-advanced-drone-manufacturing-facility-in-nagpur-2663782-2025-01-13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/maharashtra-chief-minister-devendra-fadnavis-unveils-advanced-drone-manufacturing-facility-in-nagpur-2663782-2025-01-13</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 20:09:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid H-1B visa debate, some Indians lose jobs - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amid H-1B Visa Debate, Some Indians Lose Jobs</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>As discussions surrounding the H-1B visa program intensify, some Indian workers are facing job losses due to changing immigration policies and increased scrutiny on work visas.</p><ul><li>Some workers have been laid off as companies reassess their visa sponsorships.</li><li>The debate centers on balancing job opportunities for foreign workers with opportunities for American citizens.</li><li>Concerns arise about the economic impact of such job losses on the Indian community.</li></ul><blockquote>“The current climate against foreign workers is alarming and affects many skilled professionals,” said one industry expert.</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the challenges faced by skilled workers navigating a complicated immigration landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/amid-h-1b-visa-debate-some-indians-lose-jobs/articleshow/117181707.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/amid-h-1b-visa-debate-some-indians-lose-jobs/articleshow/117181707.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires live: 16 dead as Palisades Fire spreads eastward, strong dry winds to worsen - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires Update: President Biden to Discuss Relief Measures</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/USA-BIDEN-AFGHANISTAN-0_1736717631263_1736717661087.JPG" alt="California wildfires live updates: US. President Joe Biden will hold a meeting to discuss the response to the wildfires" title="California wildfires live updates: US. President Joe Biden will hold a meeting to discuss the response to the wildfires">
<figcaption>California wildfires live updates: US. President Joe Biden will hold a meeting to discuss the response to the wildfires</figcaption>
<p>The ongoing wildfires in Los Angeles have resulted in the loss of 16 lives and the destruction of over 12,000 structures. President Biden is set to meet with local and federal officials to coordinate relief operations.</p>
<ul>
<li>16 confirmed deaths and 13 missing individuals due to the wildfires.</li>
<li>Over 12,000 structures have been damaged or destroyed.</li>
<li>Evacuation orders have impacted over 150,000 residents, with more than 700 taking refuge in shelters.</li>
<li>Governor Newsom has deployed 1,000 National Guard members to assist with response efforts.</li>
<li>The National Weather Service has issued warnings for high winds, complicating firefighting efforts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Eaton Fire - 15% contained, Palisades Fire - 11% contained, Hurst Fire - 76% contained.” - Governor Newsom</blockquote>
<p>This disaster emphasizes the urgent need for federal and local cooperation in crisis management and disaster relief as the situation evolves.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:26:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taliban don’t regard women as human beings: Malala - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Taliban don’t regard women as human beings: Malala</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>Malala Yousafzai harshly critiques the Taliban, stating that they do not recognize women as human beings, highlighting issues of gender inequality and oppression in Afghanistan.</p><ul><li>Malala emphasizes the need for global awareness and action regarding women's rights in Taliban-controlled regions.</li><li>She urges world leaders to take a stand against the oppression of women and girls.</li><li>The statement comes amid ongoing reports of human rights violations against women in Afghanistan.</li></ul><blockquote>“We must stand with the women of Afghanistan, who are fighting for their rights and dignity.”</blockquote><p>This statement reflects ongoing concerns surrounding women's rights under Taliban rule and the call for international support.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/taliban-dont-regard-women-as-human-beings-malala/articleshow/117181022.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/taliban-dont-regard-women-as-human-beings-malala/articleshow/117181022.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK PM Keir Starmer under pressure to sack Hasina’s niece Tulip Siddiq - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UK PM Keir Starmer under pressure to sack Hasina’s niece Tulip Siddiq</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source]</p><p>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer is facing intense pressure to remove Tulip Siddiq, a member of Parliament and niece of Bangladesh’s Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, from her position. This comes as various factions within the Labour Party voice their concerns about Siddiq's connections and political stance.</p><ul><li>Starmer’s leadership is being scrutinized in light of Siddiq's affiliations.</li><li>Concerns raised about the implications of her ties to international politics.</li><li>Possible repercussions for the Labour Party if action is not taken.</li></ul><blockquote>“The leadership must address this issue decisively,” said a party insider.</blockquote><p>In summary, the situation presents a significant challenge for Starmer as he navigates party dynamics and public perception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/uk-pm-keir-starmer-under-pressure-to-sack-hasinas-niece-tulip-siddiq/articleshow/117180871.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/uk-pm-keir-starmer-under-pressure-to-sack-hasinas-niece-tulip-siddiq/articleshow/117180871.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tawang walks in solidarity with Tibet earthquake victims - The Arunachal Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tawang Marches in Support of Tibet Earthquake Victims</h1><p><strong>Date: 12 Jan</strong> | <strong>Source: Arunachal Times</strong></p><img src="https://arunachaltimes.in/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Tawang-walks-in-solidarity-with-Tibet-earthquake-victims.webp" alt="Tawang walks in solidarity with Tibet earthquake victims"><figcaption>Tawang walks in solidarity with Tibet earthquake victims</figcaption><p>Thousands in Tawang participated in a candlelight march to support the victims of the recent earthquake in Tibet, organized by local leaders.</p><ul><li>Thousands of participants, including lamas and students, joined the candlelight march.</li><li>The march was initiated by local MLA Namgey Tsering to honor earthquake victims.</li><li>The earthquake occurred on 7 January, affecting over 126 people and leaving many injured and homeless.</li><li>The event highlighted community solidarity and included prayers for the victims at a local monastery.</li><li>Candlelight march started from Tawang monastery and ended at Masang Dungyur Mani in Old Market.</li></ul><blockquote>“We offered condolences to those who lost their lives and prayed for the wellbeing of the injured and the homeless.” - Namgey Tsering</blockquote><p>The community's response reflects a strong sense of solidarity and support for Tibetans affected by the disaster, emphasizing the importance of compassion in times of crisis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://arunachaltimes.in/index.php/2025/01/13/tawang-walks-in-solidarity-with-tibet-earthquake-victims/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arunachaltimes.in/index.php/2025/01/13/tawang-walks-in-solidarity-with-tibet-earthquake-victims/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:50:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Greenland PM Ready To Speak To Trump, Denmark Sends Private Messages To US President-Elect - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Greenland PM Ready To Speak To Trump, Denmark Sends Private Messages To US President-Elect</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Amid Greenland PM Mute Egede expressing willingness to speak to Donald Trump, it was also reported that the Danish government sent private messages to the US President-elect regarding the security of the island. (IMAGE: REUTERS/NASA)" title="Amid Greenland PM Mute Egede expressing willingness to speak to Donald Trump, it was also reported that the Danish government sent private messages to the US President-elect regarding the security of the island. (IMAGE: REUTERS/NASA)" />
<figcaption>Amid Greenland PM Mute Egede expressing willingness to speak to Donald Trump, it was also reported that the Danish government sent private messages to the US President-elect regarding the security of the island. (IMAGE: REUTERS/NASA)</figcaption>
<p>Denmark has sent private messages to US President-elect Donald Trump's team, expressing a willingness to discuss boosting security in Greenland amidst recent comments from Greenland's Prime Minister Mute Egede about dialogue with Trump.</p>
<ul>
<li>Denmark is willing to discuss increasing US military presence in Greenland.</li>
<li>Greenland PM Mute Egede is open to speaking with Trump regarding security concerns.</li>
<li>Trump's comments on controlling Greenland reflect a strategic interest in the resource-rich island.</li>
<li>Greenland is a self-governing territory of Denmark, aiming for greater autonomy and independence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We have a desire for independence, a desire to be the master of our own house … This is something everyone should respect.” - Mute Egede</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing dialogue highlights significant geopolitical interests and the aspirations for greater autonomy of Greenland.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/greenland-pm-ready-to-speak-to-trump-denmark-sends-private-messages-to-us-president-elect-9186082.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/greenland-pm-ready-to-speak-to-trump-denmark-sends-private-messages-to-us-president-elect-9186082.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:32:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[President Biden and Israeli PM Netanyahu discuss ceasefire, hostage deal: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden and Netanyahu Discuss Ceasefire and Hostage Release</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 13, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/-LEBANON-CONFLICT-POLITICS-B_1736704488180_1736704488418.jpg" alt="President Biden and PM Netanyahu discussed a ceasefire deal involving the Gaza conflict(Jim Watson/AFP)"><figcaption>President Biden and PM Netanyahu discussed a ceasefire deal involving the Gaza conflict(Jim Watson/AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>US President Joe Biden and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu discussed a potential ceasefire and hostage release deal in Gaza amid ongoing negotiations.</p><ul><li>Biden and Netanyahu spoke during a phone call regarding a ceasefire deal being mediated in Doha.</li><li>National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan indicated that they are "very close" to reaching a deal.</li><li>Outgoing President Biden is receiving regular updates about the talks and aims to use remaining days in office to finalize the agreement.</li><li>Roughly 100 hostages are currently held by Hamas, and over 46,000 people have reportedly died in Gaza, according to health ministry statistics.</li><li>Future negotiations may involve perspectives from the incoming Trump administration, which promises a new approach to Middle East peace.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are still determined to use every day we have in office to get this done...” - Jake Sullivan</blockquote><p>The discussion highlights the urgency of addressing the hostages and the humanitarian crisis in Gaza, even as the political landscape shifts with the imminent transition in the US administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/president-biden-and-israeli-pm-netanyahu-discuss-ceasefire-hostage-deal-report-101736704157514.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/president-biden-and-israeli-pm-netanyahu-discuss-ceasefire-hostage-deal-report-101736704157514.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump stuns netizens by giving hilarious twist to his viral moment with Barack Obama: 'Elite level trolling' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Stuns Netizens by Giving Hilarious Twist to His Viral Moment with Barack Obama: 'Elite Level Trolling'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/US-STATE-FUNERAL-HELD-IN-WASHINGTON-DC-FOR-FORMER-_1736617472617_1736704410047.jpg" alt="Donald Trump, Obama and a number of other former US leaders, such as Mike Pence, Bill Clinton, and George W. Bush, were seated close to each other at Carter's funeral.(Getty Images via AFP)" title="Donald Trump, Obama and a number of other former US leaders, such as Mike Pence, Bill Clinton, and George W. Bush, were seated close to each other at Carter's funeral.(Getty Images via AFP)"><figcaption>Donald Trump, Obama and a number of other former US leaders, such as Mike Pence, Bill Clinton, and George W. Bush, were seated close to each other at Carter's funeral.(Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>Donald Trump took a hilarious dig at former President Barack Obama during their viral interaction at ex-President Jimmy Carter’s state funeral.</p><ul><li>The video of Trump and Obama at Carter's funeral became a viral sensation, igniting discussions on social media.</li><li>Trump humorously responded to speculation about their conversation by editing the clip with humorous voiceovers.</li><li>Comedians pointed out the irony of their past criticisms and the camaraderie displayed at the event.</li><li>Netizens expressed their reactions, praising Trump's antics as 'elite level trolling.'</li></ul><blockquote>“Elite level trolling,” wrote one user in response to Trump’s video.</blockquote><p>Trump’s playful interaction with Obama showcases a unique and humor-filled side of political rivalries, drawing both laughter and engagement from the public.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-stuns-netizens-by-giving-hilarious-twist-to-his-viral-moment-with-barack-obama-elite-level-trolling-101736701893924.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-stuns-netizens-by-giving-hilarious-twist-to-his-viral-moment-with-barack-obama-elite-level-trolling-101736701893924.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:57:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump likes this version of viral lip-reading where Obama calls Kamala Harris 'horrendous' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump likes this version of viral lip-reading where Obama calls Kamala Harris 'horrendous'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 12, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a humorous twist, former President Donald Trump shared a viral lip-reading video where President Obama seemingly refers to Kamala Harris as 'horrendous'. The video has sparked various reactions from netizens and political commentators alike.</p><ul><li>The video showcases a creative lip-reading interpretation of a conversation between Obama and Harris.</li><li>Trump found the video particularly amusing, sharing it with his followers on social media.</li><li>The incident highlights ongoing political dynamics and discourse surrounding prominent figures like Harris and Obama.</li></ul><blockquote>"This video is hilarious and perfectly points out the absurdity in today's politics!" - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>This viral moment reflects the intersection of humor and political commentary, showcasing how social media continues to shape public perceptions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-likes-this-version-of-viral-lip-reading-where-obama-calls-kamala-harris-horrendous/articleshow/117179288.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-likes-this-version-of-viral-lip-reading-where-obama-calls-kamala-harris-horrendous/articleshow/117179288.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires can expand due to 80 kmph winds: 'Dangerous, strong ' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-can-expand-due-to-80-kmph-winds-dangerous-strong-101736701915580.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-can-expand-due-to-80-kmph-winds-dangerous-strong-101736701915580.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:19:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia calls for Syria sanctions to be lifted - Arab News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saudi Arabia Calls for Lifting Sanctions on Syria</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Sunday, Date Unknown - <strong>Source:</strong> Arab News</p><p>Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Faisal bin Farhan urges for the lifting of sanctions on Syria during a press briefing, emphasizing that these restrictions hinder the country’s rebuilding and development.</p><ul><li>Prince Faisal highlights the importance of lifting both unilateral and international sanctions.</li><li>The Riyadh meeting on Syria included representatives from various nations including the UK and US.</li><li>Positive steps by the new Syrian administration were acknowledged, focusing on dialogue and combating terrorism.</li><li>Humanitarian and economic support is essential for Syria's stability and the return of refugees.</li><li>EU officials discussed the potential easing of sanctions based on Syrian administration's progress.</li></ul><blockquote>Kaja Kallas, EU commissioner for foreign affairs, stated, “The EU is prepared to take further steps if progress is positive, but could also reverse course if it is not.”</blockquote><p>Saudi Arabia remains committed to supporting Syria and calls for international collaboration in aiding the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.arabnews.com/node/2586115/saudi-arabia</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.arabnews.com/node/2586115/saudi-arabia</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:54:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is JD Vance not on the same page with Trump on pardoning Jan 6 rioters? 'A little bit of gray area' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JD Vance's Position on Pardoning January 6 Rioters: Inconsistencies with Trump</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In a recent discussion, Senator JD Vance expressed his views on the controversial topic of pardoning individuals involved in the January 6 riots, revealing a divergence from former President Trump's stance.</p><ul><li>Vance acknowledges a 'little bit of gray area' regarding the pardoning issue.</li><li>The senator's comments suggest a complex viewpoint that may not align entirely with Trump's definitive calls for pardons.</li><li>This poses questions about the unity of the Republican party on this issue.</li></ul><blockquote>“There’s a little bit of gray area in terms of figuring out who should get a pardon.”</blockquote><p>This discussion highlights potential rifts within the Republican party, particularly concerning their approach to the events of January 6 and the individuals involved.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/is-jd-vance-not-on-the-same-page-with-trump-on-pardoning-jan-6-rioters-a-little-bit-of-gray-area/articleshow/117178045.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/is-jd-vance-not-on-the-same-page-with-trump-on-pardoning-jan-6-rioters-a-little-bit-of-gray-area/articleshow/117178045.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump to hold call with Putin in coming days? Prez-elect security advisor hints at major development amid Ukraine war - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump to hold call with Putin in coming days? Prez-elect security advisor hints at major development amid Ukraine war</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Mike_1736697222936_1736697226650.jpg' alt='Donald Trump's national security advisor pick Mike Walz(AP)' title='Donald Trump's national security advisor pick Mike Walz(AP)'><figcaption>Donald Trump's national security advisor pick Mike Walz(AP)</figcaption></figure><p>Trump's national security advisor pick, Mike Walz, stated that he expects a call between the US President-elect and Russian President Putin in the coming days and weeks amid ongoing tensions related to the Ukraine war.</p><ul><li>Mike Walz anticipates a call between Trump and Putin soon.</li><li>Trump has made promises to resolve the Russia-Ukraine conflict swiftly.</li><li>Trump indicated that a meeting with Putin is being arranged, which will be closely monitored by Ukraine and its allies.</li><li>Russia's Kremlin spokesperson welcomed Trump's approach to dialogue.</li><li>Critics express skepticism regarding Russia's openness to genuine negotiation.</li></ul><blockquote>“President Putin wants to meet,” Trump stated. “We have to get that war over with. That’s a bloody mess.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the anticipated communication between Trump and Putin could signify a shift in US-Russia relations, especially concerning the Ukraine conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-to-hold-call-with-putin-in-coming-days-prez-elect-security-advisor-hints-at-major-development-amid-ukraine-war-101736695361039.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-to-hold-call-with-putin-in-coming-days-prez-elect-security-advisor-hints-at-major-development-amid-ukraine-war-101736695361039.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:55:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump calls California leaders ‘incompetent’ over fire response - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Criticizes California Officials Over Wildfire Response</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Sunday, September 30, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Dawn</p><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Image related to California wildfires'><figcaption>Trump speaks out on California wildfires</figcaption><p>US President-elect Donald Trump has openly criticized California leaders for their handling of the wildfires devastating the Los Angeles area, calling their response incompetent.</p><ul><li>Trump took to Truth Social to accuse politicians of failing to control the wildfires.</li><li>The wildfires have resulted in the deaths of at least 16 people and displaced 150,000 individuals.</li><li>California's fire infrastructure has been severely tested, with hydrants running dry in affected areas.</li><li>Governor Gavin Newsom has extended an invitation to Trump to visit the sites of devastation.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is one of the worst catastrophes in the history of our Country. They just can’t put out the fires.” – Donald Trump</blockquote><p>Trump's remarks have sparked controversy and raised questions about California's emergency preparedness as the state continues to combat the raging wildfires.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1884727</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1884727</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Say No To Olaf Scholz': Elon Musk Ahead Of Germany's Snap Elections Next Month - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk Calls for Germans to Reject Olaf Scholz Ahead of Elections</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Elon Musk has openly called for German Chancellor Olaf Scholz's resignation (AP Image)" />
<figcaption>Elon Musk has openly called for German Chancellor Olaf Scholz's resignation (AP Image)</figcaption>
<p>Elon Musk has called on German citizens to “say no” to Chancellor Olaf Scholz as the country prepares for snap elections on February 23, following Scholz's nomination by the ruling Social Democrats (SPD).</p>
<ul>
  <li>Musk labeled Scholz as an “incompetent fool” and criticized his government.</li>
  <li>The Tesla CEO has endorsed the far-right Alternative for Germany (AfD) party and its co-leader Alice Weidel.</li>
  <li>He expressed that only the AfD can save Germany, promoting their agenda through social media.</li>
  <li>Scholz has rebuked Musk for interfering in German elections, urging voters to resist external manipulation.</li>
  <li>The German government has publicly condemned Musk's attempts to influence the elections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Sag Nein zu Scholz!” translates to “Say No to Scholz”, emphasizing Musk's call to action.</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming elections have become a focal point for discussions on political integrity and foreign influence in Germany.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/say-no-to-olaf-scholz-elon-musk-ahead-of-germanys-snap-elections-next-month-9186300.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/say-no-to-olaf-scholz-elon-musk-ahead-of-germanys-snap-elections-next-month-9186300.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:56:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Burglary attempt at Kamala Harris' Brentwood home as massive looting reported amid LA fires - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Burglary attempt at Kamala Harris' Brentwood home as massive looting reported amid LA fires</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>Los Angeles Times</p><p>Authorities reported a burglary attempt at the home of Vice President Kamala Harris in Brentwood, coinciding with significant looting incidents in the Los Angeles area as fires rage across the region.</p><ul><li>Burglary attempt at Kamala Harris' residence.</li><li>Widespread looting reported across Los Angeles during ongoing fires.</li><li>Increased police presence in affluent areas.</li><li>Community concerns about safety and property protection.</li></ul><blockquote>“We must remain vigilant as these events unfold.” - Local law enforcement spokesperson</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the interplay between natural disasters and crime rates, raising alarms about public safety during emergency situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/burglary-attempt-at-kamala-harris-brentwood-home-as-massive-looting-reported-amid-la-fires/articleshow/117176517.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/burglary-attempt-at-kamala-harris-brentwood-home-as-massive-looting-reported-amid-la-fires/articleshow/117176517.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadly California wildfires: 16 lives lost, 150,000 displaced, over 5,300 homes gone amidst widespread ch - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/deadly-california-wildfires-16-lives-lost-150000-displaced-over-5300-homes-gone-amidst-widespread-chaos-and-destruction-in-la/articleshow/117176055.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/deadly-california-wildfires-16-lives-lost-150000-displaced-over-5300-homes-gone-amidst-widespread-chaos-and-destruction-in-la/articleshow/117176055.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steve Bannon says he will have 'Elon Musk run out of here by Jan 20': 'I will take this guy down' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Steve Bannon says he will have 'Elon Musk run out of here by Jan 20': 'I will take this guy down'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p>
<p>Steve Bannon has made a controversial statement regarding Elon Musk, claiming he plans to 'run him out' by January 20. This marks a significant escalation in tensions between the two figures.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bannon vowed to displace Musk from his current position.</li>
  <li>The statement reflects underlying political and personal conflicts.</li>
  <li>Public interest is piqued due to the prominence of both individuals.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I will take this guy down.”</blockquote>
<p>This statement highlights Bannon's determination and the potential volatility of their rivalry.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/steve-bannon-says-he-will-have-elon-musk-run-out-of-here-by-jan-20-i-will-take-this-guy-down/articleshow/117175796.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/steve-bannon-says-he-will-have-elon-musk-run-out-of-here-by-jan-20-i-will-take-this-guy-down/articleshow/117175796.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump inauguration guest list: Global leaders, tech giants invited amid VIP passes running low - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump inauguration guest list: Global leaders, tech giants invited amid VIP passes running low</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/12/20241211112438_BeFunky-collage-2024-12-11T165424.810.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Trump" title="Trump" width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>Donald Trump</figcaption>
<p>US President-elect Donald Trump has invited an array of global leaders to his upcoming inauguration ceremony, challenging traditional customs that favor domestic figures.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Invited leaders include Chinese President Xi Jinping (expected to send an envoy), India’s External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar, and several right-wing leaders across the globe.</li>
  <li>Major tech firms such as Meta, Amazon, and OpenAI are financially supporting the inauguration, donating $1 million each.</li>
  <li>The inaugural committee has reportedly raised over $170 million, with expectations to surpass $200 million.</li>
  <li>High-profile tech attendees include CEOs from major companies like Uber and Coinbase, and notable supporters like Elon Musk.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The inaugural committee has already amassed over $170 million.”</blockquote>
<p>This inauguration signifies a notable shift in US foreign policy by its inclusion of global figures, reflecting Trump's ideologically aligned approach.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/donald-trump-inauguration-guest-list-global-leaders-tech-giants-invited-amid-vip-passes-running-low-12908432.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/donald-trump-inauguration-guest-list-global-leaders-tech-giants-invited-amid-vip-passes-running-low-12908432.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:47:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US sanctions on Russian oil to push China, India to seek supply from US, West Asia and Africa - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Sanctions on Russian Oil to Drive China and India Towards New Supply Sources</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><div><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2025/01/Representational-Image-22-2025-01-3f116f3e285f0a173d9a0761be38e802.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="US sanctions on Russian oil to push China, India to seek supply from US, West Asia and Africa" title="US sanctions on Russian oil to push China, India to seek supply from US, West Asia and Africa"><figcaption>Representational Image - Reuters</figcaption></div><p>The article discusses the impact of recent US sanctions on Russian oil exports, which are driving China and India to seek alternative oil supplies from West Asia, Africa, and the Americas.</p><ul><li>New US sanctions on Russia's energy sector announced by the US and UK limit supply to major Russian oil consumers.</li><li>The sanctions will force Chinese independent refiners to reduce their refining output due to limited supply.</li><li>Affected tankers previously transported oil primarily to India and China, redirecting the trade from Europe to Asia.</li><li>Impacts include rising prices and freight costs in the oil market.</li><li>Russian oil exports are expected to be significantly reduced, influencing global oil supply dynamics.</li></ul><blockquote>“These sanctions will significantly reduce the fleet of ships available to deliver crude from Russia in the short term, pushing freight rates higher.” - Matt Wright, Kpler's lead freight analyst.</blockquote><p>The sanctions on Russian oil are prompting China and India to pivot back towards compliant oil markets, seeking supplies from alternative regions like West Asia and the Americas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/world/us-sanctions-on-russian-oil-to-drive-china-india-to-west-asia-africa-and-us-for-supply-13852122.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/world/us-sanctions-on-russian-oil-to-drive-china-india-to-west-asia-africa-and-us-for-supply-13852122.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:43:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Countries With The Best Work-Life Balance - Rediff.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 Countries With The Best Work-Life Balance</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Rediff.com</p>
<img src="https://im.rediff.com/getahead/2025/jan/12--web-story-work-life-balance-1.png" width="720" height="1280" alt="" />
<figcaption>Work-Life Balance in the Best Countries</figcaption>
<p>This article explores the countries that offer the greatest work-life balance, showcasing their benefits and practices that prioritize employee well-being.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>New Zealand:</strong> Offers a superior blend of work and play with extensive parental leave and quality of life.</li>
  <li><strong>Finland:</strong> Provides a shorter flexible work week and emphasizes mental health.</li>
  <li><strong>Australia:</strong> Known for high minimum wages and excellent work-life equilibrium.</li>
  <li><strong>Denmark:</strong> Workers enjoy flexible hours, generous annual leave, and they are often ranked high on happiness scales.</li>
  <li><strong>Norway:</strong> Follows closely behind Denmark with high levels of worker satisfaction and benefits.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Denmark prioritises employee well-being with flexible working hours, ranking second in the Happiness Index.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, these countries exemplify how prioritizing employee well-being leads to happier and more productive societies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQTXN2bWViSXFtSkhpWXlEdF94VU4xdzlsRlc4el9lQjdlN0hZV0lWcExWcTF3dmxMVnhYRDlDdjY5ZHVLN0dLbmt6UGhOdGk2VmhZOEpTQjJZVEpqUzFQdGV4Unowc2ZfTVR1WkJHZFdHVk1jYWZyUEFJM01jbFByQ1lnUjdQay1JLW9ObEloZ0xDUDg3VmxZVlFjejE1U1BZWnhPSGVkMm1nZ9IBqgFBVV95cUxQTXN2bWViSXFtSkhpWXlEdF94VU4xdzlsRlc4el9lQjdlN0hZV0lWcExWcTF3dmxMVnhYRDlDdjY5ZHVLN0dLbmt6UGhOdGk2VmhZOEpTQjJZVEpqUzFQdGV4Unowc2ZfTVR1WkJHZFdHVk1jYWZyUEFJM01jbFByQ1lnUjdQay1JLW9ObEloZ0xDUDg3VmxZVlFjejE1U1BZWnhPSGVkMm1nZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxQTXN2bWViSXFtSkhpWXlEdF94VU4xdzlsRlc4el9lQjdlN0hZV0lWcExWcTF3dmxMVnhYRDlDdjY5ZHVLN0dLbmt6UGhOdGk2VmhZOEpTQjJZVEpqUzFQdGV4Unowc2ZfTVR1WkJHZFdHVk1jYWZyUEFJM01jbFByQ1lnUjdQay1JLW9ObEloZ0xDUDg3VmxZVlFjejE1U1BZWnhPSGVkMm1nZ9IBqgFBVV95cUxQTXN2bWViSXFtSkhpWXlEdF94VU4xdzlsRlc4el9lQjdlN0hZV0lWcExWcTF3dmxMVnhYRDlDdjY5ZHVLN0dLbmt6UGhOdGk2VmhZOEpTQjJZVEpqUzFQdGV4Unowc2ZfTVR1WkJHZFdHVk1jYWZyUEFJM01jbFByQ1lnUjdQay1JLW9ObEloZ0xDUDg3VmxZVlFjejE1U1BZWnhPSGVkMm1nZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:40:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US-China 6th-Gen Race: Designed To Keep U.S. Air Force Out Of Western Pacific, USAF Speaks On New-Age Chinese Threats - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US-China 6th-Gen Race: Designed To Keep U.S. Air Force Out Of Western Pacific, USAF Speaks On New-Age Chinese Threats</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown, <strong>Source:</strong> EurAsian Times</p>
<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/b-21.jpg" alt="B-21 raider" width="696" height="392"><figcaption>B-21 raider</figcaption></figure>
<p>In a recent interview, USAF Secretary Frank Kendall stated that China's new combat aircraft will not alter the USAF's strategic plans or the Next Generation Air Dominance (NGAD) program, which has faced delays and funding issues.</p>
<ul>
<li>USAF Secretary Frank Kendall asserts that new Chinese military capabilities do not change US Air Force plans.</li>
<li>China's sixth-generation fighters were showcased on December 26, with prototypes designated as Chengdu J-36 and Shenyang J-XX/J-50.</li>
<li>The NGAD program is currently on hold due to high costs and strategic reevaluations.</li>
<li>The B-21 Raider is being prioritized, with its first flight occurring in November 2023.</li>
<li>Comparison with China's military advances highlight a need for US adaptation and resource allocation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“They’re working aggressively to build a military designed to keep the U.S. out of the Western Pacific...they have more ambitions than even that.” - Frank Kendall</blockquote>
<p>Overall, while the NGAD is postponed, both the US and China continue to advance their military capabilities in preparation for future conflicts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/chinas-new-warplanes-designed-to-keep/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/chinas-new-warplanes-designed-to-keep/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:13:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NGAD: Designed To Keep U.S. Air Force Out Of Western Pacific, USAF Speaks On New-Age Chinese Aircraft - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US-China 6th-Gen Race: Designed To Keep U.S. Air Force Out Of Western Pacific, USAF Speaks On New-Age Chinese Threats</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> EurAsian Times</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/b-21.jpg" alt="B-21 raider" width="696" height="392">
<figcaption>B-21 raider</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The article discusses USAF Secretary Frank Kendall's remarks regarding China's advancements in military technology, particularly their sixth-generation fighter jets and the implications for U.S. defense strategies.</p>
<ul>
<li>China's new combat aircraft have not impacted USAF's plans for the Next Generation Air Dominance (NGAD) program.</li>
<li>Kendall emphasizes continued U.S. focus on military modernization and strategic priorities despite Chinese developments.</li>
<li>China's sixth-generation fighters, including the Chengdu J-36 and Shenyang J-XX, represent a significant leap in military capabilities.</li>
<li>The U.S. NGAD program has faced delays and cost concerns, with a focus on other strategic areas.</li>
<li>The B-21 Raider is prioritized for the USAF, with expected entry into service in the mid-2020s.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“They’re working aggressively to build a military designed to keep the U.S. out of the Western Pacific.” - Frank Kendall</blockquote>
<p>This article highlights the competitive military developments between the U.S. and China, showcasing the strategic challenges faced by the USAF.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/chinas-new-warplanes-designed-to-keep/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/chinas-new-warplanes-designed-to-keep/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:13:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Russian airport scene goes viral as woman mistakes conveyor belt for boarding path - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Viral Video of Woman Mistakenly Riding Luggage Conveyor Belt at Russian Airport</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 9, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> WION</p><p>A viral video shows an unexpected incident at a Russian airport where a woman mistook a luggage conveyor belt for the boarding path to her plane, resulting in a confusing 10-minute ride.</p><ul><li>The event took place at an airport in Vladikavkaz, Russia.</li><li>A senior citizen, dressed in a mustard yellow coat and pink hat, mistakenly stepped onto the conveyor belt.</li><li>She lost her balance and was carried through the facility, later being rescued by airport staff.</li><li>The incident has garnered widespread attention on social media, generating mixed reactions among viewers.</li></ul><blockquote>A family from Vladikavkaz, Russia, went to the airport to travel. While they were at the baggage area, their grandmother thought the conveyor belt for luggage was the way to the airplane. So, she got on it and went along for a 10-minute ride. — Ibra ❄️ (@IbraHasan_) January 9, 2025</blockquote><p>Fortunately, the elderly woman was not seriously injured following her unusual journey.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/world/watch-russian-airport-scene-goes-viral-as-woman-mistakes-conveyor-belt-for-boarding-path-8613035</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/world/watch-russian-airport-scene-goes-viral-as-woman-mistakes-conveyor-belt-for-boarding-path-8613035</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 13:06:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Universities In Germany for Free Education - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Best Universities In Germany for Free Education</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> 12 Jan 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<img src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/gws/ms/best-universities-in-germany-for-free-education/assets/16.jpeg?1736685736" alt="Best Universities In Germany" />
<figcaption>Image: Unsplash</figcaption>
<p>Germany is renowned for its public universities that offer tuition-free Bachelor’s and Master’s programs, making higher education accessible to many international students.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Public universities in Germany typically charge no tuition for international and local students.</li>
  <li>The University of Cologne provides diverse programs with minimal semester contributions.</li>
  <li>RWTH Aachen University is a leader in engineering and technology education.</li>
  <li>The University of Hamburg has a vibrant academic environment and a wide range of programs.</li>
  <li>The Free University of Berlin is noted for its strong programs in humanities and social sciences.</li>
  <li>The University of Bonn offers top-tier programs in various fields without tuition fees.</li>
  <li>Many universities feature English-taught programs for international students.</li>
  <li>Students only pay a small semester fee covering administrative costs and transport.</li>
  <li>German universities emphasize innovation and research opportunities for students.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Most public universities in Germany offer tuition-free Bachelor's and Master's programs, making them ideal for affordable higher education.”</blockquote>
<p>This accessibility to higher education in Germany exemplifies a commitment to inclusivity and student support, emphasizing the value placed on education in society.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/education/webstories/best-universities-in-germany-for-free-education-30811</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/education/webstories/best-universities-in-germany-for-free-education-30811</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:42:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Wants To Buy Greenland: Here's What It Could Cost The US - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-wants-to-buy-greenland-heres-what-it-could-cost-the-us-9186373.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-wants-to-buy-greenland-heres-what-it-could-cost-the-us-9186373.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:17:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why these 14 locations are the most forbidden on Earth - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why These 14 Locations are the Most Forbidden on Earth</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p>
<img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=640&amp;height=360" alt="Forbidden locations" />
<figcaption>Forbidden locations on Earth</figcaption>
<p>This article explores some of the most restricted and inaccessible places around the world. These destinations are often off-limits due to their secrets, dangers, or the need to protect them from human interference.</p>
<ul>
<li>North Sentinel Island, India - Home to the hostile Sentinelese tribe.</li>
<li>Svalbard Global Seed Vault, Norway - A secure facility preserving plant seeds.</li>
<li>Coca-Cola Recipe Vault, USA - The closely guarded Coca-Cola formula.</li>
<li>Vatican Secret Archives, Vatican City - Contains valuable and sensitive documents.</li>
<li>Lascaux Caves, France - Prehistoric art at risk from visitor damage.</li>
<li>Snake Island, Brazil - Home to a deadly snake species, accessible only to scientists.</li>
<li>Area 51, USA - A military site surrounded by secrecy and conspiracy theories.</li>
<li>Tomb of Qin Shi Huang, China - Tomb preserved for artifact integrity.</li>
<li>Surtsey Island, Iceland - A developing ecosystem, off-limits to tourists.</li>
<li>Ise Grand Shrine, Japan - A sacred site only accessible to the imperial family.</li>
<li>North Brother Island, USA - A protected historical site and bird sanctuary.</li>
<li>Heard Island, Australia - A pristine environment reserved for scientific research.</li>
<li>Dulce Base, USA - Subject of conspiracy theories and kept secret.</li>
<li>Mount Kailash, Tibet - A sacred site deemed off-limits for climbers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Many of these locations hold invaluable cultural, environmental, or historical significance.”</blockquote>
<p>Some of the world's most forbidden places remain untouched, preserving their secrets and unique ecosystems for generations to come.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/travel/destinations/mount-kailash-area-51-coca-cola-recipe-vault-14-most-forbidden-locations-on-earth-19538725.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/photos/travel/destinations/mount-kailash-area-51-coca-cola-recipe-vault-14-most-forbidden-locations-on-earth-19538725.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 11:28:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>