<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 16:24:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 16:24:17 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Henley Passport Rankings 2025: India Goes Up, Pakistan Falls Behind Somalia And Bangladesh - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Henley Passport Rankings 2025: India Goes Up, Pakistan Falls Behind Somalia And Bangladesh</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The strength of a country's passport is determined by how many countries its holders can visit without a visa or with a visa on arrival. (Representative/Shutterstock)"><figcaption>The strength of a country's passport is determined by how many countries its holders can visit without a visa or with a visa on arrival. (Representative/Shutterstock)</figcaption><p>India's passport has improved in the global rankings, moving from 85th in 2024 to 80th in 2025, while Pakistan's ranking has dropped to 103rd, below Somalia and Bangladesh.</p><ul><li>India's passport ranking rose from 85th in 2024 to 80th in 2025.</li><li>Pakistan's passport ranking fell from 101st in 2024 to 103rd in 2025.</li><li>Singapore maintains the top position as the world's most powerful passport, allowing visa-free entry to 195 countries.</li><li>Indian passport holders can now travel visa-free to 62 countries, an increase from 57.</li><li>Pakistan passport holders can access 34 countries without requiring prior visas.</li></ul><blockquote>“India’s passport holders can now travel visa-free to 62 countries, an increase from 57.”</blockquote><p>The rankings indicate rising mobility for Indian citizens compared to regional counterparts, highlighting significant changes in passport strength.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/henley-passport-rankings-2025-india-goes-up-pakistan-falls-behind-somalia-and-bangladesh-ws-ab-9182945.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/henley-passport-rankings-2025-india-goes-up-pakistan-falls-behind-somalia-and-bangladesh-ws-ab-9182945.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 15:08:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Firefighters battle devastating Los Angeles wildfires as winds calm somewhat - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Firefighters Tackle Major Wildfires in Los Angeles as Winds Subside</h1><p><strong>Published on January 09, 2025 by The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/jw68s/article69079443.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/2025-01-09T040042Z_1429762339_RC2T5CANOE5T_RTRMADP_3_CALIFORNIA-WILDFIRES.JPG" alt="" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Firefighters in action battling the wildfires.</figcaption><p>Firefighters in Los Angeles are working tirelessly to control multiple wildfires that have resulted in five fatalities and widespread destruction across communities.</p><ul><li>The fires have affected an area from the Pacific Coast to Pasadena, leading to thousands of evacuations.</li><li>Calmer winds today have provided an opportunity for firefighters to combat the blazes.</li><li>Nearly 2,000 structures, including homes and businesses, have been destroyed, and evacuation orders are in place for over 130,000 people.</li><li>The Palisades Fire is reported to be the most destructive wildfire in Los Angeles history.</li><li>Notable celebrities, including Mandy Moore and Billy Crystal, have lost their homes.</li></ul><blockquote>“When you look at the grand scheme of things, as long as your family is well and everyone’s alive, you’re still winning, right?” - Teddy Leonard, owner of Reel Inn in Malibu.</blockquote><p>The wildfires highlight the severe impact of climate change on California's fire season, as conditions continue to worsen.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/firefighters-battle-devastating-los-angeles-wildfires-as-winds-calm-somewhat/article69081287.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/firefighters-battle-devastating-los-angeles-wildfires-as-winds-calm-somewhat/article69081287.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 14:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Satellite images show wildfires raging unchecked in Los Angeles - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Satellite images show wildfires raging unchecked in Los Angeles</h1><p><strong>Jan 09, 2025</strong> | <strong>Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/US-FIRE-CALIFORNIA-2_1736429208379_1736429237471.jpg" alt="Satellite image showing homes and buildings burning on East Altadena Drive during the Eaton Fire in Altadena, California.(AFP)"><figcaption>Satellite image showing homes and buildings burning on East Altadena Drive during the Eaton Fire in Altadena, California.(AFP)</figcaption><p>Wildfires are raging across Los Angeles as firefighters struggle to put out the blazes three days after they began. Near 2,000 buildings have been affected, with 130,000 residents evacuated. Strong winds have exacerbated the situation.</p><ul><li>Over 1,000 structures destroyed; five fatalities reported.</li><li>Evacuations triggered in smoke-filled neighborhoods.</li><li>Firefighters face challenges due to ferocious winds.</li></ul><blockquote>“Scenes of flames were everywhere as many areas continued to burn.”</blockquote><p>The intense wildfires disrupting lives in Los Angeles highlight the rising threat of such disasters in urban settings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-satellite-images-fire-hollywood-california-burning-101736428509518.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-satellite-images-fire-hollywood-california-burning-101736428509518.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 13:47:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lebanon’s new president promises to rebuild what ‘Israel has destroyed’ - Arab News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lebanon’s new president promises to rebuild what ‘Israel has destroyed’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Arab News</p><p>Newly elected Lebanese president Joseph Aoun has vowed to reconstruct areas destroyed by Israel and address key regional issues, including the Palestinian plight.</p><ul><li>Aoun pledges to remove Israeli occupation and reconstruct damage in southern Lebanon and Beirut.</li><li>He rejects the settlement of Palestinians, affirming their right to return.</li><li>The election was marked by political tension, with Aoun securing the presidency after multiple voting rounds.</li><li>Lebanon has been without a president since October 2022, complicating governance.</li><li>International pressure has mounted to enhance stability in Lebanon amidst ongoing regional conflicts.</li></ul><blockquote>“I promise to reconstruct what Israel destroyed in the south and Beirut’s southern suburbs.”</blockquote><p>The new president faces significant challenges, including significant economic struggles and rebuilding efforts following recent conflicts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.arabnews.com/node/2585758/middle-east</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.arabnews.com/node/2585758/middle-east</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 13:18:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CPP Inflation Increase 2025 - Here's Everything You Need to Know about CPP Increase with Inflation - BSEB Inter Org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CPP Inflation Increase 2025 - Here's Everything You Need to Know about CPP Increase with Inflation</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<div>
  <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://bsebinter.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/CPP-Inflation-Increase-2025-Heres-Everything-You-Need-to-Know-about-CPP-Increase-with-Inflation-1024x683.jpg" alt="CPP Inflation Increase 2025 - Here's Everything You Need to Know about CPP Increase with Inflation">
  <figcaption>CPP Inflation Increase 2025 - Here's Everything You Need to Know about CPP Increase with Inflation</figcaption>
</div>
<p>The Canada Pension Plan (CPP) benefits increase annually based on inflation rates. This year, seniors can expect a rise in their CPP payments due to high inflation rates that have impact on living costs.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The CPP payments are set to increase due to inflation adjustments in January 2025.</li>
  <li>Estimates suggest a 3% rise in monthly payments.</li>
  <li>All recipients over 60, disabled individuals, and survivors of deceased contributors will benefit from this increase.</li>
  <li>The CPP contribution rate has seen increases aimed at enhancing benefits over time.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The time has passed and this year will see an increase in the maximum pensionable earnings, which will eventually reach $81,200.”</blockquote>
<p>This adjustment aims to protect retirees' purchasing power and reflect real cost of living changes. The final calculations are yet to be made, with general expectations of a 3% increase in light of the previous year's inflation rates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bsebinter.org/cpp-inflation-increase-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bsebinter.org/cpp-inflation-increase-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 13:17:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[F-15EX ‘Nightmare’ For Chinese Navy! U.S. Set To Integrate Long-Range Anti-Ship Missile On World’s Fastest Jet - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>F-15EX 'Nightmare' For Chinese Navy! U.S. Set To Integrate Long-Range Anti-Ship Missile On World's Fastest Jet</h1><p><strong>Date: January 8, 2024 | Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/mfc-180607-n-uz648-025-st-02.jpg.pc-adaptive.1280.medium.jpg" alt="LRASM in Action" width="1280" height="750"><figcaption>LRASM in Action. Image Credits Lockheed Martin.</figcaption></figure><p>The US Air Force is preparing to equip its F-15E and F-15EX fighter jets with the AGM-158C Long Range Anti-Ship Missile (LRASM), enhancing its maritime strike capabilities against an expanding Chinese Navy.</p><ul><li>The AGM-158C missile has a range of up to 600 miles.</li><li>Currently deployed on F/A-18E/F Super Hornets and B-1 bombers, its integration into the F-15 lineup is upcoming.</li><li>The missile is designed for stealth and precision against maritime threats.</li><li>This upgrade marks a significant enhancement in U.S. military capabilities in the Pacific region.</li></ul><blockquote>“Stand-off weapons like the LRASM would allow U.S. aircraft to strike enemy warships from greater distances, minimizing their exposure to hostile air defenses.”</blockquote><p>This integration reflects the U.S. military's focus on countering China’s growing naval power, ensuring readiness for potential conflicts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/f-15-to-enhance-naval-power-anti-ship-missiles/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/f-15-to-enhance-naval-power-anti-ship-missiles/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 12:48:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lebanon parliament elects army chief Joseph Aoun as president - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/9/lebanon-parliament-elects-army-chief-joseph-aoun-as-president</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/9/lebanon-parliament-elects-army-chief-joseph-aoun-as-president</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 12:45:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Millionaire CEO sparks outrage over hiring private firefighters during LA wildfire crisis - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Millionaire CEO Sparks Outrage for Hiring Private Firefighters During LA Wildfire Crisis</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 09, 2025 06:05 PM IST<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/kk_1736425468598_1736425474907.jpg" alt="Keith Wasserman deleted the post after backlash. (X/@KeithWasserman)"><figcaption>Keith Wasserman deleted the post after backlash. (X/@KeithWasserman)</figcaption><p>Amid a wildfire crisis in Los Angeles, CEO Keith Wasserman faced backlash after offering to pay for private firefighters to protect his home while many others suffered losses.</p><ul><li>Wasserman made the controversial offer during the Palisades wildfire.</li><li>His plea, seen over a million times, sparked criticism for prioritizing personal property over community safety.</li><li>Critics highlighted the ethical implications of diverting resources to wealthy individuals amidst a crisis.</li><li>The wildfires have claimed at least five lives and forced thousands to evacuate, impacting over 27,000 acres.</li></ul><blockquote>“Incredible nerve… Incredibly tone deaf.” – Sam Vance</blockquote><blockquote>“A tone-deaf, public display of ‘rich privilege’ in a time of community crisis is a curious choice.” – Manish Kapoor</blockquote><p>The incident highlights the tension between privilege and community responsibility during emergencies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/millionaire-ceo-sparks-outrage-over-hiring-private-firefighters-during-la-wildfire-crisis-101736425368206.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/millionaire-ceo-sparks-outrage-over-hiring-private-firefighters-during-la-wildfire-crisis-101736425368206.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 12:35:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet Japan's 'do nothing' guy: Once fired for being idle, now gets paid millions for it - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/meet-japans-do-nothing-guy-once-fired-for-being-idle-now-gets-paid-millions-for-it-101736424587840.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/meet-japans-do-nothing-guy-once-fired-for-being-idle-now-gets-paid-millions-for-it-101736424587840.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 12:26:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India slips 5 spots in list of world's most powerful passports; Singapore leads - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-slips-5-spots-in-list-of-worlds-most-powerful-passports-singapore-leads-101736415586962.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/india-slips-5-spots-in-list-of-worlds-most-powerful-passports-singapore-leads-101736415586962.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 10:54:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In rare interview, Joe Biden says he could have defeated Donald Trump - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>In rare interview, Joe Biden says he could have defeated Donald Trump</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 9, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/5oj13o/article69080297.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2025-01-08T201259Z_1926268257_RC2S5CAFWB0O_RTRMADP_3_USA-BIDEN.JPG" alt="U.S. President Joe Biden gestures before boarding Air Force One, in Los Angeles, California" title="U.S. President Joe Biden gestures before boarding Air Force One, in Los Angeles, California"><figcaption>U.S. President Joe Biden gestures before boarding Air Force One, in Los Angeles, California | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>In a rare interview, President Joe Biden revealed he believes he could have won reelection against Donald Trump, despite being uncertain about serving another full term.</p><ul><li>Biden expressed confidence in possibly winning the presidential race, citing unspecified polling.</li><li>He acknowledged his age might have influenced his decision to not seek reelection.</li><li>Discussed his regrets over misinformation and infrastructure planning during his presidency.</li><li>Confirmed he is considering preemptive pardons for individuals at risk due to Trump’s policies.</li><li>Stressed his desired legacy of restoring the economy and reestablishing U.S. leadership globally.</li></ul><blockquote>“I really thought I had the best chance of beating him... But I also wasn't looking to be president when I was 85 years old, 86 years old.” - Joe Biden</blockquote><p>The interview sheds light on Biden's reflections as he prepares to leave office, along with his aspirations for how he will be remembered.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/in-rare-interview-joe-biden-says-he-could-have-defeated-donald-trump/article69080283.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/in-rare-interview-joe-biden-says-he-could-have-defeated-donald-trump/article69080283.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 10:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles wildfire may have caused damage worth $57 billion, one of US' costliest disaster: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Los Angeles Wildfire May Have Caused Damage Worth $57 Billion, One of US' Costliest Disasters: Report</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-81_1736417487495_1736417558755.jpg" alt="The Getty Villa art museum is threatened by the flames of the wind-driven Palisades Fire in Pacific Palisades, California.(AFP)" title="The Getty Villa art museum is threatened by the flames of the wind-driven Palisades Fire in Pacific Palisades, California.(AFP)">
<figcaption>The Getty Villa art museum is threatened by the flames of the wind-driven Palisades Fire in Pacific Palisades, California.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>The Los Angeles wildfire is potentially one of the most expensive natural disasters in US history, with damages estimated between $52 billion and $57 billion. Driven by hurricane-force winds, the fires are affecting wealthy neighborhoods and are expected to continue causing significant damage.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The wildfire has a potential cost of up to $57 billion, making it one of the costliest disasters.</li>
  <li>It threatens high-value areas around Santa Monica and Malibu.</li>
  <li>At least five fatalities and over 1,000 structures have been destroyed.</li>
  <li>The wildfires are likely to have long-term health effects and impact the tourism sector.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is already one of the worst wildfires in California history,” said Jonathan Porter, AccuWeather’s chief meteorologist.</blockquote>
<p>As the wildfires rage on, the potential for further devastation looms, stressing the urgency for firefighting efforts and community preparedness.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-may-have-caused-damage-worth-57-billion-one-of-us-costliest-disaster-report-101736417300952.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-may-have-caused-damage-worth-57-billion-one-of-us-costliest-disaster-report-101736417300952.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 10:15:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles wildfires escalate to $57 billion disaster, threatening homes, health, and economy - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Los Angeles wildfires escalate to $57 billion disaster, threatening homes, health, and economy</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Local News Network</p><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Wildfire damage in Los Angeles'><figcaption>Wildfire damage caused by recent fires in Los Angeles.</figcaption><p>The wildfires in Los Angeles have escalated significantly, resulting in damage estimated at $57 billion, threatening the lives and livelihoods of many residents. The situation poses serious risks to health and the economy.</p><ul><li>Wildfires have caused extensive damage across the greater Los Angeles area.</li><li>The disaster is projected to cost approximately $57 billion in recovery efforts.</li><li>Local residents are facing immediate threats to their homes and health due to the smoke and flames.</li><li>The economic impact will be felt for years to come, affecting various sectors.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is one of the worst wildfire seasons we have seen in decades,” said a local fire chief.</blockquote><p>The escalating wildfires in Los Angeles are a stark reminder of the growing threat posed by climate change and the need for effective disaster response strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/los-angeles-wildfires-escalate-to-57-billion-disaster-threatening-homes-health-and-economy/articleshow/117082093.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/los-angeles-wildfires-escalate-to-57-billion-disaster-threatening-homes-health-and-economy/articleshow/117082093.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 10:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's Pakistani, not Asian, grooming gangs at work. Saying what UK won't - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>It's Pakistani, not Asian, grooming gangs at work. Saying what UK won't</h1><p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 9, 2025 | <strong>Published By:</strong> Sushim Mukul</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/grooming-gang-092632843-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=rB9Pg9UC_jz0HGheqZ09ghFN_tqgzHuQ&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="grooming gang" title="The UK in 2022 saw protests demanding justice for the victims of grooming gangs and accountability from authorities for years of systemic failures and inaction."><figcaption>The UK in 2022 saw protests demanding justice for the victims of grooming gangs and accountability from authorities for years of systemic failures and inaction. (Image: Getty)</figcaption><p>The article discusses the misleading terminology surrounding the grooming gangs in the UK, highlighting the involvement of Pakistani-origin men in these heinous crimes against young white girls. It calls for the term 'Asian grooming gangs' to be replaced with 'Pakistani grooming gangs' to accurately reflect the ethnic background of the perpetrators.</p><ul><li>The term 'Asian grooming gangs' stigmatizes the broader Asian community.</li><li>Elon Musk supports using 'Pakistani' instead of 'Asian' in relation to these grooming gangs.</li><li>The scale of abuse has been alarming, with reports indicating thousands of victims.</li><li>There have been institutional failures in addressing the issue, allowing perpetrators to evade justice.</li><li>Accurate terminology is crucial for accountability and addressing failures within the system.</li></ul><blockquote>“By far, the majority of perpetrators were described as 'Asian' by victims, yet throughout the entire period, councillors did not engage directly with the Pakistani-heritage community.” - Alexis Jay</blockquote><p>The article emphasizes the need for accurate representations of these crimes to ensure justice for the victims and to prevent the unfair stigmatization of other communities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/uk-news/story/uk-asian-grooming-gangs-keir-starmer-elon-musk-term-pakistani-perpetrators-explained-2662197-2025-01-09</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/uk-news/story/uk-asian-grooming-gangs-keir-starmer-elon-musk-term-pakistani-perpetrators-explained-2662197-2025-01-09</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 10:10:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iranian woman snatches cleric’s turban, uses it as hijab in act of defiance. Video - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Iranian Woman Defies Cleric By Wearing His Turban as Hijab</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/Hijab_1736416843523_1736416848427.jpeg" alt="The incident took place at Tehran’s Mehrabad Airport.(X/@AlinejadMasih)">
<figcaption>The incident took place at Tehran’s Mehrabad Airport.(X/@AlinejadMasih)</figcaption>
<p>A viral video from Tehran’s Mehrabad Airport captures a woman snatching a cleric’s turban and wearing it as a scarf during a confrontation, symbolizing a powerful act of defiance against Iran's strict hijab laws.</p>
<ul>
<li>The incident escalated when the cleric demanded the woman wear a hijab.</li>
<li>In the video, the woman questions the cleric's honor before searching for her husband.</li>
<li>The event is part of a larger movement of civil disobedience in Iran against mandatory hijab laws, following the death of Mahsa Amini.</li>
<li>The Iranian International reported mixed reactions, with some supporting the woman's boldness and others labeling her actions as stemming from psychological issues.</li>
<li>Over 30,000 women faced legal consequences for hijab non-compliance in December, indicating intensified enforcement of the law.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We’re witnessing something quite unprecedented: Women leading the charge against an immoral, illegitimate Islamic regime.”</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights the ongoing rebellion against oppressive dress codes in Iran and the increasing resolve of women to resist such mandates.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/iranian-woman-snatches-cleric-s-turban-uses-it-as-hijab-in-act-of-defiance-video-101736416197584.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/iranian-woman-snatches-cleric-s-turban-uses-it-as-hijab-in-act-of-defiance-video-101736416197584.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 10:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nora Fatehi Evacuates With Her Team As Los Angeles Wildfires Escalate: 'This is Insane' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxORkpuTlVoUER3V1B3ck91MWxCdUdlejNROFBtd01VRk01bGxGMnNLT01iNXZMNzBTQmdoOTVrOHExZlRpQXpnQnhza3ltQ3B0dUtUVFp3RXVFdWx0aHBJNWpPckVNeXF5Y0hfdVpxQmpLOFZ1MFd3LXdTMUFiQUkwNGc0c0dmUmVrWmpxVVFXZ3pxNU9jV1R6djFZMlk4WVREby1OTk1MVGJ0c1FqMDFUUTA5TnRNLTRIM0x1WTZTRXp5TDU0NVHSAcsBQVVfeXFMUElfekkyaUFHZDlyUUNLMkZtdHdUUlc0cFBlM3kxaGxBRGR5a29Gb0NuNllGQ1VnOWptWHRza05KeWZkQXNhTEpGc0U5RWxxRHd5eWkzaW1heExCN01DMnFNM3VFOFBtNUZFekJTNlF3cTZCTEpNcnhhY2htblR3a0lUMHdmRHhkQjhNLWp5WG9oUDIzYzBXWEcyOWFhcEFKTG16YUFqdS1lZWUydEY5cG96Q2V0Q1FFcmNGMWtIZVNNeFc4bTBKVFhXNXM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxORkpuTlVoUER3V1B3ck91MWxCdUdlejNROFBtd01VRk01bGxGMnNLT01iNXZMNzBTQmdoOTVrOHExZlRpQXpnQnhza3ltQ3B0dUtUVFp3RXVFdWx0aHBJNWpPckVNeXF5Y0hfdVpxQmpLOFZ1MFd3LXdTMUFiQUkwNGc0c0dmUmVrWmpxVVFXZ3pxNU9jV1R6djFZMlk4WVREby1OTk1MVGJ0c1FqMDFUUTA5TnRNLTRIM0x1WTZTRXp5TDU0NVHSAcsBQVVfeXFMUElfekkyaUFHZDlyUUNLMkZtdHdUUlc0cFBlM3kxaGxBRGR5a29Gb0NuNllGQ1VnOWptWHRza05KeWZkQXNhTEpGc0U5RWxxRHd5eWkzaW1heExCN01DMnFNM3VFOFBtNUZFekJTNlF3cTZCTEpNcnhhY2htblR3a0lUMHdmRHhkQjhNLWp5WG9oUDIzYzBXWEcyOWFhcEFKTG16YUFqdS1lZWUydEY5cG96Q2V0Q1FFcmNGMWtIZVNNeFc4bTBKVFhXNXM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 10:04:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires live: Posh Los Angeles lit by fire, darkened by massive power cut - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires Live: Posh Los Angeles Lit by Fire, Darkened by Massive Power Cut</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/california_los_angeles_hollywood_hills_wildfires_1736411767215_1736411767500.jpg" alt="A sports car decorated with Christmas lights drives past a burning bank during the Palisades Fire in Pacific Palisades, California, on January 8, 2025." title="A sports car decorated with Christmas lights drives past a burning bank during the Palisades Fire in Pacific Palisades, California, on January 8, 2025."></img><figcaption>A sports car decorated with Christmas lights drives past a burning bank during the Palisades Fire in Pacific Palisades, California, on January 8, 2025.</figcaption><p>Massive wildfires in Los Angeles, fueled by strong winds, have resulted in five fatalities, destroyed hundreds of homes, and led to the evacuation of thousands, including celebrities.</p><ul><li>Wildfires have claimed the lives of five individuals and damaged up to 1,500 buildings.</li><li>A total of approximately 100,000 people have been evacuated.</li><li>The wildfires are driven by dry winds, particularly the 'Santa Anas', and have burned around 42 square miles.</li><li>A satellite image revealed vast smoke plumes from the Palisades Fire near Pacific Palisades.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are indebted to you,” said President Biden, addressing the firefighters battling the blazes.</blockquote><p>This devastating event underscores the increasing frequency and intensity of wildfires, largely attributed to climate change, and emphasizes the urgent need for effective fire management and environmental policies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-live-updates-palisades-evacuation-malibu-fire-map-la-air-quality-101736327230446.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-live-updates-palisades-evacuation-malibu-fire-map-la-air-quality-101736327230446.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:44:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Lebanon finally elect a president? - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2025/1/9/explainer-lebanons-presidential-election</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2025/1/9/explainer-lebanons-presidential-election</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:22:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk agrees with Uddhav Thackeray's Shiv Sena leader Priyanka Chaturvedi over Pakistani grooming gangs | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk agrees with Uddhav Thackeray’s Shiv Sena leader Priyanka Chaturvedi over Pakistani grooming gangs</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>Amidst growing objections to the term 'Asian' used to refer to grooming gangs in the UK, Priyanka Chaturvedi advocates for specific labeling, calling them 'Pakistani grooming gangs'.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Priyanka Chaturvedi's comments were made in light of the child sexual abuse scandal in the UK.</li>
  <li>Elon Musk, influential in social media, supported her stance on the platform X.</li>
  <li>The British Prime Minister defended his previous statements regarding the term 'Asian grooming gangs'.</li>
  <li>Chaturvedi's tweet gained significant traction, receiving over 1.2 million views and widespread attention.</li>
  <li>Social media reactions varied, with some praising her comments while others provided critical counterarguments.</li>
  <li>The Network of Sikh Organisations criticized the vague reference to 'Asian' by the British Prime Minister.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>True — Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1877001375852212399?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 8, 2025</a></blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights ongoing debates regarding political correctness and accountability in addressing serious crimes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/india/elon-musk-agrees-with-shiv-sena-leader-priyanka-chaturvedi-over-pakistani-grooming-gangs-uk-keir-starmer-11736412254443.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/india/elon-musk-agrees-with-shiv-sena-leader-priyanka-chaturvedi-over-pakistani-grooming-gangs-uk-keir-starmer-11736412254443.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 09:22:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfire: 100-year-old Starbucks building becomes 'unrecognizable' - video - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California wildfire: 100-year-old Starbucks building becomes 'unrecognizable' - video</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In a devastating wildfire, a historic Starbucks building in California that stood for over a century has been rendered unrecognizable, showcasing the severe impact of climate change and wildfires.</p><ul><li>The wildfire resulted in the destruction of several historic buildings.</li><li>Local residents are expressing shock and grief over the loss of the Starbucks location.</li><li>This incident highlights the ongoing issue of wildfires in California exacerbated by climate factors.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's heartbreaking to see a place that has been part of our community for so long vanish in an instant.”</blockquote><p>The loss of such a historic structure underscores the need for increased awareness and action regarding wildfire management and climate change repercussions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/california-wildfire-100-year-old-starbucks-building-becomes-unrecognizable-video/articleshow/117079369.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/california-wildfire-100-year-old-starbucks-building-becomes-unrecognizable-video/articleshow/117079369.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk backs Rajya Sabha MP Priyanka Chaturvedi's post against UK PM Starmer over Pakistani grooming... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxPTmdtMm11R1RtNkFDRVFqODQ1NDVnOVRNOUtiOFNlYzhHaVliYnVvb2xuRjktLUltYTBYMm9TVkt2Z2NSVWcyeHpVbnJpRkpFSGVrWklzaXRIeHY4cWg4dDE0b3BkaVRfWTE1YlVBQUlTaE90bHVqXzNFZk9kcDhTQlMweGZDQmkxZjhxM3VsQjdJUXFUY2tRRWtWX0RuTUt3RHdmWjlyTlZTX2JzclItaVZzb1BSSlE2SWhpYTMzUEVDUU1aZ0VVTGtVT3laN2FSN1hiZHBXQy1fV3JWTjY2LUJHR0lUaU3SAewBQVVfeXFMTmNocExuQUVUMzc3LTlsd3hxNTJWZ05EWlltSjJRWTRFRnhYUW5kcXI3VEJfVXh2Z3VncFJPSnNMTDloeGpfbV92c2VDSmhYNzBDVDVPdzkxVXZCMzd5cHFsWlFQSnBzTkQ3MXhZMUNTOXRQMFp6SkxPaUlidnBHT3BoM01PTEYydmxRemQ1X1JWM09Eb3ZhdEw4WWZtWHB4elg1bmxTRE45XzNURHlKZDRkZkRkZUJXZDlkcXEtNXpkRzlJOHlsbFpjWjMwYzZsZ1hnTGVlc0RzUHh0MUhMR05RbU1NQlRlTEpOdUY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5wFBVV95cUxPTmdtMm11R1RtNkFDRVFqODQ1NDVnOVRNOUtiOFNlYzhHaVliYnVvb2xuRjktLUltYTBYMm9TVkt2Z2NSVWcyeHpVbnJpRkpFSGVrWklzaXRIeHY4cWg4dDE0b3BkaVRfWTE1YlVBQUlTaE90bHVqXzNFZk9kcDhTQlMweGZDQmkxZjhxM3VsQjdJUXFUY2tRRWtWX0RuTUt3RHdmWjlyTlZTX2JzclItaVZzb1BSSlE2SWhpYTMzUEVDUU1aZ0VVTGtVT3laN2FSN1hiZHBXQy1fV3JWTjY2LUJHR0lUaU3SAewBQVVfeXFMTmNocExuQUVUMzc3LTlsd3hxNTJWZ05EWlltSjJRWTRFRnhYUW5kcXI3VEJfVXh2Z3VncFJPSnNMTDloeGpfbV92c2VDSmhYNzBDVDVPdzkxVXZCMzd5cHFsWlFQSnBzTkQ3MXhZMUNTOXRQMFp6SkxPaUlidnBHT3BoM01PTEYydmxRemQ1X1JWM09Eb3ZhdEw4WWZtWHB4elg1bmxTRE45XzNURHlKZDRkZkRkZUJXZDlkcXEtNXpkRzlJOHlsbFpjWjMwYzZsZ1hnTGVlc0RzUHh0MUhMR05RbU1NQlRlTEpOdUY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After ‘Stealth’ J-35A From China, Pakistan Discusses Acquiring 5th-Gen KAAN Fighters From Turkey: Reports - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE1NMm53VEJXQ3FnbGdZOS1VZjNzeDhjRENNM2xNOFd5UTJIeHBQa29KeHQ4WThRRXpVM1QyM2xGTU4wMlgyTmU4cHN5MDloOGRHdnNMY1hmaU04NVZUREZwQ29yUHd0MHEyVnNfQUN5SFVXaGluWm96TDNn0gF6QVVfeXFMTU0ybndUQldDcWdsZ1k5LVVmM3N4OGNEQ00zbE04V3lRMkh4cFBrb0p4dDhZOFFFelUzVDIzbEZNTjAyWDJOZThwc3kwOWg4ZEd2c0xjWGZpTTg1VlRERnBDb3JQd3QwcTJWc19BQ3lIVVdoaW5ab3pMM2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTE1NMm53VEJXQ3FnbGdZOS1VZjNzeDhjRENNM2xNOFd5UTJIeHBQa29KeHQ4WThRRXpVM1QyM2xGTU4wMlgyTmU4cHN5MDloOGRHdnNMY1hmaU04NVZUREZwQ29yUHd0MHEyVnNfQUN5SFVXaGluWm96TDNn0gF6QVVfeXFMTU0ybndUQldDcWdsZ1k5LVVmM3N4OGNEQ00zbE04V3lRMkh4cFBrb0p4dDhZOFFFelUzVDIzbEZNTjAyWDJOZThwc3kwOWg4ZEd2c0xjWGZpTTg1VlRERnBDb3JQd3QwcTJWc19BQ3lIVVdoaW5ab3pMM2c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 08:01:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles wildfires live: 5 dead as Posh Hollywood houses burn in ‘worst US disaster’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Severe Wildfires Rage Through Los Angeles, Resulting in Evacuations and Power Outages</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/california_los_angeles_hollywood_hills_wildfires_1736411767215_1736411767500.jpg" alt="A sports car decorated with Christmas lights drives past a burning bank during the Palisades Fire in Pacific Palisades, California, on January 8, 2025." /><figcaption>A sports car decorated with Christmas lights drives past a burning bank during the Palisades Fire in Pacific Palisades, California, on January 8, 2025.</figcaption><p>The wildfires in Los Angeles have led to the evacuation of thousands, with at least five fatalities reported. Key areas impacted include the upscale neighborhoods of Pacific Palisades, Pasadena, and Altadena. The incident has caused significant property damage, affecting numerous celebrity homes.</p><ul><li>The wildfires have resulted in the deaths of five individuals and burnt down hundreds of structures.</li><li>Over 100,000 residents have been evacuated due to the fires raging across multiple neighborhoods.</li><li>The total area consumed by the wildfires has grown to approximately 42 square miles.</li><li>Electrical outages have affected over 456,000 individuals in Southern California.</li><li>Financial losses from the wildfires are estimated to range between $52 billion and $57 billion.</li></ul><blockquote>“Immediate threat to life. This is a lawful order to LEAVE NOW,” stated the Los Angeles Fire Department.</blockquote><p>This disaster highlights the increasing frequency and intensity of wildfires in California, largely attributed to climate change.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-live-updates-palisades-evacuation-malibu-fire-map-la-air-quality-101736327230446.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-live-updates-palisades-evacuation-malibu-fire-map-la-air-quality-101736327230446.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:40:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfire: Burning Los Angeles looks ‘apocalyptic’ in scary visuals - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires Turn Los Angeles Into 'Apocalyptic' Scene</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 09, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/los_angeles_fire_1736405447019_1736405456706.jpg" alt="Los Angeles looks apocalyptic, said social media users as wildfires ripped through the city housing Hollywood" title="Los Angeles looks apocalyptic, said social media users as wildfires ripped through the city housing Hollywood"><figcaption>Los Angeles looks apocalyptic, said social media users as wildfires ripped through the city housing Hollywood</figcaption><p>The city of Los Angeles is facing devastating wildfires that have turned the sky orange and burned through famous neighborhoods, prompting evacuations and showcasing scenes likened to an apocalypse.</p><ul><li>Wildfires fueled by 'Santa Ana' winds reached areas including Hollywood Hills and inflicted damage upon celebrity homes.</li><li>Social media is flooded with visuals depicting fireballs and thick smoke, resembling scenes from a nightmare.</li><li>Approximately 100 elderly residents were evacuated from a senior care facility in Altadena as flames encroached on their location.</li><li>The wildfires have resulted in five fatalities and numerous destroyed homes.</li><li>Strong winds, comparable to hurricane force, have complicated firefighting efforts, with aerial support only resuming recently.</li></ul><blockquote><p>🚨 LOS ANGELES IS BURNING<br/>Our hearts ache for everyone in Pacific Palisades and Los Angeles as these insane devastating fires rage on.</p></blockquote><p>The ongoing wildfires in Los Angeles highlight the severe impact of climate-driven disasters, as communities rally to support those affected while firefighting efforts continue.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfire-burning-los-angeles-looks-apocalyptic-in-scary-visuals-101736403112374.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfire-burning-los-angeles-looks-apocalyptic-in-scary-visuals-101736403112374.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:35:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Focus shifts to Tibet earthquake survivors as search called off - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/focus-shifts-tibet-earthquake-survivors-search-called-off-2025-01-09/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/focus-shifts-tibet-earthquake-survivors-search-called-off-2025-01-09/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 07:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is UK's ‘Pakistani grooming gangs’ scandal? Why is Elon Musk slamming PM Keir Starmer? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What is UK's ‘Pakistani grooming gangs’ scandal? Why is Elon Musk slamming PM Keir Starmer?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/final_1722938040334_1736405107533.jpg" alt="Elon Musk's &quot;civil war is inevitable&quot; in UK remark was condemned by PM Keir Starmer.(AP)" title="Elon Musk's &quot;civil war is inevitable&quot; in UK remark was condemned by PM Keir Starmer.(AP)"><figcaption>Elon Musk's "civil war is inevitable" in UK remark was condemned by PM Keir Starmer.(AP)</figcaption></figure><p>The UK Parliament is moving to improve protections for home-schooled children following the tragic murder of Sara Sharif. Meanwhile, Elon Musk has publicly criticized Prime Minister Keir Starmer regarding his handling of the grooming gangs scandal.</p><ul><li>UK lawmakers backed the Children's Wellbeing and Schools Bill after a vote influenced by recent events regarding grooming gangs.</li><li>MPs rejected a Conservative proposal for a new inquiry into grooming gangs.</li><li>Elon Musk accused Starmer of complicity in the crimes of child sex offenders, causing a public backlash.</li><li>The grooming gangs scandal involves the sexual exploitation of young girls by groups predominantly from Pakistani backgrounds.</li><li>Notable statistics include the Rotherham inquiry revealing that at least 1,400 girls were victimized over 16 years.</li></ul><blockquote>“Starmer was deeply complicit in the mass rapes in exchange for votes. That's what the inquiry would show.” - Elon Musk</blockquote><p>The ongoing discourse surrounding the grooming gangs scandal and comments by high-profile figures like Elon Musk highlights the complexity and sensitivity of the issues surrounding child safety and institutional accountability in the UK.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/what-is-uks-pakistani-grooming-gangs-scandal-why-is-elon-musk-slamming-pm-keir-starmer-101736397566558.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/what-is-uks-pakistani-grooming-gangs-scandal-why-is-elon-musk-slamming-pm-keir-starmer-101736397566558.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:49:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California Los Angeles Wildfires LIVE Updates: Over 100,000 flee, 5 dead as wildfires rage in Hollywood Hills, Los Angeles - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Los Angeles Wildfires LIVE Updates</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/los-angeles-wildfires.jpg?w=640" alt="Los Angeles Wildfires" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>LA Fire Department firefighters work to extinguish a house fire as the Palisades Fire ravages a neighborhood amid high winds in the Pacific Palisades neighborhood of Los Angeles. (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>Raging wildfires have surrounded Los Angeles, killing at least five people and destroying hundreds of homes as over 100,000 were ordered to evacuate.</p><ul><li>A new wildfire erupted in the Hollywood Hills, exacerbated by strong Santa Ana winds.</li><li>Communities in Pacific Palisades and Hollywood Hills have been severely affected.</li><li>More than 1,000 structures have been destroyed, and nearly one million homes lost power.</li><li>Schools were closed across the county due to the fires.</li><li>Evacuations included both residents and high-profile individuals.</li></ul><blockquote>“The flames consumed homes and properties worth millions.”</blockquote><p>This wildfire crisis highlights the ongoing challenges California faces with wildfire management, particularly during high-risk seasons.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/california-hollywood-hills-los-angeles-wildfires-live-updates-death-toll-9768223/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/california-hollywood-hills-los-angeles-wildfires-live-updates-death-toll-9768223/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:35:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles wildfires live: LA looks ‘apocalyptic’ as posh Hollywood houses burn; 5 killed - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Severe Wildfires Rage Through Los Angeles, Resulting in Evacuations and Power Outages</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 8, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/09/550x309/california_los_angeles_hollywood_hills_wildfires_1736411767215_1736411767500.jpg" alt="A sports car decorated with Christmas lights drives past a burning bank during the Palisades Fire in Pacific Palisades, California, on January 8, 2025." /><figcaption>A sports car decorated with Christmas lights drives past a burning bank during the Palisades Fire in Pacific Palisades, California, on January 8, 2025.</figcaption><p>The wildfires in Los Angeles have led to the evacuation of thousands, with at least five fatalities reported. Key areas impacted include the upscale neighborhoods of Pacific Palisades, Pasadena, and Altadena. The incident has caused significant property damage, affecting numerous celebrity homes.</p><ul><li>The wildfires have resulted in the deaths of five individuals and burnt down hundreds of structures.</li><li>Over 100,000 residents have been evacuated due to the fires raging across multiple neighborhoods.</li><li>The total area consumed by the wildfires has grown to approximately 42 square miles.</li><li>Electrical outages have affected over 456,000 individuals in Southern California.</li><li>Financial losses from the wildfires are estimated to range between $52 billion and $57 billion.</li></ul><blockquote>“Immediate threat to life. This is a lawful order to LEAVE NOW,” stated the Los Angeles Fire Department.</blockquote><p>This disaster highlights the increasing frequency and intensity of wildfires in California, largely attributed to climate change.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-live-updates-palisades-evacuation-malibu-fire-map-la-air-quality-101736327230446.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-live-updates-palisades-evacuation-malibu-fire-map-la-air-quality-101736327230446.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 06:29:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk looking to oust UK PM Keir Starmer? Report suggests efforts at destabilisation - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk looking to oust UK PM Keir Starmer? Report suggests efforts at destabilisation</h1>
<p><strong>Published:</strong> 09 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> The Financial Times</p>
<p>Tech billionaire Elon Musk is reportedly collaborating with his allies to find ways to depose Keir Starmer as the UK Prime Minister in the lead-up to the next general elections.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Musk is exploring support for alternative political movements, particularly Reform UK, led by Nigel Farage.</li>
  <li>The billionaire has voiced that the Reform UK party "needs a new leader" and is considering candidates.</li>
  <li>Rupert Lowe, a Reform UK MP, has emerged as a potential candidate for leadership replacement.</li>
  <li>Musk has accused PM Starmer of being complicit in significant issues facing the UK.</li>
  <li>There is an increasing interest from Musk in UK politics, including calls for investigations into exploitation cases.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Musk has labeled UK PM Starmer as "complicit" in the social troubles besieging Britain.</blockquote>
<p>This report indicates Musk's growing influence and interest in UK political dynamics, hinting at significant shifting possibilities in the political landscape depending on the upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/elon-musk-looking-to-oust-uk-pm-keir-starmer-report-suggests-efforts-at-destabilisation-3347700</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/elon-musk-looking-to-oust-uk-pm-keir-starmer-report-suggests-efforts-at-destabilisation-3347700</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 05:49:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Why don't we call it América Mexicana?': Mexico President's befitting counter to Trump's rename proposal - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Why don't we call it América Mexicana?': Mexico President's befitting counter to Trump's rename proposal</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 09, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/11/20241127015208_President-Claudia-Sheinbaum.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431' alt='Beyond the name change proposal, Sheinbaum also addressed Trump’s threat to impose a 25% tariff on Mexican imports.' title='Beyond the name change proposal, Sheinbaum also addressed Trump’s threat to impose a 25% tariff on Mexican imports.' width='770' height='431'>
<figcaption>Claudia Sheinbaum, Mexico's newly inaugurated president.</figcaption>
<p>Claudia Sheinbaum, Mexico's newly inaugurated president, provided a rapid response to Donald Trump’s suggestion to rename the Gulf of Mexico, using a historical map as a visual aid to convey her message.</p>
<ul>
<li>Claudia Sheinbaum presented a 400-year-old map of North America labeled 'América Mexicana'.</li>
<li>Sheinbaum humorously suggested renaming the region 'Mexican America'.</li>
<li>She addressed Trump’s comments regarding Mexico's sovereignty, emphasizing Mexico's independence.</li>
<li>She highlighted the misinformation surrounding Trump's remarks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In Mexico, the people rule. We are a free, independent, and sovereign country. We will always defend that.” - Claudia Sheinbaum</blockquote>
<p>This response highlights Mexico's stance on its sovereignty and the historical significance of its identity, resonating deeply in diplomatic discussions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/sheinbaum-sharpens-sword-in-duel-with-trump-seeks-to-call-the-continent-am-rica-mexicana-12906368.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/sheinbaum-sharpens-sword-in-duel-with-trump-seeks-to-call-the-continent-am-rica-mexicana-12906368.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 05:44:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>