<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 18:22:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 18:22:34 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Genocidal Rape’: Musk Questions UK’s Starmer Over Silence On Pakistani Rape Gangs - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Musk Challenges UK PM Starmer on Rotherham Rape Scandal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 05, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="SpaceX, Tesla and X CEO Elon Musk questioned the UK government over the Rotherham sex scandal." title="SpaceX, Tesla and X CEO Elon Musk questioned the UK government over the Rotherham sex scandal."><figcaption>SpaceX, Tesla and X CEO Elon Musk questioned the UK government over the Rotherham sex scandal. (IMAGE: REUTERS FILE)</figcaption><p>Tech mogul Elon Musk has recently criticized UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer regarding the Rotherham sex scandal, accusing him of complicity during his time as Director of Public Prosecutions.</p><ul><li>Musk referred to the incidence of “genocidal rape” following a post by journalist Peter Imanuelsen.</li><li>He highlighted Starmer's failure to prosecute rape gangs effectively while in office.</li><li>Musk shared posts from other MPs calling for a national inquiry into child sexual abuse incidents.</li><li>A significant report revealed that at least 1,400 children in Rotherham were abused, with a systemic failure in addressing the issue reported.</li><li>Fear of being labeled racist limited officials' responses to the abuse cases, as many perpetrators were of Pakistani heritage.</li></ul><blockquote>“Starmer was complicit in the RAPE OF BRITAIN when he was head of Crown Prosecution for 6 years. Starmer must go and he must face charges for his complicity in the worst mass crime in the history of Britain.” — Elon Musk</blockquote><p>Musk's remarks have generated considerable debate and highlight serious concerns regarding the historical handling of sexual abuse cases in the UK.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/genocidal-rape-musk-questions-uks-starmer-over-silence-on-pakistani-rape-gangs-9177768.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/genocidal-rape-musk-questions-uks-starmer-over-silence-on-pakistani-rape-gangs-9177768.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 16:05:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chinese hack of US telecoms compromised more firms than previously known, WSJ says - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chinese Hack Compromises More US Telecoms Than Previously Known</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Recent | <strong>Source:</strong> Wall Street Journal</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal reports that a Chinese hacking incident has compromised a larger number of U.S. telecoms than earlier believed, raising concerns about national security and infrastructure vulnerability.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Hacks affected companies including Charter Communications, Consolidated Communications, and Windstream.</li>
  <li>Exploited vulnerabilities in security equipment from Fortinet and routers from Cisco.</li>
  <li>Previous intrusions included AT&T, Verizon, Lumen Technologies, and T-Mobile.</li>
  <li>Chinese hackers allegedly gained the capability to shut down critical U.S. infrastructure.</li>
  <li>Chinese government denies involvement and accuses the U.S. of misinformation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Verizon has contained the activities associated with this particular incident.” - Vandana Venkatesh, Chief Legal Officer at Verizon.</blockquote>
<p>The incident highlights the pressing need for U.S. telecoms to enhance cybersecurity measures and the ongoing risks posed by foreign cyber threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/business/chinese-hack-of-us-telecoms-compromised-more-firms-than-previously-known-wsj-says/articleshow/116969042.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/business/chinese-hack-of-us-telecoms-compromised-more-firms-than-previously-known-wsj-says/articleshow/116969042.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:13:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Farage Doesn't Have What It Takes': Musk Calls For New Reform UK Leader Weeks After Mar-A-Lago Meet - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Musk Calls for New Reform UK Leader, Criticizes Farage's Leadership</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 06, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Elon Musk and Nigel Farage (Photo: X/Nigel Farage)" title="Elon Musk and Nigel Farage (Photo: X/Nigel Farage)"><figcaption>Elon Musk and Nigel Farage (Photo: X/Nigel Farage)</figcaption></figure><p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk has publicly stated that Nigel Farage "doesn't have what it takes" to lead the Reform UK party, calling for a leadership change shortly after their meeting at Mar-a-Lago.</p><ul><li>Musk's comments came after speculations that he could donate a large sum to the Reform UK party.</li><li>He emphasized the need for new leadership within the party.</li><li>Farage has been viewed as a key figure in the party's establishment but was challenged by Musk's remarks.</li><li>Disagreements have arisen between Musk and Farage regarding political figures like Tommy Robinson.</li></ul><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Reform Party needs a new leader. Farage doesn’t have what it takes.— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1875904634419859928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">January 5, 2025</a></p></blockquote><p>The event underscores the evolving dynamics within the Reform UK party and Musk's growing influence in political discussions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/elon-musk-nigel-farage-doesnt-have-what-it-takes-reform-party-uk-leader-mar-a-lago-meet-donation-9177933.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/elon-musk-nigel-farage-doesnt-have-what-it-takes-reform-party-uk-leader-mar-a-lago-meet-donation-9177933.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 15:12:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What role will China’s mystery 6th-gen stealth fighter play in actual combat? - South China Morning Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Is China’s mystery 6th-gen stealth fighter poised to be a command centre for combat drones?</h1><p><strong>Published: 10:00pm, 5 Jan 2025</strong></p><figure><img src="https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/1020x680/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/01/04/1a76d33c-cbd3-41e9-bb94-0aff480aa89c_b0b4f7ef.jpg?itok=Ns0WIL56&amp;v=1735982742" alt="China’s first sixth-generation stealth fighter jets appear to have made their first flights on December 26. Photo: Weibo/师伟微博"/><figcaption>China’s first sixth-generation stealth fighter jets appear to have made their first flights on December 26. Photo: Weibo/师伟微博</figcaption></figure><p>China’s mystery sixth-generation stealth combat aircraft spotted last month might have sacrificed flexibility and carrier mission opportunities for other roles, according to military experts. One such role could be serving as a command centre to direct combat drones, the observers said.</p><ul><li>The new J-36 is expected to feature multiple breakthroughs.</li><li>It might act as a node in a larger system of attacks.</li><li>Footage of two similar models of the fighter jet has circulated on social media since December 26.</li><li>The first sightings coincided with the 131st anniversary of Mao Zedong’s birth.</li></ul><blockquote>Military experts suggest the J-36 is likely to serve a pivotal role in directing drone operations.</blockquote><p>The introduction of the J-36 represents a significant development in China’s military capabilities and could impact future combat scenarios.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3293421/chinas-mystery-6th-gen-stealth-fighter-poised-be-command-centre-combat-drones</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3293421/chinas-mystery-6th-gen-stealth-fighter-poised-be-command-centre-combat-drones</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:00:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Syria's new Islamist rulers urge US to lift sanctions during visit to Doha - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Syria's new Islamist rulers urge US to lift sanctions during visit to Doha</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/World_3_1734523201355_1734523249781.jpg" alt="Syria's new Islamist rulers urge US to lift sanctions during visit to Doha" title="Syria's new Islamist rulers urge US to lift sanctions during visit to Doha"><figcaption>Syria's new Islamist rulers urge US to lift sanctions during visit to Doha</figcaption></figure><p>During a diplomatic visit to Qatar, Syria's new Islamist rulers expressed that US sanctions hinder the war-torn country's recovery and urged their removal.</p><ul><li>Syria's Foreign Minister Asaad Hassan al-Shibani emphasized sanctions as an obstacle to recovery.</li><li>He called for lifting sanctions, stating they now impact the Syrian people more than the former Assad regime.</li><li>The officials from Syria are on their second trip abroad since the ousting of former President Bashar al-Assad.</li><li>Shibani indicated that Qatar will play a pivotal role in Syria's new phase.</li><li>A roadmap for rebuilding Syria and restoring relations was presented to Qatari officials.</li></ul><blockquote>“These sanctions constitute a barrier and an obstacle to the rapid recovery and development of the Syrian people.” - Asaad Hassan al-Shibani</blockquote><p>The meeting signifies a shift in Syrian diplomacy post-Assad, with hopes for international partnerships to aid their recovery.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/syrias-new-islamist-rulers-urge-us-to-lift-sanctions-during-visit-to-doha-101736083949111.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/syrias-new-islamist-rulers-urge-us-to-lift-sanctions-during-visit-to-doha-101736083949111.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 13:32:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[War in Ukraine: After Leaving the Mediterranean, the Russian Attack Submarine Novorossiysk Spotted Near French Shores, Heading Toward Brittany - Indian Defence Review]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>War in Ukraine: After Leaving the Mediterranean, the Russian Attack Submarine Novorossiysk Spotted Near French Shores, Heading Toward Brittany</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 5, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Defence Review</p><figure><img src="https://indiandefencereview.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/russian20submarine-geopolitical20tensions-maritime20security.jpeg" alt="What's that Russian Sub Doing Near France?"><figcaption>War in Ukraine: After Leaving the Mediterranean, the Russian Attack Submarine Novorossiysk Spotted Near French Shores, Heading Toward Brittany | Indian Defence Review</figcaption></figure><p>A Russian attack submarine, the <strong>Novorossiysk</strong>, was recently spotted near the French coast, causing quite a stir across Europe. This sighting underscores ongoing geopolitical tensions and strategic military maneuvers happening in international waters.</p><ul><li>The Novorossiysk was first reported by Portuguese military in their exclusive economic zone.</li><li>Heightened security measures were implemented in response to its movement towards Cape Finisterre.</li><li>This incident recalls previous sightings of Russian submarines in the region, indicating a pattern of naval activity.</li><li>The submarine's deployment could signal shifts in Russian military strategy, especially following political changes in Syria.</li></ul><blockquote>“Getting a handle on these movements helps us gauge potential effects on regional security dynamics.”</blockquote><p>As tensions increase, understanding maritime security is crucial for protecting national interests and fostering regional stability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indiandefencereview.com/war-in-ukraine-after-leaving-the-mediterranean-the-russian-attack-submarine-novorossiysk-spotted-near-french-shores-heading-toward-brittany/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiandefencereview.com/war-in-ukraine-after-leaving-the-mediterranean-the-russian-attack-submarine-novorossiysk-spotted-near-french-shores-heading-toward-brittany/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israeli strikes kill 14 people in Gaza, mediators strive for a truce deal - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israeli Strikes Kill 14 People in Gaza, Mediators Strive for a Truce Deal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 05, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/42p3wi/article69064921.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2025-01-05T112224Z_1389188548_RC2N3CAGBKEZ_RTRMADP_3_ISRAEL-PALESTINIANS-GAZA.JPG" alt="Smoke rises as buildings lie in ruin in Beit Hanoun and Jabaliya in the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and Hamas, as seen from southern Israel, on January 5, 2025." title="Smoke rises as buildings lie in ruin in Beit Hanoun and Jabaliya in the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and Hamas, as seen from southern Israel, on January 5, 2025."><figcaption>Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>The ongoing conflict in Gaza escalated on January 5, 2025, with Israeli airstrikes resulting in the deaths of at least 14 Palestinians, contributing to a rising death toll amid ceasefire negotiations.</p><ul><li>Israeli airstrikes killed 14 Palestinians in multiple attacks.</li><li>The death toll in the weekend has reached 102, according to Palestinian medics.</li><li>Amidst escalating violence, U.S. and Arab mediators are intensifying efforts for a ceasefire deal.</li><li>Health officials reported significant casualties and injuries, including 88 deaths and over 200 injuries reported in 24 hours prior.</li><li>Search operations are ongoing for missing individuals under rubble in affected areas.</li><li>Israel asserts that dozens of Hamas militants were killed in the attacks.</li><li>Negotiators from Israel were sent to resume talks in Doha to reach an agreement before U.S. President-elect Donald Trump's inauguration.</li></ul><blockquote>“Approximately 11 people have been martyred here,” said Ammar Zuhd, a relative of the victims.</blockquote><p>This recent spike in violence underscores the urgent need for a ceasefire amid devastating humanitarian implications for the people in Gaza.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/israeli-strikes-kill-several-people-in-gaza-mediators-strive-for-a-truce-deal/article69064864.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/israeli-strikes-kill-several-people-in-gaza-mediators-strive-for-a-truce-deal/article69064864.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 13:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[100X Faster To Produce, Ukraine To Test AI-Enabled, Anti-Drone Missile Designed To Defeat Russian UAVs - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ukraine to Test AI-Enabled Anti-Drone Missile Amid Russian Attacks</h1> <p><strong>Date: January 4, 2025 | Source: Eurasian Times</strong></p> <figure><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Su-57-1290-x-650-px-19.png" alt="Mark 1 missile imagery"><figcaption>Mark 1 official imagery / Image credit: Frankenburg Technologies.</figcaption></figure> <p>Ukraine is set to test a new low-cost, AI-enabled missile designed specifically to counter increasing drone attacks from Russia, with trials expected to begin in early 2025.</p> <ul> <li>The missile, named Mark 1, is developed by Frankenburg Technologies, an Estonian firm.</li> <li>It is designed to identify and engage drones flying at altitudes of up to 2 kilometers.</li> <li>Ukrainian President Zelenskyy reported over 300 drone attacks by Russia in the first three days of 2025 alone.</li> <li>If successful, Ukraine could enter into a domestic production agreement for the missile.</li> <li>The testing comes in response to a significant rise in Russian drone assaults, which have reportedly increased sixfold over six months.</li> </ul> <blockquote>“Our goal is to help Ukraine win this war...,” said Kusti Salm, CEO of Frankenburg Technologies.</blockquote> <p>The introduction of the Mark 1 missile system is a significant development in Ukraine's defense strategy as it adapts to the evolving threats of drone warfare, emphasizing innovation and cost-effectiveness in military technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/ukraine-to-test-estonian-low-cost-ai-enabled-mk1-anti-drone-missile/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/ukraine-to-test-estonian-low-cost-ai-enabled-mk1-anti-drone-missile/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 13:25:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where was Nasrallah when he was killed by Israel? Close aide reveals details - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/where-was-nasrallah-when-he-was-killed-by-israel-close-aide-reveals-details/articleshow/116967369.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/where-was-nasrallah-when-he-was-killed-by-israel-close-aide-reveals-details/articleshow/116967369.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 13:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nagasaki atomic bomb survivor, who devoted his life for peace, dies at 93 - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nagasaki Atomic Bomb Survivor Shigemi Fukahori Passes Away at 93</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/h28hl0/article69064811.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/Obit_Japan_Nagasaki_Survivor_41127.jpg" alt="Shigemi Fukahori" title="Shigemi Fukahori was only 14 when the U.S. dropped the bomb on Nagasaki on August 9, 1945. File">
<figcaption>Shigemi Fukahori was only 14 when the U.S. dropped the bomb on Nagasaki on August 9, 1945. File | Photo Credit: AP</figcaption>
<p>Shigemi Fukahori, a 93-year-old survivor of the 1945 Nagasaki atomic bombing, known for his lifelong advocacy for peace and nuclear disarmament, has passed away in Nagasaki.</p>
<ul>
<li>Fukahori died on January 3, 2025, in a hospital in Nagasaki, reportedly from old age.</li>
<li>He was just 14 years old when the atomic bomb was dropped on Nagasaki, which killed tens of thousands.</li>
<li>Fukahori became more vocal about his experiences 15 years ago, inspired by a discussion with a survivor of the bombing of Guernica.</li>
<li>He often spoke to students, encouraging them to carry on his advocacy for peace.</li>
<li>During a visit from Pope Francis in 2019, Fukahori presented a wreath, symbolizing his lifelong commitment to peace.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“On the day the bomb dropped, I heard a voice asking for help. When I walked over and held out my hand, the person’s skin melted. I still remember how that felt.” - Shigemi Fukahori</blockquote>
<p>Fukahori's passing marks the loss of a significant voice in the movement advocating for nuclear disarmament and peace.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/nagasaki-atomic-bomb-survivor-who-devoted-his-life-for-peace-dies-at-93/article69064798.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/nagasaki-atomic-bomb-survivor-who-devoted-his-life-for-peace-dies-at-93/article69064798.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 13:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World Bank to approve $20 billion programme for Pakistan: Report - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>World Bank to approve $20 billion programme for Pakistan: Report</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 - <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The World Bank is set to approve a significant financial programme aimed at supporting Pakistan's economy amidst ongoing challenges.</p><ul><li>The programme amounts to $20 billion.</li><li>It is expected to address pressing economic issues in Pakistan.</li><li>This approval highlights ongoing international support for the country.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is a crucial development for Pakistan as it seeks to stabilize its economy."</blockquote><p>This financial assistance is anticipated to have a major impact on Pakistan's recovery efforts and economic stability in the near future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/world-bank-to-approve-20-billion-programme-for-pakistan-report/articleshow/116966227.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/world-bank-to-approve-20-billion-programme-for-pakistan-report/articleshow/116966227.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 12:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YouTuber Ankush Bahuguna's scary 40-hour-long digital arrest: ‘Lost money, mental health’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>YouTuber Ankush Bahuguna's 40-Hour Digital Arrest: A Cautionary Tale</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/Ankush-Bahuguna_digital_arrest_1736078109179_1736078109374.jpg" alt="Detailing how the scam unfolded, Ankush said he got a call day before yesterday on returning from the gym from a “very weird number” which started with +1. (File image)" title="Detailing how the scam unfolded, Ankush said he got a call day before yesterday on returning from the gym from a “very weird number” which started with +1. (File image)"><figcaption>Detailing how the scam unfolded, Ankush said he got a call day before yesterday on returning from the gym from a “very weird number” which started with +1. (File image)</figcaption></figure><p>Popular YouTuber Ankush Bahuguna revealed that he fell victim to a digital arrest scam where he was manipulated into losing money and suffering mental distress over 40 hours.</p><ul><li>Ankush received a suspicious call claiming a package was seized with illegal contents.</li><li>He was coerced into believing he was under digital arrest linked to serious crimes.</li><li>Scammers used personal information and heightened fear to control him.</li><li>He emphasized the need for awareness to prevent others from experiencing similar situations.</li></ul><blockquote>“I have lost money, I have lost my mental health to this, I can't believe this has happened to me.” - Ankush Bahuguna</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Bahuguna urges everyone to stay vigilant and to help raise awareness about the tactics used by scammers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ankush-bahuguna-digital-arrest-youtuber-cyber-fraud-mumbai-police-101736076648923.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/ankush-bahuguna-digital-arrest-youtuber-cyber-fraud-mumbai-police-101736076648923.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 11:55:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Zealand Relaxes Visa Rules To Combat Labour Shortages, Indian Migrants May Be Impacted - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Zealand Eases Visa Regulations to Address Labor Shortages, Affecting Indian Migrants</h1>
<p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 05, 2025, 22:45 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Representative Image" title="Representative Image">
<figcaption>Representative Image</figcaption>
<p>The New Zealand government has relaxed various visa rules for immigrants seeking job opportunities in the country, particularly impacting Indian migrants.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The work experience requirement has been reduced from three years to two years, making it easier for migrants to seek employment.</li>
  <li>New visa pathways include a three-year multi-entry visa for experienced seasonal workers and a seven-month single-entry visa for lower-skilled workers.</li>
  <li>The median pay criteria for the Accredited Employer Work Visa (AEWV) and Specific Purpose Work Visa (SPWV) have been slashed, allowing for greater flexibility.</li>
  <li>A minimum annual earnings threshold of NZ$55,844 is required for AEWV holders wishing to bring children to New Zealand.</li>
  <li>Visas for skill levels 4 or 5 jobs have been extended from two to three years, with options for extensions for current employees.</li>
  <li>Changes have also been made to the Post Study Work Visa, allowing students to work in New Zealand for up to three years post-graduation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The new rules will significantly benefit Indian migrants looking for job opportunities in New Zealand.”</blockquote>
<p>This easing of visa rules indicates a positive shift for migrants while addressing labor shortages in New Zealand.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/new-zealand-relaxes-visa-rules-to-combat-labour-shortages-indian-migrants-may-be-impacted-9177839.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/new-zealand-relaxes-visa-rules-to-combat-labour-shortages-indian-migrants-may-be-impacted-9177839.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 11:45:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ralph Lauren, Michael J Fox honoured with Presidential Medal of Freedom - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ralph Lauren, Michael J Fox honoured with Presidential Medal of Freedom</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/US-POLITICS-MEDAL-BIDEN-52_1736076148686_1736076171368.jpg" alt="Ralph Lauren receives the Medal of Freedom from President Biden." title="Ralph Lauren receives the Medal of Freedom from President Biden."><figcaption>Fashion designer Ralph Lauren receives the Medal of Freedom from United States President Joe Biden during a ceremony at the White House in Washington, DC, January 4, 2025. (Photo by Chris Kleponis / AFP)(AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>Ralph Lauren and Michael J. Fox will be awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the highest civilian honor in the U.S. President Biden will present the awards during a ceremony.</p><ul><li>Ralph Lauren is recognized for his contributions to American style and culture spanning over six decades.</li><li>Michael J. Fox is also among the honorees, along with other notable figures like Denzel Washington and Messi.</li><li>The medal is awarded to individuals who have made exemplary contributions to the United States and beyond.</li><li>Ralph Lauren is the first fashion designer to receive this honor.</li></ul><blockquote>“These nineteen individuals are great leaders who have made America a better place.” – White House statement</blockquote><p>This award signifies the exceptional contributions of Lauren and Fox to society, celebrating their achievements and influence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/ralph-lauren-michael-j-fox-to-be-honoured-with-presidential-medal-of-freedom-101736075437175.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/ralph-lauren-michael-j-fox-to-be-honoured-with-presidential-medal-of-freedom-101736075437175.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 11:31:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid outrage over grooming gangs in UK, tweet of Muslim ‘journalist’ justifying sex with minors goes viral - OpIndia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UK: Tweet of 'journalist' Sulaiman Ahmed justifying sex with minors goes viral</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 5, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> OpIndia</p>
<img src="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/180725d442ad4738949a9efb00058db1?s=96&amp;d=mm&amp;r=g" alt="OpIndia Staff">
<figcaption>OpIndia Staff</figcaption>
<p>Amid growing outrage over the prevalence of grooming gangs in the UK, a controversial tweet by journalist Sulaiman Ahmed has sparked widespread condemnation for his justification of sexual acts with minors.</p>
<ul>
    <li>A two-year-old tweet by Sulaiman Ahmed attempted to deflect attention from Pakistani grooming gangs to white individuals.</li>
    <li>Ahmed claimed underage victims ‘consented’ to sexual acts, misleadingly framing statutory rape claims.</li>
    <li>Public backlash included criticisms from netizens and political commentators condemning Ahmed's views as dangerous and harmful.</li>
    <li>Ahmed has a history of defending controversial positions related to Pakistan and Islam.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Social workers said CONSENT was given by these women. When CONSENT is given there is no rape and there CANNOT be any grooming…” — Sulaiman Ahmed</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing discourse reveals significant tensions in how sexual violence is perceived and discussed in the context of ethnicity and religion within the UK.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.opindia.com/2025/01/uk-grooming-gangs-sulaiman-ahmed-tweet-statutory-rape-sex-with-minors-goes-viral/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opindia.com/2025/01/uk-grooming-gangs-sulaiman-ahmed-tweet-statutory-rape-sex-with-minors-goes-viral/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 11:28:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYC MS Halal food worker sparks outrage after catching pigeon with bare hands - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Outrage erupts as MS Halal Food worker grabs pigeon bare-handed in NYC, people call for stricter actions.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/Screenshot_2025-01-05_164932_1736075989114_1736075995261.png" alt="A viral video shows a worker from MS Halal Food cart in NYC catching a pigeon with bare hands, raising concerns about hygiene and food safety.(@unlimited_ls/X)" title="A viral video shows a worker from MS Halal Food cart in NYC catching a pigeon with bare hands, raising concerns about hygiene and food safety.(@unlimited_ls/X)"><figcaption>A viral video shows a worker from MS Halal Food cart in NYC catching a pigeon with bare hands, raising concerns about hygiene and food safety.(@unlimited_ls/X)</figcaption></img><p>A viral video capturing a worker from the MS Halal Food cart in New York City grabbing a pigeon with bare hands has ignited widespread outrage online. The footage has prompted calls for stricter hygiene regulations and greater accountability for street food vendors, as concerns over public health and food safety escalate.</p><ul><li>The worker was seen catching the pigeon directly off the pavement without gloves.</li><li>Footage shows the worker carrying the pigeon back into the food truck.</li><li>Onlookers expressed alarm and called for health department investigations.</li></ul><blockquote>A user wrote, “We used to have a thing called the health department !!! But I guess those days are gone forever !!!”</blockquote><p>The incident has raised significant public health concerns and has sparked discussions about food safety regulations concerning street vendors in NYC.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/nyc-ms-halal-food-worker-sparks-outrage-after-catching-pigeon-with-bare-hands-101736074701465.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/nyc-ms-halal-food-worker-sparks-outrage-after-catching-pigeon-with-bare-hands-101736074701465.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 11:23:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[18 crore people have been denied their voting rights, says Bangladesh CEC - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>18 Crore People Denied Voting Rights in Bangladesh, Says CEC</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> 05 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> The Dhaka Tribune</p><p>Bangladesh’s Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin announced that nearly 180 million people have been deprived of their voting rights, emphasizing the Election Commission's commitment to rectify this situation.</p><ul><li>The CEC addressed a training program for election officers focused on updating the voter list.</li><li>The Election Commission aims to alleviate the suffering of those deprived of voting rights.</li><li>Door-to-door data collection for updating the voter list will begin on January 20.</li><li>The CEC highlighted the need for a fair and credible election.</li><li>The commission will investigate irregularities in past elections, particularly the controversial elections held during the Awami League's governance.</li><li>Upcoming elections are expected around early 2026 after updating the voters’ list.</li></ul><blockquote>“We want to remove the pain of their deprivation. We are steadfast in our commitment.” - AMM Nasir Uddin</blockquote><p>This initiative reflects the Election Commission's commitment to ensuring a democratic process and addressing longstanding grievances regarding voting rights in Bangladesh.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/18-crore-people-have-been-denied-their-voting-rights-says-bangladesh-cec-3342171</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/18-crore-people-have-been-denied-their-voting-rights-says-bangladesh-cec-3342171</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 11:23:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India ruins Pakistan's 'tango' moment, says for Pakistan T is…; Islamabad tries to cajole Dhaka by referring - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Challenges Pakistan's Diplomatic Efforts Amid Rising Terrorism</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 3, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><figure><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/QT-shahbaz-BEFUN-1.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="India, Pakistan, tango, Islamabad, Dhaka, Ishaq Dar, Randhir Jaiswal, terrorism, PMLN, Bangladesh, Muhamad Yunus, Yunus, Afghanistan, TTP, Kabul, nuclear energy, Chashma 5, C5"><figcaption></figcaption></figure><p>India has responded critically to Pakistan's foreign minister Ishaq Dar's recent comments on improving bilateral relations, emphasizing that the key issue is terrorism rather than diplomatic gestures. Dar expressed intentions to rebuild ties with Bangladesh while addressing the challenges posed by terrorism in Pakistan.</p><ul><li>Ishaq Dar states, “It takes two to tango,” referring to the need for mutual effort in diplomacy.</li><li>MEA spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal replies, stating that the relevant 'T' word is 'terrorism'.</li><li>Dar plans to visit Bangladesh to strengthen ties, calling it a 'lost brother'.</li><li>Amid rising terrorism since the Taliban's takeover in Afghanistan, Pakistan is focusing on its nuclear power development.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bangladesh is like a lost brother. We aim to strengthen economic and trade cooperation,” said Ishaq Dar.</blockquote><p>The tensions between India and Pakistan remain high as both nations navigate complex geopolitical landscapes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/india/india-ruins-pakistans-tango-moment-says-for-pakistan-t-is-for-islamabad-tries-to-cajole-dhaka-by-referring-to-lost-terrorism-bangladesh-afghanistan-kabul-7515970/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/india/india-ruins-pakistans-tango-moment-says-for-pakistan-t-is-for-islamabad-tries-to-cajole-dhaka-by-referring-to-lost-terrorism-bangladesh-afghanistan-kabul-7515970/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 10:41:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[George Soros gets US' top civilian award, Elon Musk furious - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/george-soros-gets-us-top-civilian-award-elon-musk-furious-101736070729283.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/george-soros-gets-us-top-civilian-award-elon-musk-furious-101736070729283.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 10:02:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Ugly people, breakfast in tubes': Bizarre 100-year-old predictions about 2025 revealed - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bizarre 100-Year-Old Predictions About Life in 2025</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/Image_3_1664104876532_1736069355185.jpg" alt="While some of the prophecies seem absurd, many of them have weirdly came true.(Representational)"><figcaption>While some of the prophecies seem absurd, many of them have weirdly came true.(Representational)</figcaption><p>In 1925, thinkers made predictions about life in 2025, envisioning advancements in technology, societal changes, and global governance. Some visions have surprisingly come true while others remain bizarre.</p><ul><li>Albert E. Wiggam predicted a future where beauty declines due to 'homely' people's dominance in reproduction.</li><li>Sir Ronald Ross envisioned humans living up to 150 years, hinting at the possibility of immortality.</li><li>H.G. Wells theorized a world where global power is consolidated into three super-nations: USA, Europe, and China.</li><li>Predictions included a singular global language and currency, alongside freedoms in travel and trade.</li><li>Inventor Archibald M. Low forecasted futuristic gadgets such as breakfast tubes, automatic beds, and wireless banking.</li><li>Concerns about global hunger were raised, with predictions of artificial food supplies and portrayal of a future without poverty.</li></ul><blockquote>“There should be no pauper child in this country, and no able-bodied child should be anywhere except in its home.” - Sophie Irene Loeb</blockquote><p>The predictions from 1925 reflect a fascinating intersection of aspiration and absurdity, projecting a world that both challenges and inspires contemporary thought.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/ugly-people-breakfast-in-tubes-bizarre-100-year-old-predictions-about-2025-revealed-101736068715595.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/ugly-people-breakfast-in-tubes-bizarre-100-year-old-predictions-about-2025-revealed-101736068715595.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 09:42:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Coldest Countries in the World! Check India’s Rank! - Jagran Josh]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Which is the Coldest Country in the World? Check India’s Rank!</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>World Atlas</p><h2>Introduction</h2><p>The coldest inhabited place on Earth is Oymyakon in Russia, where temperatures can dip below -60°C. The article explores the coldest countries and highlights India's surprising ranking.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>The top three coldest countries are Canada, Russia, and Mongolia.</li><li>Alaska, part of the USA, does not rank among the coldest due to its overall climate.</li><li>India ranks 17th among the coldest countries, with northern regions experiencing severe winters.</li></ul><h2>List of Coldest Countries</h2><table><tr><th>Rank</th><th>Country</th><th>Average Yearly Temperature (°C)</th><th>Minimum Temperature (°C)</th></tr><tr><td>1</td><td>Canada</td><td>-5.35</td><td>-63.0</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>Russia</td><td>-5.10</td><td>-67.8</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>Mongolia</td><td>-0.70</td><td>-40.0</td></tr><tr><td>17</td><td>India</td><td>26</td><td>-50</td></tr></table><h2>Notable Quotes</h2><blockquote>“Snowfall is common in these regions, impacting local communities that rely on agriculture and tourism linked to winter sports.”</blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>Despite being known for its tropical climate, India's northern regions endure extreme winter conditions, placing it among the coldest countries in the world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jagranjosh.com/general-knowledge/list-of-coldest-countries-in-the-world-1736024760-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jagranjosh.com/general-knowledge/list-of-coldest-countries-in-the-world-1736024760-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 09:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S., China Engage In “Drone War”; Washington Mulls Rules To Ban “Superior” Chinese Drones - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>U.S., China Engage In "Drone War"; Washington Mulls Rules To Ban "Superior" Chinese Drones</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> EurAsian Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Su-57-1290-x-650-px-18.png" alt="Drone Technology Comparison"><figcaption>China vs US in drone technology. Edited Image.</figcaption></figure><p>President Joe Biden has proposed cutting China out of the drone supply chain amidst escalating trade tensions, coinciding with Beijing's bans on American companies.</p><ul><li>The US Department of Commerce is seeking public opinion on risks associated with China and Russia in drone technology.</li><li>Drones have become significant in modern warfare, with concerns over data security from adversaries.</li><li>China’s DJI faces scrutiny from the US for allegations of data leakage.</li><li>Both nations are intensely competing in the military tech domain, particularly with unmanned aerial vehicles.</li><li>Chinese advancements in drone technology are raising alarms in the US regarding national security.</li></ul><blockquote>“China’s development of new unmanned aerial vehicle capabilities for military use is rapidly catching up to the United States’ own advancements in the technology.”</blockquote><p>This ongoing conflict over drone technology highlights the broader implications of US-China relations and raises concerns about the future of international trade and technological security.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/u-s-and-china-decoupling-trade/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/u-s-and-china-decoupling-trade/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 08:44:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel is on target of Pakistan's nuclear missile, know the strength of Shaheen-3, US considers this missile - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel is on target of Pakistan's nuclear missile, know the strength of Shaheen-3, US considers this missile a...</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> <em>December 2024</em> <strong>Source:</strong> <em>India.com</em></p><figure><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pakistan-missile-us-shaheen.png?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Pakistan missile us shaheen"><figcaption>Pakistan was blackmailing US to act against India, started developing Washington killer missile after..., and then...</figcaption></figure><p>Pakistan's Shaheen-3 missile, capable of striking targets up to 2,700 kilometers away, raises concerns regarding its potential to target Israel. Experts discuss the implications of Pakistan's missile program amidst recent US sanctions on entities involved in this development.</p><ul><li>Shaheen-3 can reach any part of Israel.</li><li>Recent US sanctions targeted organizations contributing to Pakistan's missile capabilities.</li><li>The US considers the missile program a threat, with geopolitical implications for Israel.</li><li>No current intention from Pakistan to explicitly target Israel is noted.</li></ul><blockquote>“In light of the continuing proliferation threat of Pakistan’s long-range missile development, the United States is designating four entities for sanctions...” - US Department of State</blockquote><p>This development highlights growing military tensions in the region and reflects the broader geopolitical dynamics at play between Pakistan, the US, and Israel.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/israel-is-on-target-of-pakistans-nuclear-missile-know-the-strength-of-shaheen-3-us-considers-this-missile-a-7515677/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/israel-is-on-target-of-pakistans-nuclear-missile-know-the-strength-of-shaheen-3-us-considers-this-missile-a-7515677/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 08:39:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tourists who mocked burqa-clad woman in Dubai arrested - Aaj News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxOUlE4VThLTG9CSkE2MVVsYWl3eGprWURxaXN3N1Y0aFZkY19CR3J4RjloRW1MS1E4M0thN2FUYnI2aTVXSlhTZ2otOTRULWpYTHcxNDBPYVBHQkZXakRySFpGRFYwTEEzeGh4emkzeWdQZTdWb3VScjJsQ2FMMWdpMWk4RUJaaF96NnQydGo2dzVfdmlKa3lN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxOUlE4VThLTG9CSkE2MVVsYWl3eGprWURxaXN3N1Y0aFZkY19CR3J4RjloRW1MS1E4M0thN2FUYnI2aTVXSlhTZ2otOTRULWpYTHcxNDBPYVBHQkZXakRySFpGRFYwTEEzeGh4emkzeWdQZTdWb3VScjJsQ2FMMWdpMWk4RUJaaF96NnQydGo2dzVfdmlKa3lN?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 08:06:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8-year-old boy survives five days lost in Zimbabwe's dangerous lion-filled reserve, here's how - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>8-Year-Old Boy Survives Five Days Lost in Zimbabwe's Lion-Filled Reserve</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 05, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/05/550x309/rvdsc_xxssssssssddsssssssss_xssssss_1736063687135_1736063692585.jpg" alt="An 8-year-old boy survived 5 days in a Zimbabwe forest, enduring lions and elephants.(X)"><figcaption>An 8-year-old boy survived 5 days in a Zimbabwe forest, enduring lions and elephants.(X)</figcaption><p>An eight-year-old boy named Tinotenda Pundu survived five days in Matusadona National Park, Zimbabwe, by relying on wild fruits and digging for water after wandering away from his village.</p><ul><li>Tinotenda disappeared on December 27, 2024, and was found approximately 30 miles away from his home.</li><li>He survived by consuming tsvanzva fruit and digging for water along a riverbank.</li><li>The community, including park rangers and local residents, played a crucial role in the search and rescue efforts, using traditional methods to assist in locating him.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are overwhelmed with gratitude,” said MP Murombedzi. “The brave rangers, the tireless Nyaminyami community, and everyone who joined the search embody the power of unity, hope, and prayer.”</blockquote><p>This extraordinary survival story highlights the resilience and resourcefulness of the young boy and the collaborative efforts of his community.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/8yearold-boy-survives-five-days-lost-in-zimbabwes-dangerous-lion-filled-reserve-heres-how-101736063237252.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/8yearold-boy-survives-five-days-lost-in-zimbabwes-dangerous-lion-filled-reserve-heres-how-101736063237252.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:57:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea: Thousands protest for and against Yoon's arrest - DW (English)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Thousands Protest in South Korea Over President Yoon's Impeachment and Arrest</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Article Reporter</p><figure><img src="" alt="Anti-Yoon protesters attend a rally demanding the arrest of impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol on January 5, 2025" title="Anti-Yoon protesters attend a rally demanding the arrest of impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol on January 5, 2025"><figcaption>Protesters have rallied on the streets of Seoul in the sub-zero weather<small>Image: Ahn Young-joon/AP Photo/picture alliance</small></figcaption></figure><p>Thousands gathered in Seoul as protests erupted both for and against the impeachment of President Yoon Suk Yeol amidst a national crisis that has reached a boiling point.</p><ul><li>Protests took place near Yoon's residence with supporters and opponents clashing.</li><li>An arrest warrant for Yoon is set to expire soon, raising tensions for a possible standoff.</li><li>Anti-Yoon protesters are demanding his ouster due to legal and constitutional concerns.</li><li>Conversely, pro-Yoon supporters rallied to express their support and denounce the impeachment.</li></ul><blockquote>“We must bring down the criminal Yoon Suk Yeol and arrest and detain him as soon as possible.” - Yang Kyung-soo, leader of the Korean Confederation of Trade Unions</blockquote><p>The protests reflect the deep societal divisions over President Yoon’s leadership as the nation braces for potential upheaval.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dw.com/en/south-korea-thousands-brave-cold-to-protest-for-and-against-yoon/a-71218834</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dw.com/en/south-korea-thousands-brave-cold-to-protest-for-and-against-yoon/a-71218834</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:55:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia: Multiple visits to Rawdah in Madinah allowed annually, conditions apply - The Siasat Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saudi Arabia Allows Multiple Visits to Rawdah in Madinah Annually</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> April 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Siasat Daily</p><figure><img src="https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Rawdah-Madinah.jpg" alt="Saudi Arabia: Multiple visits to Rawdah in Madinah allowed annually, conditions apply" width="1200" height="900"><figcaption> Photo: @imarat_almadina/X </figcaption></figure><p>Worshippers will now be allowed to visit Al-Rawdah Al-Sharifa in the Prophet’s Mosque in Madinah more than once throughout the year, according to an update from the Nusuk application.</p><ul><li>The permit to visit is available every 20 minutes.</li><li>Visits are allowed as long as individuals are in close proximity to the Prophet’s Mosque.</li><li>Users must update the Nusuk app and activate the GPS feature during booking.</li><li>Booking must be done via the instant track.</li></ul><p>In December 2023, Saudi Arabia’s Ministry of Haj and Umrah announced the permit availability for visiting Rawdah only once a year, but this new update relaxes those restrictions.</p><blockquote>“More than ten million worshippers performed prayers in Rawdah during the year 2024.”</blockquote><p>Since the beginning of 2024, over 57,923 tonnes of Zamzam water have been provided to visitors, and 2.4 million worshippers have benefitted from a perfuming service at the mosque.</p><p>This decision allows greater flexibility for worshippers who undertake Umrah at Makkah’s Grand Mosque and wish to visit Rawdah for prayer.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.siasat.com/saudi-arabia-multiple-visits-to-rawdah-in-madinah-allowed-annually-conditions-apply-3159737/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.siasat.com/saudi-arabia-multiple-visits-to-rawdah-in-madinah-allowed-annually-conditions-apply-3159737/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:54:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Take Decisions Thinking Your Kids Are Hostages’: Captive’s Kin To Netanyahu As Hamas Releases Video - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Take Decisions Thinking Your Kids Are Hostages’: Captive’s Kin To Netanyahu As Hamas Releases Video</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 05, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Liri Albag, Hamas captive, was spotted in a video released by the Palestinian militant group." title="Liri Albag, Hamas captive, was spotted in a video released by the Palestinian militant group." loading="eager"><figcaption>Liri Albag, Hamas captive, was spotted in a video released by the Palestinian militant group. (IMAGE: X)</figcaption></figure><p>The family of 19-year-old Liri Albag urged Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and global leaders to consider their own children’s safety when making decisions, following the release of a video by Hamas showing Albag, who has been held in captivity in Gaza since her kidnapping on October 7, 2023.</p><ul><li>Hamas released a video featuring Liri Albag, appealing for her release.</li><li>Albag was kidnapped along with six other women conscripts; five remain captive.</li><li>The family called for decision-makers to act with urgency regarding the hostages.</li><li>Negotiations for a truce and hostage release are ongoing in Qatar.</li><li>There is public pressure on Prime Minister Netanyahu to finalize a deal for the hostages' return.</li></ul><blockquote>The family stated, “We appeal to the prime minister, world leaders and all decision-makers: it’s time to take decisions as if it were your own children there.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, this appeal reflects the deep emotional impact of the hostage crisis on families and calls for compassionate action from political leaders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/take-decisions-thinking-your-kids-are-hostages-captives-kin-to-netanyahu-as-hamas-releases-video-9177565.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/take-decisions-thinking-your-kids-are-hostages-captives-kin-to-netanyahu-as-hamas-releases-video-9177565.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:16:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baba Vanga's Predictions for 2025: 5 Zodiac Signs That Will Thrive in 2025 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baba Vanga's Predictions for 2025: 5 Zodiac Signs That Will Thrive in 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Published on: </strong>October 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Baba Vanga Predictions Image" />
<figcaption>Baba Vanga's astrological insights for 2025.</figcaption>
<p>Baba Vanga, a famous clairvoyant, has made some intriguing predictions for the year 2025. According to her, five zodiac signs are set to experience significant positive changes and thrive.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The predictions highlight the zodiac signs that will have favorable opportunities in 2025.</li>
  <li>Individuals under these signs can expect improvements in their personal and professional lives.</li>
  <li>Baba Vanga is known for her unique insights, and this prediction continues to draw interest in astrology.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Predictions for the future are made based on the cosmic alignments and energies at play during that time."</blockquote>
<p>The anticipated impact of these predictions on the followers of astrology could cultivate hope and inspire preparation for the forthcoming year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/astrology/zodiacs-astrology/baba-vangas-predictions-for-2025-5-zodiac-signs-that-will-thrive-in-2025/articleshow/116960592.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/astrology/zodiacs-astrology/baba-vangas-predictions-for-2025-5-zodiac-signs-that-will-thrive-in-2025/articleshow/116960592.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea protesters rally for, against Yoon arrest as deadline looms - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/south-korea-protesters-rally-against-yoon-arrest-deadline-looms-2025-01-05/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/south-korea-protesters-rally-against-yoon-arrest-deadline-looms-2025-01-05/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 07:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>