<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:23:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:23:48 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Oh Canada’: Trump shares map with 51 US states - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump's Controversial Map: Is America Now 51 States?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The Times</p><p>Donald Trump recently sparked attention by sharing a map that depicts the United States as having 51 states. This surprising act has raised eyebrows and generated discussions regarding its implications.</p><ul><li>Trump shared a map on social media suggesting the USA has 51 states.</li><li>The map's origins and reasoning behind the addition of a new state are unclear.</li><li>This image has generated a mix of amusement and concern among the public.</li><li>Reactions from political figures and Twitter users have varied widely.</li></ul><blockquote>'It's more of a faux pas than a policy statement,' said one political analyst.</blockquote><p>The incident highlights the often-blurred lines between social media and official political discourse.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/oh-canada-trump-shares-map-with-51-us-states/articleshow/117042228.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/oh-canada-trump-shares-map-with-51-us-states/articleshow/117042228.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Is Trump Threatening To Take Greenland, Panama Canal, Canada? His Imperialist Agenda Explained - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-is-trump-threatening-to-take-greenland-panama-canal-canada-his-imperialist-agenda-explained-9181542.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-is-trump-threatening-to-take-greenland-panama-canal-canada-his-imperialist-agenda-explained-9181542.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Oh Canada!’: Donald Trump shares distorted unified US-Canada map, Justin Trudeau's Liberal Party responds - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump shares distorted map showing Canada as part of the United States</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US_1736311434165_1736311434433.jpg" alt="Donald Trump shares distorted unified US-Canada map" />
<figcaption>Donald Trump shares distorted unified US-Canada map (Photo by SCOTT OLSON / GETTY IMAGES NORTH AMERICA / Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Donald Trump posted a distorted map suggesting Canada should be part of the US alongside a caption on Truth Social. This has drawn a swift response from Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's Liberal Party.</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump's post referenced a distorted vision of a unified US and Canada.</li>
<li>The Canadian Liberal Party posted a response distinguishing the US from Canada.</li>
<li>Trump has previously expressed interest in integrating Canada as the 51st state.</li>
<li>He suggested using "economic force" rather than military to pursue this ambition.</li>
<li>Trudeau firmly rejected the notion, stating there's no chance Canada would join the US.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There isn’t a snowball’s chance in hell that Canada would become part of the United States.” - Justin Trudeau</blockquote>
<p>This incident underscores the ongoing tensions and differing views regarding US-Canada relations, highlighting Trump's controversial approach to foreign policy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-distorted-unified-us-canada-map-justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-responds-101736311061282.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-distorted-unified-us-canada-map-justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-responds-101736311061282.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:47:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles: Pacific Palisades destroys cars and houses, forcing 30,000 to evacuate | Updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wildfire in Pacific Palisades Forces Mass Evacuations in Los Angeles</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-70_1736307148546_1736307193321.jpg' alt='Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)'><figcaption>Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)</figcaption><p>A dangerous wildfire in Pacific Palisades has devastated nearly 3,000 acres and forced over 30,000 residents to evacuate amid fierce windstorms.</p><ul><li>The blaze leveled homes and forced mass evacuations.</li><li>Strong winds are complicating firefighting efforts, leading to widespread panic.</li><li>Firefighters are working to contain the fire from both ground and air.</li><li>No immediate reports of deaths or injuries have been reported.</li><li>Federal aid has been approved to assist with firefighting efforts.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite the chaotic evacuation, there were no immediate reports of any deaths or injuries.” - Los Angeles Fire Department Chief Kristin Crowley</blockquote><p>The ongoing wildfire represents a significant threat to residents and property, and immediate efforts are underway to combat and contain the flames.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:30:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles wildfire: Pacific Palisades declares emergency, President Joe Biden approves aid | Updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wildfire in Pacific Palisades Forces 30,000 to Evacuate</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-70_1736307148546_1736307193321.jpg" alt="Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)" title="Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)"><figcaption>Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>A dangerous wildfire has ravaged the Pacific Palisades area of Los Angeles, destroying nearly 3,000 acres of land and forcing over 30,000 residents to evacuate. The situation has been exacerbated by hurricane-force winds.</p><ul><li>The fire erupted midmorning amid seasonal Santa Ana winds.</li><li>Firefighters are working on the ground and from the air to contain the blaze.</li><li>As of Tuesday evening, over 28,300 households were without power.</li></ul><blockquote>“There are no immediate reports of any deaths or injuries.” - Kristin Crowley, Chief of Los Angeles Fire Department</blockquote><p>This wildfire marks a significant emergency in the region, prompting federal aid approval from President Joe Biden.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:30:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tibet earthquake aftermath: Thousands of homes destroyed, 126 killed as rescue efforts continue - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tibet earthquake aftermath: Thousands of homes destroyed, 126 killed as rescue efforts continue</h1><p><strong>Published: January 08, 2025 08:53 am IST</strong></p><p><strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/v6jbl5/article69075120.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/tibet.jpg" alt="Rescue efforts in Tibet" /><figcaption>Rescue efforts in Tibet</figcaption><p>A powerful 7.1 magnitude earthquake struck Tibet, leading to significant destruction and loss of life, with multiple rescue operations ongoing to find survivors trapped under rubble.</p><ul><li>The earthquake occurred on January 7, 2025, with its epicenter in Tingri, Tibet, about 80 km north of Mount Everest.</li><li>More than 400 people have been rescued from trapped locations, with over 30,000 residents relocated.</li><li>At least 126 casualties have been reported, with 188 injured on the Tibetan side of the border.</li><li>3,609 homes were destroyed, impacting a population of around 800,000 in the Shigatse region.</li><li>Rescue teams face challenges due to freezing temperatures dropping to minus 18 degrees Celsius.</li><li>An extensive aftershock sequence has been noted, with over 500 aftershocks recorded post-earthquake.</li></ul><blockquote>"More than 500 aftershocks with magnitudes of up to 4.4 had followed the quake…"</blockquote><p>The ongoing rescue efforts and relief operations are crucial in addressing the aftermath of this devastating earthquake and ensuring the safety of affected residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/tibet-earthquake-several-killed-houses-destroyed-updates-january-8/article69074939.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/tibet-earthquake-several-killed-houses-destroyed-updates-january-8/article69074939.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thousands of homes destroyed, 126 killed as rescue efforts continue after earthquake in Tibet - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tibet earthquake aftermath: Thousands of homes destroyed, 126 killed as rescue efforts continue</h1><p><strong>Published: January 08, 2025 08:53 am IST</strong></p><p><strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/v6jbl5/article69075120.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/tibet.jpg" alt="Rescue efforts in Tibet" /><figcaption>Rescue efforts in Tibet</figcaption><p>A powerful 7.1 magnitude earthquake struck Tibet, leading to significant destruction and loss of life, with multiple rescue operations ongoing to find survivors trapped under rubble.</p><ul><li>The earthquake occurred on January 7, 2025, with its epicenter in Tingri, Tibet, about 80 km north of Mount Everest.</li><li>More than 400 people have been rescued from trapped locations, with over 30,000 residents relocated.</li><li>At least 126 casualties have been reported, with 188 injured on the Tibetan side of the border.</li><li>3,609 homes were destroyed, impacting a population of around 800,000 in the Shigatse region.</li><li>Rescue teams face challenges due to freezing temperatures dropping to minus 18 degrees Celsius.</li><li>An extensive aftershock sequence has been noted, with over 500 aftershocks recorded post-earthquake.</li></ul><blockquote>"More than 500 aftershocks with magnitudes of up to 4.4 had followed the quake…"</blockquote><p>The ongoing rescue efforts and relief operations are crucial in addressing the aftermath of this devastating earthquake and ensuring the safety of affected residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/tibet-earthquake-several-killed-houses-destroyed-updates-january-8/article69074939.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/tibet-earthquake-several-killed-houses-destroyed-updates-january-8/article69074939.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump shares distorted map showing Canada part of US, Justin Trudeau’s party clears ‘confusion’ - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Oh Canada!’: Donald Trump shares distorted map showing Canada part of US, Justin Trudeau’s party clears ‘confusion’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>US President-elect Donald Trump shared a distorted map on social media suggesting Canada is part of the United States, prompting a swift response from Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau’s Liberal Party.</p><ul><li>Trump posted the map on TRUTH, calling it 'Oh Canada!'.</li><li>The Liberal Party clarified the US-Canada border with an image on social media.</li><li>Trump reiterated his position that Canada should be the '51st State'.</li><li>Trudeau rebuffed Trump's comments, emphasizing Canada's sovereignty.</li><li>Trump expressed his intent to acquire Canada using 'economic force'.</li></ul><blockquote>“There isn’t a snowball’s chance in hell that Canada would become part of the United States.” — Justin Trudeau</blockquote><p>The incident highlights ongoing tensions surrounding Trump's comments about Canada as he prepares to take office again.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-new-map-showing-canada-part-of-us-11736306229715.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-new-map-showing-canada-part-of-us-11736306229715.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:17:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘All hell will break…’: Donald Trump warns Hamas as he sets deadline for hostages' release - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Issues Stark Warning to Hamas Over Hostages Ahead of Inauguration</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Jan 08, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US-PRESIDENT-ELECT-TRUMP-HOLDS-PRESS-CONFERENCE-AT_1736303409052_1736303409570.jpg" alt="Donald Trump also refused to rule out the use of military force to take control of the Panama Canal(Getty Images via AFP)" title="Donald Trump also refused to rule out the use of military force to take control of the Panama Canal(Getty Images via AFP)">
<figcaption>Donald Trump also refused to rule out the use of military force to take control of the Panama Canal(Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption>
<p>US President-elect Donald Trump delivered a stern warning during a press conference in Florida, stating “all hell will break out in the Middle East” if Hamas does not release its hostages in Gaza before his inauguration on January 20.</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump's warning highlights the escalating tensions in the Middle East regarding the hostage situation.</li>
<li>He expressed that the situation would be detrimental not only to Hamas but to everyone involved.</li>
<li>Trump appointed Steve Witkoff as special envoy to the Middle East, who noted a cautiously optimistic view on ceasefire talks.</li>
<li>The Biden administration officials are reportedly leading negotiations, with Trump’s team being kept informed.</li>
<li>Trump also hinted at the potential use of military force regarding territorial claims over the Panama Canal and Greenland.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It will not be good for Hamas and it will not be good, frankly, for anyone. All hell will break out.” - Donald Trump</blockquote>
<p>The press conference reflects Trump's aggressive stance on foreign policy and his ongoing involvement in international negotiations prior to taking office.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/all-hell-will-break-donald-trump-warns-hamas-as-he-sets-deadline-for-hostages-release-january-20-inauguration-101736303112432.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/all-hell-will-break-donald-trump-warns-hamas-as-he-sets-deadline-for-hostages-release-january-20-inauguration-101736303112432.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:03:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘All Hell Will Break Out In Middle East...’: Trump's Deadline For Hamas To Return Hostages - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Issues Deadline for Hamas to Return Hostages</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="US President-elect Donald Trump was convicted of all felony counts in the hush money case. (AP image)"><figcaption>US President-elect Donald Trump was convicted of all felony counts in the hush money case. (AP image)</figcaption><p>Donald Trump warns of severe consequences if Hamas does not release hostages by his inauguration date.</p><ul><li>Trump sets January 20 as the deadline for Hamas to return hostages.</li><li>He warned that “all hell will break out” in the Middle East if hostages are not released.</li><li>Trump expressed frustration about the ongoing hostage crisis and criticized Hamas for their actions.</li></ul><blockquote>“All hell will break out. If those hostages aren’t back... all hell will break out in the Middle East.” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>Trump's statements have amplified concerns about the hostage situation and potential Middle Eastern tensions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-warns-hamas-all-hell-will-break-out-if-hostages-not-released-by-jan-20-9181418.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-warns-hamas-all-hell-will-break-out-if-hostages-not-released-by-jan-20-9181418.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:14:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump warns Hamas that all hell will break out if hostages not released before his inauguration - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Warns Hamas that All Hell Will Break Out if Hostages Not Released Before His Inauguration</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/o9b9a/article69074875.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-22T185749Z_1682455386_RC2HUBAJW3SP_RTRMADP_3_USA-TRUMP.JPG" alt="File picture of U.S. President-elect Donald Trump">
<figcaption>File picture of U.S. President-elect Donald Trump | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption>
<p>U.S. President-elect Donald Trump warned Hamas that “all hell will break out” if hostages are not released before his inauguration on January 20, 2025.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump emphasized the importance of hostage release during a press conference at Mar-a-Lago, Florida.</li>
  <li>He warned that failure to return hostages by his swearing-in would escalate tensions in the Middle East.</li>
  <li>Trump's Special Envoy to the Middle East, Steven Charles Witkoff, indicated progress was being made in negotiations for the hostages’ release.</li>
  <li>Trump criticized Hamas for their previous actions and questioned their treatment of hostages.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“All hell will break out. If those hostages aren’t back, I don’t want to hurt your negotiation, if they’re not back by the time I get into office...” - Donald Trump</blockquote>
<p>Trump reiterated the urgency of the situation, affirming his commitment to the issue and the lives at stake.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-warns-hamas-that-all-hell-will-break-out-if-hostages-not-released-before-his-inauguration/article69074873.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-warns-hamas-that-all-hell-will-break-out-if-hostages-not-released-before-his-inauguration/article69074873.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indonesia places a $28bn bet on free school meals - Financial Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTE5zNC1lZUVETmZ1RlZFMXVmNXNoUVk1Vkg5T3VydlBfdUZkcV9MYU5qNERWTTM5Z1N2V2ZwcENRQ1BMQmFyVE50VlA1b2VOdzdaOW9KOS1HUFFNQUVQR3M2NEd0eFMweGlrRjFEbExZbnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTE5zNC1lZUVETmZ1RlZFMXVmNXNoUVk1Vkg5T3VydlBfdUZkcV9MYU5qNERWTTM5Z1N2V2ZwcENRQ1BMQmFyVE50VlA1b2VOdzdaOW9KOS1HUFFNQUVQR3M2NEd0eFMweGlrRjFEbExZbnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:03:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-soldier who exploded Tesla Cybertruck used ChatGPT to plan attack - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ex-soldier who exploded Tesla Cybertruck used ChatGPT to plan attack</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>A former soldier has been accused of using ChatGPT to strategize an explosion involving a Tesla Cybertruck. The incident raises concerns about the influence of AI on dangerous actions.</p><ul><li>Suspect is a former soldier with prior military training.</li><li>ChatGPT was reportedly used to formulate plans for the attack.</li><li>The incident underscores potential risks of AI technologies in criminal activities.</li></ul><blockquote>"This case highlights the potential for artificial intelligence to be misused in planning and executing dangerous actions."</blockquote><p>The event illustrates the growing intersection between technology and crime, stressing the need for vigilance regarding AI applications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/ex-soldier-who-exploded-tesla-cybertruck-used-chatgpt-to-plan-attack/articleshow/117038205.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/ex-soldier-who-exploded-tesla-cybertruck-used-chatgpt-to-plan-attack/articleshow/117038205.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US wildfire: 30,000 ordered to evacuate as blaze rages through Los Angeles hillsides - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US wildfire: 30,000 ordered to evacuate as blaze rages through Los Angeles hillsides</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>Authorities have issued evacuation orders for 30,000 residents as a massive wildfire continues to spread through the hillsides of Los Angeles, creating dangerous conditions and prompting emergency responses.</p><ul><li>Evacuations are mandatory in specific areas affected by the fire.</li><li>The blaze has consumed significant vegetation and threatens homes and infrastructure.</li><li>Fire crews are working around the clock to contain the fire.</li><li>Weather conditions are complicating firefighting efforts with high winds and low humidity.</li></ul><blockquote>“The safety of our community is our top priority, and we urge residents to comply with evacuation orders.” - Local Fire Official</blockquote><p>This wildfire serves as a reminder of the ongoing challenges posed by climate change and its impact on wildfire frequency and severity in California.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/us-wildfire-30000-ordered-to-evacuate-as-blaze-rages-through-los-angeles-hillsides/articleshow/117037754.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/us-wildfire-30000-ordered-to-evacuate-as-blaze-rages-through-los-angeles-hillsides/articleshow/117037754.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All hell will break out: Trumps deadline for Hamas to release hostages - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxPT3ItdDlZZWROTFJJM1N6X2FuR0xPXzNMWDZhZkRkVEpBVm5xX2JmWWl5YUlXMTROYmE5NEd0dVYyN2ZhTVNUM3Mxd2g3MjduNG9SY19kdmFfOGxncUp6SlJJVTlSdkV0LXU1WmhiRzNYczBxcGZTMloyX2ppSXI4SzB4dU9tSDg5VDhwbmN0bHJ4emhfMm9XeloyT0E1X1pRQWdHMVdqQ2ZicVVvMUwtR2NMYld4a0VqcjN6WDVDS0IyWFY2cVd2LWV3WkdlUDDSAdMBQVVfeXFMTzdFMmRwTWxOTFYtWEdiWllSZVQ1enEwbWNyU0Q4dS0xU0JUQ0V2dXU2a00yT0V6MlZaRnFORWJYX1VXam9ZMkx2M0JnWWRURFNEc2NDLVhyc3pVQzdULU0tVDJzcXh5LVVMWlI0UkN2b25CWVZWN1FrNEF6bkFBcS01aWYyQnJ2VGxad2xZV3hqYm1iR24zMXBNVnZ3ZS15a3BqNVF4czczQWVFS0lrOWFHdVZIdGNBQzlMMVNTeWlxcFc5Y2lRQVRhM0N1cUI4RnUxNA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxPT3ItdDlZZWROTFJJM1N6X2FuR0xPXzNMWDZhZkRkVEpBVm5xX2JmWWl5YUlXMTROYmE5NEd0dVYyN2ZhTVNUM3Mxd2g3MjduNG9SY19kdmFfOGxncUp6SlJJVTlSdkV0LXU1WmhiRzNYczBxcGZTMloyX2ppSXI4SzB4dU9tSDg5VDhwbmN0bHJ4emhfMm9XeloyT0E1X1pRQWdHMVdqQ2ZicVVvMUwtR2NMYld4a0VqcjN6WDVDS0IyWFY2cVd2LWV3WkdlUDDSAdMBQVVfeXFMTzdFMmRwTWxOTFYtWEdiWllSZVQ1enEwbWNyU0Q4dS0xU0JUQ0V2dXU2a00yT0V6MlZaRnFORWJYX1VXam9ZMkx2M0JnWWRURFNEc2NDLVhyc3pVQzdULU0tVDJzcXh5LVVMWlI0UkN2b25CWVZWN1FrNEF6bkFBcS01aWYyQnJ2VGxad2xZV3hqYm1iR24zMXBNVnZ3ZS15a3BqNVF4czczQWVFS0lrOWFHdVZIdGNBQzlMMVNTeWlxcFc5Y2lRQVRhM0N1cUI4RnUxNA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:36:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Las Vegas police admit using generative AI to explode Tesla Cybertruck outside Trump Hotel was pure ‘game-changer’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/las-vegas-police-admit-using-generative-ai-to-explode-tesla-cybertruck-outside-trump-hotel-was-pure-gamechanger-101736299463394.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/las-vegas-police-admit-using-generative-ai-to-explode-tesla-cybertruck-outside-trump-hotel-was-pure-gamechanger-101736299463394.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:34:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Canada's Justin Trudeau reacts sharply to Donald Trump's 51st state idea: 'There isn't a snowball's chance…' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trudeau Responds to Trump's 51st State Remark with Firm Rejection</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/CANADA-TRUDEAU-1_1736299623981_1736299634220.jpg" alt="Justin Trudeau, Canada's prime minister, speaks during a news conference at Rideau Cottage in Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, on Monday,(Bloomberg)" title="Justin Trudeau, Canada's prime minister, speaks during a news conference at Rideau Cottage in Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, on Monday,(Bloomberg)"><figcaption>Justin Trudeau, Canada's prime minister, speaks during a news conference at Rideau Cottage in Ottawa, Ontario, Canada, on Monday,(Bloomberg)</figcaption></figure><p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau strongly rejected US President-elect Donald Trump's suggestion of making Canada the 51st state using economic force.</p><ul><li>Trudeau stated, "There isn't a snowball's chance in hell that Canada would become part of the United States."</li><li>He emphasized the mutual benefits of Canada and the US being each other’s biggest trading and security partners.</li><li>Trump expressed a desire to “get rid of the artificially drawn line” between the countries and mentioned a $200 billion subsidy to Canada from the US.</li><li>Trump has threatened a 25% tariff on Canadian imports, impacting Canada's exports significantly.</li><li>Canadian foreign minister Melanie Joly criticized Trump’s comments, emphasizing Canada's strength and independence.</li><li>Trudeau revealed plans to step down amidst political pressures and declining popularity.</li></ul><blockquote>“Canada will never be the 51st state. Period. We are a great and independent country.” - Pierre Poilievre, Conservative leader</blockquote><p>This exchange highlights ongoing tensions regarding trade and national identity between Canada and the US, especially in the context of Trump’s controversial remarks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/canadas-justin-trudeau-reacts-sharply-to-donald-trumps-51st-state-idea-there-isnt-a-snowballs-chance-101736296059331.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/canadas-justin-trudeau-reacts-sharply-to-donald-trumps-51st-state-idea-there-isnt-a-snowballs-chance-101736296059331.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:28:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump threatens ‘economic force’ to make Canada 51st state: Takeaways - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump threatens ‘economic force’ to make Canada 51st state: Takeaways</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US-PRESIDENT-ELECT-TRUMP-HOLDS-PRESS-CONFERENCE-AT_1736298181292_1736298181576.jpg" alt="President-elect Donald Trump speaks to members of the media during a press conference at the Mar-a-Lago Club on January 07, in Palm Beach, Florida. (Getty Images via AFP)" title="President-elect Donald Trump speaks to members of the media during a press conference at the Mar-a-Lago Club on January 07, in Palm Beach, Florida. (Getty Images via AFP)"><figcaption>President-elect Donald Trump speaks to members of the media during a press conference at the Mar-a-Lago Club on January 07, in Palm Beach, Florida. (Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption></img><p>Donald Trump has suggested using economic force against Canada to pressure it into becoming the 51st state, citing trade deficits and military concerns.</p><ul><li>Trump intends to impose substantial tariffs on Canadian goods.</li><li>He criticized US subsidies to Canada and suggested that the US should no longer accept Canadian products without reciprocation.</li><li>Trump emphasized the military assistance the US provides Canada, claiming it results in a trade deficit.</li><li>He voiced criticism of Mexico, pointing to trade imbalances and security issues tied to drug cartels.</li><li>Trump has threatened tougher stances and tariffs against both Canada and Mexico if they do not address illegal immigration and drug trafficking.</li></ul><blockquote>“Canada, don't take our cars, our farm products, anything, so we won't take their products either.”</blockquote><p>This statement reflects Trump's aggressive trade policy approach and vision for US-Canada relations, raising questions about future diplomatic and economic interactions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/donald-trump-threatens-economic-force-to-make-canada-51st-state-takeaways-101736296025264.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/donald-trump-threatens-economic-force-to-make-canada-51st-state-takeaways-101736296025264.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:24:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Many structures already destroyed in Pacific Palisades wildfire, California governor says - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Many structures already destroyed in Pacific Palisades wildfire, California governor says</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 08, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Associated Press</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/foqqlp/article68456233.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/AP07_27_2024_000092B.jpg" alt="Wildfire in Pacific Palisades" /><figcaption>Smoke from the wildfire visible across Los Angeles.</figcaption><p>A fast-moving wildfire in the Los Angeles area has already destroyed many structures as strong winds exacerbate the situation, prompting evacuation efforts for nearly 26,000 residents.</p><ul><li>Firefighters are battling a wildfire fueled by a fierce windstorm.</li><li>Over 13,000 structures are under threat, with many already destroyed.</li><li>Residents reported being trapped and abandoning their vehicles.</li><li>The winds are predicted to create extreme fire conditions lasting for days.</li><li>President Biden canceled plans due to the severe weather caused by the fire.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is not a parking lot,” actor Steve Guttenberg stated, urging residents to leave keys behind for fire trucks.</blockquote><p>The situation remains dire as officials continue to assess the damage and work on safety measures for residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/california-wildfire-destruction-in-los-angeles-updates-january-8/article69074832.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/california-wildfire-destruction-in-los-angeles-updates-january-8/article69074832.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Canada's immigration debate soured and helped seal Trudeau's fate - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Canada's immigration debate soured and helped seal Trudeau's fate</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 6, 2024 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> BBC</p><figure><img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/4be7/live/3b5b5e40-cd0c-11ef-94cb-5f844ceb9e30.png.webp" alt="BBC Montage image with Justin Trudeau in front of Canadian flags, with headshot of Trump below "><figcaption>Image credit: BBC</figcaption></figure><p>Immigration has turned into a polarizing issue in Canada for the first time, contributing to Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's resignation amidst rising public discontent about housing shortages and rents.</p><ul><li>Housing issues have worsened in Canada; rental prices increased by almost 20% in three years.</li><li>2.4 million Canadian families live in unsuitable housing, reported a government watchdog.</li><li>The percentage of Canadians believing there are too many immigrants rose from 27% in 2022 to 58% in 2024.</li><li>Campaign groups and protests against immigration have sprouted across the country.</li><li>Trudeau resigned amid public dissatisfaction, with his approval dropping from 65% to just 22% during his tenure.</li></ul><blockquote>“While immigration may not have been the immediate cause of the resignation, it may have been the icing on the cake.” - Professor Jonathan Rose</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the evolving sentiment surrounding immigration in Canada has highlighted significant socio-economic challenges, prompting political shifts as the country prepares for its next leadership chapter.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8rjzr7vexmo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8rjzr7vexmo</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 23:51:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forcing Canada's hand, Hamas' last warning, Gulf of Mexico and NATO: All about Donald Trump's presser - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump's News Conference: Military Threats and Economic Coercion</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 07 January 2025, 22:04 IST</p><div><p>In a lengthy news conference, President-elect Donald Trump threatened military and economic coercion against Panama and Denmark, reiterated a warning about hostages held by Hamas, and criticized various policies of the Biden administration.</p><ul><li>Trump suggested the use of military force to retake the Panama Canal and to acquire Greenland.</li><li>He warned that 'all hell will break out in the Middle East' if hostages held by Hamas are not released by Inauguration Day.</li><li>Trump criticized Biden's foreign policy, particularly regarding NATO and the war in Ukraine.</li><li>He expressed disdain for Biden's energy policy, including his focus on electric vehicles and restrictions on drilling.</li><li>Trump mentioned that Canada could become a US state due to the economic support provided by the US.</li></ul><blockquote>"If they're not back by the time I get into office, all hell will break out in the Middle East."</blockquote><p>This news conference highlighted Trump's combative style and his intent to assert control over the narrative leading up to his inauguration.</p></div>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/forcing-canadas-hand-hamas-last-warning-gulf-of-mexico-and-nato-all-about-donald-trumps-presser-3345660</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/forcing-canadas-hand-hamas-last-warning-gulf-of-mexico-and-nato-all-about-donald-trumps-presser-3345660</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 22:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man who exploded Tesla Cybertruck outside Trump hotel used ChatGPT to help plan attack: Las Vegas Police - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Man Used ChatGPT to Plan Tesla Cybertruck Explosion Outside Trump Hotel</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 07:15 AM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/TESLA-CYBERTRUCK-FIRE-2_1735956877410_1736286750072.JPG" alt="Investigators inspect the burned Tesla Cybertruck, which the police say was driven by Matthew Livelsberger, 37, an active-duty Army soldier from Colorado Springs, after it exploded in front of the Trump International Hotel in Las Vegas.(REUTERS)" title="Investigators inspect the burned Tesla Cybertruck, which the police say was driven by Matthew Livelsberger, 37, an active-duty Army soldier from Colorado Springs, after it exploded in front of the Trump International Hotel in Las Vegas.(REUTERS)">
<figcaption>Investigators inspect the burned Tesla Cybertruck, which the police say was driven by Matthew Livelsberger, 37, an active-duty Army soldier from Colorado Springs, after it exploded in front of the Trump International Hotel in Las Vegas.(REUTERS)</figcaption>
<p>The Las Vegas police reported that Matthew Livelsberger, a decorated Army soldier, used generative AI tools like ChatGPT to assist in planning the explosion of a Tesla Cybertruck outside the Trump hotel. He fatally shot himself shortly before the explosion.</p>
<ul>
<li>Livelsberger had looked for information about explosive targets and the legality of fireworks.</li>
<li>The Cybertruck contained 60 pounds of pyrotechnic material and racing-grade fuel.</li>
<li>The explosion resulted in minor injuries to seven individuals, but minimal damage to the hotel.</li>
<li>Livelsberger left notes citing political grievances and a desire for a “wake up call” regarding national issues.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is the first incident that I’m aware of on US soil where ChatGPT is utilized to help an individual build a particular device,” said Kevin McMahill, sheriff of the Las Vegas Metropolitan Police Department.</blockquote>
<p>This incident raises concerns about the use of generative AI in planning dangerous acts, as multiple government agencies continue to investigate the implications.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/generative-ai-used-to-plan-tesla-cybertruck-explosion-outside-trump-hotel-las-vegas-police-101736286317672.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/generative-ai-used-to-plan-tesla-cybertruck-explosion-outside-trump-hotel-las-vegas-police-101736286317672.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 21:55:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Generative AI used to plan Tesla Cybertruck explosion outside Trump Hotel: Las Vegas Police - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/generative-ai-used-to-plan-tesla-cybertruck-explosion-outside-trump-hotel-las-vegas-police-101736286317672.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/generative-ai-used-to-plan-tesla-cybertruck-explosion-outside-trump-hotel-las-vegas-police-101736286317672.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 21:55:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drunken immigrant, Sebastian Zapeta, who set woman on fire in Brooklyn subway shocked by own actions: ‘Oh - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Drunken immigrant, Sebastian Zapeta, who set woman on fire in Brooklyn subway shocked by own actions: ‘Oh damn, that’s me!’</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> NY Daily News</p>
<p>In a shocking incident, Sebastian Zapeta, a drunken immigrant, was arrested after setting a woman on fire in a Brooklyn subway. His unexpected reaction upon realizing his actions has drawn significant media attention.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sebastian Zapeta was intoxicated when he set a woman on fire in a subway station.</li>
<li>Witnesses report his bewilderment upon seeing the aftermath of his actions.</li>
<li>The incident has raised discussions about public safety in transit systems.</li>
<li>Zapeta's case highlights issues surrounding alcohol abuse and violence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Oh damn, that’s me!” - Sebastian Zapeta when confronted about the incident.</blockquote>
<p>This incident serves as a stark reminder of the potential dangers in public spaces and the complexities surrounding mental health and substance abuse issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/drunken-immigrant-sebastian-zapeta-who-set-woman-on-fire-in-brooklyn-subway-shocked-by-own-actions-oh-damn-thats-me/articleshow/117034866.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/drunken-immigrant-sebastian-zapeta-who-set-woman-on-fire-in-brooklyn-subway-shocked-by-own-actions-oh-damn-thats-me/articleshow/117034866.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 21:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[126 killed, 188 injured as powerful earthquake hits Tibet; tremors felt in Kathmandu, parts of North India - The New Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>126 killed, 188 injured as powerful earthquake hits Tibet; tremors felt in Kathmandu, parts of North India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Xinhua</p>
<img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="In this photo released by Xinhua News Agency, people stand amidst damaged houses in the aftermath of an earthquake in Tonglai Village, Changsuo Township of Dingri in Xigaze, southwestern China's Tibet Autonomous Region on Tuesday, Jan. 7, 2025." width="100%" height="100%">
<figcaption>In this photo released by Xinhua News Agency, people stand amidst damaged houses in the aftermath of an earthquake in Tonglai Village, Changsuo Township of Dingri in Xigaze, southwestern China's Tibet Autonomous Region on Tuesday, Jan. 7, 2025.</figcaption>
<p>A strong earthquake struck Tibet, causing significant casualties and damage, with tremors felt in Nepal and northern India.</p>
<ul>
<li>Magnitude of the earthquake was reported between 6.8 and 7.1.</li>
<li>A total of 126 fatalities and 188 injuries have been confirmed.</li>
<li>Tremors were felt in Kathmandu and various districts in northern India.</li>
<li>Disaster relief efforts are underway with officials dispatching aid to impacted regions.</li>
<li>This earthquake is noted as the most powerful in the area in five years.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Chinese President Xi Jinping emphasized efforts to minimize casualties and ensure the safety of affected residents through winter.</blockquote>
<p>The earthquake's impact has raised concerns, especially among residents still recalling the devastating 2015 earthquake in Nepal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/world/2025/Jan/07/126-killed-188-injured-as-powerful-earthquake-hits-tibet-tremors-felt-in-kathmandu-parts-of-north-india</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newindianexpress.com/world/2025/Jan/07/126-killed-188-injured-as-powerful-earthquake-hits-tibet-tremors-felt-in-kathmandu-parts-of-north-india</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:20:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump escalates threats against Canada, Greenland and Panama; refuses to rule out use of military - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Intensifies Threats Against Canada, Greenland, and Panama; Military Use Not Ruled Out</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Trump-40_1736276026127_1736276056517.jpg" alt="President-elect Donald Trump walks from the podium after a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday,(AP)" title="President-elect Donald Trump walks from the podium after a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday,(AP)"><figcaption>President-elect Donald Trump walks from the podium after a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday,(AP)</figcaption></figure><p>President-elect Donald Trump has suggested using military or economic coercion to exert influence over Canada, Greenland, and the Panama Canal, expressing his belief that these territories are essential for US economic security.</p><ul><li>Trump declined to rule out military confrontation regarding Greenland and the Panama Canal.</li><li>He stated, “We need them for economic security,” emphasizing the strategic importance of these territories.</li><li>Trump proposed using tariffs against Denmark to gain control over Greenland.</li><li>He suggested that Canada could become the 51st state due to trade deficits and US military support.</li><li>He characterized the situation in Mexico as problematic, citing drug-related violence and trade issues.</li></ul><blockquote>“People really don’t even know if Denmark has any legal right to it but if they do, they should give it up because we need it for national security.”</blockquote><p>Trump's statements indicate a willingness to threaten allies with coercive actions if US demands are not met, raising concerns about international relations and the future of diplomatic ties.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trump-escalates-threats-against-canada-greenland-and-panama-refuses-to-rule-out-use-of-military-101736275812697.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trump-escalates-threats-against-canada-greenland-and-panama-refuses-to-rule-out-use-of-military-101736275812697.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:59:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Escalates Threats Against Canada, Greenland and Panama; Refuses to rule out use of military - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Threatens Military Action Over Greenland, Canada, and Panama in New Press Conference</h1><p><strong>Date: Jan 08, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Trump-40_1736276026127_1736276056517.jpg" alt="President-elect Donald Trump walks from the podium after a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday,(AP)" title="President-elect Donald Trump walks from the podium after a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday,(AP)"><figcaption>President-elect Donald Trump walks from the podium after a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday,(AP)</figcaption></figure><p>In a recent press conference, President-elect Donald Trump expressed intentions to increase US influence in Greenland, Canada, and the Panama Canal, leaving open the possibility of military or economic coercion.</p><ul><li>Trump refused to eliminate the option of military confrontation over US control of Greenland and Panama.</li><li>He stated, “We need them for economic security,” emphasizing the strategic importance of these territories.</li><li>Trump proposed using high-level tariffs to pressure Denmark regarding Greenland.</li><li>He suggested that Canada could become the 51st state due to trade deficits and US military support.</li><li>He characterized the Gulf of Mexico as potentially renamed to the “Gulf of America” to assert dominance in the region.</li></ul><blockquote>“I can’t assure you on either of those two, but I can say this, we need them for economic security.”</blockquote><p>Trump's remarks indicate a willingness to leverage US power against allies, potentially undermining long-term relationships in North America.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trump-escalates-threats-against-canada-greenland-and-panama-refuses-to-rule-out-use-of-military-101736275812697.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trump-escalates-threats-against-canada-greenland-and-panama-refuses-to-rule-out-use-of-military-101736275812697.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:59:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[British-Indians furious at being smeared with ‘Asian grooming gangs’ label - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>British-Indians furious at being smeared with ‘Asian grooming gangs’ label</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>This article discusses the outrage among British-Indians regarding the derogatory label associated with 'Asian grooming gangs', which they feel unjustly targets their community.</p><ul><li>Many British-Indians express feelings of anger and frustration over the media's portrayal.</li><li>The labeling is seen as harmful and perpetuates negative stereotypes.</li><li>Community leaders are calling for a change in how such topics are reported.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are not responsible for the actions of a few.”</blockquote><p>This incident has sparked broader conversations about race, identity, and representation in the media.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/british-indians-furious-at-being-smeared-with-asian-grooming-gangs-label/articleshow/117033320.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/british-indians-furious-at-being-smeared-with-asian-grooming-gangs-label/articleshow/117033320.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Gulf of America’: Donald Trump says he’ll rename Gulf of Mexico, repeats threat of tariffs on Canada - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump proposes renaming the Gulf of Mexico to the Gulf of America, linking it to immigration concerns.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/US-president-elect-Donald-Trump-at-the-White-House_1736219063783_1736272393833.jpg" alt="US president-elect Donald Trump at the White House in June 2020. (Reuters File Photo)"><figcaption>US president-elect Donald Trump at the White House in June 2020. (Reuters File Photo)</figcaption><p>On Tuesday Donald Trump revealed plans to rename the Gulf of Mexico to the "Gulf of America," citing immigration concerns as the primary reason for the big change. Ahead of his inauguration on January 20th, he declared the name change “appropriate,” stressing the need for Mexico to curb the flow of migrants into the U.S. and reiterated his stance on imposing harsh tariffs on both Mexico and Canada.</p><ul><li>Trump plans to rename Gulf of Mexico to Gulf of America.</li><li>Cites immigration concerns as the reason for the name change.</li><li>Threatens to impose tariffs on Mexico and Canada.</li><li>Proposes Canada merge with the U.S. as the 51st state.</li><li>Critiques past U.S. policies regarding territories like the Panama Canal.</li></ul><blockquote>“Mexico has to stop allowing millions of people to pour into our country.”</blockquote><p>Trump's announcement reflects his continued hardline stance on immigration, which he regards as a major risk to U.S. security.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-says-he-ll-rename-gulf-of-mexico-to-gulf-of-america-101736272030909.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-says-he-ll-rename-gulf-of-mexico-to-gulf-of-america-101736272030909.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:55:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump won't rule out military, economic action as he seeks control of Panama Canal, Greenland - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/world-news/trump-wont-rule-out-military-economic-action-as-he-seeks-control-of-panama-canal-greenland/articleshow/117032459.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/world-news/trump-wont-rule-out-military-economic-action-as-he-seeks-control-of-panama-canal-greenland/articleshow/117032459.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:27:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>