<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:50:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:50:52 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biden grants deportation protection to 900,000 immigrants just before Trump’s inauguration - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Grants Deportation Protection to 900,000 Immigrants Just Before Trump's Inauguration</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/New-Orleans-Car-Into-Crowd-Biden-19_1736331756435_1736543057996.jpg" alt="President Joe Biden speaks during an interfaith prayer service for the victims of the deadly New Years truck attack, at St. Louis Cathedral in New Orleans, Monday, Jan. 6, 2025. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)(AP)" title="President Joe Biden speaks during an interfaith prayer service for the victims of the deadly New Years truck attack, at St. Louis Cathedral in New Orleans, Monday, Jan. 6, 2025. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)(AP)"><figcaption>President Joe Biden speaks during an interfaith prayer service for the victims of the deadly New Years truck attack, at St. Louis Cathedral in New Orleans, Monday, Jan. 6, 2025. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)(AP)</figcaption><p>President Joe Biden’s administration has extended Temporary Protected Status (TPS) for 600,000 Venezuelans and over 200,000 Salvadorans, allowing them to remain in the US for an additional 18 months just before Donald Trump’s inauguration.</p><ul><li>The decision was made by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) citing ‘inhumane’ conditions under Venezuela's government.</li><li>Protections were also granted for about 100,000 people from Ukraine and 1,900 from Sudan.</li><li>This extension fulfills Biden's promise to protect vulnerable immigrant populations.</li><li>TPS has become a subject of controversy among Republicans regarding its broad application.</li><li>About 1 million people from various countries currently benefit from TPS in the US.</li></ul><blockquote>“TPS is intended to provide foreigners already in the US with protections from deportation amid political strife, natural disasters or armed conflict in their home countries.”</blockquote><p>The Biden administration's move underscores a protective stance towards immigrants amid impending policy changes expected from the Trump administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/biden-grants-deportation-protection-to-900-000-immigrants-just-before-trump-s-inauguration-101736542894893.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/biden-grants-deportation-protection-to-900-000-immigrants-just-before-trump-s-inauguration-101736542894893.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:05:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California fire live updates: Los Angeles fire larger than Manhattan - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Fire Live Updates: Los Angeles Fire Larger Than Manhattan</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/CALIFORNIA-WILDFIRES--86_1736521271776_1736521291258.JPG" alt="Firefighters battle fire in the Angeles National Forest" title="Firefighters battle fire in the Angeles National Forest"><figcaption>Firefighters battle the fire in the Angeles National Forest near Mount Wilson as the wildfires burn in the Los Angeles area.</figcaption><p>California wildfires have resulted in at least 10 deaths and destroyed more than 10,000 structures, including homes and local landmarks. The fires have forced around 180,000 people to evacuate, with significant damage reported.</p><ul><li>The Kenneth fire started close to a school serving as an evacuation shelter.</li><li>The Eaton fire near Pasadena has burned over 5,000 structures.</li><li>The fires have consumed areas larger than Manhattan, affecting nearly 45 square miles.</li><li>Schools across the Los Angeles Unified School District are closed due to heavy smoke.</li><li>AccuWeather estimates property damage and economic loss could range from $135 billion to $150 billion.</li></ul><blockquote>“Looting is a despicable crime,” said LA district attorney Nathan Hochman.</blockquote><p>The wildfires continue to pose a significant threat to communities across Los Angeles, with efforts to contain the fires ongoing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/california-wildfire-live-updates-los-angeles-united-states-death-toll-destruction-evacuation-10-january-2025-holywood-101736500460840.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/california-wildfire-live-updates-los-angeles-united-states-death-toll-destruction-evacuation-10-january-2025-holywood-101736500460840.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 19:45:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadline to Apply for a Student Loan with FAFSA in 2025 - Here's Why You Shouldn't Wait Any Longer - BSEB Inter Org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Deadline to Apply for a Student Loan with FAFSA in 2025 - Here's Why You Shouldn't Wait Any Longer</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://bsebinter.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Deadline-to-Apply-for-a-Student-Loan-with-FAFSA-in-2025-Heres-Why-You-Shouldnt-Wait-Any-Longer-1024x683.jpg" alt="Deadline to Apply for a Student Loan with FAFSA in 2025 - Here's Why You Shouldn't Wait Any Longer"><figcaption>Image depicting the deadline for FAFSA applications for 2025.</figcaption><p>The FAFSA application is now open, and the deadline to apply is June 30, 2025. Timely submission is crucial as funding is allocated on a first-come, first-served basis.</p><ul><li>FAFSA deadline is June 30, 2025, for AY 2025-2026.</li><li>Submitting the FAFSA early increases chances of receiving federal aid.</li><li>Processing times: paper version takes 7–10 days; online version takes 3–5 days.</li><li>Eligibility is dependent on the Expected Family Contribution (EFC).</li><li>Potential consequences for missing the deadline include loss of access to federal aid.</li></ul><blockquote>“Punctuality is a must when completing the FAFSA.”</blockquote><p>It's essential to complete your FAFSA promptly to secure necessary financial aid for college.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bsebinter.org/deadline-to-apply-for-a-student-loan-with-fafsa-in-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bsebinter.org/deadline-to-apply-for-a-student-loan-with-fafsa-in-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 19:06:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US hits Russian oil with toughest sanctions yet in bid to give Ukraine, Trump leverage - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-hits-russian-oil-toughest-sanctions-yet-bid-give-ukraine-trump-leverage-2025-01-10/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-hits-russian-oil-toughest-sanctions-yet-bid-give-ukraine-trump-leverage-2025-01-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:40:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Despicable charade, no merit’ says Donald Trump after unconditional discharge in hush money case - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Claims 'Witch Hunt' After Being Discharged in Hush Money Case</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/USA-TRUMP-NEW-YORK-91_1736533761930_1736533984969.JPG" alt="Donald Trump was sentenced to an unconditional discharge on Friday after being convicted of 34 felony counts(Jane Rosenberg/REUTERS)" /><figcaption>Donald Trump was sentenced to an unconditional discharge on Friday after being convicted of 34 felony counts(Jane Rosenberg/REUTERS)</figcaption></figure><p>Donald Trump expressed his outrage over the Biden-Harris administration's actions against him, labeling it a 'witch hunt' after receiving an unconditional discharge in his hush money trial despite 34 felony counts.</p><ul><li>Trump was convicted of 34 felony counts but received an unconditional discharge, avoiding jail time and fines.</li><li>He condemned the charges as baseless and claimed they were a result of political oppression.</li><li>Trump announced plans to appeal the case, which he called a 'hoax' and a 'scam'.</li><li>The case involved a $130,000 payment to an adult film star to prevent an affair from being disclosed during his presidential campaign.</li></ul><blockquote>“That result alone proves that, as all Legal Scholars and Experts have said, THERE IS NO CASE, THERE WAS NEVER A CASE, and this whole Scam fully deserves to be DISMISSED,” said Trump.</blockquote><p>This case highlights the ongoing legal battles Trump faces and has reignited his claims of being unjustly targeted by political opponents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/despicable-charade-no-merit-says-donald-trump-after-unconditional-discharge-in-hush-money-case-101736531648235.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/despicable-charade-no-merit-says-donald-trump-after-unconditional-discharge-in-hush-money-case-101736531648235.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:40:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IDF strikes targets in Yemen as Israel threatens to hunt down Houthi leaders - The Times of Israel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>20 Israeli jets attack two ports and a power plant used by Houthis in Yemen</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of Israel</p>
<img src="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2025/01/dd722d8a-0d94-4d4e-be35-46356ac20523-640x400.jpg" alt="IAF F-16I fighter jets prepare to take off" width="600" height="375">
<figcaption>IAF F-16I fighter jets prepare to take off from the Ramon Airbase in southern Israel for strikes against the Houthis in Yemen, January 10, 2025. (Israel Defense Forces)</figcaption>
<p>The Israeli Air Force conducted significant airstrikes against Houthi targets in Yemen, targeting key sites including ports and a power plant, and issued warnings to the group over its ongoing missile and drone attacks.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Over 20 Israeli aircraft were involved in the strikes, dropping around 50 munitions.</li>
  <li>Main targets included the Hodeidah and Ras Isa ports, and the Hezyaz power plant.</li>
  <li>The IDF stated the power plant was crucial for the Houthi military operations.</li>
  <li>Israeli leaders warned of further action if attacks on Israel persisted.</li>
  <li>Netanyahu emphasized the need to counter Iranian influence via the Houthis.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"As we promised, the Houthis are paying, and will continue to pay, a heavy price for their aggression against us." - Benjamin Netanyahu</blockquote>
<p>The Israeli airstrikes represent a continuing escalation in the conflict, reflecting the regional tension stemming from Iran's involvement and the threat posed to Israel.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesofisrael.com/idf-strikes-targets-in-yemen-as-israel-threatens-to-hunt-down-houthi-leaders/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesofisrael.com/idf-strikes-targets-in-yemen-as-israel-threatens-to-hunt-down-houthi-leaders/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:48:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kenneth Fire arsonist suspect claims he was using blowtorch to smoke marijuana; detained by locals in dra - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kenneth Fire arsonist suspect claims he was using blowtorch to smoke marijuana; detained by locals in dramatic video</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>In a dramatic incident captured on video, a suspect accused of starting a fire in Kenneth claims he was merely using a blowtorch to smoke marijuana. Local residents intervened and detained him.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The incident involves a suspect who allegedly ignited a fire.</li>
  <li>Locals detained the suspect, showcasing a community response to the crisis.</li>
  <li>The suspect claims his intention was to use the blowtorch for smoking marijuana.</li>
  <li>The video of the event has circulated widely, highlighting the dramatic nature of the situation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I was just trying to smoke, man!” – The suspect's statement during the confrontation.</blockquote>
<p>This incident raises questions about fire safety and community vigilance in addressing potential threats. The dramatic nature of the detainment emphasizes the role of local involvement in crisis situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/kenneth-fire-arsonist-suspect-claims-he-was-using-blowtorch-to-smoke-marijuana-detained-by-locals-in-dramatic-video/articleshow/117125535.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/kenneth-fire-arsonist-suspect-claims-he-was-using-blowtorch-to-smoke-marijuana-detained-by-locals-in-dramatic-video/articleshow/117125535.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump 1st US President To Be Sentenced As Felon, But Avoids Jail, Penalty - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Becomes First US President Sentenced as Felon, Escapes Jail Time</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>January 25, 2025 | <strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p><div><img alt="Stormy Daniels had testified in vivid detail about her alleged encounter with Trump in a hotel in Navada." src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/d29oiflk_stormy-daniels-reuters_625x300_10_January_25.jpg"><figcaption>Stormy Daniels had testified in vivid detail about her alleged encounter with Trump in a hotel in Navada.</figcaption></div><p>Donald Trump has made history by becoming the first felon in the White House, as a US court upholds his conviction in a hush money case. Although he was sentenced to an 'unconditional discharge', he will not serve jail time due to his position as President-elect.</p><ul><li>Trump was convicted of falsifying business records related to payments made to Stormy Daniels.</li><li>He faced potential jail time of four years but was spared due to presidential immunity.</li><li>Judge Juan Merchan described the circumstances as unique and remarked on the legal implications of sentencing a sitting president.</li><li>Trump did not attend the court session in person and instead appeared virtually.</li><li>He characterized the legal proceedings as damaging to his reputation and a setback for the New York court system.</li></ul><blockquote>"This court has determined that the only lawful sentence that permits entry of a judgement of conviction without encroaching on the highest office of the land, is an unconditional discharge." - Judge Juan Merchan</blockquote><blockquote>"It was done to damage my reputation, just so that I may lose the election." - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>In a significant ruling, this event illustrates the complexities of legal accountability at the highest levels of government, setting a precedent for the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-becomes-1st-us-president-to-be-sentenced-as-a-felon-avoids-jail-time-7445027</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-becomes-1st-us-president-to-be-sentenced-as-a-felon-avoids-jail-time-7445027</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:24:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US to impose sanctions on Russian oil fleet and traders, document shows - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/new-us-sanctions-russian-tankers-hit-oil-supplies-india-refining-sources-say-2025-01-10/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/new-us-sanctions-russian-tankers-hit-oil-supplies-india-refining-sources-say-2025-01-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:24:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hush money case: US judge sentences Donald Trump, declines to impose jail term, fine - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Sentenced in Hush Money Case</h1><p><strong>Date: January 10, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/USA-TRUMP-NEW-YORK-49_1736522354982_1736522376464.JPG" alt="Todd Blanche, attorney for former US President Donald Trump, and US President-elect Donald Trump at Manhattan criminal court in New York." title="Todd Blanche, attorney for former US President Donald Trump, and US President-elect Donald Trump at Manhattan criminal court in New York."><figcaption>Todd Blanche, attorney for former US President Donald Trump, and US President-elect Donald Trump are seen on the screen at Manhattan criminal court in New York.(Reuters)</figcaption><p>A US judge sentenced President-elect Donald Trump over a criminal conviction related to hush money paid to a porn star. The verdict marks the first felony conviction for a US president, but Trump will not face jail or a fine.</p><ul><li>The judge imposed the mildest criminal sanction available: an unconditional discharge.</li><li>Judge Juan M Merchan cited unique circumstances surrounding the case.</li><li>Trump was convicted on 34 counts of falsifying business records.</li><li>He claims the conviction is intended to sabotage his presidential campaign.</li></ul><blockquote>"Never before has this court been presented with such a unique and remarkable set of circumstances." - Judge Juan M Merchan</blockquote><p>The case revolves around a payment of $130,000 to Stormy Daniels, made to suppress disclosure about an alleged encounter during Trump's 2016 campaign. Trump denied the encounter and claimed the verdict was politically motivated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/hush-money-case-us-judge-sentences-donald-trump-declines-to-impose-jail-fine-101736522223806.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/hush-money-case-us-judge-sentences-donald-trump-declines-to-impose-jail-fine-101736522223806.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:17:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gnanasara: Controversial Sri Lankan monk jailed for insulting Islam - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gnanasara: Controversial Sri Lankan monk jailed for insulting Islam</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>A hardline Sri Lankan monk, Galagodaatte Gnanasara, has been sentenced to nine months in prison for insulting Islam and inciting religious hatred during remarks made in 2016.</p><ul><li>Convicted by the Colombo Magistrate's Court, marking his second jail term over hate speech.</li><li>Previously received a presidential pardon in 2019 for a six-year sentence related to intimidation.</li><li>Gnanasara was also fined 1,500 Sri Lankan rupees (approximately $5) by the court.</li><li>He has filed an appeal against this sentence and was denied bail during the appeal process.</li><li>During his previous tenure, he was closely allied with former president Gotabaya Rajapaksa.</li></ul><blockquote>“All citizens, regardless of religion, are entitled to the freedom of belief under the Constitution.”</blockquote><p>This ruling represents a rare conviction for a Buddhist monk in Sri Lanka, signaling a potential shift in handling hate speech related to religious intolerance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce8jdy8j41lo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce8jdy8j41lo</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:15:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Porn star hush money case: Trump avoids jail term, Judge imposes unconditional discharge - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Porn star hush money case: Trump avoids jail term, Judge imposes unconditional discharge</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p><p>Former President Donald Trump has managed to avoid serving time in connection with the hush money payments made during the 2016 election campaign, as a judge sentenced him to an unconditional discharge.</p><ul><li>Trump was involved in a legal dispute concerning payments made to silence allegations of an affair.</li><li>The judge ruled favorably for Trump, leading to no jail time.</li><li>This case continues to generate substantial media coverage and public interest.</li></ul><blockquote>"This case illustrates the complexities of politics and legal obligations around financial settlements in campaigns."</blockquote><p>Despite avoiding jail, the case raises important questions about campaign finance and ethical conduct in political spheres.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/hush-money-case-donald-trump-sentenced-to-unconditional-discharge/articleshow/117124963.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/hush-money-case-donald-trump-sentenced-to-unconditional-discharge/articleshow/117124963.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: Massive fire erupts in New York apartment, 7 injured - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Massive Fire in New York Apartment Leaves 7 Injured</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Local News Network</p><p>A significant fire broke out in a residential apartment building in New York, resulting in injuries to seven people. Eyewitness reports describe the scene as chaotic, with emergency services responding rapidly to contain the flames.</p><ul><li>The fire erupted late at night, causing an immediate evacuation of residents.</li><li>Seven individuals were treated for smoke inhalation and other injuries.</li><li>Firefighters battled the blaze for several hours before bringing it under control.</li><li>The cause of the fire is currently under investigation.</li></ul><blockquote>“This was a terrifying experience,” said one resident. “I never thought I’d have to escape a fire from my apartment.”</blockquote><p>Emergency services continue to assess the damage and provide support to those affected.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/video-massive-fire-erupts-in-new-york-apartment-7-injured/articleshow/117124676.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/video-massive-fire-erupts-in-new-york-apartment-7-injured/articleshow/117124676.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China hacked US Treasury's CFIUS, which reviews foreign investments for national security risks - TechCrunch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chinese Hackers Breach U.S. Treasury's Foreign Investment Committee</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> TechCrunch</p><p>Chinese hackers have reportedly breached a key office within the U.S. Treasury tasked with reviewing foreign investments that could threaten U.S. national security.</p><ul><li>The Committee on Foreign Investment in the U.S. (CFIUS) was targeted by Chinese hackers.</li><li>U.S. officials confirmed that the hackers gained access through a stolen key from a security vendor.</li><li>The breach could potentially impact corporate mergers and access to sensitive U.S. information.</li><li>The hackers are linked to a group known as Silk Typhoon, known for stealing information.</li></ul><blockquote>“The hackers broke in using a stolen BeyondTrust key to remotely access employee workstations and documents.”</blockquote><p>The cyberattack highlights ongoing cybersecurity concerns related to foreign threats and the integrity of U.S. national security.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/10/china-hacked-us-treasurys-cfius-which-reviews-foreign-investments-for-national-security-risks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/10/china-hacked-us-treasurys-cfius-which-reviews-foreign-investments-for-national-security-risks/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:49:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US to impose sanctions on Russian oil fleet, document shows - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US to impose sanctions on Russian oil fleet and traders, document shows</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 10, 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p>
<img src="https://www.reuters.com/resizer/v2/NZODG5TJ6NJQPO6SYU6TPCAFGM.jpg?auth=50def6aea4db6d1b18605d3761adf490a12b52ab6024d0d4cdd87de4ded40742&amp;width=4000&amp;quality=80" alt="Illustration shows pump jack in the front word 'Sanctions', U.S. and Russia flag colours">
<figcaption>A model of a pump jack is seen in front of the displayed word "Sanctions", U.S. and Russia flag colours in this illustration taken March 8, 2022. REUTERS/Dado Ruvic/Illustration/File Photo.</figcaption>
<p>The United States plans to impose stringent sanctions on Russia's oil industry, affecting around 180 ships and multiple traders. This move follows ongoing tensions due to the Ukraine war and could significantly disrupt Russian oil exports to major buyers like India and China.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sanctions target around 180 ships, dozens of traders</li>
<li>Gazprom Neft, Surgut, ship insurers added to the list</li>
<li>Biden team had sought to avoid price spike</li>
<li>New Trump administration has said will seek to end Ukraine war</li>
<li>Reuters could not immediately verify the document</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>According to the document, the U.S. Treasury would allow a transition period to March 12, allowing some energy-related transactions to be completed.</blockquote>
<p>This action represents a significant escalation in U.S. efforts to minimize Russia's capacity to fund its military actions through oil exports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/new-us-sanctions-russian-tankers-hit-oil-supplies-india-refining-sources-say-2025-01-10/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/new-us-sanctions-russian-tankers-hit-oil-supplies-india-refining-sources-say-2025-01-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:17:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The US economy closed out 2024 with another solid month of job gains - CNN International]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>One of the strongest labor markets in US history just ended 2024 with a bang</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 5, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CNN Business</p>
<img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/ap24242605357805-20250109162744443.jpg?c=original" alt="Economists predicted a total of 153,000 jobs would be added to the US economy in December and an unemployment rate holding at 4.2%.">
<figcaption>Image showing the robust US job market statistics.</figcaption>
<p>The US economy finished strong in December 2024, adding 256,000 jobs and decreasing the unemployment rate to 4.1%. This marks a significant turn towards pre-pandemic norms and a noteworthy year for the labor market.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The US economy added 256,000 jobs in December.</li>
  <li>The unemployment rate dropped from 4.2% to 4.1%.</li>
  <li>In total, approximately 2.2 million jobs were added in 2024, averaging 186,000 jobs per month.</li>
  <li>The US labor market has seen job growth for 48 consecutive months.</li>
  <li>Stock futures dropped sharply despite the positive job report.</li>
  <li>The labor market's stability is continuously challenged by external economic pressures.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The solid labor market has helped fuel consumer spending, which in turn has kept the overall economy strong as inflation has eased.”</blockquote>
<p>In summary, the labor market's resilience after the pandemic lays a complex foundation as the economy approaches 2025, raising questions about future job growth and the potential impacts of changing policies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://edition.cnn.com/2025/01/10/economy/us-jobs-report-december-final/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://edition.cnn.com/2025/01/10/economy/us-jobs-report-december-final/index.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yemeni military targets US carrier with missiles, drones - Mehr News Agency - English Version]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxPY2VlbjQ5MVdPLWFJNzFSNzluZDZoYmp6VDNIMlJISnVFZVZLNHphUHJnSGxIQTFvMFliYnlJSXg1MlR5Y0JjdFVBUURhZHBRd0dlYnR4R3RYVmowUzBrT1N3UHpDSUNaUXViQkd3SHNtSTVXNG1GazRBRUQtMWo1YjRRNmQ2VUZQU2l6cm1wS19EaXVo0gFLQVVfeXFMTWJOQ1BfTmwtbHhyUjRpbmFwckJTVGM3N2JOTVIxSFpqLXVsY0pXWTJBX1pqNk5lVWJZM3BhVWR1RC1ZeGhnakQtVlVv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxPY2VlbjQ5MVdPLWFJNzFSNzluZDZoYmp6VDNIMlJISnVFZVZLNHphUHJnSGxIQTFvMFliYnlJSXg1MlR5Y0JjdFVBUURhZHBRd0dlYnR4R3RYVmowUzBrT1N3UHpDSUNaUXViQkd3SHNtSTVXNG1GazRBRUQtMWo1YjRRNmQ2VUZQU2l6cm1wS19EaXVo0gFLQVVfeXFMTWJOQ1BfTmwtbHhyUjRpbmFwckJTVGM3N2JOTVIxSFpqLXVsY0pXWTJBX1pqNk5lVWJZM3BhVWR1RC1ZeGhnakQtVlVv?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big threat for US, West, as TTP terrorists kidnap Pakistani nuclear scientists, loot uranium to make 'dirty b - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxNRUdwZXZkeU1qLW0xS25hY19PMHNhNnhwM01DX0lhOU50M29iWWhCTHhKVXNqWXRvVWNxMVpzUllkWU55RnlDNlh6X0NyWk5qTHlLdW9xM3FrNXQ3RTY2dEp2SnlNdE92VWt4ZV9pUzBVZmlaTEp1bERnbWltdjUyT25QM3lCb3lZQzV0QldMenc5Sk9WRW9DMVhzY0NIaGVITGtHNkF0Qm9qeTdsQ1ZZVnNxOG9pSzRlS1FkUjR1ejdKRUw3dFRNN0pjR3g1LVV5NmZrd3BQc0NKSDVZdm50emFkakxZeVBiR056YUdRaVpEUVRJcVhF0gH8AUFVX3lxTFBOV2pMWXRidWVFa0ZEV19IMmhkYmhOWDRvYzFBVjd6RWJOUG91ekN0VnV5QXdCcmFxRTVYeVlXaUdvbVFaUDgwQ1kzMnlFNUl6aTVoN2VhUEJFN0k3UWZqUWhDZ29rS0U0YkI4ZEU5ZWZGX2FrUHZDdy1mNUQxZl8zWUtRejE1eEhENTlZVnkteFBieHVJVDFDd0RpOGJySXB1T29PZXB6QUQ0SHZ6cEdVVW80dlhjZGZzbXdXZGN0NC1DQk00ZDQzcXYtTW9reVhMYkxkcFVXRXpZQVZyVUdCdlZydzlXbElCdFJKSWJQRVNLOWZuZ3BZcU1jVw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9wFBVV95cUxNRUdwZXZkeU1qLW0xS25hY19PMHNhNnhwM01DX0lhOU50M29iWWhCTHhKVXNqWXRvVWNxMVpzUllkWU55RnlDNlh6X0NyWk5qTHlLdW9xM3FrNXQ3RTY2dEp2SnlNdE92VWt4ZV9pUzBVZmlaTEp1bERnbWltdjUyT25QM3lCb3lZQzV0QldMenc5Sk9WRW9DMVhzY0NIaGVITGtHNkF0Qm9qeTdsQ1ZZVnNxOG9pSzRlS1FkUjR1ejdKRUw3dFRNN0pjR3g1LVV5NmZrd3BQc0NKSDVZdm50emFkakxZeVBiR056YUdRaVpEUVRJcVhF0gH8AUFVX3lxTFBOV2pMWXRidWVFa0ZEV19IMmhkYmhOWDRvYzFBVjd6RWJOUG91ekN0VnV5QXdCcmFxRTVYeVlXaUdvbVFaUDgwQ1kzMnlFNUl6aTVoN2VhUEJFN0k3UWZqUWhDZ29rS0U0YkI4ZEU5ZWZGX2FrUHZDdy1mNUQxZl8zWUtRejE1eEhENTlZVnkteFBieHVJVDFDd0RpOGJySXB1T29PZXB6QUQ0SHZ6cEdVVW80dlhjZGZzbXdXZGN0NC1DQk00ZDQzcXYtTW9reVhMYkxkcFVXRXpZQVZyVUdCdlZydzlXbElCdFJKSWJQRVNLOWZuZ3BZcU1jVw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:04:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California Los Angeles Wildfires LIVE Updates: New blaze rips through Los Angeles neighbourhood, death toll now at 10 - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Los Angeles Wildfires LIVE Updates:</h1><p><strong>Date: January 12, 2025</strong><br><strong>Source: Indian Express</strong></p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/wildfires-california-los-angeles.jpg?w=640" alt="Los Angeles Wildfires Live Updates: california fires, world news, indian express" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Water is dropped by helicopter on the Kenneth Fire in the West Hills section of Los Angeles, Thursday. AP Photo</figcaption><p>With five wildfires still burning, the death toll in Los Angeles has reached 10 due to the ongoing wildfires, with the Palisades and Eaton fires becoming some of the most destructive in California history.</p><ul><li>The wildfires have destroyed at least 10,000 structures, including homes and businesses.</li><li>The Kenneth fire has burned 900 acres and evacuation warnings have been lifted.</li><li>Over 90,000 homes and businesses are without power.</li><li>The economic impact is expected to exceed $50 billion.</li><li>California Governor Gavin Newsom approved the deployment of National Guard for law enforcement in evacuation zones due to looting reports.</li><li>Air quality has deteriorated, leading officials to recommend masks.</li></ul><blockquote>"The fires have burned over 29,000 acres, displacing tens of thousands."</blockquote><p>This tragic event showcases the severe impact of wildfires, highlighting the urgent need for safety measures and proactive responses in affected areas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/california-hollywood-hills-los-angeles-wildfires-live-updates-death-toll-9768223/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/california-hollywood-hills-los-angeles-wildfires-live-updates-death-toll-9768223/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 13:01:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[George Soros Indulges In Political Interference: Italy's Giorgia Meloni - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>George Soros Indulges In Political Interference: Italy's Giorgia Meloni</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Thursday, Location: Rome, Italy</p><p>Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni accused George Soros of using his wealth to interfere in other countries' politics, contrasting him with Elon Musk, who she claims does not threaten democracy.</p><ul><li>Meloni stated that Soros destabilizes nations with his political influence.</li><li>She defended Musk's comments on European politics as an exercise of free speech.</li><li>Meloni raised concerns over wealthy individuals financing political movements, suggesting this is a genuine threat to democracy.</li><li>Despite Musk's influence, she claims he does not financially support political parties globally, unlike Soros.</li></ul><blockquote>“I consider that to be dangerous interference in the affairs of nation states and in their sovereignty.” – Giorgia Meloni</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/george-soros-indulges-in-political-interference-italys-giorgia-meloni-7443886</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/george-soros-indulges-in-political-interference-italys-giorgia-meloni-7443886</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:46:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kremlin says Putin ready for talks with Trump - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE5oMVo3NFdpR2tpcVF0U25TSjA0SHdzM3JRYkVOQzRFR0dJcHpRc3l4VXNCcm5rTGpGbmZoZnZ4N3hGS1BqU3V6Tw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE5oMVo3NFdpR2tpcVF0U25TSjA0SHdzM3JRYkVOQzRFR0dJcHpRc3l4VXNCcm5rTGpGbmZoZnZ4N3hGS1BqU3V6Tw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:22:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Don't hide behind America': Turkey angered by possible French presence on Syrian border - Middle East Eye]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Turkey Rejects French Military Presence Near Syrian Border</h1><p><strong>Published Date:</strong> 10 January 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Middle East Eye</p><div><img loading="lazy" src="/sites/default/files/styles/max_2600x2600/public/images-story/turkey-fm-hakan-fidan-istanbul-10jan2025-afp.jpg.jpg?itok=9CUXwxP2" width="1400" height="818" alt="Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan"/><figcaption>Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan addresses a press briefing in Istanbul.</figcaption></div><p>Turkey has expressed strong disapproval of potential French troop deployment along its Syrian border, emphasizing that it does not take small European nations seriously in military operations.</p><ul><li>Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan criticized France for attempting to gain influence in Syria while hiding behind U.S. military support.</li><li>Ankara has warned of possible military action against the Kurdish YPG militia if they do not comply with Turkish demands.</li><li>Fidan stated that for Turkey to consider France's views on Syria, France would need to act independently of U.S. support.</li><li>The article discusses the ongoing tensions between Ankara and the Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF), who Turkey views as terrorists.</li><li>The French government has not officially proposed sending troops, but support for the SDF remains a point of contention.</li></ul><blockquote>"If France intends to act in Syria, it should first repatriate, prosecute, and imprison its own citizens who are terrorists being held in Syrian camps." - Hakan Fidan</blockquote><p>The situation highlights the complexities of foreign involvement in the Syrian conflict and Turkey's assertive stance in its neighboring regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.middleeasteye.net/news/turkey-angered-possible-french-presence-syrian-border</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.middleeasteye.net/news/turkey-angered-possible-french-presence-syrian-border</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[$3,000 CPP Bonus Coming for these seniors in 2025 – Check Eligibility Criteria & Payment Date - LKO Uniexam.in]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTkFVX3lxTE9PMnZMOUFFcURJS2xhVE1EQnRhbnR6VTlPZEZfWU1KckNTeS04cXUtMU9iU3YwV2NMRjNvUnpMZW9WS1UwejBzMlJueGExZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTkFVX3lxTE9PMnZMOUFFcURJS2xhVE1EQnRhbnR6VTlPZEZfWU1KckNTeS04cXUtMU9iU3YwV2NMRjNvUnpMZW9WS1UwejBzMlJueGExZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 12:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['...Not American': Justin Trudeau Fires Back At Donald Trump Over 'Canada 51st State' Jibe - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Trudeau Responds to Trump’s 51st State Comments</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> Times Now</p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-117119155,thumbsize-1890327,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/117119155.jpg" alt="Justin Trudeau Responds To Donald Trump's Jibes" title="Justin Trudeau Responds To Donald Trump's Jibes"><figcaption>Justin Trudeau Responds To Donald Trump's Jibes</figcaption><p>In response to Donald Trump's remarks about Canada potentially becoming the '51st state', Prime Minister Justin Trudeau asserted that Canadians take pride in their identity and distanced himself from Trump's claims.</p><ul><li>Trudeau called Trump’s comments a distraction tactic.</li><li>He emphasized that Canadians are proud of not being American.</li><li>Trudeau addressed Trump's proposal of tariffs on Canadian imports, which would raise prices for American consumers.</li><li>The discussion arose after Trump's social media comments following Trudeau’s announcement of stepping down as PM.</li><li>Trudeau plans to resign as party leader while continuing his role until a new leader is elected.</li></ul><blockquote>Trudeau stated, "That's not gonna happen. Canadians are incredibly proud of being Canadian. One of the ways we define ourselves most easily is - we are not American."</blockquote><p>In summary, Trudeau firmly rejected Trump’s suggestion, reinforcing Canada’s distinct identity and addressing the implications of potential tariffs on trade.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/world/canada/justin-trudeau-fires-back-at-donald-trump-over-canada-51st-state-jibe-not-american-article-117118670</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/world/canada/justin-trudeau-fires-back-at-donald-trump-over-canada-51st-state-jibe-not-american-article-117118670</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:10:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trudeau says Trump talk of annexing Canada is a distraction tactic - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trudeau says Trump talk of annexing Canada is a distraction tactic</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/d1uoys/article69084664.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Jimmy_Carter_80034.jpg" alt="President-elect Donald Trump and Melania Trump arrive before the state funeral for former President Jimmy Carter at Washington National Cathedral in Washington, as Canada’s Prime Minister Justin Trudeau (seated in the middle of the first row) watches" title="President-elect Donald Trump and Melania Trump arrive before the state funeral for former President Jimmy Carter at Washington National Cathedral in Washington, as Canada’s Prime Minister Justin Trudeau (seated in the middle of the first row) watches"><figcaption>President-elect Donald Trump and Melania Trump during a state funeral, with Justin Trudeau in attendance.</figcaption><p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau responded to U.S. President-elect Donald Trump's comments about annexing Canada, stating that they are a tactic to distract from Trump's proposed tariffs on Canadian imports.</p><ul><li>Trudeau noted Canada's potential countermeasures against U.S. tariffs on imports.</li><li>Trump's tariff proposal includes a 25% increase on Canadian products unless border security is improved.</li><li>Trudeau characterized the conversation about annexation as a distraction orchestrated by Trump to divert attention from economic issues.</li><li>He emphasized the economic impact of the tariffs on both Canadian consumers and American workers.</li></ul><blockquote>"What I think is happening in this is President Trump, who is a very skillful negotiator, is getting people to be somewhat distracted by that conversation." - Justin Trudeau</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Trudeau reiterated Canada's firm stance against becoming part of the U.S. and the importance of maintaining amicable trade relations despite potential economic conflicts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trudeau-says-trump-talk-of-annexing-canada-is-a-distraction-tactic/article69084651.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trudeau-says-trump-talk-of-annexing-canada-is-a-distraction-tactic/article69084651.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NFP data set to show US hiring eased in December - FXStreet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Nonfarm Payrolls increase by 256,000 in December vs. 160,000 expected</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> US Bureau of Labor Statistics</p><p>Nonfarm Payrolls (NFP) in the US rose by 256,000 in December, significantly exceeding the market expectation of 160,000. This follows a revised increase of 212,000 in November. The unemployment rate also improved slightly to 4.1%. Annual wage inflation declined to 3.9%, down from 4%.</p><ul><li>Nonfarm Payrolls increased by 256,000 in December, higher than the expected 160,000.</li><li>The previous month’s NFP was revised down to 212,000 from 227,000.</li><li>The Unemployment Rate fell to 4.1% from 4.2%.</li><li>Annual wage inflation decreased to 3.9% from 4%.</li><li>The US Dollar strengthened following the positive NFP data.</li></ul><blockquote>“The change in total nonfarm payroll employment for October was revised up by 7,000, from +36,000 to +43,000.” - US Bureau of Labor Statistics</blockquote><p>In summary, the December NFP report shows a robust addition of jobs, indicating a healthier labor market than expected, which could influence the Federal Reserve's monetary policy moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fxstreet.com/news/nonfarm-payrolls-forecast-us-december-job-gains-set-to-decline-sharply-from-november-202501100500</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fxstreet.com/news/nonfarm-payrolls-forecast-us-december-job-gains-set-to-decline-sharply-from-november-202501100500</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paris, we are coming today: Twitter erupts over post by Pakistan International Airlines (PIA) - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Twitter Reacts to PIA's Announcement of Flights to Paris</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The announcement by Pakistan International Airlines (PIA) regarding flights to Paris has sparked a lively discussion on Twitter, with many users expressing their excitement and curiosity over the development.</p><ul><li>PIA has announced new flights to Paris.</li><li>Twitter users are elated, sharing their excitement and planning future trips.</li><li>The announcement has also elicited humorous responses and memes.</li><li>Travel plans and promotions are being discussed widely among users.</li></ul><blockquote>“Finally, a reason to look forward to traveling again!”</blockquote><p>This conversation highlights the importance of social media in shaping public reactions and promoting travel opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/pakistan-airlines-twitter-pia-paris-9-11/articleshow/117118737.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/pakistan-airlines-twitter-pia-paris-9-11/articleshow/117118737.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iran to unveil new missile, drone complexes soon - Mehr News Agency - English Version]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxOY1lxNGRsaTl3U1dhTXJsVzktTWhzWk52Nk5VRW9oaGo1cWdQTklaLURiNmlKbDQ2VDkxb3Vsd1djdmgzTEZzQzZFd1dzTUI0TV9yUDNiTURZZmpocGNha3dKV01WOXAxOEEtS01KQ0tidHROdllyZnh0VFNWbjZjN3BCdlRLUFdGVVRmcW9MYXPSAUtBVV95cUxPVGd6ajI1MUVCTlY2TU9WTHBXSWpzNERFeGY0NWo0dldXOVRYSkxMQWdHWFZldktxUkUtQ042Sk1mb1NNN1hsWDh6X3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxOY1lxNGRsaTl3U1dhTXJsVzktTWhzWk52Nk5VRW9oaGo1cWdQTklaLURiNmlKbDQ2VDkxb3Vsd1djdmgzTEZzQzZFd1dzTUI0TV9yUDNiTURZZmpocGNha3dKV01WOXAxOEEtS01KQ0tidHROdllyZnh0VFNWbjZjN3BCdlRLUFdGVVRmcW9MYXPSAUtBVV95cUxPVGd6ajI1MUVCTlY2TU9WTHBXSWpzNERFeGY0NWo0dldXOVRYSkxMQWdHWFZldktxUkUtQ042Sk1mb1NNN1hsWDh6X3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump breaks silence on viral moment with Obama at Carter's funeral, 'I didn't realise…' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Reflects on Viral Interaction with Obama at Carter's Funeral</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 10, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/US-STON-DC-FOR-FORMER-PRESIDENT-JIMM-29_1736503598235_1736503598532.jpg" alt="Trump and Obama at Carter's funeral" />
<figcaption>Former President Donald Trump speaks with Barack Obama during Jimmy Carter's funeral at Washington National Cathedral.</figcaption>
<p>President-elect Donald Trump addressed the friendly moment he shared with Barack Obama at Jimmy Carter's funeral, admitting he didn't realize how friendly their interaction appeared.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump acknowledged the friendly nature of his moment with Obama, which went viral.</li>
  <li>He mentioned not knowing how their conversation looked to the public during a Fox News interview.</li>
  <li>Trump hinted at differing philosophies but stated they got along despite them.</li>
  <li>A forensic lip reader suggested their conversation was serious, discussing important matters.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It did look very friendly, I must say... we probably do [like each other],” Trump commented.</blockquote>
<p>This moment has sparked a discussion about the relationship and dynamics between past and current presidents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-breaks-silence-on-viral-moment-with-obama-at-carters-funeral-i-didnt-realise-101736501691659.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-breaks-silence-on-viral-moment-with-obama-at-carters-funeral-i-didnt-realise-101736501691659.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['So you have honour now?': Iranian woman removes cleric's turban to use as hijab - video goes viral - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'So you have honour now?': Iranian woman removes cleric's turban to use as hijab - video goes viral</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='Iranian woman removes cleric's turban' />
<figcaption>An Iranian woman uses a cleric's turban as a hijab in a viral video.</figcaption>
<p>The incident has sparked widespread reactions across social media after a woman in Iran removed a cleric's turban and used it as a hijab, leading to questions of authority and women's rights.</p>
<ul>
<li>The video has gone viral, receiving millions of views.</li>
<li>Critics have expressed that the act challenges patriarchal norms.</li>
<li>Support for the woman's actions has surged, calling it a symbol of resistance against oppressive regulations.</li>
<li>The incident sheds light on ongoing issues surrounding women's freedom in Iran.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We will not be silenced. Women hold the power to challenge this authority.”</blockquote>
<p>This act illustrates the growing defiance among women in Iran against strict dress codes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/so-you-have-honour-now-iranian-woman-removes-clerics-turban-to-use-as-hijab-video-goes-viral/articleshow/117115769.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/so-you-have-honour-now-iranian-woman-removes-clerics-turban-to-use-as-hijab-video-goes-viral/articleshow/117115769.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 10:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>