<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 10:19:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 10:19:32 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How latest US sanctions on Russia’s oil trade might affect India’s crude imports - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Sanctions on Russia's Oil Trade Could Impact India's Crude Imports</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: January 10, 2024 | Source: Indian Express</strong></p>
<p>The recent sanctions by the United States targeting Russia's oil trade may significantly affect India's crude oil imports, as Russia has become India's main supplier since the war in Ukraine.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The US imposed sanctions on 183 tankers crucial for transporting Russian oil, impacting major consumers like India and China.</li>
  <li>This sanctions package is the largest since Russia's invasion of Ukraine and aims to reduce Moscow's oil revenue.</li>
  <li>India has relied heavily on Russian oil, with 38% of its total imports stemming from Russia in 2024.</li>
  <li>Indian refiners plan to refuse oil from sanctioned vessels after March 12, with an expectation of increased imports from West Asia.</li>
  <li>The sanctions have prompted Russia to seek ways to navigate the impact on its oil exports.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The swift sanctions aim to disrupt Russian oil exports, forcing sellers to seek alternative vessels to address the shipping shortfall—a challenge that will take time to resolve.” - Matt Wright, Kpler’s lead freight analyst.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while immediate impacts may be mitigated, the long-term landscape for India's crude oil imports may shift significantly towards West Asian suppliers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/us-sanctions-russias-oil-trade-indias-crude-imports-9779906/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/us-sanctions-russias-oil-trade-indias-crude-imports-9779906/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 08:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TikTok prepares for shutdown in US this Sunday. What does it mean? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>TikTok prepares for shutdown in US this Sunday. What does it mean?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/US_Tiktok_ban_1733543427984_1736921940134.jpg" alt="TikTok logo is displayed on the screen of an iPhone in front of a US flag and Chinese flag background in Washington, DC.(AFP)" title="TikTok logo is displayed on the screen of an iPhone in front of a US flag and Chinese flag background in Washington, DC.(AFP)">
<figcaption>TikTok logo is displayed on the screen of an iPhone in front of a US flag and Chinese flag background in Washington, DC.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>TikTok is set to shut down for US users due to a federal ban take effect. A new law requires TikTok to be sold off from its parent company ByteDance or face a ban.</p>
<ul>
  <li>TikTok plans to shut down the app for US users starting this Sunday.</li>
  <li>The shutdown follows a new law signed by President Biden in April 2024.</li>
  <li>If the ban is enacted, users may not be able to download the app, though current users can still use it temporarily.</li>
  <li>TikTok will provide users with a pop-up message directing them to details about the ban.</li>
  <li>The company is aiming to allow users to download their personal data before shutting down.</li>
  <li>TikTok claims that one-third of 170 million American users would stop using the app if the ban lasts over a month.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"One-third of the 170 million Americans who use the app would stop doing so if the ban lasts over a month."</blockquote>
<p>This shutdown marks a significant development regarding the regulation of social media platforms in the US, with implications for users and the broader social media landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/tiktok-prepares-for-shutdown-in-us-this-sunday-what-does-it-mean-101736921665809.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/business/tiktok-prepares-for-shutdown-in-us-this-sunday-what-does-it-mean-101736921665809.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 07:04:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ukraine war: North Korean troops 'blowing themselves up' in chilling battlefield tactics - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ukraine War: North Korean Troops Employ Self-Destructive Tactics</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Major News Network</p><p>In a chilling turn of events, North Korean troops are reportedly using self-destructive tactics on the battlefield in Ukraine, raising concerns about their implications for international conflict dynamics.</p><ul><li>North Korean forces are allegedly resorting to suicide missions in combat.</li><li>This tactic is said to reflect desperation or severe challenges in standard military operations.</li><li>Experts speculate on the psychological and strategic impacts of such tactics on both friendly and hostile forces.</li></ul><blockquote>"The use of self-destructive tactics indicates a significant shift in military strategy among North Korean troops, highlighting their urgent operational challenges." - Military Analyst</blockquote><p>This development suggests a potentially dangerous evolution of warfare tactics that could escalate tensions in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/ukraine-war-north-korean-troops-blowing-themselves-up-in-chilling-battlefield-tactics/articleshow/117255761.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/ukraine-war-north-korean-troops-blowing-themselves-up-in-chilling-battlefield-tactics/articleshow/117255761.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hamas Accepts Gaza Ceasefire Draft Agreement, Hostage Release Plan: Report - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hamas Accepts Gaza Ceasefire Draft Agreement, Hostage Release Plan: Report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Associated Press</p><p>Palestine-based Hamas has accepted a ceasefire and hostage release draft agreement amid the ongoing conflict with Israel. Negotiations in Qatar have brought both sides closest to concluding the deal.</p><ul><li>Marathon talks in Qatar have brought progress towards a ceasefire.</li><li>The U.S., Egypt, and Qatar are involved in finalizing the agreement.</li><li>Hamas is expected to release 33 Israeli hostages.</li><li>Israeli forces' withdrawal will be phased but maintain border defense.</li><li>Increased humanitarian aid is planned for Gaza amidst a severe crisis.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s closer than it’s ever been before,” - US Secretary of State Antony Blinken</blockquote><p>The outcome of these negotiations holds significant implications for the future governance of Gaza and the humanitarian situation in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-accepts-gaza-ceasefire-draft-agreement-hostage-release-plan-report-7477340</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-accepts-gaza-ceasefire-draft-agreement-hostage-release-plan-report-7477340</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 06:26:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Canada Open Work Permit Eligibility Effective January 21 - INC – Immigration News Canada]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Canada Open Work Permit Eligibility Effective January 21</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Last Updated On 14 January 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Immigration News Canada</p><p>The Immigration, Refugees, and Citizenship Canada (IRCC) has announced changes to eligibility criteria for Open Work Permits for family members of international students and foreign workers, effective January 21, 2025. These changes aim to align temporary resident programs with Canadian economic objectives.</p><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li><strong>Spouses of International Students:</strong> Eligibility is based on the student's program length and type.</li><li><strong>Spouses of Foreign Workers:</strong> Only eligible if the foreign worker has a permit for high-skill jobs or in sectors facing labor shortages.</li><li>Dependent children will no longer be eligible for family OWPs.</li><li>Current holders of family OWPs will remain valid until expiry but must meet new criteria for renewals.</li><li>Exceptions include free-trade agreements and pathways to permanent residency.</li><li>Alternative options for those no longer eligible are available under broader immigration permits.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes</h2><blockquote><p>“The changes to the Open Work Permit eligibility for family members of international students and foreign workers in Canada are poised to redefine who can call Canada home, at least temporarily.”</p></blockquote><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>As these new policies roll out, their effects on Canada’s immigration landscape and economy will be closely monitored, raising questions about the balance between skilled workforce objectives and family unity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://immigrationnewscanada.ca/canada-open-work-permit-eligibility/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://immigrationnewscanada.ca/canada-open-work-permit-eligibility/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:51:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Nurse Stabbed In Neck With Scissors By 'Angry' Patient At UK Hospital - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/indian-origin-nurse-stabbed-in-neck-with-scissors-by-angry-patient-at-uk-hospital-9189122.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/indian-origin-nurse-stabbed-in-neck-with-scissors-by-angry-patient-at-uk-hospital-9189122.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:31:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Nurse Stabbed In Neck With Scissors By 'Angry' Patient At UK Hospital - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/indian-origin-nurse-stabbed-in-neck-with-scissors-by-angry-patient-at-uk-hospital-9189122.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/indian-origin-nurse-stabbed-in-neck-with-scissors-by-angry-patient-at-uk-hospital-9189122.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:31:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Impeached South Korean President Yoon arrested in second attempt over martial law imposition - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Impeached South Korean President Yoon Arrested Over Martial Law Charges</h1><p><strong>Date: January 15, 2025</strong><br><strong>Source: Indian Express</strong></p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/South-Korea-Yoon-Arrest.jpg?w=640" alt="South Korea's Impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol Arrest" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>South Korea's Impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol Arrest: Investigators from the state anti-corruption agency and police officers make their way to the residence of impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol to execute a warrant to detain Yoon in Seoul, South Korea. (AP Photo)</figcaption><p>South Korea’s impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol was arrested, marking the first time a sitting president has been detained. Yoon faces charges of insurrection over his imposition of martial law.</p><ul><li>Yoon's arrest comes after a failed attempt earlier in January.</li><li>He is accused of overstepping his authority and suppressing dissent.</li><li>More than 1,000 police officers made a careful attempt to detain Yoon amid barriers and blockades.</li></ul><blockquote>“Today, when I saw them invading the security perimeter with fire equipment, I decided to appear before the CIO, even though it is an illegal investigation.” — Yoon Suk Yeol</blockquote><p>The arrest symbolizes significant political turmoil in South Korea, as the Constitutional Court deliberates Yoon's potential reinstatement amidst charges against him. The situation has drawn widespread attention both nationally and internationally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-impeached-president-yoon-arrested-in-second-attempt-9779357/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-impeached-president-yoon-arrested-in-second-attempt-9779357/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Millions under threat as winds bring fresh wildfire warnings, power outages in Southern California - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Millions under threat as winds bring fresh wildfire warnings, power outages in Southern California</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Local News Network</p><p>The article discusses the alarming situation in Southern California where strong winds have reignited wildfire warnings and led to potential power outages affecting millions.</p><ul><li>Strong winds are exacerbating wildfire risks in Southern California.</li><li>Evacuation orders may be issued for high-risk areas.</li><li>Power companies are preemptively shutting off electricity to prevent fire outbreaks.</li><li>Millions of residents are directly impacted by these measures.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a dangerous situation, and we urge residents to stay alert and prepared.” - Local Fire Chief</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical, and residents are advised to stay informed about evacuation routes and safety protocols.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/millions-under-threat-as-winds-bring-fresh-wildfire-warnings-power-outages-in-southern-california/articleshow/117250167.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/millions-under-threat-as-winds-bring-fresh-wildfire-warnings-power-outages-in-southern-california/articleshow/117250167.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 04:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iran refutes claims of plotting to assassinate US President-elect Trump - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Iran refutes claims of plotting to assassinate US President-elect Trump</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Iran has dismissed allegations suggesting it was involved in plotting to assassinate US President-elect Trump, labeling the claims as unfounded and part of a larger conspiracy.</p><ul><li>The Iranian government firmly rejects accusations of assassination plans against the US President-elect.</li><li>Authorities characterize the claims as a fabrication aimed at affecting US-Iran relations.</li><li>Officials emphasize the need for diplomacy over hostility amid heightened tensions.</li></ul><blockquote>“These allegations are baseless and part of a political narrative aimed at escalating tensions,” stated an Iranian official.</blockquote><p>This response from Iran underscores ongoing geopolitical disputes and the delicate nature of US-Iran relations, making a strong diplomatic approach essential for future interactions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/iran-refutes-claims-of-plotting-to-assassinate-us-president-elect-trump/articleshow/117251911.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/iran-refutes-claims-of-plotting-to-assassinate-us-president-elect-trump/articleshow/117251911.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 03:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Jaishankar to Elon Musk: Who is attending Donald Trump's inauguration on January 20 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>From Jaishankar to Elon Musk: Who is attending Donald Trump's inauguration on January 20</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 20, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Trump Inauguration" /><figcaption>Inauguration Day attendees</figcaption><p>As Donald Trump prepares for his inauguration, a diverse array of prominent figures are set to attend, reflecting a blend of political, business, and celebrity circles.</p><ul><li>Indian External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar will be present as a significant diplomatic figure.</li><li>Elon Musk, CEO of SpaceX and Tesla, is also confirmed to attend, indicating the importance of tech industry leaders in political events.</li><li>Other notable guests include key Republican figures and members of the entertainment industry.</li></ul><blockquote>"This inauguration represents a pivotal moment for America's future and a chance for unity among diverse leaders."</blockquote><p>This gathering underscores the intersection of politics and various sectors, as attendees from different domains come together to support the new administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/from-jaishankar-to-elon-musk-who-is-attending-donald-trumps-inauguration-on-january-20/articleshow/117250881.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/from-jaishankar-to-elon-musk-who-is-attending-donald-trumps-inauguration-on-january-20/articleshow/117250881.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 03:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Secretary of genocide’: Antony Blinken heckled by pro-Palestinian protester at farewell address: Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/secretary-of-genocide-antony-blinken-heckled-by-pro-palestinian-protester-at-farewell-address-watch-101736906158153.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/secretary-of-genocide-antony-blinken-heckled-by-pro-palestinian-protester-at-farewell-address-watch-101736906158153.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 02:58:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RedNote becomes most downloaded app on US Apple App Store as threat of TikTok ban looms - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/rednote-becomes-most-downloaded-app-on-us-apple-app-store-as-threat-of-tiktok-ban-looms-101736907562946.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/rednote-becomes-most-downloaded-app-on-us-apple-app-store-as-threat-of-tiktok-ban-looms-101736907562946.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 02:24:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korean impeached President Yoon arrested by law enforcement officers - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol Arrested</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/itq9i9/article69099142.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2025-01-15T014834Z_1265791479_RC21ACAIZMW4_RTRMADP_3_SOUTHKOREA-POLITICS.JPG" alt="A motorcade believed to be carrying impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol following his arrest" /><figcaption>A motorcade believed to be carrying impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol following his arrest drives down a road, in Seoul, South Korea, January 15, 2025. | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol was arrested by law enforcement on January 15, 2025, following a series of corruption investigations and tensions surrounding his declaration of martial law.</p><ul><li>Yoon was detained after police and investigators arrived at his presidential compound.</li><li>He has been accused of attempting rebellion through his martial law declaration on December 3, 2024.</li><li>The anti-corruption agency stated that they were forced to act after Yoon ignored several summons for questioning.</li></ul><blockquote>“I will fight to the end,” stated Yoon during his standoff with authorities.</blockquote><p>This event marks a significant turning point in South Korean politics as tensions rise regarding governance and law enforcement relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/south-korea-president-yoon-impeached-arrest-seoul-police-detain/article69099141.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/south-korea-president-yoon-impeached-arrest-seoul-police-detain/article69099141.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 02:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Critical condition: Indian-origin nurse stabbed in the neck by patient at Manchester hospital; accused appears in court - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian-Origin Nurse Stabbed in Manchester Hospital</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/indian_origin_nurse_stabbed_1736906573381_1736906583566.jpg" alt="Indian-origin nurse Achamma Cherian, stabbed at a Manchester hospital on Saturday evening, is still receiving treatment for her &quot;life-changing&quot; injuries. She was pictured for the first time this week.(Daily Mail)" title="Indian-origin nurse Achamma Cherian, stabbed at a Manchester hospital on Saturday evening, is still receiving treatment for her &quot;life-changing&quot; injuries. She was pictured for the first time this week.(Daily Mail)"/>
<figcaption>Indian-origin nurse Achamma Cherian, stabbed at a Manchester hospital on Saturday evening, is still receiving treatment for her "life-changing" injuries. She was pictured for the first time this week.(Daily Mail)</figcaption>
<p>An Indian-origin nurse, Achamma Cherian, in her 50s, was stabbed by a patient at the Oldham Royal Hospital in Manchester.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Victim Achamma Cherian is in critical condition following the attack.</li>
  <li>The accused, Roman Haque, 37, is charged with attempted murder and possession of a bladed article.</li>
  <li>The incident occurred in the acute medical unit, with Haque becoming angry over wait times.</li>
  <li>Cherian has been commended as an experienced and popular nurse.</li>
  <li>The attack is not believed to be racially motivated.</li>
  <li>Official statements have condemned the violence against healthcare workers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Nurses are the backbone of our NHS and should be able to care for patients without fear of violence.” - Wes Streeting, Health Secretary</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights the ongoing violence faced by healthcare workers, emphasizing the need for safety in medical environments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/critical-condition-indian-origin-nurse-stabbed-in-the-neck-by-patient-at-manchester-hospital-accused-appears-in-court-101736901846876.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/critical-condition-indian-origin-nurse-stabbed-in-the-neck-by-patient-at-manchester-hospital-accused-appears-in-court-101736901846876.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 02:08:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Complying with investigators to avoid bloodshed': Impeached South Korean President Yoon arrested - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Complying with investigators to avoid bloodshed: Impeached South Korean President Yoon arrested</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Various News Outlets</p><p>Former South Korean President Yoon has been arrested amid ongoing investigations into alleged corruption. This event marks a significant moment in South Korea's political landscape.</p><ul><li>Yoon's arrest is a result of his compliance with investigators.</li><li>The situation highlights ongoing political tensions and the public's response to government accountability.</li><li>Questions arise regarding the implications for future leadership in South Korea.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a crucial step in our fight against corruption in politics,” stated a senior government official.</blockquote><p>The arrest of an impeached president emphasizes the complexities of South Korean politics and raises concerns about the future of governance in the nation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/impeached-south-korean-president-yoon-arrested-after-failed-martial-law-bid/articleshow/117250093.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/impeached-south-korean-president-yoon-arrested-after-failed-martial-law-bid/articleshow/117250093.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 01:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The economic costs of internet shutdowns - Finshots]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxPLS02NTEwODJqdEJ3WnlmN3lIb2VicG4tR2tUOFNlYW8wbjFjRXF6ODc4Q2NOUXZvTnBwWnhnNHBYUVdYU0J0NjZJZmdycW5oR09qbEt6ZzUxMUVTdk15ZExsZk1QbXlOMW9ZaU52X19uV0dLWWFGSGNtNG55RTVBZTU4OW1kOUdfUVdBZmhHYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxPLS02NTEwODJqdEJ3WnlmN3lIb2VicG4tR2tUOFNlYW8wbjFjRXF6ODc4Q2NOUXZvTnBwWnhnNHBYUVdYU0J0NjZJZmdycW5oR09qbEt6ZzUxMUVTdk15ZExsZk1QbXlOMW9ZaU52X19uV0dLWWFGSGNtNG55RTVBZTU4OW1kOUdfUVdBZmhHYw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 01:33:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LA fires might still get worse — officials warn 'critical' weather conditions could fan the flames into Wednesday - Business Insider]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/la-wildfire-new-fire-firefighters-brace-high-winds-palisades-eaton-2025-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.businessinsider.com/la-wildfire-new-fire-firefighters-brace-high-winds-palisades-eaton-2025-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 01:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iran never plotted to kill Donald Trump, Iranian president says - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iran-never-plotted-kill-donald-trump-iranian-president-says-2025-01-15/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/iran-never-plotted-kill-donald-trump-iranian-president-says-2025-01-15/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 01:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['They will start paying': Donald Trump announces plans for 'External Revenue Service' to collect foreign - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Plans to Establish 'External Revenue Service' for Foreign Tariffs Collection</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a recent announcement, Donald Trump shared his proposal for the establishment of an 'External Revenue Service' aimed at collecting tariffs from foreign entities. This initiative is part of his broader economic strategy as he prepares for his upcoming presidential campaign.</p><ul><li>Trump's plan includes the creation of a new governmental body focused on tariff collections.</li><li>The initiative seeks to strengthen the American economy by imposing foreign tariffs.</li><li>This proposal aligns with Trump's previous policies regarding trade and tariffs during his presidency.</li></ul><blockquote>“They will start paying,” Trump emphasized, referring to foreign businesses.</blockquote><p>The announcement has sparked discussions about the implications of such a move for international trade relations and the U.S. economy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/they-will-start-paying-donald-trump-announces-plans-for-external-revenue-service-to-collect-foreign-tariffs/articleshow/117249301.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/they-will-start-paying-donald-trump-announces-plans-for-external-revenue-service-to-collect-foreign-tariffs/articleshow/117249301.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[High drama as South Korean investigators enter Presidential compound to arrest impeached Yoon Suk Yeol - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwJBVV95cUxNbUtiV0w0ZWtXeEJpSWNzbkxhU1RoVTVrMmhEajdka19pS1FUOEFhYmlVOHpTa041cWU0RTNIaHdlbjNacWg0Mm5xd0ZKVENRVVNWU185TDMwcExCenR3V0JRbGFTLXN3c3pqaE5uMTZWRG5wZHlYaG8tRjN0RXdMVldKeGhSUXptZFVXM1FxSGtzRGVGNy1sbDFvUFNxMkRvZXpzQmxmMVFab3pNbnBMVXJncUx3UkVFbW5IVG5pNlVfOFhNNER4UjZwQ2ZqUW1jZW9iU1pYZkNfaDFvVEN1TGZyejQ0blVHT0ZMdHJlT3RDUFBwcE92cXNpQ040NVYzVmdUWFN1S1pjRzDSAZACQVVfeXFMT2Z5ajQ0YlZZa0gzZmd3RmJJZUVKZWE5eUpqQkJxOEFsaHItV2RxVmM4djV1WFU0SjI2ZTJlLXNOeGhBclRyNFpYSExrNmI4TW5YTXZNNzVBTTlfTGZrOUctZFdnVUc5My1PdkUwU2ZKaXNqUmR0ZXdyeThWbkNwaURoRUZzeFZ0ZWZfaWo5Z2J6VHRsRWxlaktyRGlXaTBmdkI2WF9lek94b3pOTURZWE1HN0kxNDFUQkZ0QlRpTjNSeUhKOXROdTJValV3UFpWYzlrNW0tY0k5S3RtWVJNV3ZkbEFTeUl6SkVnUFpncTVTNnZkVXhIVnF1MElrRnpJbEVPSFFaemN4Q3diZmZYUDI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiwJBVV95cUxNbUtiV0w0ZWtXeEJpSWNzbkxhU1RoVTVrMmhEajdka19pS1FUOEFhYmlVOHpTa041cWU0RTNIaHdlbjNacWg0Mm5xd0ZKVENRVVNWU185TDMwcExCenR3V0JRbGFTLXN3c3pqaE5uMTZWRG5wZHlYaG8tRjN0RXdMVldKeGhSUXptZFVXM1FxSGtzRGVGNy1sbDFvUFNxMkRvZXpzQmxmMVFab3pNbnBMVXJncUx3UkVFbW5IVG5pNlVfOFhNNER4UjZwQ2ZqUW1jZW9iU1pYZkNfaDFvVEN1TGZyejQ0blVHT0ZMdHJlT3RDUFBwcE92cXNpQ040NVYzVmdUWFN1S1pjRzDSAZACQVVfeXFMT2Z5ajQ0YlZZa0gzZmd3RmJJZUVKZWE5eUpqQkJxOEFsaHItV2RxVmM4djV1WFU0SjI2ZTJlLXNOeGhBclRyNFpYSExrNmI4TW5YTXZNNzVBTTlfTGZrOUctZFdnVUc5My1PdkUwU2ZKaXNqUmR0ZXdyeThWbkNwaURoRUZzeFZ0ZWZfaWo5Z2J6VHRsRWxlaktyRGlXaTBmdkI2WF9lek94b3pOTURZWE1HN0kxNDFUQkZ0QlRpTjNSeUhKOXROdTJValV3UFpWYzlrNW0tY0k5S3RtWVJNV3ZkbEFTeUl6SkVnUFpncTVTNnZkVXhIVnF1MElrRnpJbEVPSFFaemN4Q3diZmZYUDI?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:14:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IRCC to implement restrictions on family Open Work Permits in January 2025 - Canada Immigration News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IRCC to implement restrictions on family Open Work Permits in January 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Canada Visa</p>
<p>The government of Canada is set to impose new restrictions on family open work permits (OWPs) for international students and foreign workers, effective January 21, 2025, limiting eligibility to spouses or common-law partners in specific educational and occupational categories.</p>
<ul>
<li>Family OWPs for international students will be restricted mainly to those enrolled in longer master's programs, doctoral programs, or select professional programs.</li>
<li>Foreign workers’ family OWPs will be limited to spouses or common-law partners of individuals in specific high-skill job categories (TEER 0, TEER 1, and certain TEER 2 and 3 roles).</li>
<li>Dependent children of foreign workers will no longer qualify for family OWPs.</li>
<li>Individuals currently holding family OWPs will retain the right to renew their permits.</li>
</ul>
<p>Minister of Immigration Marc Miller indicated these changes are part of a broader strategy to manage the influx of temporary residents in Canada.</p>
<blockquote>“These changes are expected to reduce the number of permits issued by 50,000 to 100,000 over the next three years.”</blockquote>
<p>This policy shift reflects concerns regarding housing supply and affordability in Canada.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cicnews.com/2025/01/ircc-to-implement-restrictions-on-family-open-work-permits-in-january-2025-0150500.html#gs.jqzn0h</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cicnews.com/2025/01/ircc-to-implement-restrictions-on-family-open-work-permits-in-january-2025-0150500.html#gs.jqzn0h</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 22:48:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US House passes bill barring transgender athletes from women's sports teams: 'Men cannot become women' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US House passes bill barring transgender athletes from women's sports teams</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Various News Outlets</p><p>This article discusses a recent bill passed by the US House of Representatives that prohibits transgender athletes from participating in women's sports teams, emphasizing the viewpoint that 'men cannot become women'.</p><ul><li>The bill aims to ensure fair competition in women's sports.</li><li>It has sparked significant debate across the nation.</li><li>Proponents claim it protects women's sports, while opponents argue it discriminates against transgender individuals.</li></ul><blockquote>“Men cannot become women,” a statement reflecting the perspective of bill supporters.</blockquote><p>This legislative move continues the ongoing discussion regarding gender identity and rights in sports.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/us-house-passes-bill-barring-transgender-athletes-from-womens-sports-teams-men-cannot-become-women/articleshow/117247172.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/us-house-passes-bill-barring-transgender-athletes-from-womens-sports-teams-men-cannot-become-women/articleshow/117247172.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 22:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LA fires might get worse Tuesday — officials warn 'extreme' weather conditions could fan the flames - Business Insider]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>LA Fires Could Get Worse With 'Extreme' Conditions Set to Continue</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Business Insider</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://i.insider.com/6786b31fe294a7514e8d125b" alt="image of winds blowing fire and burning brush">
  <figcaption>High winds can spread current fires and spark new ones, like the Auto Fire seen here on January 13. <span>Etienne Laurent/AFP via Getty Images</span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Firefighters in Los Angeles are bracing for more deadly winds as the ongoing fires enter their second week. Authorities warn that 'extreme' fire conditions are expected to continue, creating potential for further disaster.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The LA fires have burned over 40,000 acres, with damage estimates reaching up to $275 billion.</li>
  <li>At least 88,000 residents were under evacuation orders, with additional 84,000 facing warnings.</li>
  <li>Fatalities have been reported, with 24 confirmed deaths linked to the fires.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Life-threatening and destructive and widespread winds are already here." - Kristin Crowley, LA City Fire Chief</blockquote>
<p>The significance of the event is immense, with rising damages impacting not only local communities but the economy as well. Firefighters continue their battle against flames that have already devastated numerous structures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/la-wildfire-new-fire-firefighters-brace-high-winds-palisades-eaton-2025-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.businessinsider.com/la-wildfire-new-fire-firefighters-brace-high-winds-palisades-eaton-2025-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 22:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tim Kaine grills Pete Hegseth over 'cheating' on wife, social media users ask what about Doug Emhoff - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tim Kaine grills Pete Hegseth over 'cheating' on wife, social media users ask what about Doug Emhoff</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p>
<p>This article discusses a heated exchange between Senator Tim Kaine and Fox News host Pete Hegseth, focusing on allegations of personal misconduct and the reactions from social media regarding the situation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Senator Tim Kaine confronted Pete Hegseth about alleged infidelity.</li>
  <li>The discussion sparked conversations on social media, with users bringing up Doug Emhoff.</li>
  <li>Reactions from the public indicated a broader concern about hypocrisy in political narratives.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"It’s important to hold public figures accountable for their actions, especially when they speak on family values." - Tim Kaine</blockquote>
<p>The article highlights the ongoing dialogue about integrity among public figures, especially amidst contrasting public personas and personal allegations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/tim-kaine-grills-pete-hegseth-over-cheating-on-wife-social-media-users-ask-what-about-doug-emhoff/articleshow/117246615.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/tim-kaine-grills-pete-hegseth-over-cheating-on-wife-social-media-users-ask-what-about-doug-emhoff/articleshow/117246615.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 20:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biden moves to lift state sponsor of terrorism designation for Cuba, part of deal to free prisoners - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden moves to lift state sponsor of terrorism designation for Cuba, part of deal to free prisoners</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/qbre93/article69099087.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/EU_Russia_US_45063.jpg" alt="Joe Biden notified Congress of his intent to lift the U.S. designation of Cuba as a state sponsor of terrorism." title="Joe Biden notified Congress of his intent to lift the U.S. designation of Cuba as a state sponsor of terrorism." /><figcaption>Joe Biden notified Congress of his intent to lift the U.S. designation of Cuba as a state sponsor of terrorism.</figcaption><p>President Joe Biden announced his intention to lift the U.S. designation of Cuba as a state sponsor of terrorism, part of a deal to facilitate the release of political prisoners on the island.</p><ul><li>Biden informed Congress about the decision as part of a deal brokered by the Catholic Church.</li><li>Many political prisoners are expected to be released by the end of the current Biden administration.</li><li>The U.S. intends to ease economic pressures on Cuba, reversing tough measures imposed by the Trump administration.</li><li>Human rights groups have urged the Biden administration to make this change to alleviate Cuba's economic struggles.</li><li>Republican lawmakers have criticized the move, preemptively cautioning that a reversal could occur once Trump assumes office again.</li></ul><blockquote>“Today’s decision is unacceptable on its merits.” - Texas Sen. Ted Cruz</blockquote><p>The decision is part of ongoing tensions between U.S. and Cuban relations, particularly regarding human rights and economic sanctions, with significant reactions expected from both sides.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/biden-administration-will-announce-its-lifting-state-sponsor-of-terrorism-designation-for-cuba/article69099086.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/biden-administration-will-announce-its-lifting-state-sponsor-of-terrorism-designation-for-cuba/article69099086.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fact check: Viral claims on California wildfires - DW (English)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxPUXg2WGFFNFJ2N3ViTlBESldxVEtoeEZ4TGFvRUFwMUk1cHpCMUpJOGtGT21xWi12dHh4TFRnWXpBX0dmSmtMcHlTRlU4RlBHTXZZZDdZWXZNekJJeU1TaldhdVBNWTZNclJMWUJRWlZKdV90aGJSekJaX1BjaF83bWJTWnhqeVU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwFBVV95cUxPUXg2WGFFNFJ2N3ViTlBESldxVEtoeEZ4TGFvRUFwMUk1cHpCMUpJOGtGT21xWi12dHh4TFRnWXpBX0dmSmtMcHlTRlU4RlBHTXZZZDdZWXZNekJJeU1TaldhdVBNWTZNclJMWUJRWlZKdV90aGJSekJaX1BjaF83bWJTWnhqeVU?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:43:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LA Fires on Track to Cause up to $275 Billion in Destruction: Estimate - Business Insider]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>LA fires could get worse with 'extreme' conditions set to continue</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source: </strong> Business Insider</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://i.insider.com/6786b31fe294a7514e8d125b" alt="image of winds blowing fire and burning brush">
  <figcaption>High winds can spread current fires and spark new ones, like the Auto Fire seen here on January 13. <span> Etienne Laurent/AFP via Getty Images </span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Los Angeles continues to battle devastating wildfires, with new reports indicating that the fires have consumed over 40,000 acres and could lead to economic damages up to $275 billion. Evacuations have affected over 172,000 residents as extreme weather persists.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Firefighters are contending with deadly winds as they fight multiple blazes.</li>
  <li>Estimated damages from the fires may exceed $275 billion, surpassing earlier disasters in Maui and Hurricane Helene.</li>
  <li>Approximately 88,000 individuals currently under evacuation orders, with a significant number residing in areas considered at high risk.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Life-threatening and destructive and widespread winds are already here," stated LA City Fire Chief Kristin Crowley.</blockquote>
<p>As fire conditions worsen, the community braces for ongoing challenges, and fire teams continue their efforts to contain the rapidly spreading fires.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/la-wildfire-new-fire-firefighters-brace-high-winds-palisades-eaton-2025-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.businessinsider.com/la-wildfire-new-fire-firefighters-brace-high-winds-palisades-eaton-2025-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump to create new department to collect revenue from foreign sources on inauguration day - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump to Establish New Revenue Collection Agency on Inauguration Day</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 15, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/14/550x309/AP12-23-2024-000005B-0_1736538936843_1736880914399.jpg" alt="Trump did not specify whether the new agency would replace collections of tariffs, duties, fees and fines by US Customs and Border Protection.(AP)" title="Trump did not specify whether the new agency would replace collections of tariffs, duties, fees and fines by US Customs and Border Protection.(AP)">
<figcaption>Trump did not specify whether the new agency would replace collections of tariffs, duties, fees and fines by US Customs and Border Protection.(AP)</figcaption>
<p>US President-elect Donald Trump announced plans to create a new government agency called the External Revenue Service on January 20, coinciding with his second inauguration. This agency will focus on collecting tariffs and duties from foreign sources as part of a broader strategy to implement new import tariffs.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump aims to shift revenue collection from the IRS to the new department.</li>
  <li>He criticized existing trade agreements for burdening American taxpayers.</li>
  <li>The proposal includes tariffs of 10% on global imports and higher tariffs on goods from Canada, Mexico, and China.</li>
  <li>Economic forecasts predict significant revenue generation from the proposed tariffs, but potential adverse effects on the economy.</li>
  <li>Senator Ron Wyden condemned Trump's plan as a tax increase on families and small businesses.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We will begin charging those that make money off of us with Trade, and they will start paying, FINALLY, their fair share." - Donald Trump</blockquote>
<p>This initiative reflects Trump's ongoing commitment to reshape U.S. trade policy and revenue structure as he resumes presidential duties.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trump-says-to-create-new-department-to-collect-revenue-from-foreign-sources-on-inauguration-day-101736880514256.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trump-says-to-create-new-department-to-collect-revenue-from-foreign-sources-on-inauguration-day-101736880514256.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 19:00:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pete Hegseth grilled in Senate hearing over drinking, infidelity, sexual misconduct; JD Vance says this g - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pete Hegseth grilled in Senate hearing over drinking, infidelity, sexual misconduct; JD Vance says this grandstanding is perplexing</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The Senate hearing involving Pete Hegseth has brought to light serious allegations concerning his personal conduct, including issues of drinking and sexual misconduct. JD Vance expressed confusion over the nature of the scrutiny Hegseth faced during the proceedings.</p><ul><li>Hegseth was questioned about allegations of infidelity and substance abuse.</li><li>Senator JD Vance criticized the hearing as unnecessary grandstanding.</li><li>The implications of the hearing on Hegseth's future political career remain uncertain.</li></ul><blockquote>“This kind of grandstanding is perplexing,” - JD Vance</blockquote><p>The outcome of this hearing could have lasting implications for Pete Hegseth, reflecting broader issues of accountability for public officials.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/pete-hegseth-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-drinking-infidelity-sexual-misconduct-jd-vance-says-this-grandstanding-is-perplexing/articleshow/117245439.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/pete-hegseth-grilled-in-senate-hearing-over-drinking-infidelity-sexual-misconduct-jd-vance-says-this-grandstanding-is-perplexing/articleshow/117245439.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 18:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>