<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:22:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:22:16 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Ukrainian military was carrying out terrorist attacks when Azerbaijani flight tried to land': Russia cla - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia Accuses Ukrainian Military of Terrorism During Azerbaijani Flight Incident</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Russia has claimed that the Ukrainian military was conducting terrorist attacks at the time an Azerbaijani flight attempted to land, escalating tensions between the nations.</p><ul><li>The incident allegedly occurred during the approach of the flight.</li><li>Russia's statement reflects ongoing conflicts and accusations in the region.</li><li>The situation adds to the broader geopolitical tensions involving Ukraine and Azerbaijan.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ukrainian military was carrying out terrorist attacks when Azerbaijani flight tried to land.”</blockquote><p>This claim from Russia could exacerbate existing conflicts and further strain relations in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/ukrainian-military-was-carrying-out-terrorist-attacks-when-azerbaijani-flight-tried-to-land-russia-claims/articleshow/116715822.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/ukrainian-military-was-carrying-out-terrorist-attacks-when-azerbaijani-flight-tried-to-land-russia-claims/articleshow/116715822.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Akin To B-21 Raider’s Broad-Spectrum Stealth, China’s New 6th-Gen Stealth Fighters Bound To Rattle U.S. Military - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Unveils New 6th-Generation Stealth Fighters</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Eurasian Times</p><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/China-sixth-generation-1.jpg" alt="China’s 6th-Gen Aircraft" width="696" height="392"><figcaption>File Image: China’s 6th-Gen Aircraft</figcaption><p>China has recently unveiled two new stealth fighter prototypes, featuring broad-spectrum stealth technology that enhances their ability to evade radar detection across various frequencies.</p><ul><li>Broad-spectrum stealth minimizes detectability to both high and low-frequency radars.</li><li>This technology was previously seen only in strategic bombers, marking a significant leap for fighter jets.</li><li>The introduction of these fighters positions China ahead in global stealth capabilities.</li><li>The larger fighter, possibly the J-36, has enhanced payload capacity and stealth features.</li><li>The smaller fighter, likely from SAC, is designed for agility and air superiority roles.</li><li>Capabilities of the new fighters may include optional manning and next-generation power plants.</li></ul><blockquote>“China’s rapid advancement in military aviation technology is unquestionable.”</blockquote><p>The prototypes reveal China's significant progress in military technology but actual capabilities will be assessed as they develop further.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/akin-to-b-21-raiders-broad-spectrum-stealth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/akin-to-b-21-raiders-broad-spectrum-stealth/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:40:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MAGA crowd demands no H-1B visas for Indians, Vivek Ramaswamy says American parents raising their kids wrong - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MAGA supporters call for H-1B visa freeze as Vivek Ramaswamy blames American parenting for STEM shortfall</h1><p><strong>Published On: </strong>Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Published By: </strong>Nandini Yadav</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/vivek-ramaswamy-113223538-16x9.jpg?VersionId=Y_5jp5SEGmmNeScboJkmGTDqzvcQvq1D&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Vivek Ramaswamy, 2024 US presidential candidate" title="Vivek Ramaswamy, 2024 US presidential candidate" height="388"><figcaption>Vivek Ramaswamy, 2024 US presidential candidate</figcaption><p>The debate over H-1B visas has reignited as Trump supporters demand a halt to hiring foreign skilled workers. Vivek Ramaswamy argues the real issue lies in American culture and parenting.</p><ul><li>Trump supporters are pushing for a complete freeze on H-1B visas for skilled workers.</li><li>Vivek Ramaswamy attributes the STEM workforce shortfall to American parenting practices.</li><li>He contrasts the cultural values of immigrant families with those of mainstream American culture.</li><li>Critics accuse Ramaswamy of undermining American workers' concerns.</li><li>The H-1B visa debate highlights tensions between low-cost foreign labor and domestic job security.</li></ul><blockquote>The reason top tech companies often hire foreign-born & first-generation engineers over “native” Americans isn’t because of an innate American IQ deficit... — Vivek Ramaswamy</blockquote><p>Ramaswamy's comments have sparked significant backlash, highlighting the cultural divide in America's approach to education and success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/maga-crowd-demands-no-h-1b-visas-for-indians-vivek-ramaswamy-says-american-parents-raising-their-kids-wrong-2656273-2024-12-27</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/maga-crowd-demands-no-h-1b-visas-for-indians-vivek-ramaswamy-says-american-parents-raising-their-kids-wrong-2656273-2024-12-27</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:03:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German President dissolves parliament, calls early election for February 23 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>German President dissolves parliament, calls early election for February 23</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 23, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> News Network</p><p>The German President has taken the historic step of dissolving the parliament, prompting early elections to be scheduled for February 23, 2024. This decision follows a period of political unrest and is expected to reshape the current government.</p><ul><li>The parliament's dissolution is seen as a reaction to political instability.</li><li>Early elections aim to restore confidence in the political system.</li><li>Key political parties are preparing their campaign strategies for the upcoming elections.</li></ul><blockquote>"This decision reflects the need for a renewed mandate from the public." - German President</blockquote><p>The dissolution of parliament signals a critical moment in German politics, highlighting the challenges faced by the current administration and the call for a renewed democratic process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/german-president-dissolves-parliament-calls-early-election-for-february-23/articleshow/116711830.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/german-president-dissolves-parliament-calls-early-election-for-february-23/articleshow/116711830.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea Parliament impeaches acting President Han Duck-soo amid political tension - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Parliament impeaches acting President Han Duck-soo amid political tension</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>In a surprising turn of events, the South Korean Parliament has voted to impeach acting President Han Duck-soo amidst escalating political tensions. This decision has been met with significant public attention and implications for the future of the nation's governance.</p><ul><li>The impeachment vote reflects deep-rooted political discord.</li><li>Public demonstrations have surged in response to the government's actions.</li><li>This event may lead to a profound impact on upcoming elections.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“This is a critical moment for our democracy,” said a key opposition leader.</p></blockquote><p>The impeachment of Han Duck-soo marks a pivotal moment in South Korea's political landscape, potentially reshaping the country's future governance and political alignment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/south-korea-parliament-impeaches-acting-president-han-duck-soo-amid-political-tension/articleshow/116710133.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/south-korea-parliament-impeaches-acting-president-han-duck-soo-amid-political-tension/articleshow/116710133.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBI ‘Found Covid Was Leaked From China Lab’ But Joe Biden Was Kept In Dark: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FBI ‘Found Covid Was Leaked From China Lab’ But Joe Biden Was Kept In Dark: Report</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2024/12/joe-biden-2024-12-ec6a4bfd2f5d18dc90d1be0455bc6953.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="US President Joe Biden | Reuters Image" /><figcaption>US President Joe Biden | Reuters Image</figcaption><p>The FBI is reported to have found evidence suggesting that Covid-19 leaked from a Chinese lab, but the findings were excluded from a report sent to President Joe Biden. This raises concerns about transparency and the influence of intelligence officials over significant scientific inquiries.</p><ul><li>The FBI allegedly silenced the US defense department and researchers supporting the lab leak theory.</li><li>Research indicated similarities between Covid-19 and techniques described in a 2008 study from the Wuhan Institute of Virology.</li><li>Findings that supported the lab leak theory were excluded from an August 2021 report presented to Biden.</li><li>Federal grant documents detailing virus engineering were improperly classified according to a whistleblower.</li><li>The WHO and China claimed the virus likely moved from bats to humans via another animal in a 2021 report.</li></ul><blockquote>“What ended up on the cutting-room floor needs to be re-examined.” - FBI scientist Jason Bannan</blockquote><p>This article highlights the ongoing debate about the origins of the Covid-19 virus and the implications of governmental transparency in scientific investigation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/fbi-found-covid-was-leaked-from-china-lab-but-joe-biden-was-kept-in-dark-report-9169573.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/fbi-found-covid-was-leaked-from-china-lab-but-joe-biden-was-kept-in-dark-report-9169573.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:54:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea’s parliament votes to impeach acting president Han - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/27/south-koreas-acting-president-faces-impeachment-vote-as-won-plunges</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/27/south-koreas-acting-president-faces-impeachment-vote-as-won-plunges</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:45:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Type 076 Sichuan: China Unveils World’s Largest Amphibious Assault Ship With EMALS; Comes After 6th-Gen Aircraft “Debut” - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Launches Type 076 Sichuan, Largest Amphibious Assault Ship</h1><p><strong>Date: December 27, 2023</strong> | <strong>Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://cdn.bsky.app/img/feed_fullsize/plain/did:plc:rikbs5dvvjaoioq3n3d7udq2/bafkreidnucizbe4gyuugwlbxwt76v5cngd7pmrdyutjy3c5dcbfbvt5zya@jpeg" alt="Type 076 Sichuan Launch" width="1000" height="665"><figcaption>The first Chinese PLA Navy Type 076 amphibious assault ship was launched on the morning of Dec. 27 at the Hudong-Zhonghua Shipyard in Shanghai. It was named after the province of Sichuan and has a hull number of 51. PLA Navy</figcaption></figure><p>The Type 076 amphibious assault ship, named Sichuan, was ceremoniously launched in Shanghai, marking a significant advancement in China's naval capabilities.</p><ul><li>The vessel is the largest amphibious assault ship globally, with a full displacement of over 40,000 tons.</li><li>Sichuan integrates cutting-edge technology, featuring twin island superstructures and electromagnetic catapults for aircraft operations.</li><li>The ship is designed to carry fixed-wing aircraft, helicopters, and amphibious equipment.</li><li>It will play a vital role in China’s maritime defense strategy, including the use of unmanned aerial vehicles.</li><li>It has advanced close-in defense systems for protection against aerial threats.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Sichuan will enhance the PLA Navy's capacity for amphibious operations, power projection, and quick responses in the region.” - PLA Navy Statement</blockquote><p>The launch of the Type 076 Sichuan represents a significant step in China's increasing naval power and capabilities, particularly in amphibious warfare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/cina-unveils-worlds-largest-amphibious-assault-ship/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/cina-unveils-worlds-largest-amphibious-assault-ship/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel attorney general orders probe on PM Benjamin Netanyahu's wife Sara - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Attorney General Orders Probe on PM Netanyahu's Wife Sara</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date]</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> [Source]</p><p>Israeli Attorney General has initiated an investigation concerning the actions of Sara Netanyahu, wife of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, following allegations of misconduct.</p><ul><li>The investigation aims to examine various claims regarding Sara Netanyahu's behavior related to public funds.</li><li>This probe is part of a broader portrayal of corruption allegations surrounding the Netanyahu family.</li><li>It has significant political implications amidst ongoing tensions in the Israeli government.</li></ul><blockquote>“This investigation is essential to uphold the rule of law and accountability among public officials.”</blockquote><p>This inquiry may lead to increased scrutiny of public officials in Israel and impact public trust in the political system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/israel-attorney-general-orders-probe-on-pm-benjamin-netanyahus-wife-sara/articleshow/116705317.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/israel-attorney-general-orders-probe-on-pm-benjamin-netanyahus-wife-sara/articleshow/116705317.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Super weapon': China’s new stealth fighter jet could be a 'game-changer' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's Stealth Fighter Jet: A Potential Game-Changer</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The Times</p><p>This article explores the implications of China's new stealth fighter jet, which has been touted as a revolutionary addition to military aviation.</p><ul><li>The stealth fighter is designed to evade radar detection.</li><li>Experts believe it could alter the balance of power in the Asia-Pacific region.</li><li>China aims to enhance its air superiority with this advanced aircraft.</li><li>The new jet features cutting-edge technology and weaponry.</li></ul><blockquote>“This aircraft represents a significant leap in China's military capabilities,” said a defense analyst.</blockquote><p>The development of this stealth fighter could have far-reaching effects on regional security and military strategy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/j-36-chinas-stealthy-sixth-generation-fighter-jet-super-weapon/articleshow/116708110.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/j-36-chinas-stealthy-sixth-generation-fighter-jet-super-weapon/articleshow/116708110.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 08:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia warns US on possible nuclear testing under Trump - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPVl85WXlBeFlQVkZrX0Q5ZWRoXzJicHg0WmRLeldieHlZOWVyS2ZacXZlanc3VVRNbDhWR3RTWk1DZlVybUVTRjNPY09DSzNCVzB2QThaUG1TLXFnc2ZhaWpDSjF1ZTNIR2h3ODlRRFZIdDFNOThNY1FndEJ6ejFZZGtJX1FwYk5reHFsUzRtZWxRaTA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxPVl85WXlBeFlQVkZrX0Q5ZWRoXzJicHg0WmRLeldieHlZOWVyS2ZacXZlanc3VVRNbDhWR3RTWk1DZlVybUVTRjNPY09DSzNCVzB2QThaUG1TLXFnc2ZhaWpDSjF1ZTNIR2h3ODlRRFZIdDFNOThNY1FndEJ6ejFZZGtJX1FwYk5reHFsUzRtZWxRaTA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:36:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baba Vanga's Prophetic timeline: Predictions from 2025 to the end of the world - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/astrology/others/baba-vangas-prophetic-timeline-predictions-from-2025-to-the-end-of-the-world/articleshow/116677241.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/astrology/others/baba-vangas-prophetic-timeline-predictions-from-2025-to-the-end-of-the-world/articleshow/116677241.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk responds to tech CEO who asked if foreign-born workers are really taking jobs away from America - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAJBVV95cUxObE81RFd6QXlxUmF0cEI0c3FNOGtJMFZQQkxTSWJxMDZEcEFEWmpUaFBuZGx2ZkhGcTNiY0QtQ3VsNlFkTnhYV3hKV2FPN2JIaERiWVc3RUJjTVhJam9EOF9OeENiT3dEQlBHbTFSX1NIOWlSQ1IwNWY1U00yX2hDWWlkZEJyTjRNS1Z2SWl1U3JpQ2NEbmsyaXVUZXp0cEFTYk9LUmV2dEJjcXllcDhKeVBaVUZrS2JYZi1BRFF0cFRkRjBBRlhfY1NaTm1TcjFTUjVNaUZONTlKSUh0NDUyemd0T21LdXgxZVdNem9Ia21GSG1wVHlKdUpXMHczbFY2Wm5fZjJSVjnSAY4CQVVfeXFMUDh5eDV6U1ZLSllNZUh4Y3p0MnlIMDB1X3VxblRXYXE1ZkJnSS1ZTFBYVVZjZEhDSEVZTUN5eHlDWlRhaXo0dlF3VVQ3UXFLNWxuMERyelNPX1JXd0hHdFJqN3l0eHYwMUQ4Nms3Z2pOQzdHZU1JSDYzc3Z4UHU2dmRFeU5sa2ktYXJHSGM1eEhSSDJuQVFYRU9qN0c2cU5UVkZtQ056RXR0YVlZSDNFQlBpa2lST0FFc2hEdEZ0T0tDQWg0SU9ka05SRUFySjBrYlFkcG5ybUpXNGREdHdiZlE4S3NaY0xTTWU4dXFQdmRPZG9WT0xvaW9laWx3bVAyaF9SQU5PWmp0S0ZNdnF3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiiAJBVV95cUxObE81RFd6QXlxUmF0cEI0c3FNOGtJMFZQQkxTSWJxMDZEcEFEWmpUaFBuZGx2ZkhGcTNiY0QtQ3VsNlFkTnhYV3hKV2FPN2JIaERiWVc3RUJjTVhJam9EOF9OeENiT3dEQlBHbTFSX1NIOWlSQ1IwNWY1U00yX2hDWWlkZEJyTjRNS1Z2SWl1U3JpQ2NEbmsyaXVUZXp0cEFTYk9LUmV2dEJjcXllcDhKeVBaVUZrS2JYZi1BRFF0cFRkRjBBRlhfY1NaTm1TcjFTUjVNaUZONTlKSUh0NDUyemd0T21LdXgxZVdNem9Ia21GSG1wVHlKdUpXMHczbFY2Wm5fZjJSVjnSAY4CQVVfeXFMUDh5eDV6U1ZLSllNZUh4Y3p0MnlIMDB1X3VxblRXYXE1ZkJnSS1ZTFBYVVZjZEhDSEVZTUN5eHlDWlRhaXo0dlF3VVQ3UXFLNWxuMERyelNPX1JXd0hHdFJqN3l0eHYwMUQ4Nms3Z2pOQzdHZU1JSDYzc3Z4UHU2dmRFeU5sa2ktYXJHSGM1eEhSSDJuQVFYRU9qN0c2cU5UVkZtQ056RXR0YVlZSDNFQlBpa2lST0FFc2hEdEZ0T0tDQWg0SU9ka05SRUFySjBrYlFkcG5ybUpXNGREdHdiZlE4S3NaY0xTTWU4dXFQdmRPZG9WT0xvaW9laWx3bVAyaF9SQU5PWmp0S0ZNdnF3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 07:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian family’s behavior on Finland train sparks clash over cultural norms - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian Family’s Behavior on Finland Train Sparks Clash Over Cultural Norms</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [INSERT DATE] <strong>Source:</strong> [INSERT SOURCE]</p><p>This article discusses a cultural clash involving an Indian family on a train in Finland, highlighting the differences in social behavior and cultural expectations.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred on a Finnish train where an Indian family engaged in behavior deemed inappropriate by local standards.</li><li>Passengers expressed discomfort, leading to a social media debate over cultural norms and expectations.</li><li>This situation raises questions about the integration of diverse cultures and mutual respect in public spaces.</li></ul><blockquote>"Culture is a complex social construct that requires understanding and adaptation from both parties involved."</blockquote><p>The clash serves as a reminder of the importance of cultural sensitivity and awareness, especially in multicultural environments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/indian-familys-behavior-on-finland-train-sparks-clash-over-cultural-norms/articleshow/116637434.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/indian-familys-behavior-on-finland-train-sparks-clash-over-cultural-norms/articleshow/116637434.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['You've got to be switched on': Ricky Ponting slams Rohit Sharma's shot selection - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxNLTVUUGpNNXd6TTZkZGxsVWdJTGNRcFJYTFFfU19xUTE0dmdhX1lWZ2pfVlR1NDBubmtnb213Y2dvdGxMV3JDSXpKSm0tVi15dmtJYUlKVTZQRkNyVVM1dEpUS1RnTUFucElLa3VfdHdpNm9MSkQ3ekR1cFBaQXJlTmUtd0FHS1VySXpzZkM3azlIWWdubUtjeHl6XzRTYzBrc2RJTGtJYzdKUk5hZGJKUTBHSHlNTEdIdjJTSHpZaWlYMjFpeUdpNUpMeTVoM0k5dFd5QktvMXJQUjJ6VGhLLThmSG14Sks0cnAxaGUtTmtwaDRyVWRHampsVDRiUkhFUWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggJBVV95cUxNLTVUUGpNNXd6TTZkZGxsVWdJTGNRcFJYTFFfU19xUTE0dmdhX1lWZ2pfVlR1NDBubmtnb213Y2dvdGxMV3JDSXpKSm0tVi15dmtJYUlKVTZQRkNyVVM1dEpUS1RnTUFucElLa3VfdHdpNm9MSkQ3ekR1cFBaQXJlTmUtd0FHS1VySXpzZkM3azlIWWdubUtjeHl6XzRTYzBrc2RJTGtJYzdKUk5hZGJKUTBHSHlNTEdIdjJTSHpZaWlYMjFpeUdpNUpMeTVoM0k5dFd5QktvMXJQUjJ6VGhLLThmSG14Sks0cnAxaGUtTmtwaDRyVWRHampsVDRiUkhFUWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Pathetic. Never happened in the history of Indian cricket': Rohit Sharma destroyed by former BCCI selector MSK Prasad - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MSK Prasad Criticizes Rohit Sharma's Captaincy Amidst Poor Performance</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 27, 2024<br><strong>Source: </strong>Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/CRICKET-AUS-IND-103_1735279362113_1735279372574.jpg" alt="No respite for Rohit Sharma(AFP)" title="No respite for Rohit Sharma(AFP)"><figcaption>No respite for Rohit Sharma(AFP)</figcaption><p>Rohit Sharma faces harsh criticism from former BCCI selector MSK Prasad for his recent performances and captaincy during the ongoing Border-Gavaskar Trophy against Australia.</p><ul><li>Rohit scored just 6, 3, and 10 in his first three innings, emphasizing his underwhelming form.</li><li>MSK Prasad stated, "It was pathetic. Never happened in the history of Indian cricket that we lost back-to-back three games... he had absolutely no runs in that series."</li><li>Rohit's captaincy has been criticized for ineffective decisions and poor field placements.</li></ul><blockquote>“I personally feel that it has got a direct impact. If the captain comes into some sort of form, that has a direct impact on the side.” - MSK Prasad</blockquote><p>The commentary surrounding Rohit Sharma highlights the ongoing struggles within the Indian cricket team, particularly under his leadership, suggesting significant questions about his future as captain.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/pathetic-never-happened-in-the-history-of-indian-cricket-rohit-sharma-destroyed-by-former-bcci-selector-msk-prasad-101735279268993.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/cricket/pathetic-never-happened-in-the-history-of-indian-cricket-rohit-sharma-destroyed-by-former-bcci-selector-msk-prasad-101735279268993.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 06:09:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rohit Sharma's form directly impacting his captaincy: Former chief selector - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Rohit Sharma's Form Affecting His Captaincy, Says Former Chief Selector</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> New Delhi | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116702424,imgsize-32234,width-400,resizemode-4/116702424.jpg" alt="Rohit Sharma during the Boxing Day Test against Australia" title="Rohit Sharma during the Boxing Day Test against Australia at Melbourne Cricket Ground. (Photo by Robert Cianflone/Getty Images)"><figcaption>Rohit Sharma during the Boxing Day Test against Australia at Melbourne Cricket Ground. (Photo by Robert Cianflone/Getty Images)</figcaption><p>The performance of Indian cricket captain Rohit Sharma has come under scrutiny as his low scores in the ongoing series against Australia reportedly impact his leadership. Former chief selector MSK Prasad highlighted this concern during commentary.</p><ul><li>Rohit was dismissed for just 3 runs in the Boxing Day Test, continuing a trend of low scores (3, 6, and 10) in the series.</li><li>MSK Prasad pointed out that Rohit's recent poor form is linked to his captaincy performance.</li><li>In previous Tests against New Zealand, Rohit had disappointing scores, contributing to a series whitewash.</li><li>Prasad noted that captaincy requires a player to be in form, and Rohit's recent failures might reflect on how he leads the team.</li><li>After missing the first Test, Rohit returned but faced challenges with his leadership and decision-making during the matches.</li></ul><blockquote>“If a captain comes with some sort of form, that has a direct impact on the side.” - MSK Prasad</blockquote><p>Overall, the article suggests that Rohit Sharma's poor batting form is not just a personal issue but one that affects the broader dynamics and performance of the Indian cricket team.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rohit-sharmas-form-directly-impacting-his-captaincy-former-chief-selector/articleshow/116702446.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rohit-sharmas-form-directly-impacting-his-captaincy-former-chief-selector/articleshow/116702446.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea’s acting president faces impeachment vote as currency plunges - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/27/south-koreas-acting-president-faces-impeachment-vote-as-won-plunges</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/27/south-koreas-acting-president-faces-impeachment-vote-as-won-plunges</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 05:03:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Lazy, not committed": Ricky Ponting hammers Rohit Sharma for gifting his wicket to Pat Cummins in fourth Test - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ricky Ponting Criticizes Rohit Sharma's Dismissal in Fourth Test</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Crictoday</p>
<img src="https://crictoday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Rohit-Sharma-1.webp" alt="Rohit Sharma" width="1200" height="675">
<figcaption>He failed to complete a shot, and the ball went in the air, allowing Scott Boland to settle under it and complete a simple catch. The contribution of 3 runs increased his tally of poor scores in red-ball cricket.</figcaption>
<p>Ricky Ponting has lambasted Rohit Sharma for his lazy shot against Pat Cummins during the fourth Test at the MCG, which saw the Indian captain score only three runs. This performance has contributed to his ongoing struggles in red-ball cricket.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Ponting criticized Sharma for being lazy and not committed during his innings.</li>
  <li>Sharma’s struggles with form continued after a poor home series against Bangladesh and New Zealand.</li>
  <li>This dismissal marks an ongoing trend for Sharma, who has yet to find his footing in Australia.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“He was lazy and not switched on. The type of shot he played was strange. He has been one of the best hookers and pullers since he started playing international cricket but he is not there at the moment.” - Ricky Ponting</blockquote>
<p>The criticism from Ponting highlights the growing concern over Sharma's form and readiness to compete against top-tier Australian bowlers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/lazy-not-committed-ricky-ponting-hammers-rohit-sharma-for-gifting-his-wicket-to-pat-cummins-in-fourth-test/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crictoday.com/cricket/news/lazy-not-committed-ricky-ponting-hammers-rohit-sharma-for-gifting-his-wicket-to-pat-cummins-in-fourth-test/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy Says H-1B 'Broken' But A Solution For US Is Fewer Reruns Of 'Friends' Show - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vivek Ramaswamy Says H-1B 'Broken' But A Solution For US Is Fewer Reruns Of 'Friends' Show</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src='https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270' alt='Vivek Ramaswamy will lead the Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) with Elon Musk.' /><figcaption>Vivek Ramaswamy will lead the Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) with Elon Musk.</figcaption><p>Vivek Ramaswamy addresses the issues surrounding the H-1B visa program and emphasizes the need for a cultural shift in America to elevate excellence over mediocrity.</p><ul><li>Ramaswamy discusses the hiring practices of tech giants favoring foreign-born engineers.</li><li>He advocates for a shift towards celebrating academic and engineering excellence.</li><li>Ramaswamy suggests that American culture has been too focused on mediocrity.</li><li>He refers to this moment as America’s 'Sputnik moment' and calls for awakening from cultural slumber.</li></ul><blockquote>“Our American culture has venerated mediocrity over excellence for way too long.” - Vivek Ramaswamy</blockquote><p>Ramaswamy urges a change in cultural values to prioritize hard work and achievement in order to strengthen America's position in the world.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/vivek-ramaswamy-says-h-1b-broken-but-a-solution-for-us-is-fewer-reruns-of-friends-show-9169460.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/vivek-ramaswamy-says-h-1b-broken-but-a-solution-for-us-is-fewer-reruns-of-friends-show-9169460.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:05:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What climate records were broken in 2024? - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/longform/2024/12/27/climate-records-broken-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/longform/2024/12/27/climate-records-broken-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:57:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Miraculous Landing” After Shootdown By Russian SAM: Azerbaijan Plane Crash Remind Of ‘Very Similar’ 2003 Incident - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Miraculous Landing After Shootdown By Russian SAM: Azerbaijan Plane Crash Reminds Of 'Very Similar' 2003 Incident</h1>
<p><strong>The Azerbaijani plane crash in Kazakhstan has sparked speculations that a Russian surface-to-air missile may have struck the aircraft. The tragic incident has also revived memories of an aircraft that was hit by a missile in 2003 and managed to land safely with no fatalities.</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/WhatsApp-Image-2024-12-26-at-1.33.27-AM.jpeg" alt="Wreckage of the Azerbaijan airline that crashed in Aktau, Kazakhstan" width="800" height="450">
<figcaption>Wreckage of the Azerbaijan airline that crashed in Aktau, Kazakhstan</figcaption>
<p>The aircraft, an Embraer 190, was flying from Baku to Grozny but crashed near Aktau in Kazakhstan. Andrii Kovalenko, head of the Center for Countering Disinformation at Ukraine's National Security and Defense Council, stated that the plane was shot down by a Russian air defense system. The crash has raised suspicions of a Russian strike on the aircraft.</p>
<p>The incident has drawn parallels with a 2003 event involving a DHL cargo plane that was hit by a missile but landed safely. The Azerbaijan Airlines crash, with 38 fatalities, is under investigation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/shot-down-by-a-surface-to-air-missile-this-aircraft/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/shot-down-by-a-surface-to-air-missile-this-aircraft/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:53:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk says his $1 billion offer to Wikipedia “still stands” - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxPME0yZEZVMGZvU09pdTFnSm9nUXRTU1AwYjdTd2t0SHVDWU41U2VEQkxSWWp4RlFuc0JTUmxncFVjZ0stYXNmd1RvNDFXbU9yZjRocjR1NDNMMU5nQ19ZRVdhZmExX293cXI0NGF6ZHM5M0szMzduZFUycFJpNnJJN1JvVnhIa0ZnN0luVU5XU0dzYnBacDVDNzgwSjRkUGJMc3dMdmdmOFd4UmgzSjFDLXRWeTRKUHF1aDlMRnMycGJyN0taME5hUmF1VXNDYU43MG5xeUZWNGFJb3M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2wFBVV95cUxPME0yZEZVMGZvU09pdTFnSm9nUXRTU1AwYjdTd2t0SHVDWU41U2VEQkxSWWp4RlFuc0JTUmxncFVjZ0stYXNmd1RvNDFXbU9yZjRocjR1NDNMMU5nQ19ZRVdhZmExX293cXI0NGF6ZHM5M0szMzduZFUycFJpNnJJN1JvVnhIa0ZnN0luVU5XU0dzYnBacDVDNzgwSjRkUGJMc3dMdmdmOFd4UmgzSjFDLXRWeTRKUHF1aDlMRnMycGJyN0taME5hUmF1VXNDYU43MG5xeUZWNGFJb3M?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk wants to create in Texas what no other company and business leader has ever done - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk wants to create in Texas what no other company and business leader has ever done</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Available <strong>Source:</strong> Not Available</p><p>An overview of Elon Musk's unique plans for innovation and development in Texas, aiming to set a precedent unmatched by previous initiatives.</p><ul><li>Introduction of groundbreaking technology aimed at transforming various sectors.</li><li>Musk's vision includes collaboration with local governments and communities.</li><li>Potential impacts on job creation and economic growth in the area.</li></ul><blockquote>“This will be a historic move for the industry,” said Musk.</blockquote><p>This ambitious project has the potential to reshape the landscape of Texas and set new standards in business innovation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-wants-to-create-in-texas-what-no-other-company-and-business-leader-has-ever-done/articleshow/116638548.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-wants-to-create-in-texas-what-no-other-company-and-business-leader-has-ever-done/articleshow/116638548.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Failure at No.6, failure as an opener: Rohit Sharma dismissed for 3 runs after removing KL Rahul from the opening slot - Crictoday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxQWHBNby1xTFd4M3BtTDB6MFRaT3VVU2RsR1d3MjJzRURsb1ZmMXlMNkZJY21DdVU4YUtkYkRrZHcyNXJaVWJpLU1rMGhscmswdV9vNFZXblozY2FRYzJJeHNBT3lkc1dvb1NaYTlPYmlDb0pNQTlVSTB2aTU4WjEzeTA1UGVrTWUwM2E1TGE2a2YtcDFwOFhKVUNuSDhjYkJQQ2RkWUw1WUt3alNNT3dtS2o2d2lKZjl1WE04RzdnYUdKQm9NdmhHd3ZHNnFyNGRsRll1SEdSTi1STDE0bDBCZEs3cjh3SW9JaDBHZkZYTWZOQzNxd2hjSFdR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-gFBVV95cUxQWHBNby1xTFd4M3BtTDB6MFRaT3VVU2RsR1d3MjJzRURsb1ZmMXlMNkZJY21DdVU4YUtkYkRrZHcyNXJaVWJpLU1rMGhscmswdV9vNFZXblozY2FRYzJJeHNBT3lkc1dvb1NaYTlPYmlDb0pNQTlVSTB2aTU4WjEzeTA1UGVrTWUwM2E1TGE2a2YtcDFwOFhKVUNuSDhjYkJQQ2RkWUw1WUt3alNNT3dtS2o2d2lKZjl1WE04RzdnYUdKQm9NdmhHd3ZHNnFyNGRsRll1SEdSTi1STDE0bDBCZEs3cjh3SW9JaDBHZkZYTWZOQzNxd2hjSFdR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:33:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Passenger who miraculously survived Azerbaijan Airlines plane crash in Kazakhstan shares fresh video of aircraft - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Azerbaijan Airlines plane crash: Subkhon Rakhimov miraculously survived the plane crash and shared videos with his wife documenting the damage to the craft.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/27/550x309/TOPSHOT-KAZAKHSTAN-PLANE-CRASH-0_1735270537517_1735270550731.jpg" alt="Emergency specialists work at the crash site of an Azerbaijan Airlines passenger jet near the western Kazakh city of Aktau on December 25, 2024. (AFP)" title="Emergency specialists work at the crash site of an Azerbaijan Airlines passenger jet near the western Kazakh city of Aktau on December 25, 2024. (AFP)"><figcaption>Emergency specialists work at the crash site of an Azerbaijan Airlines passenger jet near the western Kazakh city of Aktau on December 25, 2024. (AFP)</figcaption><p>Subkhon Rakhimov, one of the passengers who survived the tragic Azerbaijan Airlines plane crash near Kazakhstan's Aktau on December 25, documented the suspected shrapnel damage to the aircraft in a fresh video.</p><ul><li>The crash occurred while the plane was attempting to land in Aktau.</li><li>A total of 38 people died, and all 29 survivors were injured.</li><li>Azerbaijani President stated the crash was due to dense fog, but no confirmed cause has been determined yet.</li><li>Russian authorities suggest a bird strike may have contributed to the crash.</li></ul><blockquote>“It would be wrong to make hypotheses before investigators make their verdict.” - Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov</blockquote><p>The incident has raised numerous questions regarding aviation safety and the circumstances of the crash.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/azerbaijan-airlines-plane-crash-in-kazakhstan-passenger-shares-damaged-flight-video-101735266063751.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/azerbaijan-airlines-plane-crash-in-kazakhstan-passenger-shares-damaged-flight-video-101735266063751.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:33:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Putin predicts victory in Ukraine conflict: 'God is with us' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Putin predicts victory in Ukraine conflict: 'God is with us'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In a recent statement, President Vladimir Putin expressed confidence in Russia’s eventual victory in the ongoing conflict in Ukraine, asserting that divine support is on their side.</p><ul><li>Putin claims historical narratives favor Russian strength.</li><li>He emphasizes resilience among the Russian people.</li><li>The statement comes amidst ongoing military operations in Ukraine.</li></ul><blockquote>“God is with us,” Putin stated, reinforcing his belief in the righteousness of Russia's cause.</blockquote><p>This proclamation illustrates Putin's strategy of intertwining faith and nationalism in his political rhetoric regarding the Ukraine conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/putin-predicts-victory-in-ukraine-conflict-god-is-with-us/articleshow/116698969.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/putin-predicts-victory-in-ukraine-conflict-god-is-with-us/articleshow/116698969.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WHO chief narrowly escapes from Israel’s strikes in Yemen - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>WHO Chief Escapes Israeli Airstrikes in Yemen</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/23jb59/article69030726.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/2024-12-23T183549Z_368950279_RC2YUBAXWH3D_RTRMADP_3_ISRAEL-PALESTINIANS-LEBANON.JPG" alt="" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Israeli airstrikes have targeted Yemen, affecting WHO operations.</figcaption><p>The WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus narrowly escaped injury during recent Israeli airstrikes in Yemen. The strikes targeted the Houthi-held capital and damaged vital airport infrastructure, causing at least three fatalities and many injuries.</p><ul><li>The airstrikes occurred as Tedros was about to board a flight in Sanaa.</li><li>He reported nearby damage to the airport, including the air traffic control tower.</li><li>At least three people were killed, and dozens were injured.</li><li>The WHO's mission includes negotiating the release of UN staff and assessing the humanitarian situation in Yemen.</li><li>The ongoing violence follows retaliatory attacks between Israel and Houthi forces.</li><li>The UN Security Council is scheduled to meet in response to the escalation in hostilities.</li></ul><blockquote>“The air traffic control tower, the departure lounge — just a few meters from where we were — and the runway were damaged.” — Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus</blockquote><p>The situation remains tense as emergency assessments of the airport damage are underway, with potential implications for humanitarian aid in Yemen.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/who-chief-narrowly-escapes-from-israels-strikes-in-yemen/article69032127.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/who-chief-narrowly-escapes-from-israels-strikes-in-yemen/article69032127.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IND vs AUS: Steve Smith's majestic innings ends in bizarre fashion at the MCG - Watch - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Steve Smith's Unusual Dismissal After Stellar Innings at MCG</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> NEW DELHI <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116698505,imgsize-126698,width-400,resizemode-4/116698505.jpg" alt="Steve Smith's majestic innings ends in bizarre fashion at the MCG - Watch" title="India's Akash Deep, left, celebrates the wicket of Australia's Steve Smith. (AP/PTI Photo)" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high"><figcaption>India's Akash Deep, left, celebrates the wicket of Australia's Steve Smith. (AP/PTI Photo)</figcaption><p>Steve Smith had a remarkable but unexpected end to his innings at the MCG during the fourth Test of the Border-Gavaskar Trophy. He scored 140 runs, becoming the most successful century-maker against India in Test cricket with his 11th century against them.</p><ul><li>Smith scored 140 off 197 balls, his 34th Test century.</li><li>He is now the second-highest century-maker for Australia, trailing Ricky Ponting.</li><li>His unusual dismissal involved dragging an inside edge onto his back leg, dislodging a bail.</li><li>Smith's dismissal came amid a standing ovation from the MCG crowd.</li><li>He has scored nearly 10,000 runs in Tests, affirming his legacy in cricket.</li></ul><blockquote>“It took an extraordinary moment to bring his innings to an end.”</blockquote><p>Despite the bizarre nature of his dismissal, Smith's innings showcases his batting prowess and his significant contribution to the match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-steve-smiths-majestic-innings-ends-in-bizarre-fashion-at-the-mcg-watch/articleshow/116698437.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/ind-vs-aus-steve-smiths-majestic-innings-ends-in-bizarre-fashion-at-the-mcg-watch/articleshow/116698437.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 03:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stealthy & Long-Ranged — Russia’s New ‘Klub-10E’ Kamikaze Drone Could Prove “Nasty” For Ukrainian Forces - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Stealthy & Long-Ranged -- Russia's New 'Klub-10E' Kamikaze Drone Could Prove "Nasty" For Ukrainian Forces</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> EurAsian Times</p><figure><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/GfukSypaQAA8S6Y?format=jpg&amp;name=large" alt="Image" width="1366" height="768"><figcaption>File Image: Klub-10E</figcaption></figure><p>Kalashnikov has unveiled a new long-range kamikaze drone named Klub-10E, which is likely to significantly impact the course of the Russian military operation in Ukraine, increasing threats to Ukrainian forces and infrastructure.</p><ul><li>The Klub-10E is designed to destroy enemy military equipment, command posts, and electronic warfare facilities.</li><li>The drone is larger and has a strike range and payload capability exceeding that of its predecessor, the Kub-BLA.</li><li>The drone underwent battle testing and can strike targets deep behind enemy lines, indicating its potential range could be several hundred kilometers.</li><li>Developed to correct limitations of the Geran-2, the Klub-10E features enhanced design allowing for faster upgrades.</li></ul><blockquote>“The flight range and combat power of the new guided munition significantly exceed the indicators of previous models of the line.” - Alan Lushnikov, CEO of Kalashnikov</blockquote><p>The introduction of the Klub-10E indicates Russia's efforts to advance its drone capabilities significantly, which may affect future military operations in Ukraine.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/stealthy-long-ranged-russias-new-klub-10e/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/stealthy-long-ranged-russias-new-klub-10e/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 02:35:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>