<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 09:18:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 09:18:26 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['We need smart people in our country': Trump says he hasn't changed his mind on H1B visas - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'We need smart people in our country': Trump says he hasn't changed his mind on H1B visas</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The article discusses former President Donald Trump’s stance on H1B visas, reiterating his belief in the necessity of skilled immigrants for the U.S. economy.</p><ul><li>Trump emphasizes the importance of attracting talented individuals.</li><li>He expresses no change in his previous opposition to the current immigration policies regarding H1B visas.</li><li>Concerns are raised about the impact of immigration regulations on U.S. tech industries.</li></ul><blockquote>“We need smart people in our country.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Trump’s comments highlight ongoing debates around immigration and its role in the U.S. workforce.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/we-need-smart-people-in-our-country-trump-says-he-hasnt-changed-his-mind-on-h1b-visas/articleshow/116847250.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/we-need-smart-people-in-our-country-trump-says-he-hasnt-changed-his-mind-on-h1b-visas/articleshow/116847250.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 06:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Lack of humanity’: Why Azerbaijan is angry with Russia over plane crash - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/1/lack-of-humanity-why-azerbaijan-is-angry-with-russia-over-plane-crash</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/1/lack-of-humanity-why-azerbaijan-is-angry-with-russia-over-plane-crash</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 05:48:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: China rings in New Year with incredible drone show - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watch: China rings in New Year with incredible drone show</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 01 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> IST</p><p>China celebrated New Year's Eve with an impressive drone show featuring over 10,000 drones lighting up the sky. President Xi Jinping addressed the nation, acknowledging economic challenges while urging confidence in a brighter future.</p><ul><li>The drone show included stunning visuals, with a dragon gliding through the air.</li><li>Xi Jinping recognized the difficulties facing the economy and pledged governmental efforts for growth.</li><li>In his speech, Xi reaffirmed Taiwan's status as part of China.</li><li>Other global cities, such as Auckland and Sydney, also celebrated with fireworks and light displays.</li></ul><blockquote>“The current economic operation is facing some new situations, there are challenges from the uncertainty of the external environment...” - Xi Jinping</blockquote><p>China's display sets a vibrant tone for the New Year, showcasing technological innovation and a spirit of resilience amidst challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/watch-china-rings-in-new-year-with-incredible-drone-show-3337994</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/watch-china-rings-in-new-year-with-incredible-drone-show-3337994</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:46:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Abu Dhabi welcomes 2025 with fireworks and drone show, setting Guinness world records - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Abu Dhabi dazzled the world with a 50-minute fireworks display and a 6,000-drone show, breaking six Guinness World Records to mark the New Year.</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 01, 2025<strong> | Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/01/550x309/UAE_1735704500901_1735704506960.jpg" alt="Abu Dhabi welcomed 2025 with a record-breaking 50-minute fireworks display and 6,000-drone show.(Instagram/@cuptaleswithsafia)" title="Abu Dhabi welcomed 2025 with a record-breaking 50-minute fireworks display and 6,000-drone show.(Instagram/@cuptaleswithsafia)">
<figcaption>Abu Dhabi welcomed 2025 with a record-breaking 50-minute fireworks display and 6,000-drone show.(Instagram/@cuptaleswithsafia)</figcaption>
<p>Abu Dhabi dazzled the world with an unforgettable New Year’s Eve celebration, hosting the largest fireworks display at the Sheikh Zayed Festival in Al Wathba. The breathtaking spectacle, which lasted 50 minutes, captivated audiences and set six new Guinness World Records.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The 6,000-drone show illuminated the skies for over 20 minutes, forming intricate aerial art.</li>
  <li>Fireworks displays occurred every hour from 6 p.m. leading to a stunning midnight showcase.</li>
  <li>Major locations in Abu Dhabi, including Yas Island and the Corniche, participated in the celebrations.</li>
  <li>In 2023, the festival set three Guinness World Records for its previous fireworks display.</li>
  <li>The Sheikh Zayed Festival features a variety of attractions, including laser shows and cultural performances.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This year's event reflects Abu Dhabi’s commitment to outshining its previous records."</blockquote>
<p>The celebrations demonstrated Abu Dhabi's vibrant culture and its aim to create memorable experiences, marking a remarkable start to the new year.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/abu-dhabi-welcomes-2025-with-fireworks-and-drone-show-setting-guinness-world-records-101735704240257.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/abu-dhabi-welcomes-2025-with-fireworks-and-drone-show-setting-guinness-world-records-101735704240257.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:18:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy New Year 2025 Celebrations LIVE Updates: PM Modi extends New Year’s greetings, says ‘may this year bring new opportunities, success’ - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Happy New Year 2025 Celebrations LIVE Updates</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 - <strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/New-Year-2025-1.jpg?w=640" alt="Fireworks explode over the Sydney Opera House and Harbour Bridge during New Year’s celebrations in Sydney, Australia" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>Fireworks explode over the Sydney Opera House and Harbour Bridge during New Year’s celebrations in Sydney, Australia. (Reuters)</figcaption>
<p>As India welcomed 2025, President Droupadi Murmu greet the citizens, urging a collective commitment towards a brighter, inclusive, and sustainable future. Prime Minister Narendra Modi also expressed hopes for new opportunities in the upcoming year.</p>
<ul>
<li>Global celebrations included fireworks in major cities like Sydney, London, and Rio De Janeiro.</li>
<li>New York's iconic Ball Drop featured performances from various artists such as Kesha and The Jonas Brothers.</li>
<li>In India, police enforced measures to ensure safety during celebrations, including bans on firecrackers and deployment in major cities.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Let us renew our commitment to work together for a brighter, more inclusive and sustainable future.” - President Droupadi Murmu</blockquote>
<p>The New Year celebrations are marked by joy, music, and family gatherings, ushering in a year full of hope and new possibilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/happy-new-year-2025-celebrations-wishes-images-photos-live-updates-naye-saal-shubhkamnaye-greetings-india-world-9752440/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/happy-new-year-2025-celebrations-wishes-images-photos-live-updates-naye-saal-shubhkamnaye-greetings-india-world-9752440/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 04:08:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suchir Balaji’s mother alleges ‘murder’, demands FBI investigation into OpenAI whistleblower’s death - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Suchir Balaji’s Mother Alleges Murder, Seeks FBI Investigation into Whistleblower's Death</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Fox News</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/56usus/article69048962.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/OpenAI_Whistleblower_Death_77670.jpg" alt="Suchir Balaji poses for a photo in Hawaii in 2018. Balaji was a former OpenAI engineer and whistleblower who died in November 2024. (Balaji Ramamurthy via AP)"><figcaption>Suchir Balaji poses for a photo in Hawaii in 2018. Balaji was a former OpenAI engineer and whistleblower who died in November 2024. (Balaji Ramamurthy via AP)</figcaption><p>Suchir Balaji's mother, Poornima Rao, has accused authorities of declaring her son's death a suicide when she believes it to be murder. She is calling for an FBI investigation into the circumstances surrounding his death.</p><ul><li>Suchir Balaji was found dead in his apartment in San Francisco.</li><li>His mother claims there were signs of struggle and that the apartment was ransacked.</li><li>A private autopsy contradicted the police report regarding the cause of death.</li><li>Elon Musk publicly expressed skepticism about the suicide ruling.</li><li>Balaji previously accused OpenAI of copyright violations related to generative AI.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's a cold blooded mu*d*r declared by authorities as suicide. We demand FBI investigation.” - Poornima Rao</blockquote><p>This case has garnered significant attention, highlighting concerns about the treatment of whistleblowers and the implications of AI technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/openai-whistleblower-suchir-balajis-mother-alleges-murder-demands-fbi-investigation-into-his-death/article69048961.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/openai-whistleblower-suchir-balajis-mother-alleges-murder-demands-fbi-investigation-into-his-death/article69048961.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI whistleblower Suchir Balaji’s mother alleges ‘murder’, demands FBI investigation into his death - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Suchir Balaji’s Mother Alleges Murder, Seeks FBI Investigation into Whistleblower's Death</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Fox News</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/56usus/article69048962.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/OpenAI_Whistleblower_Death_77670.jpg" alt="Suchir Balaji poses for a photo in Hawaii in 2018. Balaji was a former OpenAI engineer and whistleblower who died in November 2024. (Balaji Ramamurthy via AP)"><figcaption>Suchir Balaji poses for a photo in Hawaii in 2018. Balaji was a former OpenAI engineer and whistleblower who died in November 2024. (Balaji Ramamurthy via AP)</figcaption><p>Suchir Balaji's mother, Poornima Rao, has accused authorities of declaring her son's death a suicide when she believes it to be murder. She is calling for an FBI investigation into the circumstances surrounding his death.</p><ul><li>Suchir Balaji was found dead in his apartment in San Francisco.</li><li>His mother claims there were signs of struggle and that the apartment was ransacked.</li><li>A private autopsy contradicted the police report regarding the cause of death.</li><li>Elon Musk publicly expressed skepticism about the suicide ruling.</li><li>Balaji previously accused OpenAI of copyright violations related to generative AI.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's a cold blooded mu*d*r declared by authorities as suicide. We demand FBI investigation.” - Poornima Rao</blockquote><p>This case has garnered significant attention, highlighting concerns about the treatment of whistleblowers and the implications of AI technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/openai-whistleblower-suchir-balajis-mother-alleges-murder-demands-fbi-investigation-into-his-death/article69048961.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/sci-tech/technology/openai-whistleblower-suchir-balajis-mother-alleges-murder-demands-fbi-investigation-into-his-death/article69048961.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New gun laws rolling out in multiple US states on Jan 1 - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Gun Laws Rolling Out in Multiple US States on January 1</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Xinhua News Agency</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/shoot11735702652.jpg" alt="New gun laws rolling out in multiple US states"><figcaption>New gun laws rolling out in multiple US states</figcaption><p>US states are implementing various gun regulations starting January 1, amidst ongoing violence and nearly 500 mass shootings in 2024. These laws aim to enhance gun safety and prevention efforts.</p><ul><li>In California, Governor Gavin Newsom signed laws for stricter gun safety regulations, including the establishment of an Office of Gun Violence Prevention.</li><li>In Colorado, handguns in unoccupied vehicles must be stored in locked containers, and concealed carry permit applicants will require eight hours of training starting in 2025.</li><li>New Hampshire expanded gun rights with laws improving privacy protections related to gun ownership.</li><li>Kentucky has joined states banning merchant category codes for gun retailers.</li><li>Minnesota has enacted a binary trigger ban effective January 1.</li><li>Delaware is extending its Safe School Zone regulations to include university campuses.</li></ul><blockquote>California has seen a significant push for stronger gun regulations, amidst a backdrop of rising gun violence across states.</blockquote><p>This wave of new gun laws reflects a growing concern over gun violence in the US, as states take action to enhance safety and regulation in response to public demand.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/articles/special-articles/new-gun-laws-rolling-out-in-multiple-us-states-143121</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/articles/special-articles/new-gun-laws-rolling-out-in-multiple-us-states-143121</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:38:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Inauspicious Start To 2025': Lightning Strikes US Capitol, Netizens Link It To Trump | Video - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lightning Strikes US Capitol and Washington Monument on New Year’s Eve</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 01, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Lightning struck the US Capitol building and Washington Monument simultaneously on New Year’s Eve." title="Lightning struck the US Capitol building and Washington Monument simultaneously on New Year’s Eve."><figcaption>Lightning struck the US Capitol building and Washington Monument simultaneously on New Year’s Eve.</figcaption><p>On New Year’s Eve, lightning struck both the US Capitol building and the Washington Monument, sparking discussions on social media regarding its implications.</p><ul><li>Lightning struck the US Capitol and Washington Monument at the same time.</li><li>Netizens interpreted the event as a sign or omen, often linked to political beliefs.</li><li>One user stated, “A sign that lightning often strikes the tallest objects.”</li></ul><blockquote>“In what may be an inauspicious start for the 2025 Republican trifecta, it looks like the Washington Monument and the US Capitol building were struck by lightning tonight.” — katya (@EhresmanKatya)</blockquote><p>This unusual occurrence has led to intense speculation on its significance as the year begins.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/inauspicious-start-to-2025-lightning-strikes-us-capitol-netizens-link-it-to-trump-video-9174286.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/inauspicious-start-to-2025-lightning-strikes-us-capitol-netizens-link-it-to-trump-video-9174286.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:20:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Sydney to Dubai: World’s spectacular NYE fireworks - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>From Sydney to Dubai: World’s spectacular NYE fireworks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 01 January 2025, 03:03 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p><img src="https://images.deccanherald.com/deccanherald%2F2025-01-01%2F2hsn0gry%2FAustralia__1_.JPG" alt="Fireworks explode over the Sydney Opera House and Harbour Bridge during New Year’s Eve celebrations in Sydney, Australia."> <figcaption>Fireworks explode over the Sydney Opera House and Harbour Bridge during New Year’s Eve celebrations in Sydney, Australia.</figcaption><p>New Year’s Eve celebrations unfolded worldwide, showcasing breathtaking fireworks across several major cities, marking the transition into 2025.</p><ul><li>Fireworks lit up the skies in Sydney, Hong Kong, Dubai, and many other locations.</li><li>Sydney’s iconic Harbour Bridge and Opera House were focal points for the celebrations.</li><li>Dubai featured stunning displays near the Burj Khalifa, the tallest building in the world.</li><li>Other global locations included celebrations in Manila, Singapore, Bangkok, and Berlin.</li><li>This year's celebrations were marked by a return to traditional festivities and large gatherings following previous disruptions.</li></ul><blockquote>“The beauty of fireworks brings people together in celebration, marking new beginnings.”</blockquote><p>This year’s New Year celebrations were vibrant and notable, emphasizing global unity and joy as people welcomed 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/from-sydney-to-dubai-the-worlds-spectacular-nye-fireworks-3337921</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/from-sydney-to-dubai-the-worlds-spectacular-nye-fireworks-3337921</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:03:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two Teens Hospitalized After Stabbings During New Year’s Eve Celebrations In Australia - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Year’s Eve Stabbings in Australia</h1><p><strong>Date & Source: January 1, 2023, Zee News</strong></p><img src='' alt='' /><figcaption>No image available</figcaption><p>Two teenagers were hospitalized following separate stabbing incidents during New Year’s Eve celebrations in Sydney and Melbourne. Authorities confirmed these incidents amidst large-scale festivities across the cities.</p><ol><li>In Sydney, a 17-year-old boy was stabbed in the back in Guildford park while a group was setting off fireworks illegally.</li><li>The victim was transported to a hospital, and the attacker fled the scene. Police made 36 arrests for various offenses during the celebrations.</li><li>In Melbourne, another teenager was stabbed, and details about this case remain limited.</li></ol><blockquote>New South Wales Police called for witnesses to come forward and emphasized responsible behavior during large gatherings.</blockquote><p>Stay informed on all the latest news, real-time breaking news updates, and follow all the important headlines in India news and World News on Zee News.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/world/two-teens-hospitalized-after-stabbings-during-new-year-s-eve-celebrations-in-australia-2838292.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/world/two-teens-hospitalized-after-stabbings-during-new-year-s-eve-celebrations-in-australia-2838292.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 03:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China steps up drive to break Boeing and Airbus grip on plane market - Financial Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's Bid to Challenge Boeing and Airbus in the Aircraft Market</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Financial Times</p>
<p>The article discusses China's initiative to reduce the dominance of Boeing and Airbus in the aircraft market, focusing on the efforts of state-run manufacturer Comac and its C919 aircraft.</p>
<img src='path_to_image.jpg' alt='C919 Aircraft' />
<figcaption>C919 Aircraft</figcaption>
<p>Key Points:</p>
<ul>
  <li>The C919 made its first commercial flight in 2023 and is now flying domestic routes.</li>
  <li>Comac aims to expand C919 operations to Southeast Asia by 2026 and seeks European certification.</li>
  <li>The global aviation market requires 42,430 new aircraft in the next two decades.</li>
  <li>Comac faces challenges with certification and maintenance support for international markets.</li>
  <li>Comac is also developing a widebody aircraft, the C929, expected to enter service after 2040.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Maintenance support is the main issue,” said a person close to Indonesia’s TransNusa.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, while Comac is positioned to grow, significant hurdles remain before it can effectively compete with established giants in the global aircraft market.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ft.com/content/7510f691-d9f6-4f07-86ad-8ba3b91517d3</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ft.com/content/7510f691-d9f6-4f07-86ad-8ba3b91517d3</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 02:38:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kathy Hochul ripped for 'taking victory lap' with new post on same day subway fire victim identified, ‘Disaster for NY’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kathy Hochul Faces Backlash for Victory Lap Amid Subway Fire Victim Identification</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 01, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/01/550x309/NEW-YORK-CONGESTION-HOCHUL-4_1735697799979_1735697809543.JPG" alt="New York's Governor Kathy Hochul answers questions from reporters" title="New York's Governor Kathy Hochul answers questions from reporters"><figcaption>New York's Governor Kathy Hochul answers questions from reporters after she made a transportation announcement on a revised congestion pricing plan at a press conference in New York City, New York, U.S., November 14, 2024. REUTERS/Kent J. Edwards(REUTERS)</figcaption><p>New York Governor Kathy Hochul is criticized for celebrating the state's successes through a video post on the same day Debrina Kawam, the victim of a subway fire, was identified.</p><ul><li>Hochul highlighted achievements including a minimum wage increase and online safety legislation.</li><li>Her post faced severe backlash from public representatives and citizens alike.</li><li>Critics questioned her focus on victories while subway safety remains an issue.</li></ul><blockquote>Rep. Ritchie Torres stated: "Governor Hochul feels the need to take a victory lap. 'Mission accomplished' is the ultimate form of gaslighting."</blockquote><p>This incident has led to heightened criticism of Hochul’s leadership and has sparked debates regarding public safety in New York.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/kathy-hochul-ripped-for-taking-a-victory-lap-with-new-post-on-same-day-subway-fire-victim-was-identified-101735697214688.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/kathy-hochul-ripped-for-taking-a-victory-lap-with-new-post-on-same-day-subway-fire-victim-was-identified-101735697214688.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 02:19:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Armed With ‘Cutting Edge’ Vertical Launch Missile System, North Korea Reveals Largest-Ever Warship - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>North Korea Unveils Largest-Ever Warship with Advanced Missile System</h1><p><strong>Date: December 29, 2024 | Source: Korean Central Television</strong></p><figure><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/GgBBr80bYAA1f9l?format=jpg&amp;name=medium" alt="North Korea Warship" width="1167" height="594"><figcaption>North Korea released four photos of its new warship on Sunday, with one showing Kim Jong Un in a white shirt and the structure still covered in netting. This suggests the image was taken in August or September. | Image: KCTV (Dec. 29, 2024)</figcaption></figure><p>North Korea has showcased the largest warship under construction in its Navy, featuring a cutting-edge vertical launch missile system, indicating a substantial enhancement of its maritime strength.</p><ul><li>The images depict Kim Jong Un inspecting the vessel, which is likely being built at the Nampo Shipyard.</li><li>The warship is approximately 100 meters long and has a beam width of about 15 meters.</li><li>Experts believe the warship will include advanced features, including vertical launch systems and radar technologies.</li><li>Analysts note that this development does not position North Korea's navy to compete with US or South Korean naval capabilities.</li></ul><blockquote>Joseph Dempsey, a researcher, noted that the dockyard includes structures designed to conceal construction.</blockquote><p>This reveal marks another significant advancement within North Korea's ongoing efforts to strengthen its naval forces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/armed-with-cutting-edge-vertical-launch/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/armed-with-cutting-edge-vertical-launch/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 02:13:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan enters UN Security Council at key juncture in global politics - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE5GUmpMVEdBd1M0a1NXSF9jbXZ4aWJEUzUtb0VLcEZDUUVULU80VlBlRGtrS0VZRzNvbi12VlpzY01jeGtuTFc3aQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE5GUmpMVEdBd1M0a1NXSF9jbXZ4aWJEUzUtb0VLcEZDUUVULU80VlBlRGtrS0VZRzNvbi12VlpzY01jeGtuTFc3aQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 01:59:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel eliminates Hamas commander Abd al-Hadi Sabah linked to Kibbutz Nir Oz attack on October 7 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel eliminates Hamas commander Abd al-Hadi Sabah linked to Kibbutz Nir Oz attack on October 7</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 9, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The Times of Israel</p>
<p>The Israeli Defense Forces carried out an operation resulting in the elimination of a prominent Hamas commander, Abd al-Hadi Sabah, who was linked to a recent attack on Kibbutz Nir Oz.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Abd al-Hadi Sabah was reportedly responsible for orchestrating attacks against Israel.</li>
    <li>The strike aimed to weaken Hamas' operational capabilities.</li>
    <li>The operation highlights ongoing tensions in the region and Israel's commitment to counter-terrorism.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This operation sends a clear message to Hamas that we will not tolerate attacks on our citizens,” said an IDF spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>This targeted action marks another chapter in the ongoing conflict and Israel's significant military efforts against organized threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/israel-eliminates-hamas-commander-abd-al-hadi-sabah-linked-to-kibbutz-nir-oz-attack-on-october-7/articleshow/116843596.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/israel-eliminates-hamas-commander-abd-al-hadi-sabah-linked-to-kibbutz-nir-oz-attack-on-october-7/articleshow/116843596.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 01:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy New Year 2025 LIVE: India and cities around the world rings in 2025 with fireworks and grand celebrations | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Happy New Year 2025 LIVE: India and cities around the world rings in 2025 with fireworks and grand celebrations</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> 31 Dec, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> HT Digital Streams Limited</p><figure><img src="https://www.livemint.com/lm-img/img/2025/01/01/600x338/NEW-YEAR-BRITAIN-FIREWORKS-10_1735692280406_1735692295637.JPG" alt="Fireworks over the London Eye" title="New year 2025 LIVE updates: Fireworks explode over the London Eye to mark the New Year's celebrations, in London. (Image: Reuters)"><figcaption>New year 2025 LIVE updates: Fireworks explode over the London Eye to mark the New Year's celebrations, in London. (Image: Reuters)</figcaption></figure><p>As the clock strikes midnight, 2025 ushers in a new year across India and worldwide, celebrated with fireworks and joy. From Sydney to Mumbai, cities are filled with excitement and reflection.</p><ul><li>New Zealand and Australia led the celebrations with vibrant fireworks displays.</li><li>Heavy snowfall in Japan led to the cancellation of around 42 flights.</li><li>Globally, gatherings are taking place despite some regions facing severe weather disruptions.</li><li>The world population reached 8.09 billion on New Year’s Day, according to estimates.</li></ul><blockquote>“More than 71 million people were added to the global population in 2024.” - US Census Bureau</blockquote><p>2025 has arrived with promises of hope and new beginnings as millions reflect on the past year and set intentions for the year to come.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/happy-new-year-2025-live-wishes-images-celebration-in-mumbai-delhi-varanasi-pune-bengaluru-kolkata-traffic-advisory-11735632632598.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/happy-new-year-2025-live-wishes-images-celebration-in-mumbai-delhi-varanasi-pune-bengaluru-kolkata-traffic-advisory-11735632632598.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 01:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian-origin doctor dies in UAE plane crash along with pilot: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian-origin doctor dies in UAE plane crash along with pilot: Report</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 01, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/01/550x309/Screenshot_1-1-2025_6725_imagekhaleejtimescom_1735692312638_1735692312975.jpeg" alt="Dr Sulaymaan was a clinical fellow at County Durham and Darlington NHS Trust, UK."><figcaption>Dr Sulaymaan was a clinical fellow at County Durham and Darlington NHS Trust, UK.</figcaption><p>An Indian-origin doctor, Sulaymaan Al Majid, tragically died in a plane crash off the coast of Ras Al Khaimah along with the pilot on December 26. He was 26 years old and was taking a sightseeing flight with his family present at the aviation club.</p><ul><li>The crash occurred shortly after takeoff near the Cove Rotana Hotel.</li><li>Sulaymaan had rented the light aircraft, and his family was there to watch his flight.</li><li>Both he and the Pakistani pilot did not survive the incident, with investigations by the GCAA ongoing.</li><li>His father described their grief and how they were looking forward to New Year celebrations together.</li><li>Sulaymaan was a clinical fellow at the County Durham and Darlington NHS NHS Trust in the UK.</li></ul><blockquote>“At first, we were told the glider had lost radio contact... Sulaymaan passed away before we could see him.” - Majid Mukarram, Sulaymaan's father</blockquote><p>This devastating loss has left the family in profound grief, impacting their future deeply without Sulaymaan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/indianorigin-doctor-dies-in-uae-plane-crash-along-with-pilot-report-101735691400689.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/indianorigin-doctor-dies-in-uae-plane-crash-along-with-pilot-report-101735691400689.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:57:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Chinese warplane triggers concerns over ‘strategic gap’ in India - South China Morning Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Chinese warplane triggers concerns over ‘strategic gap’ in India</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> South China Morning Post</p><p>China's latest warplane, speculated to be a sixth-generation model, has raised alarms in India about a widening 'strategic gap'.</p><ul><li>The aircraft features advanced stealth and endurance capabilities.</li><li>Reports suggest it could alter the balance of aerial dominance in the Indo-Pacific.</li><li>Concerns focus on potential threats to global military powers, particularly India.</li></ul><blockquote>“The aircraft's capabilities could mean a major shift in aerial dominance,” - The Economic Times</blockquote><p>This development underscores the ongoing arms race and military advancements in the region, calling for a strategic reassessment from India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3292924/new-sixth-generation-chinese-warplane-triggers-concerns-over-strategic-gap-india</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3292924/new-sixth-generation-chinese-warplane-triggers-concerns-over-strategic-gap-india</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 22:00:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Military court upholds plea deal, spares 9/11 suspects the death penalty - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Military court upholds plea deal, spares 9/11 suspects the death penalty</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 29, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Associated Press</p><p>This article discusses a military court's decision to uphold a plea deal that spares the five men accused of plotting the September 11 attacks from facing the death penalty. This ruling significantly impacts the ongoing legal proceedings related to one of the most high-profile cases in American history.</p><ul><li>The plea deal was upheld by a military judge.</li><li>The decision prevents the suspects from receiving the death penalty.</li><li>This case has been subject to lengthy legal battles since the events of 9/11.</li><li>The ruling may influence future cases involving terrorism suspects.</li></ul><blockquote>“This resolution seems to bring some closure to a lengthy legal process.” - Legal Expert</blockquote><p>The court's decision is seen as a significant moment in the ongoing attempts to bring justice for the victims of the September 11 attacks while highlighting the complexities of military and civilian legal proceedings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/military-court-upholds-plea-deal-spares-9/11-suspects-the-death-penalty/articleshow/116840466.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/military-court-upholds-plea-deal-spares-9/11-suspects-the-death-penalty/articleshow/116840466.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russian Su-57 fighters fire Kh-69 missiles, strike near Kyiv - Bulgarian Military]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russian Su-57 Fighters Strike Near Kyiv with Kh-69 Missiles</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 31, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> BulgarianMilitary.com</p><figure><img src="https://bulgarianmilitary.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Is-Algeria-quietly-acquiring-Russias-Su-57-stealth-fighter_-1.jpg" alt="Is Algeria quietly acquiring Russia’s Su-57 stealth fighter?"><figcaption>Photo credit: X</figcaption></figure><p>In the early hours of December 31, Russian Aerospace Forces launched a missile strike in the Chernihiv, Sumy, and Kyiv regions using advanced weaponry, including Kh-69 and Kinzhal missiles.</p><ul><li>Russian sources indicate a coordinated attack targeting key military facilities.</li><li>Missiles were launched from Russian airspace to avoid Ukrainian defenses.</li><li>The Vasylkiv Air Base suffered significant strikes during the assault.</li><li>The use of precision-guided missiles raises concerns about Ukraine's countermeasures.</li></ul><blockquote>“There were 8 TU-22M3s... Kyiv and Vasylkiv were preliminarily hit by a combined attack.” — Euromaidan Press</blockquote><p>The ongoing conflict continues to see advancements in missile technology, highlighting the increasing capabilities of Russian airpower in the operational theater.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bulgarianmilitary.com/2024/12/31/russian-su-57-fighters-fire-kh-69-missiles-strike-near-kyiv/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bulgarianmilitary.com/2024/12/31/russian-su-57-fighters-fire-kh-69-missiles-strike-near-kyiv/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:01:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How NYC Subway horror victim Debrina Kawam was identified: 'Charred beyond recognizability' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/how-nyc-subway-horror-victim-debrina-kawam-was-identified-charred-beyond-recognizability/articleshow/116840406.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/how-nyc-subway-horror-victim-debrina-kawam-was-identified-charred-beyond-recognizability/articleshow/116840406.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 19:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Year celebrations Highlights: India welcomes 2025 with multi-city festivities - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Celebrates New Year 2025 with Festivities Across Major Cities</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/31/550x309/WhatsApp_Image_2024-12-31_at_21.57.36_1735665930240_1735665941133.jpeg" alt="Mumbaikars celebrate new years party at Carter Road in Mumbai, India, on Tuesday, December 31, 2024. (Photo by Satish Bate/ Hindustan Times)"><figcaption>Mumbaikars celebrate new years party at Carter Road in Mumbai, India, on Tuesday, December 31, 2024. (Photo by Satish Bate/ Hindustan Times)</figcaption><p>Communities worldwide have kicked off celebrations for 2025, with India deploying extensive security measures as festive activities take place in major cities.</p><ul><li>Delhi Police has deployed nearly 20,000 personnel and set up traffic restrictions around popular areas like Connaught Place.</li><li>Mumbai's New Year’s Eve festivities will see over 14,000 police personnel ensuring safety across major locations.</li><li>Bengaluru is ramping up security with over 7,500 CCTV cameras and increased police presence.</li><li>Events across India include fireworks, public gatherings, and significant traffic arrangements to manage celebrations.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have prepared a comprehensive arrangement to ensure the safety and security of all residents and visitors during the upcoming New Year's Eve celebrations.” - Deputy Commissioner of Police, New Delhi</blockquote><p>As cities across India celebrate New Year 2025, significant attention is being given to safety, with authorities ensuring that events are conducted securely and peacefully.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/happy-new-year-2025-live-updates-new-years-eve-celebration-wishes-gif-messages-whatsapp-status-greetings-latest-updates-101735637687000.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/happy-new-year-2025-live-updates-new-years-eve-celebration-wishes-gif-messages-whatsapp-status-greetings-latest-updates-101735637687000.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 19:03:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy New Year 2025 Celebrations LIVE Updates: India rings in 2025 with joyful celebrations across the nation - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Happy New Year 2025 Celebrations LIVE Updates</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>January 1, 2025 <strong>Source: </strong>The Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/New-Year-2025-1.jpg?w=640" alt="Fireworks explode over the Sydney Opera House and Harbour Bridge during New Year’s celebrations in Sydney, Australia" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Fireworks explode over the Sydney Opera House and Harbour Bridge during New Year’s celebrations in Sydney, Australia. (Reuters)</figcaption><p>As the hour strikes midnight, India celebrates the arrival of 2025 with unparalleled enthusiasm and fervor. With vibrant celebrations at every corner, this marks the start of a new year full of hopes, dreams, and possibilities.</p><ul><li>Major cities across the globe, from Sydney to London, will illuminate the welcome with firework shows.</li><li>New York is hosting its famous Ball Drop featuring performances from various artists including Kesha, T-Pain, and The Jonas Brothers.</li><li>In India, police are taking measures for safety, including diversions around Connaught Place and bans on firecrackers in Chennai.</li></ul><blockquote>“The atmosphere is one of joy and anticipation.”</blockquote><p>This New Year’s celebration reflects not only the joy of the moment but also a hopeful vision for 2025.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/happy-new-year-2025-celebrations-wishes-images-photos-live-updates-naye-saal-shubhkamnaye-greetings-india-world-9752440/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/happy-new-year-2025-celebrations-wishes-images-photos-live-updates-naye-saal-shubhkamnaye-greetings-india-world-9752440/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 19:00:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's true! Bidens' relationship with Kamala Harris and Emhoff is frosty, claim insiders - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden's Relationship with Kamala Harris and Emhoff Reportedly Frosty, Claim Insiders</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Not Specified</p>
<p>This article discusses claims from insiders that the relationship between President Biden, Vice President Kamala Harris, and Douglas Emhoff is strained.</p>
<ul>
<li>Insiders report a frosty relationship among the trio.</li>
<li>Possible implications for political dynamics within the administration.</li>
<li>The report highlights growing tensions and differing priorities.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There’s a palpable distance that’s become increasingly hard to ignore,” said an unnamed source.</blockquote>
<p>The article reveals internal struggles that may impact Biden's administration as he navigates political challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/its-true-bidens-relationship-with-kamala-harris-and-emhoff-is-frosty-claim-insiders/articleshow/116840068.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/its-true-bidens-relationship-with-kamala-harris-and-emhoff-is-frosty-claim-insiders/articleshow/116840068.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 18:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who was Debrina Kawam? Woman burned to death in NYC subway train identified - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who was Debrina Kawam? Woman burned to death in NYC subway train identified</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 31, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/31/550x309/fire_1735035305886_1735668905255.jpg" alt="NYC Subway tragedy: 61-year-old Debrina Kawam identified as the arson attack victim burned to death on December 22, 2024.(X)" title="NYC Subway tragedy: 61-year-old Debrina Kawam identified as the arson attack victim burned to death on December 22, 2024.(X)" />
<figcaption>NYC Subway tragedy: 61-year-old Debrina Kawam identified as the arson attack victim burned to death on December 22, 2024.(X)</figcaption>
<p>A 61-year-old woman was tragically identified as the victim of a horrific subway attack in New York City. Debrina Kawam was set on fire while reportedly sleeping on the train.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The attack occurred on December 22 when Kawam was on a Brooklyn F train.</li>
  <li>Sebastian Zapeta-Calil, a Guatemalan immigrant, has been arrested and charged with first-degree murder in connection with the attack.</li>
  <li>Despite severe injuries, her identification was aided by her fingerprints.</li>
  <li>Witnesses did not intervene, and video footage shows Zapeta-Calil observing the incident from a distance.</li>
  <li>Kawam was believed to be homeless, carrying many personal belongings at the time.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Indifferent as ever, the presumed killer is seen watching the victim succumb to her fate from a bench on the platform.”</blockquote>
<p>This tragedy has sparked outrage and highlighted issues regarding homelessness and safety in public transit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/who-is-debrina-kawam-woman-burnt-to-death-in-nyc-subway-train-identified-101735666772437.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/who-is-debrina-kawam-woman-burnt-to-death-in-nyc-subway-train-identified-101735666772437.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 18:20:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heartbreaking Last Photo Of Boy, 3, Youngest Victim Killed In South Korea Plane Crash - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Heartbreaking Last Photo Of Boy, 3, Youngest Victim Killed In South Korea Plane Crash</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 31, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="South Korea plane crash: In the photo the boy can be seen gazing out of the window before the deadly South Korean plane crash which claimed 179 lives." /><figcaption>South Korea plane crash: In the photo the boy can be seen gazing out of the window before the deadly South Korean plane crash which claimed 179 lives.</figcaption><p>A devastating final photo emerged of the three-year-old boy who was killed in the South Korean plane crash alongside his parents. Kang Ko, his wife Jin Lee Seon, and their son were tragically lost in the Jeju Air Boeing 737-800 crash while attempting an emergency landing at Muan International Airport.</p><ul><li>The plane crash claimed 179 lives on December 31, 2024.</li><li>The boy was on his first trip abroad for Christmas.</li><li>Kang Ko worked in public relations for the Kia Tigers baseball team.</li><li>Two flight attendants were the only survivors among the 181 people onboard.</li><li>Authorities are investigating the crash.</li></ul><blockquote>“He was so good at his job that everyone on our company’s baseball broadcasting team liked him.” - Jung Woo-young</blockquote><p>This tragic event highlights the fragility of life and the deep impact such incidents have on families and communities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/heartbreaking-last-photo-of-boy-3-youngest-victim-killed-in-south-korea-plane-crash-9173716.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/heartbreaking-last-photo-of-boy-3-youngest-victim-killed-in-south-korea-plane-crash-9173716.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 18:01:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chengdu J-36 creator calls it the best 6th-generation jet yet - Bulgarian Military]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Chengdu J-36 Creator Declares It the Best 6th-Generation Jet Yet</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 31, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> BulgarianMilitary.com</p><figure><img src="https://bulgarianmilitary.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Chengdu-J-36-creator-calls-it-the-best-6th-generation-jet-yet.jpg" alt="Chengdu J-36 creator calls it the best 6th-generation jet yet"><figcaption>Photo credit: X</figcaption></figure><p>The revelation that Wang Haifeng is the chief designer behind China's J-36 has sparked significant interest in the future of advanced fighter jets. His insights into 6th-generation platforms highlight a revolutionary approach to air combat.</p><ul><li>The J-36 features a design philosophy focusing on a balance between penetration capabilities and high maneuverability.</li><li>Variable Cycle Engines will enhance agility and combat radius.</li><li>All-aspect stealth design aims to make the fighter undetectable across radar spectrums.</li><li>Integrated electronic warfare capabilities provide tactical advantages against advanced defense systems.</li><li>Innovative aerodynamics improve flight control and energy management.</li></ul><blockquote>“We got confirmation today Wang Haifeng (not Yang Wei) is the Chief Designer of J-36 🥳” — Húrin (@Hurin92), December 31, 2024.</blockquote><p>If these advancements materialize, the J-36 is set to redefine the landscape of aerial combat, challenging both Western and Russian dominance in the skies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bulgarianmilitary.com/2024/12/31/chengdu-j-36-creator-calls-it-the-best-6th-generation-jet-yet/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bulgarianmilitary.com/2024/12/31/chengdu-j-36-creator-calls-it-the-best-6th-generation-jet-yet/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 17:54:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who Was Debrina Kawam? Woman Set On Fire In NYC Subway Identified - Times Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Debrina Kawam Identified as Victim in NYC Subway Arson Case</h1><p><strong>Published on January 5, 2023 | Source: Times Now News</strong></p><img src="https://static.tnn.in/thumb/msid-116838954,thumbsize-1897575,width-1280,height-720,resizemode-75/116838954.jpg" alt="NYC Subway Fire Accused" title="NYC Subway Fire Accused"><figcaption>Debrina Kawam was set on fire inside a New York City subway train. Photo: Twitter</figcaption><p>The woman who was set on fire inside a New York City subway train on December 22 has been identified as Debrina Kawam, a 61-year-old resident of Toms River, New Jersey. The victim, who had also spent time in the city's shelter system, was sleeping on a stationary F train at the Coney Island-Stillwell Avenue subway station when the incident occurred.</p><ol><li>The suspect, Sebastian Zapeta Calil, a 33-year-old Guatemalan citizen who entered the U.S. illegally, has been arrested and charged with multiple counts of murder and arson.</li><li>Kawam was pronounced dead at the scene due to thermal injuries and smoke inhalation.</li><li>Zapeta was reportedly addicted to smoking the synthetic drug K2 and drank heavily on a daily basis.</li></ol><blockquote>The act was malicious and intentional, according to Brooklyn District Attorney Eric Gonzalez.</blockquote><p>This tragic event has shocked New Yorkers and highlighted the need for increased safety measures in subway systems.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesnownews.com/world/us/us-news/who-was-debrina-kawam-woman-set-on-fire-in-nyc-subway-identified-article-116838945</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesnownews.com/world/us/us-news/who-was-debrina-kawam-woman-set-on-fire-in-nyc-subway-identified-article-116838945</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 17:34:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A deadly December for aviation: At least 7 plane crashes, hundreds dead - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A Deadly December for Aviation: At Least 7 Plane Crashes, Hundreds Dead</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Major News Outlet</p><p>A string of devastating aviation disasters in December 2024 has left hundreds dead and shaken public confidence in air travel safety. The incidents include mechanical failures, challenging weather conditions, and external interference, igniting intense scrutiny of aviation safety protocols.</p><img src='url_to_image.jpg' alt='A tragic crash scene' /><figcaption>A tragic accident highlights the safety concerns in aviation.</figcaption><h2>Key Points</h2><ul><li>Over 170 people died in the Jeju Air crash in South Korea on December 28.</li><li>Azerbaijan Airlines experienced a crash on December 25, resulting in 38 fatalities.</li><li>Private plane crashes in Brazil killed 10 members of a family.</li><li>Multiple other crashes occurred in Papua New Guinea, Hawaii, Brazil, Argentina, and Scotland.</li><li>Numerous non-fatal incidents underline the urgent need for improved aviation safety protocols.</li></ul><h2>Notable Quotes or Statistics</h2><blockquote>“The month of December 2024 marks one of the deadliest periods in aviation history.”</blockquote><p>The events echo those of July 2014, one of the most catastrophic months for commercial aviation.</p><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>The aviation industry is facing increasing pressure to enhance safety measures to prevent further tragedies and restore public confidence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/aviation-disasters-december-2024-safety-concerns-124123000531_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/world-news/aviation-disasters-december-2024-safety-concerns-124123000531_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 17:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>