<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:19:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:19:55 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[European markets slide; Novo Nordisk down 20% after obesity drug results - CNBC]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>European Markets Decline; Novo Nordisk Shares Drop After Drug Trial Results</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC</p>
<p>The European markets saw significant declines as investors reacted to political instability in the U.S. and monetary policy shifts across Europe. Novo Nordisk's stock suffered a major drop following disappointing results from a key drug trial.</p>
<ul>
  <li>European markets were overall down, with the pan-European Stoxx 600 index falling by 1.7%.</li>
  <li>Political turmoil in the U.S. contributed to market apprehension, with a partial government shutdown imminent due to legislative failures.</li>
  <li>Novo Nordisk experienced its largest drop, losing over 20% of its value after news from a trial of its CagriSema obesity drug.</li>
  <li>China kept its interest rates steady, reflecting careful economic management amid monetary policy updates from major western economies.</li>
  <li>Bitcoin prices fell by approximately 8%, marking volatility in the cryptocurrency market.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The U.S. president-elect has issued a fresh trade threat to the EU regarding oil and gas purchases.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the combination of global political events and underwhelming corporate performances have resulted in heightened volatility in the European markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/20/european-markets-live-updates-us-government-shutdown-data-and-stocks.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/20/european-markets-live-updates-us-government-shutdown-data-and-stocks.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['If government shuts down...': What Elon Musk said amid spending bill row - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/if-government-shuts-down-what-elon-musk-said-amid-spending-bill-row/articleshow/116505038.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/if-government-shuts-down-what-elon-musk-said-amid-spending-bill-row/articleshow/116505038.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Democrats Are Calling Elon Musk "President Musk" - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Explained: Why Democrats Are Calling Elon Musk 'President Musk'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Elon Musk's growing influence in US politics, particularly within the Republican Party, has led to sarcastic references to him as 'President Musk' by frustrated Democrats.</p><ul><li>Musk's political prominence started when he was appointed to lead the Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) by President Trump.</li><li>His opposition to a bipartisan budget deal and public intervention has fueled speculation about his power.</li><li>Democrats express concern over Musk's influence undermining traditional political structures.</li><li>Potential political aspirations for Musk have been discussed among some Republican lawmakers.</li><li>Concerns about the relationship between billionaires and the government have been raised, with warnings from figures like Senator Bernie Sanders.</li></ul><blockquote>“At least we know who's in charge. He's president, and Trump is now vice president.” - Representative Jim McGovern</blockquote><p>The debate around Musk's role in politics raises questions about the future of American governance and the influence of wealthy individuals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-democrats-have-started-referring-to-tesla-ceo-as-president-musk-7293683</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-democrats-have-started-referring-to-tesla-ceo-as-president-musk-7293683</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:44:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump wants EU to buy more US oil and gas or face tariffs - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-says-eu-should-make-up-tremendous-deficit-with-us-by-purchasing-its-oil-2024-12-20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-says-eu-should-make-up-tremendous-deficit-with-us-by-purchasing-its-oil-2024-12-20/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:22:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russian missiles strike Kyiv on the eve of holiday season (Photos) - Kyiv Independent]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://kyivindependent.com/russian-missiles-strike-kyiv-on-the-eve-of-holiday-season/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kyivindependent.com/russian-missiles-strike-kyiv-on-the-eve-of-holiday-season/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:10:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Croatia: 7-year-old killed, 5 injured in knife attack in Zagreb school, attacker detained - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/croatia-7-year-old-killed-5-wounded-in-knife-attack-in-zagreb-school-101734692388931.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/croatia-7-year-old-killed-5-wounded-in-knife-attack-in-zagreb-school-101734692388931.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:04:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Malaysia to resume hunt for Flight MH370, 10 years after it vanished - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/malaysia-says-it-will-resume-search-wreckage-missing-flight-mh370-2024-12-20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/malaysia-says-it-will-resume-search-wreckage-missing-flight-mh370-2024-12-20/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:50:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fresh twist in Gautam Adani bribery case as US attorney who indicted billionaire businessman to... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fresh twist in Gautam Adani bribery case as US attorney resigns</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-2024-11-21T190039.385.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Fresh twist in Gautam Adani bribery case" /><figcaption></figcaption><p>Breon Peace, the US attorney who indicted Indian billionaire Gautam Adani, has announced his resignation effective January 10, 2024. He leaves behind a legacy of high-profile prosecutions.</p><ul><li>Breon Peace is stepping down as Brooklyn US attorney.</li><li>He oversaw the indictment of Gautam Adani in a bribery case.</li><li>Peace has handled significant cases including R Kelly's sex trafficking conviction.</li><li>Gautam Adani and his company deny the allegations against them.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was an honour for me to serve the United States as Attorney,” - Breon Peace</blockquote><p>Peace’s departure comes amidst ongoing investigations into the Adani Group, as he leaves a mixed legacy of impactful legal victories.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/business/fresh-twist-in-gautam-adani-bribery-case-as-us-attorney-who-indicted-billionaire-businessman-to-breon-peace-us-attorney-general-resign-7481056/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/business/fresh-twist-in-gautam-adani-bribery-case-as-us-attorney-who-indicted-billionaire-businessman-to-breon-peace-us-attorney-general-resign-7481056/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:32:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top US officials in Damascus to meet new Syrian rulers, State Department says - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/top-us-officials-damascus-meet-new-syrian-rulers-state-department-says-2024-12-20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/top-us-officials-damascus-meet-new-syrian-rulers-state-department-says-2024-12-20/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:14:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US raises alarm: Soon, Pakistan missiles could reach American soil - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Raises Alarm: Pakistan's Missiles Could Soon Reach American Soil</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="US-Pakistan Missile Threat"><figcaption>Pakistan's missile capabilities raise concerns in the US</figcaption><p>The article discusses escalating concerns within the United States regarding Pakistan's missile development program, suggesting that the advancements could eventually enable missiles to reach American territory.</p><ul><li>The US government has raised alarms over Pakistan’s evolving missile technology.</li><li>Military analysts express fears that new developments could alter the balance of power in South Asia.</li><li>Policy makers are debating potential responses and strategies to mitigate risks.</li><li>Experts highlight the importance of diplomatic engagement with Pakistan to address concerns.</li></ul><blockquote>“The evolution of Pakistan’s missile capabilities poses a significant challenge to US security interests and regional stability.” - Defense Analyst</blockquote><p>This development illustrates the complex security dynamics at play and underscores the need for proactive measures to ensure safety and mitigate threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/pakistan-nuclear-missiles-and-us-jon-finer-india-and-pakistan-us-sanctions-on-pakistan/articleshow/116498678.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/pakistan-nuclear-missiles-and-us-jon-finer-india-and-pakistan-us-sanctions-on-pakistan/articleshow/116498678.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione’s perp walk decoded: Experts unpack alleged CEO killer’s body language - 'Cold as ice and - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Luigi Mangione’s perp walk decoded: Experts unpack alleged CEO killer’s body language - 'Cold as ice and smirking'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 20, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='Luigi Mangione Perp Walk'><figcaption>Luigi Mangione during his perp walk.</figcaption><p>This article analyzes the body language of Luigi Mangione, the man accused of murdering a CEO, as he was led away by law enforcement. Experts explore the implications of his demeanor during the arrest and what it may indicate about his state of mind.</p><ul><li>Body language analysis reveals Mangione appeared 'cold as ice' and showed signs of smirking.</li><li>Experts suggest that his demeanor could reflect a lack of remorse or acknowledgment of the gravity of the situation.</li><li>The article discusses the psychological aspects of body language in high-stress situations like a perp walk.</li><li>It highlights public reaction and media coverage of Mangione’s arrest.</li></ul><blockquote>“His expression was unsettling. There was a disconnect between his actions and the severity of the charges.”</blockquote><p>The analysis suggests that body language can provide insights beyond words in understanding an individual's emotional and psychological state during critical moments.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/luigi-mangiones-perp-walk-decoded-experts-unpack-alleged-ceo-killers-body-language-cold-as-ice-and-smirking/articleshow/116497944.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/luigi-mangiones-perp-walk-decoded-experts-unpack-alleged-ceo-killers-body-language-cold-as-ice-and-smirking/articleshow/116497944.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Malaysia agrees to resume search for wreckage of missing Flight MH370 - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/malaysia-says-it-will-resume-search-wreckage-missing-flight-mh370-2024-12-20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/malaysia-says-it-will-resume-search-wreckage-missing-flight-mh370-2024-12-20/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:37:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian-origin illegal immigrant jailed for nearly 5 years as lie unravels in UK Wickes worker assault case - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian-origin illegal immigrant jailed for nearly 5 years in UK assault case</h1> <p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p> <img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/illegal_immigrant_uk_crime_1734682910434_1734682918358.jpg" alt="Karandeep Singh and Satwant Singh ended up attacking an employee at the Wickes store in Farnham Road, Slough, during a robbery attempt.(Daily Mail)" title="Karandeep Singh and Satwant Singh ended up attacking an employee at the Wickes store in Farnham Road, Slough, during a robbery attempt.(Daily Mail)" /> <figcaption>Karandeep Singh and Satwant Singh ended up attacking an employee at the Wickes store in Farnham Road, Slough, during a robbery attempt.(Daily Mail)</figcaption> <p>Karandeep Singh, an Indian national without legal status in the UK, was sentenced to nearly five years in prison for assaulting a hardware store employee during a robbery attempt.</p> <ul><li>Singh was involved in a violent attack on a Wickes employee in Slough, Berkshire, in May 2023.</li> <li>Initially claiming to be 18 years old, he faced court after failing to attend his trial.</li> <li>The assault resulted in a 9cm head wound for the victim, who subsequently feared returning to work.</li> <li>Singh lied about his age, revealing conflicting information about his identity and background during the court proceedings.</li> <li>He was convicted on robbery and grievous bodily harm charges, receiving a sentence of four years, eight months, and 14 days.</li></ul> <blockquote>“He does have three alias birthdays on the Police National Computer and he looks to me a little bit older than 19” - Judge Sarah Jane Campbell.</blockquote> <p>Singh’s case reflects broader issues of immigration status and crime, raising questions about legal accountability and the treatment of immigrants in the UK.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/indianorigin-illegal-immigrant-jailed-for-almost-5-years-as-lie-unravels-in-uk-wickes-worker-assault-case-101734678780981.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/indianorigin-illegal-immigrant-jailed-for-almost-5-years-as-lie-unravels-in-uk-wickes-worker-assault-case-101734678780981.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:25:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024: The year the rules-based global order creaked and cracked - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2024: The year the rules-based global order creaked and cracked</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/World-Yearender.jpg?w=640" alt="World Yearender" width="640" height="360">
<figcaption>From Donald Trump's victory to the COP29 summit, a list of six key factors that contributed to the apparent decline of the global order in 2024.</figcaption>
<p>2024 was a pivotal year that posed severe challenges to the ‘rules-based international order’, raising critical questions about the sustainability of a liberal, democratic world founded on free trade and international cooperation.</p>
<ul>
<li>The concept of a rules-based global order has been destabilized, especially following major global events.</li>
<li>War in the Middle East and Ukraine has shown the limitations of international agreements and support.</li>
<li>Global South's discontent with the leadership of the developed nations has grown significantly.</li>
<li>Streaming of live warfare has changed the public perception of conflicts.</li>
<li>Increased questioning of multilateral institutions amid deepening challenges.</li>
<li>The unified support for Ukraine among Western nations is beginning to erode.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This year was not the first in which the liberal world order was challenged, but the challenges were deeper and more visible in 2024.” - Ashok Sajjanhar</blockquote>
<p>The events of 2024 markedly indicate a year of transformation and critical reassessment of the global order, pushing towards new geopolitical realities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/2024-the-year-the-rules-based-global-order-creaked-and-cracked-9735897/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/2024-the-year-the-rules-based-global-order-creaked-and-cracked-9735897/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:02:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Even THAAD Will Fail! Putin Challenges U.S. For “High-Tech Duel”; Dares Them To Intercept Oreshnik Hypersonic Missile - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/even-thaad-will-fail-putin-challenges-u-s/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/even-thaad-will-fail-putin-challenges-u-s/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:10:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A ‘miracle’: Pakistani survivor of a deadly Mediterranean sea crossing - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2024/12/20/a-miracle-pakistani-survivor-of-a-deadly-mediterranean-sea-crossing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2024/12/20/a-miracle-pakistani-survivor-of-a-deadly-mediterranean-sea-crossing</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 07:03:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US campuses urge international students to return before President-elect Donald Trump inauguration - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Colleges Urge International Students to Return Before Trump's Inauguration</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/agwiqo/article68319480.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/Trump_Hush_Money_Gag_Order_71269.jpg" alt="" width="100%" height="100%"><figcaption>Image related to the article</figcaption><p>As President-elect Donald Trump prepares for his inauguration, an increasing number of U.S. colleges and universities are advising international students to return to campus to avoid potential travel bans similar to those implemented during Trump’s first administration.</p><ul><li>Over a dozen schools have issued advisories emphasizing the urgency for international students to return before January 20, 2025.</li><li>Concerns stem from Trump’s previous travel bans targeting predominantly Muslim countries, which affected students and faculty.</li><li>In total, more than 40,000 individuals were denied visas as a result of these bans.</li><li>Reports indicate that over 1.1 million international students are enrolled in U.S. institutions, with significant numbers from China and India.</li><li>Students fear that renewed restrictions will impact academic communication and research.</li></ul><blockquote>“If the U.S. is really a champion of academic freedom, what you should do is not restrict this kind of communications between different countries of the world.” - Jacky Li, University of California, Berkeley</blockquote><p>Colleges, including Ivy League institutions and those like Johns Hopkins University, have advised students to prepare for potential immigration delays and return before semester starts on January 21.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/us-campuses-urge-international-students-to-return-before-president-elect-donald-trump-inauguration/article69007824.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/us-campuses-urge-international-students-to-return-before-president-elect-donald-trump-inauguration/article69007824.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[White House in crisis? Biden and Harris 'cancel Christmas trips and rush back' amid speculations of emerg - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>White House Faces Crisis: Biden and Harris Cancel Christmas Trips Amid Emergency Speculations</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Biden and Harris" />
<figcaption>Biden and Harris during a prior event.</figcaption>
<p>The White House has entered a state of crisis as President Biden and Vice President Harris have reportedly canceled their upcoming Christmas trips, raising concerns about an unspecified emergency situation that necessitates their return.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Biden and Harris cancel Christmas trips to focus on pressing matters.</li>
  <li>Speculations arise about the nature of the emergency prompting the cancellation.</li>
  <li>Political analysts predict potential implications for upcoming elections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This situation is unusual for the holiday season, as both leaders have prioritized their return to the White House," a political analyst remarked.</blockquote>
<p>This unexpected development indicates serious underlying issues that may have significant ramifications for both the administration and the public perception of Biden and Harris.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/white-house-in-crisis-biden-and-harris-cancel-christmas-trips-and-rush-back-amid-speculations-of-emergency/articleshow/116492629.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/white-house-in-crisis-biden-and-harris-cancel-christmas-trips-and-rush-back-amid-speculations-of-emergency/articleshow/116492629.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Attorney Breon Peace, behind Adani charges, to resign before President-elect Donald Trump assumes charge | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-attorney-breon-peace-behind-adani-charges-to-resign-before-donald-trump-takes-office-11734674869518.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-attorney-breon-peace-behind-adani-charges-to-resign-before-donald-trump-takes-office-11734674869518.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:11:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shark shocks beachgoers as it devours a crocodile in chilling viral video. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Shark Devours Crocodile on Australian Beach in Shocking Video</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/vdsc_xcss_1734674572602_1734674575927.jpg" alt="A shark was spotted devouring a dead crocodile at an Australian beach.(Instagram)" title="A shark was spotted devouring a dead crocodile at an Australian beach.(Instagram)"><figcaption>A shark was spotted devouring a dead crocodile at an Australian beach.(Instagram)</figcaption>
<p>In a chilling and rare encounter, a beachgoer in Nhulunbuy, Northern Territory, Australia, captured a shark feasting on a crocodile. The incident occurred on December 13 at Town Beach, providing a dramatic display of nature's stark realities.</p>
<ul>
<li>A shark was filmed attacking a dead crocodile on an Australian beach.</li>
<li>The incident took place on December 13 in Nhulunbuy, Northern Territory.</li>
<li>The video, recorded by witness Alice Bedwell, shows the shark thrashing for a firm grip on the crocodile.</li>
<li>Sharks and crocodiles rarely confront each other despite sharing coastal habitats.</li>
<li>The encounter highlights the competitive nature of apex predators in their ecosystems.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The dead crocodile likely presented an irresistible feast for the shark, eliminating any need for a struggle."</blockquote>
<p>This extraordinary display of predator dynamics reminds viewers of the raw power of nature and the intricate balance within the animal kingdom.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/shark-shocks-beachgoers-as-it-devours-a-crocodile-in-chilling-viral-video-watch-101734673491811.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/shark-shocks-beachgoers-as-it-devours-a-crocodile-in-chilling-viral-video-watch-101734673491811.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:05:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Race against time: US govt may shut down on Friday; what does it mean? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Government Faces Shutdown as Debt Ceiling Debate Intensifies</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Today | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/US-POLITICS-GOVERNMENT-BUDGET-11_1734673992271_1734674039162.jpg" alt="The US Capitol is pictured ahead of a vote on a revised continuing resolution bill in Washington, DC.(AFP)" title="The US Capitol is pictured ahead of a vote on a revised continuing resolution bill in Washington, DC.(AFP)">
<figcaption>The US Capitol is pictured ahead of a vote on a revised continuing resolution bill in Washington, DC.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>The US government faces a shutdown as lawmakers are unable to agree on a temporary funding plan amidst a significant debt ceiling crisis.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Republican-led House rejected a temporary funding plan backed by President-elect Donald Trump.</li>
  <li>The bill failed with a vote of 235 to 174, reflecting division among Republicans.</li>
  <li>Trump is demanding a provision to raise the debt limit be included in any funding legislation.</li>
  <li>If the debt ceiling is not raised, it could lead to default and severe economic disruption.</li>
  <li>Speaker of the House Mike Johnson faces pressure as he navigates this critical issue.</li>
  <li>Key figures like Representative Chip Roy and Elon Musk have influenced the debate, voicing strong criticisms of proposed plans.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"To congratulate yourself because it’s shorter in pages but increases the debt by $5 trillion is asinine." - Representative Chip Roy</blockquote>
<p>As the deadline approaches, the nation awaits a resolution to avert a government shutdown and its possible repercussions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/race-against-time-us-govt-may-shut-down-on-friday-what-does-it-mean-101734673860098.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/race-against-time-us-govt-may-shut-down-on-friday-what-does-it-mean-101734673860098.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:05:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China KOLs banned for posing as Dubai royalty to sell subpar household products - South China Morning Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China KOLs Banned for Posing as Dubai Royalty to Promote Subpar Products</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Article Report</p>
<p>Influencers in China who disguised themselves as 'Middle Eastern princesses' to sell lifestyle products have been banned on social media platforms, stirring significant public intrigue.</p>
<ul>
<li>Influencer Luo Jialin posed as a prince's wife to promote various products.</li>
<li>Luo reminisced about her supposed royal status and plans to relocate to Saudi Arabia.</li>
<li>Items sold included products misleadingly labeled as luxury, priced below 50 yuan ($7).</li>
<li>Viewers voiced doubts over the authenticity of the products sold.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Luo Jialin stated, “I’m over four months pregnant,” while promoting her merchandise.</blockquote>
<p>This incident highlights issues of authenticity among online influencers and raises questions about consumer protection in the digital marketplace.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3291068/china-kols-banned-posing-wives-dubai-royalty-sell-subpar-household-items</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3291068/china-kols-banned-posing-wives-dubai-royalty-sell-subpar-household-items</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 06:00:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Judge Behind US Department Move Against Adani Group To Resign - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/attorney-behind-us-department-move-against-adani-group-to-resign-7291401</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/attorney-behind-us-department-move-against-adani-group-to-resign-7291401</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:53:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘President Musk’ flexes his influence as US govt shutdown looms - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/president-musk-flexes-his-influence-as-us-govt-shutdown-looms-101734671416211.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/president-musk-flexes-his-influence-as-us-govt-shutdown-looms-101734671416211.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:16:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Putin says porn is a 'global problem,' calls for more 'interesting' alternatives - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Putin says porn is a 'global problem,' calls for more 'interesting' alternatives</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Putin's Speech" width="600">
<figcaption>Russian President Vladimir Putin addressing the issue of pornography.</figcaption>
<p>In a recent statement, Russian President Vladimir Putin highlighted the widespread consequences of pornography, labeling it as a significant global challenge that necessitates more engaging alternatives.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Putin's remarks suggest a call to action towards addressing the influence of pornography on society.</li>
  <li>He advocates for creating and promoting 'interesting' and more socially constructive alternatives.</li>
  <li>The discussion around pornography has implications for national policy and societal values.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Pornography is a global problem that affects people's perception and relationships, and we must find better alternatives."</blockquote>
<p>This statement contributes to an ongoing global discourse about the impact of pornography on society and highlights the need for societal solutions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/putin-says-porn-is-a-global-problem-calls-for-more-interesting-alternatives/articleshow/116490444.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/putin-says-porn-is-a-global-problem-calls-for-more-interesting-alternatives/articleshow/116490444.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel's Netanyahu eyes Iran after triumphs over Hamas, Hezbollah, Syria - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-eyes-iran-after-triumphs-over-hamas-hezbollah-syria-2024-12-20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israels-netanyahu-eyes-iran-after-triumphs-over-hamas-hezbollah-syria-2024-12-20/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 05:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hillary Clinton slams Elon Musk's role in govt shutdown drama: 'Republican party taking orders from the w - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hillary Clinton slams Elon Musk's role in govt shutdown drama: 'Republican party taking orders from the world's richest man'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 12, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Times</p><p>In a recent commentary, Hillary Clinton has expressed her strong disapproval of Elon Musk's influence over the Republican Party, particularly in relation to the government shutdown negotiations.</p><ul><li>Clinton argues that Musk's wealth gives him undue power in politics.</li><li>She warns that such influence could undermine democratic processes.</li><li>Her comments highlight ongoing concerns about the intersection of wealth and political influence.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s alarming to see the Republican party taking orders from the world’s richest man,” Clinton stated.</blockquote><p>Clinton's remarks come amidst heightened concern about the implications of celebrity and wealth on governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/hillary-clinton-slams-elon-musks-role-in-govt-shutdown-drama-republican-party-taking-orders-from-the-worlds-richest-man/articleshow/116488133.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/hillary-clinton-slams-elon-musks-role-in-govt-shutdown-drama-republican-party-taking-orders-from-the-worlds-richest-man/articleshow/116488133.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 04:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh named The Economist's country of the year - Dhaka Tribune]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/368636/bangladesh-named-the-economist-s-country-of-the</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/368636/bangladesh-named-the-economist-s-country-of-the</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 04:25:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald and Melania Trump's kiss at basketball game goes viral: 'Let the woman breathe' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald and Melania Trump's kiss at basketball game goes viral: 'Let the woman breathe'</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> N/A | <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>An unexpected moment at a basketball game captured the attention of many as Donald and Melania Trump shared a kiss, leading to viral reactions on social media.</p><ul><li>The kiss sparked various memes and comments online.</li><li>Refreshingly, many users emphasized the importance of personal space in relationships.</li><li>Some social media users expressed mixed feelings regarding the public display of affection.</li></ul><blockquote>'Let the woman breathe' - A common caption accompanying the viral images.</blockquote><p>This playful moment showcases how public figures can create unexpected conversations about relationships and personal boundaries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-and-melania-trumps-kiss-at-basketball-game-goes-viral-let-the-woman-breathe/articleshow/116487051.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-and-melania-trumps-kiss-at-basketball-game-goes-viral-let-the-woman-breathe/articleshow/116487051.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 03:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Putin says Russia is ready to compromise with Trump on Ukraine war - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Putin Open to Compromise with Trump on Ukraine Conflict</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Thursday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has expressed readiness to compromise on Ukraine in potential talks with US President-elect Donald Trump. He indicated there are no conditions from Russia for initiating discussions with Ukrainian authorities.</p><ul><li>Putin said he is prepared for negotiations and intends to meet Trump.</li><li>Putin stated Russia has become stronger since the 2022 invasion of Ukraine.</li><li>Putin emphasized that negotiations should lead to a long-lasting peace deal, rather than a temporary truce.</li><li>He dismissed ideas of a weak negotiation stance and insisted on no major territorial concessions from Russia.</li><li>Putin remarked that Ukrainian forces would eventually diminish, suggesting fewer will want to fight.</li><li>He noted a need for legitimate Ukrainian authorities, specifically mentioning the Ukrainian parliament.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have always said that we are ready for negotiations and compromises.” - Vladimir Putin</blockquote><p>The conflict has left tens of thousands dead and millions displaced, marking a severe crisis in relations between Russia and the West. Putin noted the Russian economy shows signs of overheating due to the war.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/putin-says-russia-is-ready-to-compromise-with-trump-on-ukraine-war-9735468/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/putin-says-russia-is-ready-to-compromise-with-trump-on-ukraine-war-9735468/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 02:34:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>