<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:21:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 04:21:42 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel claims responsibility behind July killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Claims Responsibility for Killing Hamas Leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a significant escalation of tensions, Israel has publicly acknowledged its role in the killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh during an operation in Iran back in July.</p><ul><li>Israel's Prime Minister confirmed the operation was aimed at disrupting Hamas activities.</li><li>This move marks a rare admission by Israel regarding operations carried out on foreign soil.</li><li>The killing of Haniyeh raises questions about Iran's involvement and the broader implications for Middle Eastern geopolitics.</li></ul><blockquote>"This act demonstrates our commitment to fighting terrorism, no matter where it strikes." - Israeli Prime Minister</blockquote><p>The acknowledgment of this operation by Israel signals a potential shift in its approach to targeting high-profile terrorist figures beyond its immediate borders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/israel-claims-responsibility-behind-july-killing-of-hamas-leader-ismail-haniyeh-in-iran/articleshow/116613905.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/israel-claims-responsibility-behind-july-killing-of-hamas-leader-ismail-haniyeh-in-iran/articleshow/116613905.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYC subway horror: Sebastian Zapeta-Calil charged with murder for setting woman on fire - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NYC Subway Horror: Man Charged with Murder for Setting Woman on Fire</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert source name]</p>
<p>This shocking incident involves Sebastian Zapeta-Calil, who has been charged with the murder of a woman he allegedly set on fire in a subway station in New York City.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Zapeta-Calil has been charged with murder following a horrific attack.</li>
    <li>The incident occurred in a subway station, raising concerns about public safety in transit systems.</li>
    <li>The case highlights ongoing issues of violence and crime in urban environments.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This is an act of senseless violence that cannot be tolerated in our city." - [insert notable quote].</blockquote>
<p>This tragic event emphasizes the need for improved safety measures in public spaces and a stronger response to violence against individuals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/nyc-subway-horror-sebastian-zapeta-calil-charged-with-murder-for-setting-woman-on-fire/articleshow/116613725.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/nyc-subway-horror-sebastian-zapeta-calil-charged-with-murder-for-setting-woman-on-fire/articleshow/116613725.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Don't Mess With Us": Ex Mossad Agents' Revelations On Lebanon Pager Attack - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-mossad-agents-detail-planning-behind-lebanon-pager-walkie-talkie-attacks-on-hezbollah-like-truman-show-7318899</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-mossad-agents-detail-planning-behind-lebanon-pager-walkie-talkie-attacks-on-hezbollah-like-truman-show-7318899</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 02:02:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel Claims Responsibility For Hamas Leader Ismail Haniyeh's Assassination In Iran - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/israel-claims-responsibility-for-hamas-leader-ismail-haniyehs-assassination-9166278.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/israel-claims-responsibility-for-hamas-leader-ismail-haniyehs-assassination-9166278.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:59:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Scared North Korean Soldiers Run Helter-Skelter As Ukraine’s Kamikaze Drones Chase Them In Russia’s - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>North Korean Soldiers Panic as Ukrainian Drones Target Them in Russia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="North Korean soldiers were seen being attacked by Ukrainian drones in Russia’s Kursk region." /><figcaption>North Korean soldiers were seen being attacked by Ukrainian drones in Russia’s Kursk region.</figcaption><p>North Korean troops are currently under threat from Ukrainian kamikaze drones in Russia's Kursk region, as evidenced by viral videos capturing the chaos. Reports indicate a significant number of casualties among North Korean soldiers sent to fight in Ukraine.</p><ul><li>Ukrainian drones have been observed circling and targeting North Korean soldiers.</li><li>South Korea reported that one in ten North Korean soldiers in Ukraine has already been killed or wounded.</li><li>At least 100 North Korean troops are confirmed to have died since December.</li><li>South Korean intelligence suggests North Korea is manufacturing drones and supplying military equipment to Russia.</li><li>Military cooperation between North Korea and Russia has intensified since the onset of the Ukraine conflict.</li></ul><blockquote>“Through various sources of information and intelligence, we assess that North Korean troops who have recently engaged in combat with Ukrainian forces have suffered around 1,100 casualties.” - South Korea’s Joint Chiefs of Staff</blockquote><p>This incident showcases the ongoing complexities of the Russia-Ukraine conflict and highlights the involvement of North Korean forces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/watch-scared-north-korean-soldiers-run-helter-skelter-as-ukraines-kamikaze-drones-chase-them-in-russias-kursk-9166277.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/watch-scared-north-korean-soldiers-run-helter-skelter-as-ukraines-kamikaze-drones-chase-them-in-russias-kursk-9166277.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:51:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[50+ Merry Christmas Wishes, Messages, Greetings and Quotes to share joy and cheer of the season - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>50+ Merry Christmas Wishes, Messages, Greetings and Quotes</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not available</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Not available</p>
<p>Celebrate the festive season with joy by sharing these Christmas wishes, messages, greetings, and quotes with friends and family.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Over 50 heartfelt Christmas messages to share joy.</li>
  <li>Perfect for cards, social media posts, or text messages.</li>
  <li>Includes traditional and humorous greetings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>&quot;May your days be merry and bright, and may all your Christmases be white.&quot;</blockquote>
<p>Takeaway: Spread cheer and warmth this holiday season with thoughtful messages and greetings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/events/50-merry-christmas-wishes-messages-greetings-and-quotes-to-share-joy-and-cheer-of-the-season/articleshow/116467326.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/life-style/events/50-merry-christmas-wishes-messages-greetings-and-quotes-to-share-joy-and-cheer-of-the-season/articleshow/116467326.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Santa Cruz wharf in California collapses in Pacific storm; 3 fall into ocean | Video - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Santa Cruz Wharf Collapses During Pacific Storm; Three Rescued</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/24/550x309/santa_cruz_wharf_pier_california_1735001217975_1735001218207.jpg" alt="This handout image taken and released by the City of Santa Cruz shows the collapsed pier at the Santa Cruz Wharf, in Santa Cruz, California, on December 23, 2024. (AFP)"/>
<figcaption>This handout image taken and released by the City of Santa Cruz shows the collapsed pier at the Santa Cruz Wharf, in Santa Cruz, California, on December 23, 2024. (AFP)</figcaption>
<p>A section of the Santa Cruz wharf in California collapsed during a major storm, leading to the rescue of two individuals while a third managed to swim to safety. The storm is expected to bring hurricane-force winds and hazardous surf conditions.</p>
<ul>
<li>The collapse occurred at approximately 12:45 PM local time, with about 150 feet of the wharf falling into the ocean.</li>
<li>Two people were rescued by lifeguards with no serious injuries reported.</li>
<li>The section of the wharf had been closed for repairs from previous storm damage and included facilities like restrooms and a restaurant.</li>
<li>Residents were warned to avoid low-lying beach areas and evacuations were ordered for nearby ocean-facing hotels.</li>
<li>This incident comes a year after another local pier was destroyed by similar winter storms.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The area will remain closed indefinitely due to hazards posed by debris,” said Santa Cruz officials.</blockquote>
<p>The storm is predicted to continue affecting California's central coast with ocean swells and hazardous conditions along the West Coast.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/santa-cruz-wharf-in-california-collapses-in-pacific-storm-3-fall-into-ocean-video-101734999566153.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/santa-cruz-wharf-in-california-collapses-in-pacific-storm-3-fall-into-ocean-video-101734999566153.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:09:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former US President Bill Clinton hospitalised with fever - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Former US President Bill Clinton Hospitalised with Fever</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>Former President Bill Clinton has been hospitalized due to a fever. His condition is being monitored by healthcare professionals.</p><ul><li>Clinton has a history of health issues including heart surgery.</li><li>Officials assure the public that he is receiving excellent care.</li><li>The hospitalization is reportedly not life-threatening.</li></ul><blockquote>"We are closely monitoring his health condition and remain optimistic about his recovery."</blockquote><p>This incident highlights ongoing concerns regarding the health of high-profile political figures.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/former-us-president-bill-clinton-hospitalised-with-fever/articleshow/116613197.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/former-us-president-bill-clinton-hospitalised-with-fever/articleshow/116613197.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYC subway horror: Suspect Sabastian Zapeta has 'no memory of the attack' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/nyc-subway-horror-suspect-sabastian-zapeta-has-no-memory-of-the-attack/articleshow/116611407.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/nyc-subway-horror-suspect-sabastian-zapeta-has-no-memory-of-the-attack/articleshow/116611407.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 22:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel acknowledges assassinating former Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh in Iran - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Confirms Assassination of Hamas Leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 24, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> HT News</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/23/550x309/Mideast-Wars-0_1734988252621_1734988268811.jpg" alt="Ismail Haniyeh, late leader of the Palestinian militant group Hamas. (File)(AP)" title="Ismail Haniyeh, late leader of the Palestinian militant group Hamas. (File)(AP)"><figcaption>Ismail Haniyeh, late leader of the Palestinian militant group Hamas. (File)(AP)</figcaption></figure><p>Israel has acknowledged the assassination of former Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, resulting in heightened fears of regional conflict and prompting military responses from the US.</p><ul><li>Haniyeh was killed in an explosion on July 31 in Tehran.</li><li>Israeli Defense Minister Israel Katz emphasized intentions to target Houthi leaders similarly.</li><li>The attack escalated tensions, leading the US to deploy additional military resources to the region.</li><li>Haniyeh was involved in negotiations for a ceasefire in Gaza prior to his death.</li></ul><blockquote>“Anyone who raises a hand against Israel will have his hand cut off.” - Israel Katz</blockquote><p>This event has significant implications for the ongoing violence in the region and may lead to increased military engagements by Israel and its adversaries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israel-acknowledges-assassinating-former-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-in-iran-101734986996919.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israel-acknowledges-assassinating-former-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-in-iran-101734986996919.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 21:18:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk reacts to shocking revelation about migrant who set woman on fire in NYC subway - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk reacts to shocking revelation about migrant who set woman on fire in NYC subway</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>This article discusses Elon Musk's reaction to a disturbing incident where a migrant allegedly set a woman on fire in a New York City subway, sparking significant public outrage.</p><ul><li>Musk voiced his concerns on social media.</li><li>The incident raised questions about subway safety and migrant integration.</li><li>Public reactions include a mix of shock and calls for action.</li></ul><blockquote>"It's unacceptable for anyone to be put in danger like this in our city." – Elon Musk</blockquote><p>The event highlights ongoing discussions around public safety and immigration policies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-reacts-to-shocking-revelation-about-migrant-who-set-woman-on-fire-in-nyc-subway/articleshow/116610059.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-reacts-to-shocking-revelation-about-migrant-who-set-woman-on-fire-in-nyc-subway/articleshow/116610059.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 20:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Giving funds to your date is now prostitution?': Trump's former pick Matt Gaetz reacts to sexual miscond - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Giving funds to your date is now prostitution?': Trump's former pick Matt Gaetz reacts to sexual misconduct report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Economic Business</p><p>In a recent reaction to a sexual misconduct report, Matt Gaetz, former ally of Donald Trump, commented on the complexities surrounding financial exchanges in dating and relationships.</p><ul><li>Gaetz questioned the implications of giving money to dates.</li><li>The comments were made in light of ongoing discussions about consent and financial gifts.</li><li>Public reactions highlight varying opinions on the topic of transactional relationships.</li></ul><blockquote>“Are we saying that dating someone and spending money on them equates to prostitution?”</blockquote><p>This statement raises significant dialogue about societal norms and personal boundaries in relationships today.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/matt-gaetz-reacts-to-ethics-report-giving-funds-to-someone-you-/articleshow/116609912.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/matt-gaetz-reacts-to-ethics-report-giving-funds-to-someone-you-/articleshow/116609912.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Matt Gaetz reacts to ethics report: 'Giving funds to someone you...' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Giving funds to your date is now prostitution?': Trump's former pick Matt Gaetz reacts to sexual misconduct report</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p><p>In light of recent sexual misconduct allegations, former Trump adviser Matt Gaetz responds to a report suggesting that financial support between dating individuals could constitute prostitution.</p><ul><li>Gaetz questions the legitimacy of the claims being made against him and others in similar situations.</li><li>The report has raised significant discussions about dating norms and legality concerning financial exchanges.</li><li>Gaetz suggests that this mindset could hinder normal dating behaviors, equating innocent acts with accusations of misconduct.</li></ul><blockquote>“If giving funds to your date is now considered prostitution, we have a serious problem,” Gaetz commented.</blockquote><p>This report and Gaetz's reaction highlight ongoing controversies regarding personal relationships and evolving societal standards.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/matt-gaetz-reacts-to-ethics-report-giving-funds-to-someone-you-/articleshow/116609912.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/matt-gaetz-reacts-to-ethics-report-giving-funds-to-someone-you-/articleshow/116609912.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Don't Mess With Us’: Ex-Mossad Agents Make Sensational On-Air Revelation About Hezbollah Pager Plot - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/israel-ex-mossad-agents-make-on-air-revelation-about-hezbollah-pager-plot-lebanon-middle-east-latest-updates-9165307.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/israel-ex-mossad-agents-make-on-air-revelation-about-hezbollah-pager-plot-lebanon-middle-east-latest-updates-9165307.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Did Luigi Mangione and lawyer wear matching outfits? Why was Brian Thompson's accused killer smiling in c - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Did Luigi Mangione and lawyer wear matching outfits? Why was Brian Thompson's accused killer smiling in court?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>This article discusses the peculiar behavior of the accused killer of Brian Thompson in court, focusing on his smiles and potentially coordinated attire with his lawyer.</p><ul><li>The accused killer, Brian Thompson, appeared in court with a smile.</li><li>Questions were raised about the seriousness of the situation with such unexpected demeanor.</li><li>Analysis of attire choices may suggest a strategic approach in the courtroom.</li></ul><blockquote>"It's unusual to see such a demeanor in such a serious environment," stated a legal expert.</blockquote><p>The incident has sparked discussions about courtroom behavior and its implications on public perception of justice.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/did-luigi-mangione-and-lawyer-wear-matching-outfit-why-was-brian-thompsons-accused-killer-smiling-in-court/articleshow/116609442.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/did-luigi-mangione-and-lawyer-wear-matching-outfit-why-was-brian-thompsons-accused-killer-smiling-in-court/articleshow/116609442.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 19:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[France’s Macron announces fourth government of the year - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>France’s Macron announces fourth government of the year</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Monday evening</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Presidency</p><p>French President Emmanuel Macron named a new government to address ongoing political challenges in the country. The new cabinet is led by Francois Bayrou, marking Macron's fourth prime minister appointment this year.</p><ul><li>Former prime minister Elisabeth Borne appointed as education minister.</li><li>Manuel Valls returns as overseas territories minister, highlighting the importance of this role after recent criticism regarding cyclone response in Mayotte.</li><li>Gerald Darmanin takes on the position of justice minister.</li><li>Defense Minister Sebastien Lecornu and Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot retain their positions.</li><li>Eric Lombard is tasked with delivering next year's budget plan.</li><li>Macron aims for stability and seeks to avoid past government failures.</li></ul><blockquote>The announcement comes as France mourns the victims of a cyclone in Mayotte, which claimed at least 35 lives.</blockquote><p>This cabinet formation reflects Macron's strategy to build a strong governing coalition to overcome political deadlock and implement necessary budget reforms.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1880613/frances-macron-announces-fourth-government-of-the-year</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1880613/frances-macron-announces-fourth-government-of-the-year</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:58:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan plans to purchase 40 Chinese J-35 stealth fighter jets - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan plans to purchase 40 Chinese J-35 stealth fighter jets</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Pakistan has announced intentions to acquire 40 stealth fighter jets from China, enhancing its military capabilities in a move that has raised regional security dynamics.</p><ul><li>The acquisition includes advanced technology and combat capabilities.</li><li>The deal reflects strengthening military ties between Pakistan and China.</li><li>This purchase is part of Pakistan's ongoing defense modernization efforts.</li><li>The J-35 jets are designed for stealth operations and advanced air combat.</li></ul><blockquote>“This acquisition will make a substantial difference to our air force operational capabilities.”</blockquote><p>This purchase signals not just an upgrade in military asset but also potentially shifts the balance of power in the region, prompting responses from neighboring countries.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/pakistan-plans-to-purchase-40-chinese-j-35-stealth-fighter-jets/articleshow/116608638.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/pakistan-plans-to-purchase-40-chinese-j-35-stealth-fighter-jets/articleshow/116608638.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 18:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Social Security Payments and Government Shutdowns: What You Need to Know! - LKO Uniexam.in]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE5KTUdHY3lwYm1IX1doU0t6X3dmMXdnN1lXel90U25CbmllMlJxc01Cb0M3NEkxSXpHRWxwVGd2VExRN21MUVpMNG03b1BLT2x1UzNzVE4wb3pkTUozOWh4cGpRUncxdUtwOGNjUlEwcWZFNk1LUXd2ZFFrNnY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE5KTUdHY3lwYm1IX1doU0t6X3dmMXdnN1lXel90U25CbmllMlJxc01Cb0M3NEkxSXpHRWxwVGd2VExRN21MUVpMNG03b1BLT2x1UzNzVE4wb3pkTUozOWh4cGpRUncxdUtwOGNjUlEwcWZFNk1LUXd2ZFFrNnY?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ousted Syrian President Assad’s Wife Unhappy With Life In Russia? What Led Her To File For Divorce - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Asma al-Assad Files for Divorce Amid Discontent in Moscow</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Bashar al-Assad with his wife Asma al-Assad | File Image"><figcaption>Bashar al-Assad with his wife Asma al-Assad | File Image</figcaption><p>The British wife of Syria's ousted president, Bashar al-Assad, has filed for divorce after expressing dissatisfaction with her life in Moscow, where she sought asylum following her husband's ousting.</p><ul><li>Asma al-Assad wishes to return to her hometown of London.</li><li>She filed for divorce in a Russian court and awaits special permission to leave Moscow.</li><li>Bashar al-Assad was granted asylum in Moscow along with his family but lives under restrictions.</li><li>Russian authorities have frozen Assad's assets, which include significant monetary and material wealth.</li></ul><blockquote>“Her application is reportedly currently being evaluated by Russian authorities.”</blockquote><p>The situation highlights the ongoing struggle of the Assad family following their fall from power, with implications for their future living arrangements and legal battles.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/ousted-syrian-president-assads-wife-unhappy-with-life-in-russia-what-led-her-to-file-divorce-9165294.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/ousted-syrian-president-assads-wife-unhappy-with-life-in-russia-what-led-her-to-file-divorce-9165294.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:51:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Trying civilians in military courts lacks transparency,’ UK says after May 9 FGCM convictions - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Trying civilians in military courts lacks transparency,’ UK says after May 9 FGCM convictions</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Monday<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Dawn</p><p>The United Kingdom has expressed concerns regarding the transparency of military trials for civilians following the sentencing of 25 individuals related to the May 9 riots in Pakistan.</p><ul><li>The UK stated that military courts lack transparency and independent scrutiny.</li><li>Twenty-five PTI activists received sentences ranging from two to ten years.</li><li>Concerns were raised by the PTI, Human Rights Commission of Pakistan, and the EU.</li><li>The EU highlighted potential violations of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights (ICCPR).</li><li>PTI officials asserted that military trials violate both international and domestic laws.</li></ul><blockquote>“While the UK respects Pakistan’s sovereignty over its own legal proceedings, trying civilians in military courts lacks transparency, independent scrutiny, and undermines the right to a fair trial.” - UK Foreign Office Spokesperson</blockquote><p>The situation underscores increasing tensions over legal proceedings for civilians amidst political unrest in Pakistan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1880609</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1880609</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:21:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Trying civilians in military courts lacks transparency,’ UK says after May 9 convictions - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQbGJySnI2cHlHc2RCZjBLNHZFa0U0M3kydlczSEhTUEpxdll2MmdPbUctVVJJOUM0MEdaX0VlRk1jU2FrSWdKU1d6U3l6c2YtOVZXTWh2dEk0b3dkY0JvZ29hRVFRaEl3cUlfSy1HUjdzVDhvSHpmRTZQNk9YaFB2LWYxTzhGRjJvTUkzSGJxTkFRbEV5eXFFSnJtMGd6OTk0c19ZZm4wS1NJLTktTDhKWXEzc2ExMEVPbklueQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxQbGJySnI2cHlHc2RCZjBLNHZFa0U0M3kydlczSEhTUEpxdll2MmdPbUctVVJJOUM0MEdaX0VlRk1jU2FrSWdKU1d6U3l6c2YtOVZXTWh2dEk0b3dkY0JvZ29hRVFRaEl3cUlfSy1HUjdzVDhvSHpmRTZQNk9YaFB2LWYxTzhGRjJvTUkzSGJxTkFRbEV5eXFFSnJtMGd6OTk0c19ZZm4wS1NJLTktTDhKWXEzc2ExMEVPbklueQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:21:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Khamenei hints at desire to overthrow Syria's new government - ایران اینترنشنال]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUkFVX3lxTFB0UDd0aWNuUkdCYTFGOVpHVDhhZmpmUW85SEtzVm1WNHVrVU9vTGh0SGUzUGs0ejd5REVONENQQTcwUGRBY2hhU29TTEpCaHFlbWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiUkFVX3lxTFB0UDd0aWNuUkdCYTFGOVpHVDhhZmpmUW85SEtzVm1WNHVrVU9vTGh0SGUzUGs0ejd5REVONENQQTcwUGRBY2hhU29TTEpCaHFlbWc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arab diplomats flock to Damascus for meetings with new Syrian leader - The Times of Israel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Arab diplomats flock to Damascus for meetings with new Syrian leader</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Times of Israel</p>
<img src="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2024/12/AFP__20241223__36RB3JN__v1__HighRes__SyriaJordanPoliticsDiplomacy-640x400.jpg" alt="Jordan’s Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi in Damascus" width="600" height="375">
<figcaption>The handout picture released by the Jordanian Foreign Ministry shows Jordan’s Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi (L) being received by Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS) leader Ahmed al-Sharaa in Damascus on December 23, 2024. (Photo by Jordanian Foreign Ministry / AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Syria’s newly appointed leader Ahmed al-Sharaa met with senior Arab diplomats, marking a significant step in Syria's diplomatic re-engagement following the overthrow of Bashar al-Assad. The meetings are seen as pivotal for the future of Syria's reconstruction and regional relations.</p>
<ul>
<li>Sharaa, also known as Abu Mohammed al-Julani, welcomes Arab envoys to Damascus.</li>
<li>Jordan’s Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi emphasizes Jordan's support for Syria's reconstruction efforts and cooperation to tackle drug smuggling.</li>
<li>Qatar's minister of state leads a high-level delegation, reinforcing ties after a 13-year diplomatic freeze.</li>
<li>Saudi officials also engaged Sharaa to address the drug crisis linked to Syria.</li>
<li>Concerns about the Islamic State's ongoing threat were highlighted during discussions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We agree to support the Syrian people in rebuilding their state,” Ayman Safadi stated.</blockquote>
<p>The meetings among Arab leaders suggest a renewed commitment to stabilize Syria while addressing regional security issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesofisrael.com/arab-diplomats-flock-to-damascus-for-meetings-with-new-syrian-leader/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesofisrael.com/arab-diplomats-flock-to-damascus-for-meetings-with-new-syrian-leader/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explainer: What happens when Russian gas to Europe via Ukraine stops? - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/what-happens-when-russian-gas-europe-via-ukraine-stops-2024-12-23/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/what-happens-when-russian-gas-europe-via-ukraine-stops-2024-12-23/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 17:03:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYC subway horror: Accused Guatemalan migrant, Sebastian Zapeta, re-entered US after deportation - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NYC subway horror: Accused Guatemalan migrant, Sebastian Zapeta, re-entered US after deportation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 15, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="NYC Subway Horror" /><figcaption>Image depicting the NYC subway incident.</figcaption><p>A Guatemalan migrant, Sebastian Zapeta, who was previously deported from the United States, has re-entered the country and is now accused of committing a violent attack on the New York City subway.</p><ul><li>Sebastian Zapeta was deported but managed to re-enter the United States.</li><li>He is charged with attacking a fellow subway passenger, raising serious concerns about public safety.</li><li>This incident has reignited debates over immigration policies and public security.</li><li>Authorities emphasize the importance of comprehensive measures to prevent such incidents in the future.</li></ul><blockquote>“The subway should be a safe place for all New Yorkers,” said a local official responding to the attack.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights ongoing concerns regarding immigration enforcement and safety in public transportation across major cities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/nyc-subway-horror-accused-guatemalan-migrant-sebastian-zapeta-re-entered-us-after-deportation/articleshow/116607159.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/nyc-subway-horror-accused-guatemalan-migrant-sebastian-zapeta-re-entered-us-after-deportation/articleshow/116607159.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China’s Struggle With ‘Trap Landing’ Finally Traps Ex-U.S. Fighter Pilot; Will Be Extradited To U.S. For Helping PLA - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China's Struggle With 'Trap Landing' Finally Traps Ex-U.S. Fighter Pilot; Will Be Extradited To U.S. For Helping PLA</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> EurAsian Times</p>
<figure><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Fj3eznkXwAAoqcE.jpg:large" alt="Pilot Daniel Duggan" width="1240" height="744"><figcaption>Pilot Daniel Duggan – a former US Marine Corps aviator – was accused of breaking American arms control laws by training Chinese fighter pilots to land (Via X)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The former US Marine Corps pilot, Daniel Duggan, is scheduled to be extradited to the United States for unlawfully training Chinese naval aviators in aircraft-carrier landings.</p>
<ul>
<li>Duggan, 56, has been fighting extradition from Australia for two years.</li>
<li>Arrested in October 2022, he is accused of violating arms trafficking regulations.</li>
<li>China reportedly faces a shortage of skilled naval aviators and has been recruiting foreign pilots.</li>
<li>The 'Five Eyes' partners have termed China's recruitment operations a persistent danger.</li>
<li>If convicted in the U.S., Duggan faces up to 60 years in prison.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The PLA wants the skills and expertise of these individuals to make its military air operations more capable while gaining insight into Western air tactics.” – Michael Casey, National Counterintelligence and Security Center</blockquote>
<p>This case underscores the rising tensions between the U.S. and China regarding military capabilities and the legal repercussions faced by individuals involved.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/chinas-struggle-with-trap-landing-finally-trap/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/chinas-struggle-with-trap-landing-finally-trap/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:21:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel’s Netanyahu orders military to ‘destroy’ Houthis - Arab News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Some gaps have narrowed in elusive Gaza ceasefire deal, sides say</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 23, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p>
<img src="https://www.arabnews.com/sites/default/files/styles/n_670_395/public/main-image/2024/12/23/4557317-78365319.jpg?itok=0qnW_PWX" alt="Some gaps have narrowed in elusive Gaza ceasefire deal, sides say">
<figcaption>Efforts continue for a ceasefire in Gaza amidst ongoing hostilities.</figcaption>
<p>Gaps between Israel and Hamas regarding a potential ceasefire have narrowed, with mediators gaining momentum in resolving key issues, though significant differences remain.</p>
<ul>
<li>Palestinian officials report that some sticking points in ceasefire negotiations have been resolved.</li>
<li>The identities of Palestinian prisoners to be exchanged for hostages are still under negotiation.</li>
<li>Israeli officials express that they are closer to an agreement than in previous months, indicating potential stages to the ceasefire.</li>
<li>The conflict, which escalated on October 7, 2023, has resulted in significant casualties and a humanitarian crisis in Gaza.</li>
<li>The UN has raised alarms about impending famine conditions in Gaza as humanitarian aid efforts are hindered.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This ceasefire can last six months or it can last 10 years, it depends on the dynamics that will form on the ground.” - Amichai Chikli, Israeli diaspora minister</blockquote>
<p>While some progress has been made, the resolution remains heavily contingent on broader political dynamics and the future governance of Gaza.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.arabnews.com/node/2584076/middle-east</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.arabnews.com/node/2584076/middle-east</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 16:01:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione pleads not guilty; lawyer blasts mayor Eric Adams for perp walk - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Luigi Mangione pleads not guilty; lawyer blasts mayor Eric Adams for perp walk</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Date Missing] | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Main image for the article"><figcaption>Main image for the article</figcaption><p>Luigi Mangione has formally pleaded not guilty, and his lawyer has taken the opportunity to criticize Mayor Eric Adams for the way the situation has been handled, particularly regarding the perp walk.</p><ul><li>Luigi Mangione entered a not guilty plea.</li><li>His lawyer criticized the actions of Mayor Eric Adams during the arrest.</li><li>The attorney claims the perp walk was unnecessary and damaging.</li></ul><blockquote>“This kind of treatment is not just uncalled for, it’s damaging,” stated Mangione's lawyer.</blockquote><p>This case raises important questions about the treatment of individuals during legal proceedings, especially in high-profile situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/luigi-mangione-pleads-not-guilty-lawyer-blasts-mayor-eric-adams-for-perp-walk/articleshow/116606255.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/luigi-mangione-pleads-not-guilty-lawyer-blasts-mayor-eric-adams-for-perp-walk/articleshow/116606255.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Police verification now required for Pakistani travellers to UAE, Senate body informed - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE1wcjNOVmhCR0ROaG5XTzEwOFAtb3l2TDdOQkpMbnFKYkJhSHo2czg0RDUwNWQtcE9XYjUtdWR0aXBsZERCWUNQeg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE1wcjNOVmhCR0ROaG5XTzEwOFAtb3l2TDdOQkpMbnFKYkJhSHo2czg0RDUwNWQtcE9XYjUtdWR0aXBsZERCWUNQeg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:31:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Economist gives Bangladesh 'country of the year' award - OpIndia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Economist Awards Bangladesh as 'Country of the Year'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Economist</p>
<p>This year, The Economist has awarded Bangladesh the title of “Country of the Year,” praising the nation for toppling an authoritarian regime and transitioning to a new interim government. However, this recognition has been met with criticism for overlooking the increasing violence against the Hindu minority in Bangladesh.</p>
<h2>Key Points</h2>
<ul>
<li>The Economist's award is meant to celebrate countries that have shown significant improvement over the year.</li>
<li>Bangladesh was recognized for the removal of authoritarian leader Sheikh Hasina and the emergence of a technocratic interim government led by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus.</li>
<li>Critics point out that this improvement narrative ignores the escalating persecution of Hindus in Bangladesh.</li>
<li>Statistics reveal a troubling increase in attacks on Hindu minorities, with a 4,580% rise in reported incidents since 2022.</li>
<li>The article raises questions about the legitimacy of characterizing a nation as improved when its minority communities face violence and suppression.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Economist’s silence on these atrocities raises uncomfortable questions about its understanding of progress.”</blockquote>
<p>The reactions highlight a broader discussion regarding Western media's portrayal of violence against Hindus and the biases that influence narrative framing.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>The Economist’s decision to award Bangladesh while ignoring the plight of its minorities reflects a troubling trend in media narratives that prioritize certain political stories over the lived experiences of marginalized communities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.opindia.com/2024/12/the-economist-awards-strife-torn-bangladesh-country-of-the-year-celebrating-the-unending-cycle-of-violence-against-hindus/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opindia.com/2024/12/the-economist-awards-strife-torn-bangladesh-country-of-the-year-celebrating-the-unending-cycle-of-violence-against-hindus/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 15:16:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>