<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:16:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:16:25 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A timeline: IDF special op. against Iranian missile production facility in Syria - The Jerusalem Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>IDF's Operation Against Iranian Nuclear Facility: A Detailed Timeline</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-02T17:59:58+02:00">January 2, 2025</time></p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Jerusalem Post</p>
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.jpost.com/image/upload/q_auto/c_fill,g_faces:center,h_537,w_822/641964" width="290" height="260" alt="Operation Heavy Roads, involving IDF special op. against Iranian missile production facility in Syria" title="Operation Heavy Roads, involving IDF special op. against Iranian missile production facility in Syria">
  <figcaption>Operation Heavy Roads, involving IDF special op. against Iranian missile production facility in Syria (photo credit: IDF)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In an unprecedented operation, the IDF executed a combined ground and air mission on September 8, 2024, to destroy an Iranian missile production facility in Syria, following years of intelligence gathering and planning.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Iran's missile production plans in Syria began as early as September 2017.</li>
  <li>By 2018, Israel was aware of these plans.</li>
  <li>In 2021, the facility was close to operational capacity with materials being sent to it.</li>
  <li>Initial IDF strategies focused on airstrikes, which proved unsuccessful due to the facility's underground nature.</li>
  <li>Decision for a ground operation was made in August 2024 amidst evolving threats.</li>
  <li>120 soldiers participated, supported by extensive aerial operations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p>The IDF acknowledged that a significant shift in intelligence quality allowed for the operation to be deemed possible.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This operation marks a pivotal moment in Israel's military strategy towards Iran and its regional influence, indicating a willingness to act decisively in the face of imminent threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jpost.com/israel-news/article-835881</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jpost.com/israel-news/article-835881</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:59:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We strongly condemn cowardly terrorist attack in New Orleans: PM Modi - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>We strongly condemn cowardly terrorist attack in New Orleans: PM Modi</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/c9jw4c/article69049971.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/20241223033L.jpg" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi. File" /><figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi. File | Photo Credit: ANI</figcaption><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi expressed his condemnation for a terrorist attack that took place in New Orleans, resulting in the deaths of 15 individuals, and offered condolences to the victims' families.</p><ul><li>The attack happened on New Year’s Day when a driver plowed into a crowd in the French Quarter.</li><li>PM Modi emphasized the tragic loss of life and offered his prayers for those affected.</li><li>More than 30 people sustained injuries during the attack.</li><li>The FBI is investigating the incident as terrorism, suspecting the driver did not act alone.</li></ul><blockquote>We strongly condemn the cowardly terrorist attack in New Orleans. Our thoughts and prayers are with the victims and their families. May they find strength and solace as they heal from this tragedy. — Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) January 2, 2025</blockquote><p>This tragic event marks a significant act of violence in a festive location, leading to an investigation by federal authorities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/we-strongly-condemn-cowardly-terrorist-attack-in-new-orleans-pm-modi/article69054172.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/we-strongly-condemn-cowardly-terrorist-attack-in-new-orleans-pm-modi/article69054172.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US considers potential rules to restrict or bar Chinese drones - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-considers-potential-rules-restrict-or-bar-chinese-drones-2025-01-02/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-considers-potential-rules-restrict-or-bar-chinese-drones-2025-01-02/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:43:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ousted Syrian Leader Bashar al-Assad Allegedly Poisoned In Moscow: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ousted Syrian Leader Bashar al-Assad Allegedly Poisoned In Moscow: Report</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 03, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Ousted Syrian Leader Bashar al-Assad" /><figcaption>Unverified reports claimed that Syrian leader Bashar al-Assad was targeted in an assassination bid in Moscow. (IMAGE: AP)</figcaption><p>An alleged poisoning attempt has reportedly been made on ousted Syrian president Bashar al-Assad, currently in Moscow under the protection of Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p><ul><li>Assad fell ill on Sunday and showed symptoms consistent with poisoning.</li><li>Tests indicated the presence of poison in his system, but there has been no official confirmation.</li><li>Assad fled to Russia on December 8, 2024, after a rebel offensive led to his overthrow.</li></ul><blockquote>“There is every reason to believe an assassination attempt was made,” claimed a source.</blockquote><p>This incident underscores the ongoing volatile situation surrounding Assad's ousting and the precariousness of his current refuge in Moscow.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/ousted-syrian-leader-bashar-al-assad-targeted-in-alleged-poisoning-plot-in-moscow-report-9175572.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/ousted-syrian-leader-bashar-al-assad-targeted-in-alleged-poisoning-plot-in-moscow-report-9175572.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:40:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Thoughts and prayers with victims, their families': PM Modi condemns 'cowardly terrorist attack' in New - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/thoughts-and-prayers-with-victims-their-families-pm-modi-condemns-cowardly-terrorist-attack-in-new-orleans/articleshow/116888199.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/thoughts-and-prayers-with-victims-their-families-pm-modi-condemns-cowardly-terrorist-attack-in-new-orleans/articleshow/116888199.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Cowardly': PM Narendra Modi condemns New Orleans truck attack - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Narendra Modi Condemns Cowardly Truck Attack in New Orleans</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/Prime-Minister-Narendra-Modi--DPR-PMO-ANI-_1735823018944_1735823025961.jpg" alt="Prime Minister Narendra Modi (DPR PMO/ANI)" title="Prime Minister Narendra Modi (DPR PMO/ANI)">
<figcaption>Prime Minister Narendra Modi (DPR PMO/ANI)</figcaption>
<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi has condemned the tragic truck attack in New Orleans that resulted in 15 fatalities, expressing condolences for the victims and their families.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Modi described the attack as a "cowardly terrorist act" and extended his prayers to those affected.</li>
    <li>The assailant, identified as Shamsud-Din Jabbar, was a 42-year-old US citizen who targeted revelers on New Year’s Eve.</li>
    <li>After the attack, Jabbar was shot dead by law enforcement as he began firing at the scene.</li>
    <li>Two homemade explosives were found and neutralized at the attack site.</li>
    <li>FBI stated that they do not believe Jabbar acted alone.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This man was trying to run over as many people as he possibly could," - New Orleans police superintendent Anne Kirkpatrick.</blockquote>
<p>This incident raises concerns about terrorism and safety during major public celebrations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/cowardly-pm-narendra-modi-condemns-new-orleans-truck-attack-101735822939343.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/cowardly-pm-narendra-modi-condemns-new-orleans-truck-attack-101735822939343.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Orleans attack live updates: ‘Country is a disaster, laughing stock’ says Donald Trump - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New Orleans Truck Attack: 15 Killed, ISIS Inspiration, World Reaction</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 2, 2025, <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/">Hindustan Times</a></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/FBI_1735757350713_1735783698731.jpg" alt="New Orleans attack live updates: Law enforcement officers from multiple agencies work the scene on Bourbon Street after at least ten people were killed when a person allegedly drove into the crowd in the early morning hours of New Year's Day on January 1, 2025 in New Orleans, Louisiana." width="360" height="202" loading="lazy" decoding="async" /><figcaption>Law enforcement officers work the scene on Bourbon Street after a deadly truck attack in New Orleans.</figcaption>
<p><strong>Introduction:</strong> A truck attack on New Year's revelers in New Orleans' French Quarter has left 15 dead and around 30 injured, with authorities treating it as a potential act of terrorism. The suspect, a US-born Army veteran, was killed by police.</p>
<ol>
<li>The attack occurred on Bourbon Street, a popular New Year's Eve destination, with crowds swelling for the Sugar Bowl game.</li>
<li>The suspect, Shamsud-Din Jabbar, was an Army veteran with financial struggles and a recent divorce.</li>
<li>Jabbar expressed a desire to kill and was inspired by ISIS, according to videos posted before the attack.</li>
<li>Two improvised explosive devices (IEDs) were found in Jabbar's vehicle, and additional potential IEDs were discovered in the French Quarter.</li>
<li>World leaders, including Pope Francis and Indian PM Narendra Modi, condemned the attack and offered condolences.</li>
<li>Elon Musk suggested a possible link between the New Orleans attack and a Cybertruck explosion in Las Vegas.</li>
<li>Former President Trump blamed Democrats and incompetent government for the attack.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote><p>“Our Country is a disaster, a laughing stock all over the World!” – Donald Trump</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The New Orleans truck attack has sparked international outrage and condolences, with investigations ongoing to determine if the suspect acted alone and any potential links to terrorist organizations or other attacks.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/new-orleans-car-attack-live-updates-joe-biden-fbi-isis-army-veteran-jabbar-cybertruck-blast-las-vegas-hotel-jan-2-2025-101735783705610.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/new-orleans-car-attack-live-updates-joe-biden-fbi-isis-army-veteran-jabbar-cybertruck-blast-las-vegas-hotel-jan-2-2025-101735783705610.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 13:00:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rival South Korea camps face off as president holds out - CNA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxQRDJfVDkwd3FzRnI1Y3ltMEhPTU8xQXdRUFFGb25ycVgzQ2lma2FBb2E0V2N5QV9tSHhPd1dQZkVTZUcxdllWbXJIS2VJcllyWGl1N2I4QS1yMS1oaXJubS1BZ2RGWEF3aVlhdnZuak8yMzFLMmZrUnpQdXljWDFJcW1hZURtZ1k5VGZMN3hkajB0VXFyWWNtLWJmbFFhdGs4QjM4c2lLRFJhZ2FBX3FwRUtlNUlLUDdCOERWRnRMUkJtUTJO?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxQRDJfVDkwd3FzRnI1Y3ltMEhPTU8xQXdRUFFGb25ycVgzQ2lma2FBb2E0V2N5QV9tSHhPd1dQZkVTZUcxdllWbXJIS2VJcllyWGl1N2I4QS1yMS1oaXJubS1BZ2RGWEF3aVlhdnZuak8yMzFLMmZrUnpQdXljWDFJcW1hZURtZ1k5VGZMN3hkajB0VXFyWWNtLWJmbFFhdGs4QjM4c2lLRFJhZ2FBX3FwRUtlNUlLUDdCOERWRnRMUkJtUTJO?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin, Boeing Defense Among 45 US Entities Penalised By China - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Imposes Sanctions on 45 US Defense Entities Over Arms Sales to Taiwan</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date]</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>China has escalated its sanctions against American defense firms, penalizing a total of 45 entities for the sale of arms to Taiwan, a move described as a counter-offensive against U.S. actions.</p><img src='[Insert Image URL]' alt='China's sanctions on US defense firms'><figcaption>China imposes sanctions.</figcaption><p>The key points include:</p><ul><li>China has sanctioned or penalized 45 US entities for arms sales to Taiwan.</li><li>Among those affected are major defense manufacturers, including Lockheed Martin and Boeing.</li><li>The sanctioned firms are now prohibited from all import and export activities in China.</li><li>The sanctions come amidst heightened military tensions between China and Taiwan.</li><li>US President Joe Biden recently approved $571 million in defense aid to Taiwan.</li></ul><blockquote>“Such actions interfere in China's internal affairs, and undermine China's sovereignty and territorial integrity,” stated China's Ministry of Commerce.</blockquote><p>This move highlights the increasing tensions between China and the US regarding Taiwan and indicates a significant escalation in sanctions against American firms.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lockheed-martin-boeing-defense-among-45-us-entities-sanctioned-by-china-7384828</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lockheed-martin-boeing-defense-among-45-us-entities-sanctioned-by-china-7384828</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:39:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[27 migrants die off Tunisia, 83 rescued, in shipwrecks: civil defence - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE0zVDMycE8yZkkyemlVX24wLTNnUDZhLW94Y0k4aWg4RDF1Zy02MmwxUnZYc3p0X0NKaldnNjMzSm5sdEZIV3ROZQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiSEFVX3lxTE0zVDMycE8yZkkyemlVX24wLTNnUDZhLW94Y0k4aWg4RDF1Zy02MmwxUnZYc3p0X0NKaldnNjMzSm5sdEZIV3ROZQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:30:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Did Cybertruck bomber Matthew Livelsberger and New Orleans attacker Shamsud Din Jabbar plan their attacks - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/is-cybertruck-bomber-matthew-livelsberger-connected-with-new-orleans-attacker-shamsud-din-jabbar/articleshow/116886726.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/is-cybertruck-bomber-matthew-livelsberger-connected-with-new-orleans-attacker-shamsud-din-jabbar/articleshow/116886726.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 12:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New textbooks in Bangladesh credit Ziaur Rahman for declaration of independence: media report - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/new-textbooks-in-bangladesh-to-alter-credit-of-declaration-of-independence-report/article69053540.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/new-textbooks-in-bangladesh-to-alter-credit-of-declaration-of-independence-report/article69053540.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Not Mujib, now Ziaur is Bangladeshs hero as country begins to rewrite history - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ziaur Rahman, Bangladesh’s Hero as Country Rewrites Its History</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p>
<p>Bangladesh's government is rewriting history textbooks, shifting credit for the country's 1971 independence from Sheikh Mujibur Rahman to Ziaur Rahman.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The new textbooks, set to be used in 2025, will state that Ziaur Rahman declared independence.</li>
  <li>Ziaur Rahman is also noted for reiterating the declaration the following day on behalf of Mujib.</li>
  <li>This shift undermines the historical significance of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, considered the Father of the Nation.</li>
  <li>There are concerns about the influence of Islamist demands on the educational narrative.</li>
  <li>There are also reports of India’s role in the liberation war being downplayed.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The country's new textbooks in 2025 will now credit Ziaur Rahman instead of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, as the one who declared the country’s independence.”</blockquote>
<p>This change in the educational narrative raises important questions about historical accountability and the influence of political agendas in shaping national identity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/world/ziaur-rahman-bangaldeshs-hero-as-country-rewrites-its-history/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/world/ziaur-rahman-bangaldeshs-hero-as-country-rewrites-its-history/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:29:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Africa on ‘France Out’ campaign, ally Ivory Coast latest to join the bandwagon - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Africa's 'France Out' Campaign Expands as Ivory Coast Joins Call for Troop Withdrawal</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2024 &bull; <strong>Source:</strong> Firstpost</p><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/07/Untitled-2024-07-07T155515.928-2024-07-a15298fa4718caea4170ef3a8424c6a1.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Africa on ‘France Out’ campaign, ally Ivory Coast latest to join the bandwagon" title="Africa on ‘France Out’ campaign, ally Ivory Coast latest to join the bandwagon"><figcaption>French President Emmanuel Macron (Photo: AP)</figcaption><p>Ivory Coast has become the latest country to join the growing trend in Africa calling for the withdrawal of French troops, reflecting a significant shift in regional dynamics.</p><ul><li>Ivory Coast, Senegal, and Chad have recently requested French troop withdrawals, highlighting sovereignty concerns.</li><li>The campaign includes a growing sentiment against neocolonial practices attributed to France's historical influence.</li><li>France's military interventions have been cited as contributing to local opposition and growing instability in the region.</li><li>Analysts suggest that the end of French military presence marks a decline in its post-colonial influence, especially in the Sahel.</li></ul><blockquote>“We can be proud of our army, whose modernisation is now complete,” said President Alassane Ouattara, emphasizing the rationale behind the withdrawal.</blockquote><p>The withdrawal of French troops from these nations signifies a pivotal moment in Africa's redefinition of its security and diplomatic relationships, as countries increasingly seek autonomy from former colonial powers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/world/africa-on-france-out-campaign-ally-ivory-coast-latest-to-join-the-bandwagon-13849371.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/world/africa-on-france-out-campaign-ally-ivory-coast-latest-to-join-the-bandwagon-13849371.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 11:24:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Al Jazeera broadcasts suspended by Palestinian Authority - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Palestinian Authority Suspends Al Jazeera Broadcasts</h1>
<p><strong>Published: January 02, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Al Jazeera</strong></p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/5un5gk/article69053395.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/AFP__20250102__36RW776__v1__HighRes__PalestinianIsraelMediaAlJazeera.jpg" alt="Pictures of slain Palestinian journalist Shireen Abu Akleh are hung across the facade of the building housing the Doha-based Al-Jazeera TV channel in the occupied-West Bank city of Ramallah" />
<figcaption>Pictures of slain Palestinian journalist Shireen Abu Akleh are hung across the facade of the building housing the Doha-based Al-Jazeera TV channel in the occupied-West Bank city of Ramallah on January 2, 2025 | Photo Credit: AFP</figcaption>
<p>The Palestinian Authority has ordered the suspension of broadcasts by Al Jazeera across the Palestinian territories, citing accusations of incitement. This decision comes amid an ongoing conflict between the network and Israeli authorities.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The suspension of Al Jazeera's broadcasts is reported due to claims of inciting content.</li>
  <li>The Palestinian Authority's decision follows previous actions against the network, including a raid of its office by Israeli forces.</li>
  <li>Al Jazeera's office in Ramallah has received an official suspension order.</li>
  <li>The decision affects all employees and journalists associated with the network in Palestine.</li>
  <li>Hamas and Islamic Jihad have condemned the decision, arguing it undermines media freedom.</li>
  <li>The tensions between Al Jazeera and the Palestinian Authority have escalated due to recent coverage of clashes in Jenin.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>The Palestinian Authority's decision aligns with Israeli occupation practices targeting its media teams.</blockquote>
<p>The decision to suspend Al Jazeera's broadcasting underscores ongoing challenges in press freedom and raises concerns about media coverage in conflict zones.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/palestinian-authority-suspends-al-jazeera-broadcasts/article69053358.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/palestinian-authority-suspends-al-jazeera-broadcasts/article69053358.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jeju Air CEO banned from leaving South Korea after fatal crash: police - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jeju Air CEO Banned From Leaving After Fatal Plane Crash</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/rm7tzk/article69053319.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/South_Korea_Plane_Fire_45644.jpg" alt="Jeju Air CEO Kim E-bae speaks in apology" />
<figcaption>Jeju Air CEO Kim E-bae speaks in apology to relatives of passengers at the Muan International Airport in Muan, South Korea.</figcaption>
<p>The chief executive of South Korean airline Jeju Air, Kim E-bae, is facing a travel ban after a crash that killed 179 people last week.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The plane crashed last week, resulting in the death of 179 individuals.</li>
  <li>Police raided the offices of Jeju Air and Muan International Airport as part of the investigation.</li>
  <li>The flight was returning from Thailand with 181 passengers when it issued a mayday call.</li>
  <li>Only two flight attendants survived after being rescued from the wreckage.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The investigation team imposed a travel ban on two individuals, including Jeju Air CEO Kim E-bae," - South Jeolla Province Police</blockquote>
<p>This tragic incident has raised serious concerns regarding airline safety and accountability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/jeju-air-ceo-banned-from-leaving-south-korea-after-fatal-crash-police/article69053290.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/jeju-air-ceo-banned-from-leaving-south-korea-after-fatal-crash-police/article69053290.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kicked Out Of F-35 Program, Turkey Acquires Stealth Jet’s “Development Firm”: Another Massive Boost For Turkish Aviation! - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Turkey Strengthens Aerospace Industry with New Acquisitions and Developments</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 1, 2024 | Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d9/IMG-TAI-TFX.jpg/1200px-IMG-TAI-TFX.jpg" alt="TAI TF Kaan - Wikipedia" width="1200" height="800" />
<figcaption>TAI TF Kaan – Wikipedia</figcaption>
<p>Once banished from the F-35 program and left with a capability gap, Turkey has turned around its destiny by expanding its aerospace industry. From developing fifth-generation fighters to advanced drones, Turkey is now a credible aerospace power.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Turkey significantly reduced its military import reliance, going from 80% in 2004 to less than 20% today.</li>
  <li>The Turkish Aerospace Hürkus-II advanced trainer aircraft had its maiden flight on December 30.</li>
  <li>Baykar acquired the Italian aviation giant Piaggio Aerospace, expanding its reach into European markets.</li>
  <li>Turkey is indigenously developing its own stealth aircraft, known as KAAN, expected to enter service in the early 2030s.</li>
  <li>The upcoming Hurjet trainer is set for production in 2025, after its maiden flight in April 2024.</li>
  <li>Baykar's TB-2 drone has gained fame for its performance in conflicts and has been sold to numerous countries.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The rapid development of Turkey’s defense industries has resulted in many collateral benefits, such as consolidating President Erdoğan’s regime without any fear of military challenge.” - Prakash Nanda</blockquote>
<p>In summary, Turkey is poised to become a key player in aerospace and defense with substantial domestic advancements and international expansions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/turkeys-meteoric-rise-in-aerospace-after-kaan/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/turkeys-meteoric-rise-in-aerospace-after-kaan/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 09:02:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What’s Switzerland’s ‘Anti-Burqa’ Law That Comes Into Effect From January 1? | Explained - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What’s Switzerland’s ‘Anti-Burqa’ Law That Comes Into Effect From January 1? | Explained</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 02, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Switzerland's Lower House of Parliament in 2023 cemented the burqa ban into federal law and set a fine of up to 1,000 francs for violators. (File Photo: AP)" />
<figcaption>Switzerland's Lower House of Parliament in 2023 cemented the burqa ban into federal law and set a fine of up to 1,000 francs for violators. (File Photo: AP)</figcaption>
<p>From January 1, 2025, Switzerland officially bans burqas, hijabs, and any other face coverings in public spaces, as mandated by a law solidified in 2023 after a 2021 referendum where 51.2% of voters supported the ban.</p>
<ul>
<li>The law includes fines of up to 1,000 francs for violators.</li>
<li>Exceptions are made for health-related facial coverings and coverings in places of worship.</li>
<li>The proposal was driven by the right-wing Swiss People's Party, citing concerns over extremism.</li>
<li>The Muslim population in Switzerland is predominantly from Turkey, Bosnia, and Kosovo, making up about 5% of the total population.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Today’s decision opens old wounds, further expands the principle of legal inequality, and sends a clear signal of exclusion to the Muslim minority.” - Central Council of Muslims</blockquote>
<p>This law raises significant discussions on women's rights, identity, and the ongoing debate surrounding secularism and multiculturalism in Switzerland.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/explainers/whats-switzerlands-anti-burqa-law-that-comes-into-effect-from-january-1-explained-9174932.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/explainers/whats-switzerlands-anti-burqa-law-that-comes-into-effect-from-january-1-explained-9174932.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:50:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India pledges $5,00,000 relief aid to Vanuatu following 7.4 magnitude earthquake - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India pledges $500,000 relief aid to Vanuatu following 7.4 magnitude earthquake</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>Unknown</p>
<p>In response to a devastating 7.4 magnitude earthquake that struck Vanuatu, India has committed to providing $500,000 in relief aid to support the affected communities.</p>
<ul>
<li>The earthquake caused significant damage to infrastructure and homes in Vanuatu.</li>
<li>India's aid is part of a broader international response to assist those affected by the disaster.</li>
<li>The funds will be used to facilitate immediate relief efforts and recovery programs.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Our thoughts are with the people of Vanuatu during this challenging time," stated an Indian government spokesperson.</blockquote>
<p>This pledge highlights India's commitment to providing humanitarian assistance in times of disaster and underscores the need for global solidarity in the face of natural disasters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-pledges-500000-relief-aid-to-vanuatu-following-7-4-magnitude-earthquake/articleshow/116877485.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/india-pledges-500000-relief-aid-to-vanuatu-following-7-4-magnitude-earthquake/articleshow/116877485.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israeli airstrike kills at least 10 in southern Gaza, medics say - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-airstrike-kills-least-10-southern-gaza-medics-say-2025-01-02/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-airstrike-kills-least-10-southern-gaza-medics-say-2025-01-02/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Right hand mein phone mat pakdo, GST lagta hai': Man's hilarious prank over fake tax rules goes viral - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A viral prank video plays on confusion surrounding GST, informing people of absurd tax rules, like taxing the way they hold their phones.</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 02, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/Untitled-162_1735804202475_1735804212424.png" alt="Content creator Aryan Kataria pranked people on the street by informing them of bizarre things that could attract GST. (Instagram/katariaaryann)"><figcaption>Content creator Aryan Kataria pranked people on the street by informing them of bizarre things that could attract GST. (Instagram/katariaaryann)</figcaption><p>Days after the finance ministry announced a controversial tax hike on caramel popcorn, a prank video by content creator Aryan Kataria captured the absurdity of rumored GST rules, prompting confusion and laughter among the public.</p><ul><li>The finance ministry increased GST on caramel popcorn from 5% to 18%, sparking a trend on social media known as #PopcornTax.</li><li>Aryan Kataria's video humorously suggests that everyday actions like holding a phone in the right hand could result in tax penalties.</li><li>While many people took Kataria's claims seriously, some questioned the logic behind such bizarre rules.</li><li>The video concluded with Kataria revealing that it was all a prank.</li></ul><blockquote>“Isme GST lagane ka kya matlab hai?” - A confused spectator questioning the absurdity of the prank.</blockquote><p>This prank highlights the public's susceptibility to misunderstanding tax increases and regulations while providing much-needed humor in light of confusing tax policies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/right-hand-mein-phone-mat-pakdo-gst-lagta-hai-mans-hilarious-prank-over-fake-tax-rules-goes-viral-101735803912806.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/right-hand-mein-phone-mat-pakdo-gst-lagta-hai-mans-hilarious-prank-over-fake-tax-rules-goes-viral-101735803912806.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:53:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who was Matthew Livelsberger, ‘suspect’ in Tesla Cybertruck explosion outside Trump hotel in Las Vegas? - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Matthew Livelsberger Identified in Fatal Tesla Cybertruck Explosion in Las Vegas</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Jan 02, 2025</strong></p>
<p><strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/02/550x309/Tesla_cybertruck_1735802270667_1735802271007.JPG" alt="Flames rise from a Tesla Cybertruck after it exploded outside the Trump International Hotel Las Vegas, in Las Vegas, Nevada, U.S., January 1, 2025 in this screengrab taken from a social media video. (Alcides Antunes/Reuters)" />
<figcaption>Flames rise from a Tesla Cybertruck after it exploded outside the Trump International Hotel Las Vegas, in Las Vegas, Nevada, U.S., January 1, 2025 in this screengrab taken from a social media video. (Alcides Antunes/Reuters)</figcaption>
<p>A Tesla Cybertruck exploded in flames outside the Trump International Hotel in Las Vegas on January 1, 2025, resulting in the death of the driver and injuries to seven others.</p>
<ul>
<li>The explosion is under investigation by the FBI as a potential act of terrorism.</li>
<li>Videos of the explosion were widely circulated on social media.</li>
<li>Matthew Livelsberger, identified as the suspect, was reported to have been an Operations Director and former Special Forces Intelligence Manager.</li>
<li>The incident led to the evacuation of the Trump Hotel.</li>
<li>Las Vegas firefighters responded promptly to extinguish the fire.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Obviously a Cybertruck, the Trump hotel - there's lots of questions that we have to answer." - Sheriff Kevin McMahill</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the incident raises concerns and questions regarding the safety and security of high-profile locations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/who-was-matthew-livelsberger-suspect-in-tesla-cybertruck-explosion-outside-trump-hotel-in-las-vegas-101735801911852.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/who-was-matthew-livelsberger-suspect-in-tesla-cybertruck-explosion-outside-trump-hotel-in-las-vegas-101735801911852.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:43:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh rewrites textbooks: 'Ziaur Rahman declared independence, not Sheikh Mujibur Rahman' - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxNeVdlcmpkWk10N3NGN3d6QTVOV0M1aWhmenI3cHZFbWNwckUtN0dnMWR0R1JqaUJ6WVRSN2JDZlFDVFF1MExac08tcGpQbXZObFN6aFZVRElEMDVaUjhFUU1nTjFTLUNiWVc0dnJ1dGN4ejBndlhBWW5SczBkNWJISTBhbVh3T2dNSXhKanBqcXhyNENLVktieTR4UEFsM3loN3Z5VW05eVNmckFiY3NJbGRkUkJsZWI5cFVzbElicDZQU05VOExFUnA4Ulg2U01FcGExLUNHWnpORlkw0gHiAUFVX3lxTFBwSUZLZFdKVF9lcUVVLWhORGtiZjFnNGU1SXRFNi1pZHJXQVZQNk9WQ1ZYMC1ncDBHOTRHVkpUU1FvWnVvXzUtTWR5UmNhNGJGR0FfY2hRaTY4MEZmNmxMS0NrcHNROEoxWnZadDl4NmJqSVdnSzJXcFk3NDh1UEpNMU9IWGNnYUNEYTV3RzBZUXNuYzFHc24tSlhaSzVqMFN4bmU1SzVWZVQxTEZLM051RFRLV05kRWMxUEdGT2pXalBBTkwxTl9INnktc0dhWGZpTklReEV5cW5TYXdQM3VOcXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3AFBVV95cUxNeVdlcmpkWk10N3NGN3d6QTVOV0M1aWhmenI3cHZFbWNwckUtN0dnMWR0R1JqaUJ6WVRSN2JDZlFDVFF1MExac08tcGpQbXZObFN6aFZVRElEMDVaUjhFUU1nTjFTLUNiWVc0dnJ1dGN4ejBndlhBWW5SczBkNWJISTBhbVh3T2dNSXhKanBqcXhyNENLVktieTR4UEFsM3loN3Z5VW05eVNmckFiY3NJbGRkUkJsZWI5cFVzbElicDZQU05VOExFUnA4Ulg2U01FcGExLUNHWnpORlkw0gHiAUFVX3lxTFBwSUZLZFdKVF9lcUVVLWhORGtiZjFnNGU1SXRFNi1pZHJXQVZQNk9WQ1ZYMC1ncDBHOTRHVkpUU1FvWnVvXzUtTWR5UmNhNGJGR0FfY2hRaTY4MEZmNmxMS0NrcHNROEoxWnZadDl4NmJqSVdnSzJXcFk3NDh1UEpNMU9IWGNnYUNEYTV3RzBZUXNuYzFHc24tSlhaSzVqMFN4bmU1SzVWZVQxTEZLM051RFRLV05kRWMxUEdGT2pXalBBTkwxTl9INnktc0dhWGZpTklReEV5cW5TYXdQM3VOcXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:17:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Orleans attack: All about Shamsud-Din Jabbar, the ISIS-inspired US Army veteran behind truck attack... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxPU0gyNGxpamRWaTdWSDVMOTF6Z25EOGpILUdQQkhHRmYxTHZPMEg1bUZ0WkF6Y1dhbklKR0RrTVhMSTBnbHJfTklWYndHcXZyaG5VQjRaYVBvMFBhRm5iZlhvc0FaU1RXWVRMTUxkV1Z4eVI2dXkxZmFFeDB3MTQ0UUtFY3p6Q0pBRmp0cTlQOFpkaHNnemxmcDhSRjZ1NDkteEpiczl6endFOTJDZ3lDb01MbnpJRVI0bGlvVTZVZzlOcjYwckRhNGN3YVZOUTAwU3Y3a01DMGJjS3VOZU1Zc0xscVMxdmxhVHpJSDljVmlRZS1JY0xkb1g5d0NfRVnSAYQCQVVfeXFMTWZXaUtiSXFkYUx2N2VBSFhBcVVzTnBKSUhHNWNXMnNRX0x3TUtQcENQWktHNm5qRzFlenVCd21KbEJmWm53eDQ2WXM1Zl8zUkJJM3ZsMTg3MUdKbk80X1pZR0JocHExSk9mYmFTVng3U3FFdnRoZzhReS1uMWVXTmREZjFLOUdqQ1NwUGh6N1B4SFRZS09TaHdTSWE4YTVobWVEXzR0RHRlcFZvWUpQRExtSlZkZm1ZZmkyYVFRRnZqVV83NzBkZDZ2cW1jLXpaQ0JCbzl2aG00TmdCa09tUlRGdnlLdFpDTFJrZWozNTRjbnNtbXNLT3AyZzNXVXJYNlhpNDA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxPU0gyNGxpamRWaTdWSDVMOTF6Z25EOGpILUdQQkhHRmYxTHZPMEg1bUZ0WkF6Y1dhbklKR0RrTVhMSTBnbHJfTklWYndHcXZyaG5VQjRaYVBvMFBhRm5iZlhvc0FaU1RXWVRMTUxkV1Z4eVI2dXkxZmFFeDB3MTQ0UUtFY3p6Q0pBRmp0cTlQOFpkaHNnemxmcDhSRjZ1NDkteEpiczl6endFOTJDZ3lDb01MbnpJRVI0bGlvVTZVZzlOcjYwckRhNGN3YVZOUTAwU3Y3a01DMGJjS3VOZU1Zc0xscVMxdmxhVHpJSDljVmlRZS1JY0xkb1g5d0NfRVnSAYQCQVVfeXFMTWZXaUtiSXFkYUx2N2VBSFhBcVVzTnBKSUhHNWNXMnNRX0x3TUtQcENQWktHNm5qRzFlenVCd21KbEJmWm53eDQ2WXM1Zl8zUkJJM3ZsMTg3MUdKbk80X1pZR0JocHExSk9mYmFTVng3U3FFdnRoZzhReS1uMWVXTmREZjFLOUdqQ1NwUGh6N1B4SFRZS09TaHdTSWE4YTVobWVEXzR0RHRlcFZvWUpQRExtSlZkZm1ZZmkyYVFRRnZqVV83NzBkZDZ2cW1jLXpaQ0JCbzl2aG00TmdCa09tUlRGdnlLdFpDTFJrZWozNTRjbnNtbXNLT3AyZzNXVXJYNlhpNDA?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:52:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Before New Orleans attack, ISIS-inspired driver in video said ‘he planned to kill own family’ - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxPTm1WN2NwT2RBMktub2RWY05LVVVCemRqcVpxOUs5V2tCM09mQW9wTC1pQXhNSTVQXzg4dGtxM3lWOWdsbmh6VFJBMTE1azVKc2xmMGtqdHd3Mk1kdU56TVJxME54SzduT3ZJcWRvN3UwRWs5MWFiU19zOElxTGUzamljM0tjeU5FWmdHZ3lsOEs1RzJqWkJjNkIxcFJ5dWI0dkxtUURqMV9Lem9JM1MzWEZrZDhiTlg5MHRObVNjMHJoTENEX2JISXRxLVEzbk5IVmFRR2VR0gHaAUFVX3lxTE40RnlDTy1MMFlRNmstOUVsWVpxNUt6dE1uYi1Iel9WNVNFQTJaNUl5VlVQUGViZHpEV0Zzc2Z0cmRhaWk1X2JzM1ZYSlpsdHFNUk9LTWZiZkkzU3lZalJIOFhTWWM5TjVqaWUzZENnOTBkdjNoc2hpY2FWNEMzelhGellGQ05SanlqRE5hcVFCcVM5cWp5VVQ0U19hdXZYdG9nVERhTWFleFBfcDJxZ1BTM0wzWlJrMExORklCX1c3NWd4YUZMZGFhLUQ2ZnV4eEx2VkVQX2puR05B?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1gFBVV95cUxPTm1WN2NwT2RBMktub2RWY05LVVVCemRqcVpxOUs5V2tCM09mQW9wTC1pQXhNSTVQXzg4dGtxM3lWOWdsbmh6VFJBMTE1azVKc2xmMGtqdHd3Mk1kdU56TVJxME54SzduT3ZJcWRvN3UwRWs5MWFiU19zOElxTGUzamljM0tjeU5FWmdHZ3lsOEs1RzJqWkJjNkIxcFJ5dWI0dkxtUURqMV9Lem9JM1MzWEZrZDhiTlg5MHRObVNjMHJoTENEX2JISXRxLVEzbk5IVmFRR2VR0gHaAUFVX3lxTE40RnlDTy1MMFlRNmstOUVsWVpxNUt6dE1uYi1Iel9WNVNFQTJaNUl5VlVQUGViZHpEV0Zzc2Z0cmRhaWk1X2JzM1ZYSlpsdHFNUk9LTWZiZkkzU3lZalJIOFhTWWM5TjVqaWUzZENnOTBkdjNoc2hpY2FWNEMzelhGellGQ05SanlqRE5hcVFCcVM5cWp5VVQ0U19hdXZYdG9nVERhTWFleFBfcDJxZ1BTM0wzWlJrMExORklCX1c3NWd4YUZMZGFhLUQ2ZnV4eEx2VkVQX2puR05B?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:18:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govt disallows double pension on IMF, World Bank demand - Geo News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Government Bans Double Pension Following IMF and World Bank Requirements</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> The News</p><figure><img src="https://www.geo.tv/assets/uploads/updates/2025-01-02/582959_7218323_updates.jpg" alt="A woman in a face mask counts rupee notes as she walks on a street in Islamabad on April 9, 2020. — AFP" width="700" height="400"><figcaption>A woman in a face mask counts rupee notes as she walks on a street in Islamabad on April 9, 2020. — AFP</figcaption></figure><p>The Pakistani government has imposed a ban on double pensions in response to pressures from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank, necessitating significant reforms within the pension system.</p><ul><li>Pension reforms are essential due to increasing financial obligations.</li><li>The total pension liabilities of the federal government and provinces are estimated between Rs40 trillion and Rs45 trillion.</li><li>Pensions will now be calculated based on the last 24 months of salary before retirement.</li></ul><blockquote>“Pension reforms were necessary as the future obligations were mounting just like on the pattern of escalating debt burden.”</blockquote><p>The new regulations specify that individuals entitled to more than one pension can only choose one to draw. This decision reflects the government's commitment to addressing the rising pension liabilities effectively.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.geo.tv/latest/582959-govt-disallows-double-pension-on-imf-world-bank-demand</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.geo.tv/latest/582959-govt-disallows-double-pension-on-imf-world-bank-demand</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 06:06:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taiwan reports first Chinese 'combat patrol' of the New Year - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-reports-first-chinese-combat-patrol-new-year-2025-01-02/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/taiwan-reports-first-chinese-combat-patrol-new-year-2025-01-02/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New York: At least 11 shot at in night club in Queens - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>At least 11 injured in shooting at nightclub in Queens, New York</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC TV18</p><img src="https://images.cnbctv18.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/default.jpg?impolicy=website&width=640&height=360" alt="New York: At least 11 shot at in night club in Queens" title="New York: At least 11 shot at in night club in Queens" loading="lazy"/><figcaption>At least 11 people have been shot in Queens, NY at Amazura Night Club.</figcaption><p>A shooting incident occurred at the Amazura event hall in Jamaica, Queens, injuring at least 11 people. The New York Police Department is yet to provide details on the conditions of the injured.</p><ul><li>Gunfire erupted near Amazura event hall around 11:20 PM on January 1.</li><li>The incident is being characterized as an active situation.</li><li>Details from the New York Police Department are pending.</li></ul><blockquote>“#BREAKING: MASS SHOOTING IN NEW YORK CITY. At least 11 people have been shot in Queens, NY at Amazura Night Club. This is still an ACTIVE situation.” — Nick Sortor (@nicksortor, January 2, 2025)</blockquote><p>The incident follows a tragic attack earlier where a driver killed 15 people in New Orleans, raising concerns about ongoing violence.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/us-attack-new-york-at-least-11-shot-at-in-night-club-in-queens-new-orleans-19533235.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/us-attack-new-york-at-least-11-shot-at-in-night-club-in-queens-new-orleans-19533235.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:31:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New York mass shooting: At least 11 shot as gunman fires outside Amazura Night Club in Queens, say reports | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>At least 11 shot outside Amazura Night Club in Queens</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> New York Post</p><p>The incident occurred just before 11:20 pm near the Amazura nightclub in Jamaica, New York. At least 11 individuals were shot but are expected to survive, according to the NYPD.</p><ul><li>The shooting took place outside the Amazura nightclub.</li><li>Victims were transported to nearby hospitals, including Long Island Jewish Hospital.</li><li>None of the victims are in critical condition.</li><li>Footage of the scene shows a significant police and ambulance presence.</li></ul><blockquote>“All are expected to survive.” — NYPD</blockquote><p>This incident comes on the heels of a deadly attack in New Orleans that left 15 dead.</p><p>The Amazura nightclub is known for its vibrant atmosphere, featuring dancing, DJs, and live performances.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/new-york-mass-shooting-at-least-11-dead-as-gunman-shoots-inside-amazura-night-club-in-queens-say-reports-11735795383312.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/new-york-mass-shooting-at-least-11-dead-as-gunman-shoots-inside-amazura-night-club-in-queens-say-reports-11735795383312.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:28:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New York mass shooting: At least 11 shot as gunman fires inside Amazura Night Club in Queens, say reports | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>New York Mass Shooting Leaves 11 Injured Outside Amazura Night Club</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> New York Post</p><img src='path_to_image.jpg' alt='Police presence outside Amazura Night Club'><figcaption>Police and ambulance presence outside the nightclub after the shooting.</figcaption><p>At least 11 people were shot outside a nightclub in Queens, NY. While all victims are expected to survive, the city grapples with the aftermath of another mass shooting.</p><ul><li>Incident occurred near Amazura nightclub just before 11:20 PM.</li><li>Victims taken to local hospitals, none in critical condition.</li><li>Prior mass shooting in New Orleans claimed 15 lives.</li></ul><blockquote>“All are expected to survive,” - NYPD</blockquote><p>This incident raises concerns about public safety with the rising trend of mass shootings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/new-york-mass-shooting-at-least-11-dead-as-gunman-shoots-inside-amazura-night-club-in-queens-say-reports-11735795383312.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/new-york-mass-shooting-at-least-11-dead-as-gunman-shoots-inside-amazura-night-club-in-queens-say-reports-11735795383312.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 05:28:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>