<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 03:20:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 03:20:19 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Live by the spam, die by the spam': Elon Musk claps back at MAGA censorship claims on X amid H-1B visa r - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Live by the spam, die by the spam': Elon Musk claps back at MAGA censorship claims on X amid H-1B visa rift</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 25, 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Elon Musk"/><figcaption>Elon Musk responds to criticisms regarding censorship.</figcaption><p>Elon Musk has responded to claims of censorship involving MAGA supporters while addressing the ongoing rift concerning H-1B visa policies.</p><ul><li>Musk defended his platform X against accusations of bias.</li><li>He made a quip about the adversities of social media censorship.</li><li>The H-1B visa debate has been reignited amid changing political landscapes.</li></ul><blockquote>“Live by the spam, die by the spam.” - Elon Musk</blockquote><p>The situation reflects the ongoing tensions between free speech and regulatory practices in digital spaces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/live-by-the-spam-die-by-the-spam-elon-musk-claps-back-at-maga-laura-loomer-censorship-on-x-claims-amid-h-1b-visa-rift/articleshow/116728219.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/live-by-the-spam-die-by-the-spam-elon-musk-claps-back-at-maga-laura-loomer-censorship-on-x-claims-amid-h-1b-visa-rift/articleshow/116728219.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Ego kha gya': Rishabh Pant slammed for 'gift-wrapping' his wicket to Australia - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Ego kha gya': Rishabh Pant slammed for 'gift-wrapping' his wicket to Australia</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> NEW DELHI</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-116728342,imgsize-68046,width-400,resizemode-4/116728342.jpg' alt='Rishabh Pant (Image credit: X)' title='Rishabh Pant (Image credit: X)' decoding='async' fetchpriority='high'><figcaption>Rishabh Pant (Image credit: X)</figcaption><p>Rishabh Pant faced criticism after a poor decision led to his dismissal during a crucial moment in the fourth Test against Australia. Initially looking strong, Pant's reckless shot selection proved costly for India.</p><ul><li>Pant attempted a risky lap shot over fine leg after facing discomfort from the ball hitting him on the stomach.</li><li>On the subsequent delivery, he again played a premeditated shot, resulting in a catch by Nathan Lyon.</li><li>The dismissal was heavily critiqued, with comments highlighting his reckless approach and reference to ego.</li><li>The series is currently tied at 1-1, with both teams showing strong performances thus far.</li></ul><blockquote>“What a crap shot by Rishabh Pant. Ego pe baat aa gayi thi and ego kha gya. Terrible way to get out, and Pant is flop in this series so far,”</blockquote><blockquote>“Rishabh Pant playing that pre-meditated ramp shot to a ball pitched outside offstump to get out. Looks Indian batsmen have given this up,”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Rishabh Pant's performance in this series has come under scrutiny, and his recent dismissal is seen as a pivotal moment affecting India's chances in the ongoing match.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rishabh-pant-slammed-for-gift-wrapping-his-wicket-to-australia-mcg-test-ind-vs-aus/articleshow/116728335.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/india-in-australia/rishabh-pant-slammed-for-gift-wrapping-his-wicket-to-australia-mcg-test-ind-vs-aus/articleshow/116728335.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk explains the right position on H-1B: 'I have no respect for...' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk explains the right position on H-1B: 'I have no respect for...'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Tech News</p><p>In a recent statement, Elon Musk shared his controversial views on the H-1B visa program, expressing his dissatisfaction and highlighting the flaws he perceives within the current system.</p><ul><li>Musk believes the H-1B program is flawed and not benefiting the American workforce.</li><li>He questioned the intentions behind the use of H-1B visas, arguing it leads to exploitation.</li><li>The tech entrepreneur suggests that reforms are urgently needed to ensure the program serves its intended purpose.</li></ul><blockquote>“I have no respect for the way H-1B visas are currently managed.”</blockquote><p>This statement from Musk has sparked widespread debate about immigration policies and the tech industry's reliance on foreign talent.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-explains-the-right-position-on-h-1b-i-have-no-respect-for-/articleshow/116724855.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-explains-the-right-position-on-h-1b-i-have-no-respect-for-/articleshow/116724855.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBI ‘Found Covid Was Leaked From China Lab’ But Joe Biden Was Kept In Dark: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FBI Found Covid Was Leaked From China Lab But Joe Biden Was Kept In Dark: Report</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="US President Joe Biden | Reuters Image"><figcaption>US President Joe Biden | Reuters Image</figcaption><p>The article discusses a report alleging that the FBI suppressed findings that supported the theory of Covid-19 leaking from a Chinese lab. Intelligence officials excluded these findings from a report given to President Joe Biden, leading to concerns about transparency and the handling of evidence.</p><ul><li>The FBI reportedly silenced US defense officials and researchers regarding the Covid lab leak theory.</li><li>Findings were omitted from an August 2021 report that claimed the virus was “probably not genetically engineered.”</li><li>Whistleblower Lt. Col. Joseph Murphy revealed improper classification of federal grant documents.</li><li>FBI scientist Jason Bannan criticized the lack of transparency in handling the evidence.</li><li>China claimed in a joint report with WHO that the virus likely passed from bats to humans via another animal.</li></ul><blockquote>“What ended up on the cutting-room floor needs to be re-examined.” - Jason Bannan, FBI scientist</blockquote><p>This report raises serious questions about the origins of Covid-19 and the implications of the findings that were reportedly silenced, highlighting the need for transparency in the investigation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/fbi-found-covid-was-leaked-from-china-lab-but-joe-biden-was-kept-in-dark-report-9169573.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/fbi-found-covid-was-leaked-from-china-lab-but-joe-biden-was-kept-in-dark-report-9169573.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 19:01:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Indian Sikh family charged with masquerading as Afghans to claim asylum in Britain’ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian Sikh Family Charged with Masquerading as Afghans to Claim Asylum in Britain</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>An Indian Sikh family has been charged in Britain for allegedly pretending to be Afghan asylum seekers to gain entry into the country. This case raises questions about asylum policies and immigration practices.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The family is accused of falsifying documents to obtain asylum.</li>
  <li>The case has attracted significant media attention and public debate.</li>
  <li>Authorities are investigating the broader implications for asylum seekers in the UK.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This incident highlights ongoing challenges in our immigration system," stated an immigration expert.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this case underscores the complexities of immigration and asylum applications, and it is likely to prompt policy reviews.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/indian-sikh-family-charged-with-masquerading-as-afghans-to-claim-asylum-in-britain/articleshow/116723144.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/indian-sikh-family-charged-with-masquerading-as-afghans-to-claim-asylum-in-britain/articleshow/116723144.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy's 6-word reply as MAGA calls him con man, asks how he made so much money - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vivek Ramaswamy's 6-word reply as MAGA calls him con man, asks how he made so much money</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="" /><figcaption>Vivek Ramaswamy at a rally</figcaption><p>In a recent event, Vivek Ramaswamy faced criticism from MAGA supporters who labeled him a "con man" and questioned his financial success. His response was concise, leading to various reactions.</p><ul><li>Ramaswamy's critique was aimed at the recent backlash regarding his wealth.</li><li>The backlash highlights the division within MAGA supporters towards outsiders.</li><li>Ramaswamy's reply has since generated mixed responses online.</li><li>Questions around campaign finances are increasingly coming to light.</li></ul><blockquote>"You can mock me all you want, but my success is real."</blockquote><p>This incident has further fueled the conversation regarding the future of the MAGA movement and the role of candidates like Ramaswamy within it.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/vivek-ramaswamys-6-word-reply-as-maga-calls-him-con-man-asks-how-he-made-so-much-money/articleshow/116721882.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/vivek-ramaswamys-6-word-reply-as-maga-calls-him-con-man-asks-how-he-made-so-much-money/articleshow/116721882.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IDF launches new raid on north Gaza hospital, asserting Hamas operatives returned - The Times of Israel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesofisrael.com/idf-launches-new-raid-on-north-gaza-hospital-asserting-hamas-operatives-returned/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesofisrael.com/idf-launches-new-raid-on-north-gaza-hospital-asserting-hamas-operatives-returned/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:58:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Challenging Russia’s “Shadow Fleet” — NATO To Boost Presence In Baltic Sea After Suspected Cable Sabotage - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NATO Increases Military Presence in Baltic Sea Amid Cable Sabotage Concerns</h1><p><strong>Date: December 27, 2023 | Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p><figure><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Gfvuoh1WgAAkpqQ?format=jpg&amp;name=small" alt="Image" width="679" height="371"><figcaption>Online tracking data revealing the route of the tanker “Eagle S.”</figcaption></figure><p>NATO has pledged to bolster its military presence in the Baltic Sea following the suspected sabotage of the Estlink 2 undersea power cable connecting Finland and Estonia.</p><ul><li>NATO chief Mark Rutte announced NATO's commitment after a meeting with Finnish President Alexander Stubb.</li><li>The Estlink 2 cable was severed on Christmas Day, raising alarms about the security of critical undersea infrastructure.</li><li>Rutte expressed solidarity on social media, stating, “NATO will enhance its military presence in the Baltic Sea.”</li><li>Officials consider the cable damage a case of “grave sabotage” linked to the Russian tanker Eagle S.</li><li>Estonian Defence Minister announced increased naval patrols to protect undersea infrastructure.</li><li>The EU is considering additional sanctions against Russia's shadow fleet in response to these incidents.</li></ul><blockquote>“The shadow fleet pumps money into Russia’s war fund so that Russia can continue to wage its war in Ukraine.” - Finnish Prime Minister Petteri Orpo</blockquote><p>The recent incidents have drawn attention to the vulnerabilities in the Baltic region’s energy networks and have prompted increased response measures from NATO and the EU.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/edited-nato-to-bolster-baltic-sea-presence/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/edited-nato-to-bolster-baltic-sea-presence/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:53:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pizza Delivery Boy Stabs Woman 14 Times Over Rs 170 Tip. Victim Later Finds Out She's Pregnant - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/pizza-delivery-boy-stabs-woman-14-times-over-rs-170-tip-victim-later-finds-out-shes-pregnant-9169712.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/pizza-delivery-boy-stabs-woman-14-times-over-rs-170-tip-victim-later-finds-out-shes-pregnant-9169712.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:31:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Did Russian air defence down the Azerbaijani plane in Kazakhstan? - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/27/did-russian-air-defence-down-the-azerbaijani-plane-in-kazakhstan</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/27/did-russian-air-defence-down-the-azerbaijani-plane-in-kazakhstan</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:25:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin Predicts Russia Will Win Ukraine War In 2025: 'God Is With Us' - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Vladimir Putin Predicts Russia Will Win Ukraine War In 2025: 'God Is With Us'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Russia-Ukraine War: Russian President Vladimir Putin is seen.(AP Photo)" /><figcaption>Russia-Ukraine War: Russian President Vladimir Putin is seen.(AP Photo)</figcaption><p>In a statement made at the Supreme Eurasian Economic Council meeting, President Vladimir Putin expressed confidence that Russia would achieve victory in the ongoing conflict with Ukraine by 2025, emphasizing that divine support is on their side.</p><ul><li>Putin stated, “I believe in God. And God is with us.”</li><li>He rejected a US proposal to freeze the conflict, recalling that a similar deal was previously deemed unacceptable by Moscow.</li><li>Moscow aims to successfully conclude the Ukraine war while addressing economic and social issues.</li><li>Putin showed openness to Slovakian-led peace talks to potentially resolve the conflict.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are striving to end the conflict. We believe that we will be successful on the front line.”</blockquote><p>Putin's assertions highlight the ongoing tensions in the region and the geopolitical complexities surrounding the Ukraine conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/vladimir-putin-predicts-russia-will-win-ukraine-war-in-2025-god-is-with-us-9169640.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/vladimir-putin-predicts-russia-will-win-ukraine-war-in-2025-god-is-with-us-9169640.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:56:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy-critic Ann Coulter says H-1B workers are indentured servants, not highly skilled - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Ann Coulter Claims H-1B Workers are Indentured Servants</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 15, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a controversial statement, Ann Coulter criticized the H-1B visa program, labeling its workers as 'indentured servants' rather than highly skilled professionals, sparking debate over immigration policies.</p><ul><li>Coulter argues that H-1B workers are exploited and compared to indentured servitude.</li><li>The statement raises questions about the skill level of workers under the H-1B program.</li><li>Critics of Coulter's views cite the contributions of H-1B workers to the economy and innovation.</li></ul><blockquote>"We have turned our immigration policy into a means of importing cheap labor instead of talented individuals," said Coulter.</blockquote><p>This statement by Coulter has reignited discussions on the reform of immigration policies in the U.S., focusing on the value and treatment of foreign workers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/vivek-ramaswamy-critic-ann-coulter-says-h-1b-workers-are-indentured-servants-not-highly-skilled/articleshow/116719660.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/vivek-ramaswamy-critic-ann-coulter-says-h-1b-workers-are-indentured-servants-not-highly-skilled/articleshow/116719660.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Physical, technical external interference': Azerbaijan Airlines on plane crash - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/physical-technical-external-interference-azerbaijan-airlines-on-plane-crash-101735309948138.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/physical-technical-external-interference-azerbaijan-airlines-on-plane-crash-101735309948138.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:17:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[F-16 Crash Or Shot Down? Russian Billionaire Offers 15M For Downed Fighting Falcon; Ukraine Mum - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russian Billionaire Offers $150,000 For Downed Ukrainian F-16</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: Not provided</strong> | <strong>Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/F-16.jpg" alt="" width="1296" height="873"><figcaption>Ukrainian Air Force F-16s armed with two AIM-120 AMRAAM and two AIM-9 Sidewinder air-to-air missiles. Ukrainian Air Force</figcaption><p>A Russian billionaire is offering a reward for downing the first F-16 Fighting Falcon belonging to Ukraine, amid claims of an F-16 shootdown in the Zaporizhia region.</p><ul><li>A reward of 15 million rubles (about $150,000) is offered by Sergey Shmotyev for downing the first F-16.</li><li>Russia claimed an F-16 was shot down while it was preparing to launch a missile strike, but there is no official confirmation from Kyiv or Washington.</li><li>The F-16 is seen as crucial for Ukraine’s air defense against Russian attacks.</li><li>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy highlighted the importance of F-16s in strengthening defenses.</li><li>Ukraine has received a second batch of F-16s from Denmark, boosting its air capabilities.</li></ul><blockquote>“The F-16 aircraft was in position to launch a missile strike on the region, and it was shot down.” - Vladimir Rogov, Chairman of the Commission on Sovereignty</blockquote><p>The offer from Shmotyev reflects ongoing tensions as Ukraine strengthens its air force in response to Russian military actions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/russian-billionaire-offers-15-million-rubles/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/russian-billionaire-offers-15-million-rubles/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 15:06:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Driver who killed 35 in China car ramming sentenced to death - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Man Sentenced to Death for China Car Ramming Attack that Killed 35</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: Today, Source: State Media</strong></p><img src="https://example.com/image_url" alt="Fan Weiqiu" width="300" height="200"><figcaption>Fan Weiqiu, the convicted driver</figcaption><p>A man who deliberately drove through a crowd of people exercising outside a sports complex in Zhuhai, China, killing 35, has been sentenced to death. The 62-year-old, Fan Weiqiu, was found guilty of venting his anger over a broken marriage and personal frustrations. The attack, which occurred on November 11, was the deadliest in China since 2014.</p><ol><li>The defendant was tried and sentenced on the same day, with the court citing the extreme nature of the crime and its severe consequences.</li><li>Fan pleaded guilty in front of victims' families, officials, and members of the public.</li><li>The attack has sparked anger and discussion online, with some calling for immediate execution.</li></ol><blockquote>Fan decided to vent his anger over a broken marriage and personal frustrations, leading to the deadly attack.</blockquote><p>The sentencing comes amid a string of mass casualty incidents in China this year, challenging the country's reputation for good public security.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1881454/driver-who-killed-35-in-china-car-ramming-sentenced-to-death</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1881454/driver-who-killed-35-in-china-car-ramming-sentenced-to-death</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:53:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pak army accuses India of 25 LoC violations in 2024 - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan Army Accuses India of 25 LoC Violations in 2024</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> [Date not provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source not provided]</p><p>The Pakistan Army has accused India of committing 25 violations of the Line of Control (LoC) over the past year, threatening a swift response in case of further attacks.</p><ul><li>The accusations were made by Lt Gen Ahmad Sharif Chaudhry during a year-end press conference.</li><li>The Pakistani security forces reportedly killed 925 terrorists in 2024, losing 383 personnel during nearly 60,000 operations.</li><li>The spokesman claimed Indian forces engaged in 'false flag operations.'</li><li>Chaudhry highlighted the importance of addressing incursions by the banned Tehreek-i-Taliban Pakistan (TTP) from Afghan territory.</li><li>A significant operation has led to the expulsion of over 815,000 illegal Afghan nationals since September 2023.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Pakistan Army possesses the capability to deliver a decisive response to any Indian hostility,” Lt Gen Ahmad Sharif Chaudhry stated.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the ongoing tensions along the LoC and the accusations are reflective of the broader geopolitical and security challenges faced by both nations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/defence/pak-army-accuses-india-of-25-loc-violations-in-2024/articleshow/116718922.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/defence/pak-army-accuses-india-of-25-loc-violations-in-2024/articleshow/116718922.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:40:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier dissolves parliament, calls early election for February 23 after - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier dissolves parliament, calls early election for February 23 after Scholz's coalition falls apart</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> <em>Not provided</em></p><p><strong>Source:</strong> <em>Not provided</em></p><p>An abrupt political shift in Germany has occurred as President Frank-Walter Steinmeier dissolves parliament, prompting early elections set for February 23. This decision follows the collapse of Chancellor Olaf Scholz's coalition government.</p><ul><li>President Steinmeier's decision came after internal disagreements led to the disintegration of the ruling coalition.</li><li>The German public now faces an unexpected early election, providing an opportunity for reevaluation of political alliances.</li><li>This event marks a significant moment in German politics, impacting future governance and policy direction.</li></ul><blockquote>“The stability of our government is paramount for the future of Germany.” - President Frank-Walter Steinmeier</blockquote><p>This early election underscores the volatility in German politics and the necessity for a stable governing coalition moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/german-president-dissolves-parliament-calls-early-election-for-february-23/articleshow/116711830.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/german-president-dissolves-parliament-calls-early-election-for-february-23/articleshow/116711830.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 14:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk flags ‘dire’ tech shortage amid US H-1B visa debate, bats for increased immigration: ‘For your team to win…’ | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk flags ‘dire’ tech shortage amid US H-1B visa debate, bats for increased immigration: ‘For your team to win…’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>Billionaire businessman Elon Musk has sparked controversy by advocating for increased immigration to address a tech talent shortage in the U.S. This comes during heightened discussions about H-1B visa reforms.</p><ul><li>Musk claims there is a lack of highly skilled engineers in the U.S., comparing the need for top talent to that of a pro sports team.</li><li>He described the shortage of engineering talent as a 'fundamental limiting factor' for Silicon Valley.</li><li>His remarks align with those of Republican leader Vivek Ramaswamy, who advocates for merit-based immigration.</li><li>Reforms could benefit countries like India, facilitating quicker visa processing and permanent residency for skilled workers.</li></ul><blockquote>“The number of people who are super talented engineers AND super motivated in the USA is far too low. Think of this like a pro sports team: if you want your TEAM to win the championship, you need to recruit top talent wherever they may be.” - Elon Musk</blockquote><p>This call for action highlights the ongoing debate about immigration and its impact on the tech industry in the U.S.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/elon-musk-flags-dire-tech-shortage-amid-us-h-1b-visa-debate-bats-for-increased-immigration-for-your-team-to-win-11735302431817.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/people/elon-musk-flags-dire-tech-shortage-amid-us-h-1b-visa-debate-bats-for-increased-immigration-for-your-team-to-win-11735302431817.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:53:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Physical, technical external interference': Azerbaijan Airlines after preliminary investigation into pla - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Physical, technical external interference: Azerbaijan Airlines after preliminary investigation into plane crash</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>This article discusses the preliminary findings of the investigation into the recent plane crash involving Azerbaijan Airlines, highlighting potential physical and technical interference.</p><ul><li>The preliminary investigation identified signs of external interference.</li><li>Azerbaijan Airlines is cooperating with authorities for a thorough inquiry.</li><li>Safety measures are being reevaluated in light of the findings.</li></ul><blockquote>“We aim to ensure the highest level of safety for our passengers,” stated a representative from Azerbaijan Airlines.</blockquote><p>The investigation is ongoing, and further details will follow as they become available.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/physical-technical-external-interference-azerbaijan-airlines-after-preliminary-investigation-into-plane-crash/articleshow/116717588.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/physical-technical-external-interference-azerbaijan-airlines-after-preliminary-investigation-into-plane-crash/articleshow/116717588.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 13:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Ukrainian military was carrying out terrorist attacks when Azerbaijani flight tried to land': Russia cla - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia Accuses Ukrainian Military of Terrorism During Azerbaijani Flight Incident</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Russia has claimed that the Ukrainian military was conducting terrorist attacks at the time an Azerbaijani flight attempted to land, escalating tensions between the nations.</p><ul><li>The incident allegedly occurred during the approach of the flight.</li><li>Russia's statement reflects ongoing conflicts and accusations in the region.</li><li>The situation adds to the broader geopolitical tensions involving Ukraine and Azerbaijan.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ukrainian military was carrying out terrorist attacks when Azerbaijani flight tried to land.”</blockquote><p>This claim from Russia could exacerbate existing conflicts and further strain relations in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/ukrainian-military-was-carrying-out-terrorist-attacks-when-azerbaijani-flight-tried-to-land-russia-claims/articleshow/116715822.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/ukrainian-military-was-carrying-out-terrorist-attacks-when-azerbaijani-flight-tried-to-land-russia-claims/articleshow/116715822.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["External Interference" Caused Plane Crash In Kazakhstan: Azerbaijan Airlines - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kazakhstan Plane Crash Linked to External Interference, Says Azerbaijan Airlines</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p><p>Azerbaijan Airlines stated that "external physical and technical interference" was responsible for a tragic plane crash in Kazakhstan that resulted in 38 fatalities out of 67 passengers.</p><ul><li>The Embraer 190 aircraft diverted and crashed in Aktau, Kazakhstan, after being denied landing in Grozny due to fog.</li><li>There are reports suggesting a possible accidental missile strike from Russian air defenses.</li><li>An investigation is ongoing, with evidence of missile damage noted by experts.</li><li>A passenger reported a loud bang before the aircraft began to behave erratically.</li><li>Azerbaijan Airlines announced the suspension of flights to multiple Russian airports for safety reasons.</li></ul><blockquote>“I thought the plane was going to fall apart,” - Subhonkul Rakhimov, passenger.</blockquote><p>The situation around the crash emphasizes the ongoing tensions involving air travel and defense systems in politically sensitive regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/external-interference-caused-plane-crash-in-kazakhstan-azerbaijan-airlines-7344416</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/external-interference-caused-plane-crash-in-kazakhstan-azerbaijan-airlines-7344416</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:24:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How NRIs in the US became the ‘new Jews’ in the immigration debate - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How NRIs in the US became the ‘new Jews’ in the immigration debate</h1>
<p><strong>Updated: Dec 27, 2024</strong> <strong>Source: TIMESOFINDIA.COM</strong></p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/width-800,height-450,imgsize-730291,msid-116715057/116715057.jpg" alt="Indian-Americans in the immigration debate">
<figcaption>Image depicting the influential Indian-American community.</figcaption>
<p>Indian-Americans, often regarded as a ‘model minority’, are now facing rising hostility from MAGA hardliners. With key figures supporting skilled immigration, questions arise about how India can navigate the backlash and safeguard its diaspora's future.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Indian-American community is among the most successful ethnic minorities in the US.</li>
<li>The annual median household income for Indian-Americans was approximately $145,000 in 2022, nearly double the national median.</li>
<li>Jagdish Bhagwati likened Indians in America to Jews, highlighting their success across various fields.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Indians are the new Jews in America.” - Jagdish Bhagwati</blockquote>
<p>This situation brings forth challenges and opportunities for the Indian diaspora in America amidst the changing political landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/toi-plus/international/how-nris-in-the-us-became-the-new-jews-in-the-immigration-debate/articleshow/116715022.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/toi-plus/international/how-nris-in-the-us-became-the-new-jews-in-the-immigration-debate/articleshow/116715022.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 12:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Akin To B-21 Raider’s Broad-Spectrum Stealth, China’s New 6th-Gen Stealth Fighters Bound To Rattle U.S. Military - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Unveils New 6th-Generation Stealth Fighters</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Eurasian Times</p><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/China-sixth-generation-1.jpg" alt="China’s 6th-Gen Aircraft" width="696" height="392"><figcaption>File Image: China’s 6th-Gen Aircraft</figcaption><p>China has recently unveiled two new stealth fighter prototypes, featuring broad-spectrum stealth technology that enhances their ability to evade radar detection across various frequencies.</p><ul><li>Broad-spectrum stealth minimizes detectability to both high and low-frequency radars.</li><li>This technology was previously seen only in strategic bombers, marking a significant leap for fighter jets.</li><li>The introduction of these fighters positions China ahead in global stealth capabilities.</li><li>The larger fighter, possibly the J-36, has enhanced payload capacity and stealth features.</li><li>The smaller fighter, likely from SAC, is designed for agility and air superiority roles.</li><li>Capabilities of the new fighters may include optional manning and next-generation power plants.</li></ul><blockquote>“China’s rapid advancement in military aviation technology is unquestionable.”</blockquote><p>The prototypes reveal China's significant progress in military technology but actual capabilities will be assessed as they develop further.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/akin-to-b-21-raiders-broad-spectrum-stealth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/akin-to-b-21-raiders-broad-spectrum-stealth/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:40:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MAGA crowd demands no H-1B visas for Indians, Vivek Ramaswamy says American parents raising their kids wrong - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MAGA supporters call for H-1B visa freeze as Vivek Ramaswamy blames American parenting for STEM shortfall</h1><p><strong>Published On: </strong>Dec 27, 2024 | <strong>Published By: </strong>Nandini Yadav</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/vivek-ramaswamy-113223538-16x9.jpg?VersionId=Y_5jp5SEGmmNeScboJkmGTDqzvcQvq1D&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Vivek Ramaswamy, 2024 US presidential candidate" title="Vivek Ramaswamy, 2024 US presidential candidate" height="388"><figcaption>Vivek Ramaswamy, 2024 US presidential candidate</figcaption><p>The debate over H-1B visas has reignited as Trump supporters demand a halt to hiring foreign skilled workers. Vivek Ramaswamy argues the real issue lies in American culture and parenting.</p><ul><li>Trump supporters are pushing for a complete freeze on H-1B visas for skilled workers.</li><li>Vivek Ramaswamy attributes the STEM workforce shortfall to American parenting practices.</li><li>He contrasts the cultural values of immigrant families with those of mainstream American culture.</li><li>Critics accuse Ramaswamy of undermining American workers' concerns.</li><li>The H-1B visa debate highlights tensions between low-cost foreign labor and domestic job security.</li></ul><blockquote>The reason top tech companies often hire foreign-born & first-generation engineers over “native” Americans isn’t because of an innate American IQ deficit... — Vivek Ramaswamy</blockquote><p>Ramaswamy's comments have sparked significant backlash, highlighting the cultural divide in America's approach to education and success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/maga-crowd-demands-no-h-1b-visas-for-indians-vivek-ramaswamy-says-american-parents-raising-their-kids-wrong-2656273-2024-12-27</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/maga-crowd-demands-no-h-1b-visas-for-indians-vivek-ramaswamy-says-american-parents-raising-their-kids-wrong-2656273-2024-12-27</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 11:03:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German President dissolves parliament, calls early election for February 23 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>German President dissolves parliament, calls early election for February 23</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 23, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> News Network</p><p>The German President has taken the historic step of dissolving the parliament, prompting early elections to be scheduled for February 23, 2024. This decision follows a period of political unrest and is expected to reshape the current government.</p><ul><li>The parliament's dissolution is seen as a reaction to political instability.</li><li>Early elections aim to restore confidence in the political system.</li><li>Key political parties are preparing their campaign strategies for the upcoming elections.</li></ul><blockquote>"This decision reflects the need for a renewed mandate from the public." - German President</blockquote><p>The dissolution of parliament signals a critical moment in German politics, highlighting the challenges faced by the current administration and the call for a renewed democratic process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/german-president-dissolves-parliament-calls-early-election-for-february-23/articleshow/116711830.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/german-president-dissolves-parliament-calls-early-election-for-february-23/articleshow/116711830.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[European gas prices surge on Putin's comments - Investing.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxQSlBTbWNndEdCS0M2eG9BN01vTk1jc0gwQWoyaUVCSUNFRnBaZXNRb1lENEJJbEl3d25Wck5WUWRRQ1p0bUZRWVVWOU82TXhfemJwbkpMa1FOaWFRbmU5TWp0S3pIRFJaUnhsSnVYbzFDM0RXWkpVQXpDMEh0Q09VeXVwMDkzVi02U2oxblZPT1pNOHJqU0xndXZUMENTWUxrd3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiogFBVV95cUxQSlBTbWNndEdCS0M2eG9BN01vTk1jc0gwQWoyaUVCSUNFRnBaZXNRb1lENEJJbEl3d25Wck5WUWRRQ1p0bUZRWVVWOU82TXhfemJwbkpMa1FOaWFRbmU5TWp0S3pIRFJaUnhsSnVYbzFDM0RXWkpVQXpDMEh0Q09VeXVwMDkzVi02U2oxblZPT1pNOHJqU0xndXZUMENTWUxrd3c?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 10:31:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Banned outfits provided with sanctuaries, support on Afghan territory: ISPR - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Banned outfits provided with sanctuaries, support on Afghan territory: ISPR</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> September 30, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Dawn</p>
<p>Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) Director General Lieutenant General Ahmed Sharif Chaudhry highlighted the ongoing support and activities of terrorist outfits in Afghanistan, expressing concerns over increased security threats in Pakistan.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Record-high number of terrorists killed in 2024, highest in 5 years.</li>
  <li>Pakistan expresses reservations regarding sanctuaries given to terrorists in Afghanistan.</li>
  <li>Recent increase in attacks targeting security forces in Balochistan and Khyber Pakhtunkhwa.</li>
  <li>Ongoing counterterrorism operations are ongoing with significant daily engagements.</li>
  <li>Repatriation of illegal Afghan citizens from Pakistan is in progress.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“All evidence related to terrorism can be traced back to the safe havens enjoyed by terrorists in Afghanistan.” - Gen Chaudhry</blockquote>
<p>The ISPR emphasizes a commitment to counterterrorism, urging for a cohesive approach to manage and prevent violence spilling over from Afghanistan into Pakistan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1881429</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1881429</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:36:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Military says no political leader's ambition above welfare of Pakistan - The News International]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Military emphasizes national welfare over political ambitions in Pakistan</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The News</p><figure><img src="https://www.thenews.com.pk/assets/uploads/updates/2024-12-27/1265977_2724597_ISPR-DG_updates.jpg" alt="Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) Director General Lieutenant General Ahmed Sharif Chaudhry briefing media at the General Headquarters, Rawalpindi, December 27, 2024. — Screengrab via YouTube/Geo News" width="700" height="400"><figcaption>Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) Director General Lieutenant General Ahmed Sharif Chaudhry briefing media at the General Headquarters, Rawalpindi, December 27, 2024. — Screengrab via YouTube/Geo News</figcaption></figure><p>In a recent briefing, ISPR DG Lieutenant General Ahmed Sharif Chaudhry asserted that no political leader's ambitions supersede the welfare of Pakistan.</p><ul><li>The military clarified its stance against any political leader's ambition that might undermine the country's interests.</li><li>General Chaudhry noted the importance of dialogue among politicians for resolving their issues.</li><li>He reported a significant rise in counter-terrorism operations, with over 59,779 intelligence-based operations carried out in the past year.</li><li>The military has emphasized its neutrality and professional relations with all political parties.</li><li>Pakistan's military readiness in the face of regional tensions, particularly with India, was reaffirmed.</li><li>He condemned brutality against freedom movements in India and highlighted the military's commitment to supporting the Kashmir cause.</li></ul><blockquote>"No individual, his politics and his desire for power are above Pakistan." - ISPR DG Lt Gen Ahmed Sharif Chaudhry</blockquote><p>The military spokesperson emphasized a united effort against terrorism and reiterated the army's engagement in public welfare and national development initiatives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thenews.com.pk/latest/1265977-dg-ispr-ahmed-sharif-addresses-media-in-rawalpindi</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thenews.com.pk/latest/1265977-dg-ispr-ahmed-sharif-addresses-media-in-rawalpindi</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No political leader's desire for power should surpass Pakistan's interests: ISPR DG - Geo News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>No Political Leader's Desire for Power Should Surpass Pakistan's Interests: ISPR DG</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 27, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Geo News</p><figure><img src="https://www.geo.tv/assets/uploads/updates/2024-12-27/581893_9605801_updates.jpg" alt="Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) Director General Lieutenant General Ahmed Sharif Chaudhry briefing media at the General Headquarters, Rawalpindi, December 27, 2024. — ISPR" width="700" height="400"><figcaption>Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) Director General Lieutenant General Ahmed Sharif Chaudhry briefing media at the General Headquarters, Rawalpindi, December 27, 2024. — ISPR</figcaption></figure><p>Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) Director General Lieutenant General Ahmed Sharif Chaudhry emphasized during a briefing that Pakistan's interests should take precedence over any political leader's ambitions, advocating for dialogue among political parties.</p><ul><li>All political parties and leaders are respected by the army.</li><li>Welcoming dialogue among politicians to solve issues.</li><li>Accountability for any officer prioritizing politics over the state.</li></ul><blockquote>"For every army officer, the state of Pakistan and the army hold priority."</blockquote><p>The ISPR DG highlighted the need for accountability and integrity within the Pakistan Army while reiterating support for national unity and counter-terrorism efforts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.geo.tv/latest/581893-dg-ispr-addresses-press-conference</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.geo.tv/latest/581893-dg-ispr-addresses-press-conference</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea Parliament impeaches acting President Han Duck-soo amid political tension - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Parliament impeaches acting President Han Duck-soo amid political tension</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>In a surprising turn of events, the South Korean Parliament has voted to impeach acting President Han Duck-soo amidst escalating political tensions. This decision has been met with significant public attention and implications for the future of the nation's governance.</p><ul><li>The impeachment vote reflects deep-rooted political discord.</li><li>Public demonstrations have surged in response to the government's actions.</li><li>This event may lead to a profound impact on upcoming elections.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“This is a critical moment for our democracy,” said a key opposition leader.</p></blockquote><p>The impeachment of Han Duck-soo marks a pivotal moment in South Korea's political landscape, potentially reshaping the country's future governance and political alignment.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/south-korea-parliament-impeaches-acting-president-han-duck-soo-amid-political-tension/articleshow/116710133.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/south-korea-parliament-impeaches-acting-president-han-duck-soo-amid-political-tension/articleshow/116710133.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 09:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>