<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:18:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 05:18:34 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires live updates: Death toll rises to 24, officials prepare for a ‘particularly dangerous situation’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires Update: Death Toll Reaches 24 Amid Dangerous Conditions</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/LOS-ANGELES-FIRE-5_1736737760605_1736737770300.jpg" alt="Firefighters work during the Palisades Fire near Los Angeles, California" title="Firefighters work during the Palisades Fire near the Mandeville Canyon area of Los Angeles, California, US, on January 12, 2025"><figcaption>Firefighters work during the Palisades Fire near Los Angeles, California</figcaption></div><p>The wildfires in California's Los Angeles County have led to a rising death toll of 24, with mandatory evacuation orders being lifted in several parts as officials brace for worsening weather conditions.</p><ul><li>Twenty-four fatalities reported, with many more missing.</li><li>Over 12,000 structures have been damaged or destroyed.</li><li>Dangerous dry winds are expected to exacerbate the situation.</li><li>Evacuation orders in place for over 200,000 residents.</li><li>Governor Gavin Newsom has announced a “rebuilding plan” for affected areas.</li></ul><blockquote>“The fires are still raging in L.A. The incompetent pols have no idea how to put them out.” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>The fires represent one of the worst wildfire starts to a year for California, affecting countless lives and structures across the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 03:14:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Severe winds return: Los Angeles wildfire death toll climbs to 24, 'fire tornado' spotted - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Severe Winds Return: Los Angeles Wildfire Death Toll Climbs to 24, 'Fire Tornado' Spotted</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>A new wave of severe winds has exacerbated the ongoing wildfires in Los Angeles, raising the death toll to 24. Reports have also surfaced of a 'fire tornado' occurring amidst the chaos.</p><ul><li>Severe winds reach up to 60 mph, complicating firefighting efforts.</li><li>The number of casualties has risen as firefighters continue to battle the flames.</li><li>Residents are urged to evacuate high-risk areas as conditions worsen.</li><li>'Fire tornado' seen in the San Fernando Valley, creating dangerous conditions.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is one of the worst fire seasons we have seen in decades.” - Fire Chief</blockquote><p>With safety measures put in place, authorities are reminding residents of the importance of preparedness in the face of natural disasters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/severe-winds-return-los-angeles-wildfire-death-toll-climbs-to-24-fire-tornado-spotted/articleshow/117185667.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/severe-winds-return-los-angeles-wildfire-death-toll-climbs-to-24-fire-tornado-spotted/articleshow/117185667.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 03:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Completely shaken to foundation': Self-proclaimed prophet who predicted Trump's assassination now make n - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAJBVV95cUxQMTZlemxXUGtJUnhOUkpLZVdQY2JpdzV6N3pIYkpYWTNHYUtXVG80a05RMHBaM25oUmNNOVZGTzQxLTMxd2VUWkJFcWRZQlZzTzVoT3N2MG83MG9iWTRLUk5pMTNaRFRuS1NmR3dwOEtFV1dMekxWamhYRmZRZTFOSHVxTkxvd2lWVGhnU2xYSTFjZzlXcnR1cVg3MHp5TFZvTzJIdUJiNE1DRENGT1o1bjczdmRhTVpUNDlxSGdfQlQtUFZ2ay1rRWJ4ZG9nLXF0QXdCZzU2M0U5RVFSbXVadDc4cW5acGRfNmNCZV9QMU5CZEhJQ1RrNWh3QmQzdVNYOV9LR3BLenRpLTV1dmNRcTFwSWM1Ym9kTDZXNNIBogJBVV95cUxPTmtHNk81RE1WWDVvMU1pN2p1Vkl6MTNJZVBvQ3NJUk5fZWhDNFZFTEcxbTdWd2F3TDNjck9Tb2JGVU1tZFV4ZTZHNWZpcWU1ejE3UVlqeE5EZEdsOWZlRGkwUzIxYnFDaGk0SUlCSEo2WHlrOW4xbkNPbWtMZUUyQmI3Qjh1azBpSmRtaDBOaXpoalFmd1BzTHVCbnRnMlA1aXNub296MnFvYWZTdU50WFc5TUtZR3k4Sm1MaHQxaUdiaHhCVXlfTDkxVFRoWnpubmJ5ZUxkZXZCQ3Y5M3Y4UFNlRlB1eXFhaGNjeDVTZnRlWmhLMzFic295dXk5MlRSai1RN3lsM0NOOW1iZm5CYmttVFM0OGZZUXgwNmhGOGxlUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAJBVV95cUxQMTZlemxXUGtJUnhOUkpLZVdQY2JpdzV6N3pIYkpYWTNHYUtXVG80a05RMHBaM25oUmNNOVZGTzQxLTMxd2VUWkJFcWRZQlZzTzVoT3N2MG83MG9iWTRLUk5pMTNaRFRuS1NmR3dwOEtFV1dMekxWamhYRmZRZTFOSHVxTkxvd2lWVGhnU2xYSTFjZzlXcnR1cVg3MHp5TFZvTzJIdUJiNE1DRENGT1o1bjczdmRhTVpUNDlxSGdfQlQtUFZ2ay1rRWJ4ZG9nLXF0QXdCZzU2M0U5RVFSbXVadDc4cW5acGRfNmNCZV9QMU5CZEhJQ1RrNWh3QmQzdVNYOV9LR3BLenRpLTV1dmNRcTFwSWM1Ym9kTDZXNNIBogJBVV95cUxPTmtHNk81RE1WWDVvMU1pN2p1Vkl6MTNJZVBvQ3NJUk5fZWhDNFZFTEcxbTdWd2F3TDNjck9Tb2JGVU1tZFV4ZTZHNWZpcWU1ejE3UVlqeE5EZEdsOWZlRGkwUzIxYnFDaGk0SUlCSEo2WHlrOW4xbkNPbWtMZUUyQmI3Qjh1azBpSmRtaDBOaXpoalFmd1BzTHVCbnRnMlA1aXNub296MnFvYWZTdU50WFc5TUtZR3k4Sm1MaHQxaUdiaHhCVXlfTDkxVFRoWnpubmJ5ZUxkZXZCQ3Y5M3Y4UFNlRlB1eXFhaGNjeDVTZnRlWmhLMzFic295dXk5MlRSai1RN3lsM0NOOW1iZm5CYmttVFM0OGZZUXgwNmhGOGxlUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 03:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASAMS, HIMARS, Abrams, Altius 600M — Taiwan Hoards Weapons That ‘Battered’ Russia” In Ukraine War - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Taiwan Hoards Weapons That 'Battered' Russia in Ukraine War</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>October 2023<br><strong>Source: </strong>EurAsian Times</p>
<figure><img src="https://www.twz.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/NASAMS-launch-AMRAAM-ER.webp?strip=all&amp;quality=85" alt="AMRAAM-ER undergoing a test firing from a NASAMS box launcher" width="730" height="430"><figcaption>AMRAAM-ER undergoing a test firing from a NASAMS box launcher. Kongsberg</figcaption></figure>
<p>Taiwan has signed a significant arms deal with the United States to acquire NASAMS, enhancing its air defense. This agreement, valued at NT$10.31 billion (approximately US$312.9 million), will continue until 2034.</p>
<ul>
<li>The NASAMS system has proven effective in countering missile threats in the Ukraine conflict.</li>
<li>The deal includes radar systems worth US$192.6 million to be located in key Taiwanese regions.</li>
<li>Taiwan aims to integrate advanced technologies to fortify its defenses amidst escalating military tensions.</li>
<li>This procurement is part of a broader strategy by Taiwan to acquire battle-tested weaponry amid growing threats from China.</li>
<li>Additional military acquisitions include HIMARS, ATACMS missiles, Switchblade munitions, and Abrams tanks.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The NASAMS will further enhance Taiwan’s military arsenal... capable of engaging a wide range of aerial threats, including cruise missiles.”</blockquote>
<p>Taiwan's commitment to bolstering its military capabilities signifies its preparedness to address security challenges in the region, particularly from China.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/nasams-himars-abrams-altius-600m-taiwan/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/nasams-himars-abrams-altius-600m-taiwan/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:50:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles fires: 24 dead, 12,000 structures destroyed | All you need to know - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Los Angeles Fires: 24 Dead and 12,000 Structures Destroyed</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/13/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-27_1736732652239_1736732669367.jpg" alt="People affected by the Los Angeles fires visit relief center looking for needed supplies on January 12. (AFP)"><figcaption>People affected by the Los Angeles fires visit relief center looking for needed supplies on January 12. (AFP)</figcaption><p>The recent fires in Los Angeles have resulted in the death of at least 24 individuals, widespread evacuations, and the destruction of over 12,000 structures, creating devastation across an area larger than San Francisco.</p><ul><li>Over 150,000 people have been evacuated from their homes.</li><li>The fires have caused significant damage, with economic losses estimated between USD 135 billion to USD 150 billion.</li><li>Nearly 70,000 customers in California are currently without power.</li><li>335 schools across multiple counties have been closed due to the fires.</li><li>Strong Santa Ana winds have exacerbated the wildfire conditions.</li></ul><blockquote>“The city’s leadership failed my department by not allocating enough funds for firefighting.” - Los Angeles Fire Chief Kristin Crowley</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the Los Angeles fires represent a catastrophic event with significant implications for the community, and ongoing efforts are required to address the destruction caused.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/los-angeles-fires-24-dead-12-000-structures-destroyed-all-you-need-to-know-about-the-california-wildfire-devastation-101736732317435.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/los-angeles-fires-24-dead-12-000-structures-destroyed-all-you-need-to-know-about-the-california-wildfire-devastation-101736732317435.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:45:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Canada Is Not For Sale': Trudeau's Former Ally Jagmeet Singh Warns Trump Over Tariff Threat - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/canada-is-not-for-sale-trudeaus-former-ally-jagmeet-singh-warns-trump-over-tariff-threat-9186584.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/canada-is-not-for-sale-trudeaus-former-ally-jagmeet-singh-warns-trump-over-tariff-threat-9186584.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 02:16:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oil hits more than 3-month high as US sanctions hit Russia exports - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Oil hits more than 3-month high as US sanctions hit Russia exports</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p>
<img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2024/09/20240904051945_oil.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Brent crude futures climbed $1.35, or 1.69%, to $81.11 a barrel by 2339 GMT after hitting an intraday high of $81.44, the highest since August 27." width="770" height="431">
<figcaption>Brent crude futures climbed $1.35, or 1.69%, to $81.11 a barrel by 2339 GMT after hitting an intraday high of $81.44, the highest since August 27.</figcaption>
<p>Oil prices have risen to their highest level in over three months due to new US sanctions targeting Russian oil exports, affecting key importers like China and India.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The US Treasury imposed sanctions on Russian oil producers Gazprom Neft and Surgutneftegas, as well as 183 vessels shipping Russian oil.</li>
  <li>Brent crude futures reached $81.11 a barrel and peaked at $81.44, the highest since August 27.</li>
  <li>US West Texas Intermediate crude rose to $77.97 a barrel after a high of $78.32.</li>
  <li>The sanctions aim to cut revenue that funds Russia's war efforts in Ukraine.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Brent crude futures climbed $1.35, or 1.69%, to $81.11 a barrel by 2339 GMT after hitting an intraday high of $81.44."</blockquote>
<p>This escalation in oil prices highlights the impact of geopolitical tensions and ongoing sanctions on global markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/oil-hits-more-than-3-month-high-as-us-sanctions-hit-russia-exports-12908512.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/oil-hits-more-than-3-month-high-as-us-sanctions-hit-russia-exports-12908512.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 01:45:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires live: 3 out of 6 active fires in Los Angeles 100% contained, Palisades continues to burn - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires: Major Fires in Los Angeles Contained Amid Devastation</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-79_1736720709551_1736720732338.jpg" alt="A fire fighting helicopter drops water as the Palisades fire grows" title="A fire fighting helicopter drops water as the Palisades fire grows"><figcaption>A fire fighting helicopter drops water as the Palisades fire grows.</figcaption><p>The California wildfires have wreaked havoc, with at least 16 confirmed deaths and over 12,000 structures damaged. As of now, three of the six active fires in Los Angeles have been contained, but the Palisades fire continues to burn.</p><strong>Key Points:</strong><ul><li>The Palisades Fire spread to an additional 1,000 acres, prompting ongoing firefighting efforts.</li><li>Evacuation orders affect approximately 153,000 residents, with many additional residents warned to prepare for evacuation.</li><li>Governor Gavin Newsom announced significant containment progress for several fires, with different percentages confirmed.</li><li>President Biden has been coordinating relief efforts and addressing state officials regarding the crisis.</li><li>International aid is on the way, with offers from Canada and Ukraine for firefighting assistance.</li></ul><blockquote>“The fires are still raging in L.A. This is one of the worst catastrophes in the history of our Country.” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical with adverse weather predicted, and officials continue to emphasize the importance of safety and evacuation compliance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 22:28:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Kamala Harris' LA home be affected by wildfires? This is the house where... - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Will Kamala Harris' LA Home Be Affected by Wildfires?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Current Date, <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="LA Home" /><figcaption>Kamala Harris' residence in Los Angeles</figcaption><p>The article discusses the potential threat of wildfires to Kamala Harris' home in Los Angeles, along with the broader implications of increasing wildfire risks in the area.</p><ul><li>The wildfires in California are intensifying.</li><li>Utility companies have warned of potential power outages due to the fires.</li><li>Kamala Harris' residence is located in one of the areas prone to wildfires.</li></ul><blockquote>“Wildfires are becoming more frequent and severe due to climate change,” highlighting the urgency for better fire management strategies.</blockquote><p>This highlights the urgent need for preventive measures and awareness regarding climate change impacts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/will-kamala-harris-la-home-be-affected-by-wildfires-this-is-the-house-where-/articleshow/117182055.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/will-kamala-harris-la-home-be-affected-by-wildfires-this-is-the-house-where-/articleshow/117182055.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 20:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis unveils advanced drone manufacturing facility in Nagpur - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Devendra Fadnavis unveils advanced drone manufacturing facility in Nagpur</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 13, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> India Today</p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/devendra-fadnavis-113146150-16x9.jpg?VersionId=7.PojJCghLc7XT0OW59vaJooeT9AGxdF&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Devendra Fadnavis" title="The new drones facility in Nagpur was unveiled by Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis." height="388">
<figcaption>The new drones facility in Nagpur was unveiled by Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis.</figcaption>
<p>In a significant boost to India's defence manufacturing capabilities, the new drone facility established by Economic Explosives Limited in Nagpur aims to strengthen indigenous production of drones and unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs).</p>
<ul>
<li>The facility was inaugurated by Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis.</li>
<li>It will focus on producing loiter munitions, counter-drone systems, and military drone technologies.</li>
<li>The Nagastra-1, India's first indigenous loiter munition, has been introduced into the Indian Army.</li>
<li>Solar Industries aims to innovate and enhance India's self-reliance in defence technology.</li>
<li>The facility aligns with global trends recognizing drones as essential in modern warfare.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Solar Industries Chairman Satyanarayan Nuwal emphasized his vision of transforming Nagpur into a hub for the development of advanced weaponized drones.</blockquote>
<p>The launch of this facility marks a pivotal step in advancing India's defence manufacturing capabilities and confirms India's growing expertise in military technologies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/maharashtra-chief-minister-devendra-fadnavis-unveils-advanced-drone-manufacturing-facility-in-nagpur-2663782-2025-01-13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/maharashtra-chief-minister-devendra-fadnavis-unveils-advanced-drone-manufacturing-facility-in-nagpur-2663782-2025-01-13</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 20:09:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid H-1B visa debate, some Indians lose jobs - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Amid H-1B Visa Debate, Some Indians Lose Jobs</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>As discussions surrounding the H-1B visa program intensify, some Indian workers are facing job losses due to changing immigration policies and increased scrutiny on work visas.</p><ul><li>Some workers have been laid off as companies reassess their visa sponsorships.</li><li>The debate centers on balancing job opportunities for foreign workers with opportunities for American citizens.</li><li>Concerns arise about the economic impact of such job losses on the Indian community.</li></ul><blockquote>“The current climate against foreign workers is alarming and affects many skilled professionals,” said one industry expert.</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the challenges faced by skilled workers navigating a complicated immigration landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/amid-h-1b-visa-debate-some-indians-lose-jobs/articleshow/117181707.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/amid-h-1b-visa-debate-some-indians-lose-jobs/articleshow/117181707.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ready to exchange North Korean soldiers for Ukrainians held in Russia: Zelenskyy - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Zelenskyy proposes exchange of North Korean soldiers for captured Ukrainians</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 12 January 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p><p>Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelenskyy announced that Kyiv is ready to exchange North Korean soldiers for Ukrainians held captive in Russia.</p><ul><li>Zelenskyy stated that Ukraine has captured two North Korean soldiers in the Kursk region, marking the first such capture since North Korea's entry into the conflict.</li><li>He emphasized the potential for more North Korean soldiers to be captured.</li><li>Ukrainian assessments suggest around 11,000 North Korean troops are supporting Russian forces.</li><li>Zelenskyy expressed that options would be available for North Korean soldiers who do not wish to return home.</li></ul><blockquote>“In addition to the first captured soldiers from North Korea, there will undoubtedly be more. It’s only a matter of time before our troops manage to capture others.” — Volodymyr Zelenskyy</blockquote><p>This proposal highlights the ongoing complexities and human toll of the conflict, as both sides navigate military and diplomatic strategies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/ready-to-exchange-north-korean-soldiers-for-ukrainians-held-in-russia-zelenskyy-3352214</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/ready-to-exchange-north-korean-soldiers-for-ukrainians-held-in-russia-zelenskyy-3352214</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:40:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires live: 16 dead as Palisades Fire spreads eastward, strong dry winds to worsen - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires Update: President Biden to Discuss Relief Measures</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 13, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/USA-BIDEN-AFGHANISTAN-0_1736717631263_1736717661087.JPG" alt="California wildfires live updates: US. President Joe Biden will hold a meeting to discuss the response to the wildfires" title="California wildfires live updates: US. President Joe Biden will hold a meeting to discuss the response to the wildfires">
<figcaption>California wildfires live updates: US. President Joe Biden will hold a meeting to discuss the response to the wildfires</figcaption>
<p>The ongoing wildfires in Los Angeles have resulted in the loss of 16 lives and the destruction of over 12,000 structures. President Biden is set to meet with local and federal officials to coordinate relief operations.</p>
<ul>
<li>16 confirmed deaths and 13 missing individuals due to the wildfires.</li>
<li>Over 12,000 structures have been damaged or destroyed.</li>
<li>Evacuation orders have impacted over 150,000 residents, with more than 700 taking refuge in shelters.</li>
<li>Governor Newsom has deployed 1,000 National Guard members to assist with response efforts.</li>
<li>The National Weather Service has issued warnings for high winds, complicating firefighting efforts.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Eaton Fire - 15% contained, Palisades Fire - 11% contained, Hurst Fire - 76% contained.” - Governor Newsom</blockquote>
<p>This disaster emphasizes the urgent need for federal and local cooperation in crisis management and disaster relief as the situation evolves.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-live-updates-la-fires-2025-palisades-los-angeles-weather-santa-ana-winds-101736640088332.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:26:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taliban don’t regard women as human beings: Malala - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Taliban don’t regard women as human beings: Malala</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Not provided</p><p>Malala Yousafzai harshly critiques the Taliban, stating that they do not recognize women as human beings, highlighting issues of gender inequality and oppression in Afghanistan.</p><ul><li>Malala emphasizes the need for global awareness and action regarding women's rights in Taliban-controlled regions.</li><li>She urges world leaders to take a stand against the oppression of women and girls.</li><li>The statement comes amid ongoing reports of human rights violations against women in Afghanistan.</li></ul><blockquote>“We must stand with the women of Afghanistan, who are fighting for their rights and dignity.”</blockquote><p>This statement reflects ongoing concerns surrounding women's rights under Taliban rule and the call for international support.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/taliban-dont-regard-women-as-human-beings-malala/articleshow/117181022.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/taliban-dont-regard-women-as-human-beings-malala/articleshow/117181022.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK PM Keir Starmer under pressure to sack Hasina’s niece Tulip Siddiq - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>UK PM Keir Starmer under pressure to sack Hasina’s niece Tulip Siddiq</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source]</p><p>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer is facing intense pressure to remove Tulip Siddiq, a member of Parliament and niece of Bangladesh’s Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, from her position. This comes as various factions within the Labour Party voice their concerns about Siddiq's connections and political stance.</p><ul><li>Starmer’s leadership is being scrutinized in light of Siddiq's affiliations.</li><li>Concerns raised about the implications of her ties to international politics.</li><li>Possible repercussions for the Labour Party if action is not taken.</li></ul><blockquote>“The leadership must address this issue decisively,” said a party insider.</blockquote><p>In summary, the situation presents a significant challenge for Starmer as he navigates party dynamics and public perception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/uk-pm-keir-starmer-under-pressure-to-sack-hasinas-niece-tulip-siddiq/articleshow/117180871.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/uk-pm-keir-starmer-under-pressure-to-sack-hasinas-niece-tulip-siddiq/articleshow/117180871.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tawang walks in solidarity with Tibet earthquake victims - The Arunachal Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tawang Marches in Support of Tibet Earthquake Victims</h1><p><strong>Date: 12 Jan</strong> | <strong>Source: Arunachal Times</strong></p><img src="https://arunachaltimes.in/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Tawang-walks-in-solidarity-with-Tibet-earthquake-victims.webp" alt="Tawang walks in solidarity with Tibet earthquake victims"><figcaption>Tawang walks in solidarity with Tibet earthquake victims</figcaption><p>Thousands in Tawang participated in a candlelight march to support the victims of the recent earthquake in Tibet, organized by local leaders.</p><ul><li>Thousands of participants, including lamas and students, joined the candlelight march.</li><li>The march was initiated by local MLA Namgey Tsering to honor earthquake victims.</li><li>The earthquake occurred on 7 January, affecting over 126 people and leaving many injured and homeless.</li><li>The event highlighted community solidarity and included prayers for the victims at a local monastery.</li><li>Candlelight march started from Tawang monastery and ended at Masang Dungyur Mani in Old Market.</li></ul><blockquote>“We offered condolences to those who lost their lives and prayed for the wellbeing of the injured and the homeless.” - Namgey Tsering</blockquote><p>The community's response reflects a strong sense of solidarity and support for Tibetans affected by the disaster, emphasizing the importance of compassion in times of crisis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://arunachaltimes.in/index.php/2025/01/13/tawang-walks-in-solidarity-with-tibet-earthquake-victims/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arunachaltimes.in/index.php/2025/01/13/tawang-walks-in-solidarity-with-tibet-earthquake-victims/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:50:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Greenland PM Ready To Speak To Trump, Denmark Sends Private Messages To US President-Elect - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Greenland PM Ready To Speak To Trump, Denmark Sends Private Messages To US President-Elect</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 12, 2025 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Amid Greenland PM Mute Egede expressing willingness to speak to Donald Trump, it was also reported that the Danish government sent private messages to the US President-elect regarding the security of the island. (IMAGE: REUTERS/NASA)" title="Amid Greenland PM Mute Egede expressing willingness to speak to Donald Trump, it was also reported that the Danish government sent private messages to the US President-elect regarding the security of the island. (IMAGE: REUTERS/NASA)" />
<figcaption>Amid Greenland PM Mute Egede expressing willingness to speak to Donald Trump, it was also reported that the Danish government sent private messages to the US President-elect regarding the security of the island. (IMAGE: REUTERS/NASA)</figcaption>
<p>Denmark has sent private messages to US President-elect Donald Trump's team, expressing a willingness to discuss boosting security in Greenland amidst recent comments from Greenland's Prime Minister Mute Egede about dialogue with Trump.</p>
<ul>
<li>Denmark is willing to discuss increasing US military presence in Greenland.</li>
<li>Greenland PM Mute Egede is open to speaking with Trump regarding security concerns.</li>
<li>Trump's comments on controlling Greenland reflect a strategic interest in the resource-rich island.</li>
<li>Greenland is a self-governing territory of Denmark, aiming for greater autonomy and independence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We have a desire for independence, a desire to be the master of our own house … This is something everyone should respect.” - Mute Egede</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing dialogue highlights significant geopolitical interests and the aspirations for greater autonomy of Greenland.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/greenland-pm-ready-to-speak-to-trump-denmark-sends-private-messages-to-us-president-elect-9186082.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/greenland-pm-ready-to-speak-to-trump-denmark-sends-private-messages-to-us-president-elect-9186082.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:32:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[President Biden and Israeli PM Netanyahu discuss ceasefire, hostage deal: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden and Netanyahu Discuss Ceasefire and Hostage Release</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Jan 13, 2025, <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/-LEBANON-CONFLICT-POLITICS-B_1736704488180_1736704488418.jpg" alt="President Biden and PM Netanyahu discussed a ceasefire deal involving the Gaza conflict(Jim Watson/AFP)"><figcaption>President Biden and PM Netanyahu discussed a ceasefire deal involving the Gaza conflict(Jim Watson/AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>US President Joe Biden and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu discussed a potential ceasefire and hostage release deal in Gaza amid ongoing negotiations.</p><ul><li>Biden and Netanyahu spoke during a phone call regarding a ceasefire deal being mediated in Doha.</li><li>National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan indicated that they are "very close" to reaching a deal.</li><li>Outgoing President Biden is receiving regular updates about the talks and aims to use remaining days in office to finalize the agreement.</li><li>Roughly 100 hostages are currently held by Hamas, and over 46,000 people have reportedly died in Gaza, according to health ministry statistics.</li><li>Future negotiations may involve perspectives from the incoming Trump administration, which promises a new approach to Middle East peace.</li></ul><blockquote>“We are still determined to use every day we have in office to get this done...” - Jake Sullivan</blockquote><p>The discussion highlights the urgency of addressing the hostages and the humanitarian crisis in Gaza, even as the political landscape shifts with the imminent transition in the US administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/president-biden-and-israeli-pm-netanyahu-discuss-ceasefire-hostage-deal-report-101736704157514.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/president-biden-and-israeli-pm-netanyahu-discuss-ceasefire-hostage-deal-report-101736704157514.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk is rich and influential is the problem or that he is not ..., Italy PM Giorgia Meloni to journa - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk is rich and influential is the problem or that he is not ...</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>No summary content was accessible for this article.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-is-rich-and-influential-is-the-problem-or-that-he-is-not-italy-pm-giorgia-meloni-to-journalists/articleshow/117179974.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-is-rich-and-influential-is-the-problem-or-that-he-is-not-italy-pm-giorgia-meloni-to-journalists/articleshow/117179974.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 18:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump stuns netizens by giving hilarious twist to his viral moment with Barack Obama: 'Elite level trolling' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Stuns Netizens by Giving Hilarious Twist to His Viral Moment with Barack Obama: 'Elite Level Trolling'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/US-STATE-FUNERAL-HELD-IN-WASHINGTON-DC-FOR-FORMER-_1736617472617_1736704410047.jpg" alt="Donald Trump, Obama and a number of other former US leaders, such as Mike Pence, Bill Clinton, and George W. Bush, were seated close to each other at Carter's funeral.(Getty Images via AFP)" title="Donald Trump, Obama and a number of other former US leaders, such as Mike Pence, Bill Clinton, and George W. Bush, were seated close to each other at Carter's funeral.(Getty Images via AFP)"><figcaption>Donald Trump, Obama and a number of other former US leaders, such as Mike Pence, Bill Clinton, and George W. Bush, were seated close to each other at Carter's funeral.(Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>Donald Trump took a hilarious dig at former President Barack Obama during their viral interaction at ex-President Jimmy Carter’s state funeral.</p><ul><li>The video of Trump and Obama at Carter's funeral became a viral sensation, igniting discussions on social media.</li><li>Trump humorously responded to speculation about their conversation by editing the clip with humorous voiceovers.</li><li>Comedians pointed out the irony of their past criticisms and the camaraderie displayed at the event.</li><li>Netizens expressed their reactions, praising Trump's antics as 'elite level trolling.'</li></ul><blockquote>“Elite level trolling,” wrote one user in response to Trump’s video.</blockquote><p>Trump’s playful interaction with Obama showcases a unique and humor-filled side of political rivalries, drawing both laughter and engagement from the public.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-stuns-netizens-by-giving-hilarious-twist-to-his-viral-moment-with-barack-obama-elite-level-trolling-101736701893924.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-stuns-netizens-by-giving-hilarious-twist-to-his-viral-moment-with-barack-obama-elite-level-trolling-101736701893924.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:57:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump likes this version of viral lip-reading where Obama calls Kamala Harris 'horrendous' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump likes this version of viral lip-reading where Obama calls Kamala Harris 'horrendous'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 12, 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>In a humorous twist, former President Donald Trump shared a viral lip-reading video where President Obama seemingly refers to Kamala Harris as 'horrendous'. The video has sparked various reactions from netizens and political commentators alike.</p><ul><li>The video showcases a creative lip-reading interpretation of a conversation between Obama and Harris.</li><li>Trump found the video particularly amusing, sharing it with his followers on social media.</li><li>The incident highlights ongoing political dynamics and discourse surrounding prominent figures like Harris and Obama.</li></ul><blockquote>"This video is hilarious and perfectly points out the absurdity in today's politics!" - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>This viral moment reflects the intersection of humor and political commentary, showcasing how social media continues to shape public perceptions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-likes-this-version-of-viral-lip-reading-where-obama-calls-kamala-harris-horrendous/articleshow/117179288.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-likes-this-version-of-viral-lip-reading-where-obama-calls-kamala-harris-horrendous/articleshow/117179288.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires can expand due to 80 kmph winds: 'Dangerous, strong ' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-can-expand-due-to-80-kmph-winds-dangerous-strong-101736701915580.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-can-expand-due-to-80-kmph-winds-dangerous-strong-101736701915580.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:19:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia calls for Syria sanctions to be lifted - Arab News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saudi Arabia Calls for Lifting Sanctions on Syria</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Sunday, Date Unknown - <strong>Source:</strong> Arab News</p><p>Saudi Foreign Minister Prince Faisal bin Farhan urges for the lifting of sanctions on Syria during a press briefing, emphasizing that these restrictions hinder the country’s rebuilding and development.</p><ul><li>Prince Faisal highlights the importance of lifting both unilateral and international sanctions.</li><li>The Riyadh meeting on Syria included representatives from various nations including the UK and US.</li><li>Positive steps by the new Syrian administration were acknowledged, focusing on dialogue and combating terrorism.</li><li>Humanitarian and economic support is essential for Syria's stability and the return of refugees.</li><li>EU officials discussed the potential easing of sanctions based on Syrian administration's progress.</li></ul><blockquote>Kaja Kallas, EU commissioner for foreign affairs, stated, “The EU is prepared to take further steps if progress is positive, but could also reverse course if it is not.”</blockquote><p>Saudi Arabia remains committed to supporting Syria and calls for international collaboration in aiding the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.arabnews.com/node/2586115/saudi-arabia</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.arabnews.com/node/2586115/saudi-arabia</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:54:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quad eyes foreign ministers' meeting following Trump inauguration - Nikkei Asia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxOVUtab2hhaURGTEFhSG52ZFAyU2RvV0ZKbDkxUWdIaF9PY3d1eHZiQmV2c3E0YlZVZkpTS3EzX0pSQkVsbjlQMXpQRDZWRFhaN2JPR2VlNG5nQ2o1YlI0TE5pTUtocDEzdnpNVll2aVdlM1hHc29ob2VuNll2WnRkbmRaZDlhcGlFX1B0aktxWjlGT0pyckNYaVU0THBESkRsQllHTVZzNDYwZ29CbzFXWTBtOUQ5ZnBQZVNYQVRB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxOVUtab2hhaURGTEFhSG52ZFAyU2RvV0ZKbDkxUWdIaF9PY3d1eHZiQmV2c3E0YlZVZkpTS3EzX0pSQkVsbjlQMXpQRDZWRFhaN2JPR2VlNG5nQ2o1YlI0TE5pTUtocDEzdnpNVll2aVdlM1hHc29ob2VuNll2WnRkbmRaZDlhcGlFX1B0aktxWjlGT0pyckNYaVU0THBESkRsQllHTVZzNDYwZ29CbzFXWTBtOUQ5ZnBQZVNYQVRB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is JD Vance not on the same page with Trump on pardoning Jan 6 rioters? 'A little bit of gray area' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>JD Vance's Position on Pardoning January 6 Rioters: Inconsistencies with Trump</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In a recent discussion, Senator JD Vance expressed his views on the controversial topic of pardoning individuals involved in the January 6 riots, revealing a divergence from former President Trump's stance.</p><ul><li>Vance acknowledges a 'little bit of gray area' regarding the pardoning issue.</li><li>The senator's comments suggest a complex viewpoint that may not align entirely with Trump's definitive calls for pardons.</li><li>This poses questions about the unity of the Republican party on this issue.</li></ul><blockquote>“There’s a little bit of gray area in terms of figuring out who should get a pardon.”</blockquote><p>This discussion highlights potential rifts within the Republican party, particularly concerning their approach to the events of January 6 and the individuals involved.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/is-jd-vance-not-on-the-same-page-with-trump-on-pardoning-jan-6-rioters-a-little-bit-of-gray-area/articleshow/117178045.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/is-jd-vance-not-on-the-same-page-with-trump-on-pardoning-jan-6-rioters-a-little-bit-of-gray-area/articleshow/117178045.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 16:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump to hold call with Putin in coming days? Prez-elect security advisor hints at major development amid Ukraine war - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump to hold call with Putin in coming days? Prez-elect security advisor hints at major development amid Ukraine war</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/Mike_1736697222936_1736697226650.jpg' alt='Donald Trump's national security advisor pick Mike Walz(AP)' title='Donald Trump's national security advisor pick Mike Walz(AP)'><figcaption>Donald Trump's national security advisor pick Mike Walz(AP)</figcaption></figure><p>Trump's national security advisor pick, Mike Walz, stated that he expects a call between the US President-elect and Russian President Putin in the coming days and weeks amid ongoing tensions related to the Ukraine war.</p><ul><li>Mike Walz anticipates a call between Trump and Putin soon.</li><li>Trump has made promises to resolve the Russia-Ukraine conflict swiftly.</li><li>Trump indicated that a meeting with Putin is being arranged, which will be closely monitored by Ukraine and its allies.</li><li>Russia's Kremlin spokesperson welcomed Trump's approach to dialogue.</li><li>Critics express skepticism regarding Russia's openness to genuine negotiation.</li></ul><blockquote>“President Putin wants to meet,” Trump stated. “We have to get that war over with. That’s a bloody mess.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the anticipated communication between Trump and Putin could signify a shift in US-Russia relations, especially concerning the Ukraine conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-to-hold-call-with-putin-in-coming-days-prez-elect-security-advisor-hints-at-major-development-amid-ukraine-war-101736695361039.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trump-to-hold-call-with-putin-in-coming-days-prez-elect-security-advisor-hints-at-major-development-amid-ukraine-war-101736695361039.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:55:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What triggered California wildfires? Investigators probe many possibilities - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What triggered California wildfires? Investigators probe many possibilities</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 12, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/12/550x309/California-Wildfires-Inequality-3_1736696371047_1736696396543.jpg" alt="Residents embrace outside of a burning property as the Eaton Fire swept through.(AP file photo)" title="Residents embrace outside of a burning property as the Eaton Fire swept through.(AP file photo)">
<figcaption>Residents embrace outside of a burning property as the Eaton Fire swept through.(AP file photo)</figcaption>
<p>Investigators are considering various potential causes for the wildfires in California's Los Angeles area, which have resulted in 16 fatalities and extensive property destruction.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Wildfires have led to thousands of evacuations in Los Angeles, impacting residents including Hollywood celebrities.</li>
  <li>The cause of the wildfire remains unclear, with investigators ruling out lightning as a possibility.</li>
  <li>Two primary suspects for the blaze are arson and fire initiated by utility lines.</li>
  <li>Utilities are obliged to report any incidents related to wildfires to state authorities.</li>
  <li>The fire's containment status is reported as 11 percent for the Palisades Fire and 15 percent for the Eaton Fire.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Preliminary analysis by SCE of electrical circuit information for the energized transmission lines going through the area shows no interruptions or electrical or operational anomalies.”</blockquote>
<p>The investigation continues as agencies try to determine the precise origins of the devastating wildfires.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/what-triggered-california-wildfires-investigators-probe-many-possibilities-101736696036614.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/what-triggered-california-wildfires-investigators-probe-many-possibilities-101736696036614.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:40:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump calls California leaders ‘incompetent’ over fire response - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Criticizes California Officials Over Wildfire Response</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Sunday, September 30, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Dawn</p><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Image related to California wildfires'><figcaption>Trump speaks out on California wildfires</figcaption><p>US President-elect Donald Trump has openly criticized California leaders for their handling of the wildfires devastating the Los Angeles area, calling their response incompetent.</p><ul><li>Trump took to Truth Social to accuse politicians of failing to control the wildfires.</li><li>The wildfires have resulted in the deaths of at least 16 people and displaced 150,000 individuals.</li><li>California's fire infrastructure has been severely tested, with hydrants running dry in affected areas.</li><li>Governor Gavin Newsom has extended an invitation to Trump to visit the sites of devastation.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is one of the worst catastrophes in the history of our Country. They just can’t put out the fires.” – Donald Trump</blockquote><p>Trump's remarks have sparked controversy and raised questions about California's emergency preparedness as the state continues to combat the raging wildfires.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1884727</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1884727</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:02:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Say No To Olaf Scholz': Elon Musk Ahead Of Germany's Snap Elections Next Month - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk Calls for Germans to Reject Olaf Scholz Ahead of Elections</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 12, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Elon Musk has openly called for German Chancellor Olaf Scholz's resignation (AP Image)" />
<figcaption>Elon Musk has openly called for German Chancellor Olaf Scholz's resignation (AP Image)</figcaption>
<p>Elon Musk has called on German citizens to “say no” to Chancellor Olaf Scholz as the country prepares for snap elections on February 23, following Scholz's nomination by the ruling Social Democrats (SPD).</p>
<ul>
  <li>Musk labeled Scholz as an “incompetent fool” and criticized his government.</li>
  <li>The Tesla CEO has endorsed the far-right Alternative for Germany (AfD) party and its co-leader Alice Weidel.</li>
  <li>He expressed that only the AfD can save Germany, promoting their agenda through social media.</li>
  <li>Scholz has rebuked Musk for interfering in German elections, urging voters to resist external manipulation.</li>
  <li>The German government has publicly condemned Musk's attempts to influence the elections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Sag Nein zu Scholz!” translates to “Say No to Scholz”, emphasizing Musk's call to action.</blockquote>
<p>The upcoming elections have become a focal point for discussions on political integrity and foreign influence in Germany.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/say-no-to-olaf-scholz-elon-musk-ahead-of-germanys-snap-elections-next-month-9186300.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/say-no-to-olaf-scholz-elon-musk-ahead-of-germanys-snap-elections-next-month-9186300.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:56:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Burglary attempt at Kamala Harris' Brentwood home as massive looting reported amid LA fires - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Burglary attempt at Kamala Harris' Brentwood home as massive looting reported amid LA fires</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>Los Angeles Times</p><p>Authorities reported a burglary attempt at the home of Vice President Kamala Harris in Brentwood, coinciding with significant looting incidents in the Los Angeles area as fires rage across the region.</p><ul><li>Burglary attempt at Kamala Harris' residence.</li><li>Widespread looting reported across Los Angeles during ongoing fires.</li><li>Increased police presence in affluent areas.</li><li>Community concerns about safety and property protection.</li></ul><blockquote>“We must remain vigilant as these events unfold.” - Local law enforcement spokesperson</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the interplay between natural disasters and crime rates, raising alarms about public safety during emergency situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/burglary-attempt-at-kamala-harris-brentwood-home-as-massive-looting-reported-amid-la-fires/articleshow/117176517.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/burglary-attempt-at-kamala-harris-brentwood-home-as-massive-looting-reported-amid-la-fires/articleshow/117176517.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 14:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>