<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:22:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[\"Black boxes\" from crashed South Korean plane stopped recording about four minutes before disaster, officials say - CNN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Black boxes from crashed South Korean plane stopped recording four minutes before disaster</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/2025-01-11t052804z-193009803-rc2kzba5fob6-rtrmadp-3-southkorea-crash-jejuair.jpg?c=original" alt="The wreckage of the Jeju Air aircraft lies at Muan International Airport, on December 30, 2024." /><figcaption>The wreckage of the Jeju Air aircraft lies at Muan International Airport, in Muan, South Korea, on December 30, 2024.</figcaption><p>Flight recorders from the passenger jet that crashed in South Korea last month, killing more than 170 people, stopped working minutes before the plane belly-landed and exploded, according to investigators.</p><ul><li>The crash occurred on December 29, 2024, and was the deadliest aviation accident in South Korea in nearly 30 years.</li><li>179 passengers and crew members died, with only two survivors reported.</li><li>Both the cockpit voice recorder and flight data recorder stopped recording about four minutes before the crash.</li><li>South Korea's transport ministry is investigating why the recorders stopped functioning.</li><li>The cockpit voice recorder was analyzed locally and then sent to the US for further analysis.</li></ul><blockquote>“CVR and FDR data are important for accident investigations, but various data will be analyzed to identify the cause,” said the South Korean transport ministry.</blockquote><p>The investigation is expected to take months as officials try to determine the cause of this tragic accident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/11/asia/south-korean-airline-black-boxes-stopped-recording-intl-hnk/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/11/asia/south-korean-airline-black-boxes-stopped-recording-intl-hnk/index.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 07:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2nd Round $3,000 Direct Deposits for SSDI & VA in 2025 – Check Eligibility Criteria and Payment Dates - LKO Uniexam.in]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE9zbXk4WE9vRDJ5Q2tZYW9mTG1ncHAzY09IT2pZRURhWGJucHMtQXlldmhJMUNLak1iQS1lMDR6bHZyZnktTHNTQTh4cjVBaWc2czl5eEZBMmRmS3VucXhySXEtNHJVTW5pTEhnMkpNTmJDMjE3cVZQSzgwYVdQZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifkFVX3lxTE9zbXk4WE9vRDJ5Q2tZYW9mTG1ncHAzY09IT2pZRURhWGJucHMtQXlldmhJMUNLak1iQS1lMDR6bHZyZnktTHNTQTh4cjVBaWc2czl5eEZBMmRmS3VucXhySXEtNHJVTW5pTEhnMkpNTmJDMjE3cVZQSzgwYVdQZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 05:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dismay, ridicule over Pakistan Airlines 'tone deaf' ad campaign for flights to France - Euronews]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dismay over Pakistan Airlines 'tone deaf' ad for flights to France</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Various Social Media</p>
<img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Pakistan Airlines Advertisement' />
<figcaption>Image from Pakistan Airlines advertisement</figcaption>
<p>The advertisement by Pakistan International Airlines (PIA) promoting flights to Paris has sparked outrage online due to its unfortunate imagery, drawing comparisons to tragic past events.</p>
<ul>
<li>The ad features an image of a plane seemingly flying into the Eiffel Tower.</li>
<li>Social media users criticized it for insensitivity, drawing parallels to the 9/11 attacks.</li>
<li>Pakistani PR expert Omar R. Quraishi deemed the ad "completely tone deaf".</li>
<li>Some users mocked the ad while others defended its promotional intent.</li>
<li>PIA has resumed flights to Europe after a four-year ban due to safety concerns.</li>
<li>More than 300 passengers booked the inaugural flight from Islamabad to Paris.</li>
<li>PIA's ban resulted from past aviation incidents, with significant revenue losses reported.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Did the idiot who designed this graphic not see a PIA plane heading for the Eiffel Tower?" - Omar R. Quraishi</blockquote>
<p>The controversial ad has ignited discussions about sensitivity in advertising, particularly in aviation where past tragedies resonate deeply with the public.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2025/01/11/dismay-ridicule-over-pakistan-airlines-tone-deaf-ad-campaign-for-flights-to-france</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2025/01/11/dismay-ridicule-over-pakistan-airlines-tone-deaf-ad-campaign-for-flights-to-france</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 04:25:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump’s unconditional discharge in hush money case: Key takeaways - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump’s Unconditional Discharge in Hush Money Case: Key Takeaways</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250110144137_Donaldtrumprtr3.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="Trump’s party pledged in its platform to undo Biden’s executive order on AI, saying that it “imposes Radical Leftwing ideas” on the field" title="Trump’s party pledged in its platform to undo Biden’s executive order on AI, saying that it “imposes Radical Leftwing ideas” on the field"><figcaption>Trump’s party pledged in its platform to undo Biden’s executive order on AI, saying that it “imposes Radical Leftwing ideas” on the field.</figcaption><p>A New York court sentenced President-elect Donald Trump to an unconditional discharge in a hush money case involving payments to adult film actress Stormy Daniels. Despite his conviction, Trump avoids imprisonment due to his status as President-elect.</p><ul><li>Trump convicted on 34 counts of falsifying business records receives an unconditional discharge.</li><li>The ruling allows him to assume the presidency on January 20, 2025, despite his conviction.</li><li>He is the first U.S. president to face legal consequences in this manner.</li></ul><blockquote>“The only lawful sentence without compromising the presidency’s legal sanctity was an unconditional discharge.” - Judge Merchan</blockquote><p>This unprecedented situation raises questions about legal protections for elected officials and the impact on public trust in the legal system.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/judge-sentences-donald-trump-in-hush-money-case-but-declines-to-impose-any-punishment-12907783.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/judge-sentences-donald-trump-in-hush-money-case-but-declines-to-impose-any-punishment-12907783.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:04:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ahead of farewell address on Wednesday, Biden says party doubted he could ‘even move’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Reflects on Party Doubts Ahead of Farewell Address</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/biden_1736562705859_1736562706093.jpg" alt="Biden, who is set to deliver a farewell address to the nation next week, also added that Kamala Harris could have also beaten Trump.(AFP)" title="Biden, who is set to deliver a farewell address to the nation next week, also added that Kamala Harris could have also beaten Trump.(AFP)"><figcaption>Biden, who is set to deliver a farewell address to the nation next week, also added that Kamala Harris could have also beaten Trump.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>In a recent statement, outgoing US President Joe Biden expressed that doubts from his party about his ability to lead led to his decision to withdraw from the upcoming presidential race, despite believing he could win against Donald Trump.</p>
<ul>
<li>Biden stated he would have won the presidential election had he not stepped back for party unity.</li>
<li>He emphasized the importance of unifying the Democratic Party during a press conference.</li>
<li>Biden believes both he and Kamala Harris could have defeated Trump.</li>
<li>His farewell address is scheduled for January 15, where he will reflect on his public service career.</li>
<li>Despite controversies, Biden underscored his commitment to the party's success over personal ambitions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I thought I could win again, I thought it was better to unify the party.”</blockquote>
<p>Biden's withdrawal has been a significant topic, with many implications for the Democratic Party's future and strategies moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/ahead-of-farewell-address-on-wednesday-biden-says-party-doubted-he-could-even-move-101736560988024.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/ahead-of-farewell-address-on-wednesday-biden-says-party-doubted-he-could-even-move-101736560988024.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:04:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Despicable Charade': Trump Calls Out Democrats After Unconditional Discharge In Hush Money Case - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/despicable-charade-trump-calls-out-democrats-after-unconditional-discharge-in-hush-money-case-9185009.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/despicable-charade-trump-calls-out-democrats-after-unconditional-discharge-in-hush-money-case-9185009.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 03:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris ‘competent to run again and could have beaten Trump’: Biden - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Affirms Harris' Competence for 2024 Presidential Run</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>In a recent statement, President Biden expressed his belief that Vice President Kamala Harris is competent to run for president again in the 2024 election and suggested she could have defeated Trump in the previous election.</p><ul><li>Biden states Harris is 'competent to run again.'</li><li>He believes she could have won against Trump in the last election.</li></ul><blockquote>'She has what it takes to lead,' Biden remarked in his speech.</blockquote><p>This endorsement underscores Biden's support for his Vice President as they prepare for the 2024 presidential race.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/kamala-harris-competent-to-run-again-and-could-have-beaten-trump-biden/articleshow/117135516.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/kamala-harris-competent-to-run-again-and-could-have-beaten-trump-biden/articleshow/117135516.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris ‘competent to run again and could have beaten Trump’: Biden on presidential election - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Affirms Harris's Competence for 2024 Presidential Election</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified, <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>In a recent statement, President Joe Biden expressed confidence in Vice President Kamala Harris's capabilities to run for president again, suggesting she could have defeated Donald Trump in the past election.</p><ul><li>Biden believes Harris is ready and competent to run for office again.</li><li>He hinted that Harris had the capability to win against Trump in the previous election.</li><li>The statement emphasizes Biden’s support for Harris amid upcoming election talks.</li></ul><blockquote>“Harris is competent to run again and could have beaten Trump,” said Biden.</blockquote><p>This endorsement from Biden strengthens Harris's position and could influence Democratic strategies for the upcoming election.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/kamala-harris-competent-to-run-again-and-could-have-beaten-trump-biden/articleshow/117135516.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/kamala-harris-competent-to-run-again-and-could-have-beaten-trump-biden/articleshow/117135516.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biden extends legal status of nearly 1 million US immigrants for 18 months - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Extends Legal Status for Nearly 1 Million Immigrants</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Times of India</p><p>Biden's administration has extended the legal status of nearly 1 million immigrants for an additional 18 months, providing them with continued protection from deportation.</p><ul><li>The extension impacts DACA recipients and other groups.</li><li>This decision is seen as a significant relief for those immigrants whose status was set to expire.</li><li>The move reflects ongoing efforts by the Biden administration to address immigration reform.</li></ul><blockquote>"This extension allows our immigrant communities to continue contributing to our economy without the constant fear of deportation." - Administration Official</blockquote><p>The extension signifies a proactive approach by the Biden government towards immigrant rights and highlights ongoing discussions around immigration policy in the U.S.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/biden-extends-legal-status-of-nearly-1-million-us-immigrants-for-18-months/articleshow/117135296.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/biden-extends-legal-status-of-nearly-1-million-us-immigrants-for-18-months/articleshow/117135296.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 02:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biden to hail ‘stronger’ America in last foreign policy speech - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden to Hail 'Stronger' America in Last Foreign Policy Speech</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11th, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Dawn</p>
<img src='https://i.dawn.com/newskit-tts-service/1884396.84827b2e-0b18-4a6f-8d1d-8161263d1338.mp3' alt='Biden Speech Audio'><figcaption>Listen to the article</figcaption>
<p>Outgoing US president Joe Biden will give a farewell foreign policy speech, asserting that America is stronger now than when Donald Trump was in office.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Biden will speak at the State Department a week before leaving office.</li>
  <li>His speech will focus on the strengthened NATO alliance and support for Ukraine amid Russia's invasion.</li>
  <li>He will emphasize US alliances in the Asia-Pacific to address China's growing influence.</li>
  <li>Biden will mention support for Israel but does not address the peace deal in Gaza.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our alliances and partnerships are the strongest they’ve ever been thanks to our work,” a senior official stated.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Biden's address aims to sum up his foreign policy achievements before Trump's anticipated return to the presidency.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1884396/biden-to-hail-stronger-america-in-last-foreign-policy-speech</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1884396/biden-to-hail-stronger-america-in-last-foreign-policy-speech</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:52:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfires: What sparked the blaze? Investigators explore multiple causes - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires: What Sparked the Blaze?</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/LOS-ANGELES-FIRE-28_1736557214943_1736557226689.jpg" alt="A destroyed Chase bank branch during the Palisades Fire in the Pacific Palisades area of Los Angeles, California, US, on Friday, Jan. 10, 2025. (Bloomberg)" title="A destroyed Chase bank branch during the Palisades Fire in the Pacific Palisades area of Los Angeles, California, US, on Friday, Jan. 10, 2025. (Bloomberg)">
<figcaption>A destroyed Chase bank branch during the Palisades Fire in the Pacific Palisades area of Los Angeles, California, US, on Friday, Jan. 10, 2025. (Bloomberg)</figcaption>
<p>At least 11 people have died and thousands of homes and businesses have been destroyed in massive fires in the Los Angeles area, with investigators looking into possible ignition sources.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Investigators are examining multiple potential causes for the fires, having ruled out lightning.</li>
    <li>Prominent figures such as Hollywood stars Jamie Lee Curtis and Billy Crystal have lost their homes in the blaze.</li>
    <li>Utility line sparks and intentional fires are also being considered as possible sources of ignition.</li>
    <li>Southern California Edison has reported findings to regulators concerning the Eaton Fire.</li>
    <li>The 2017 Thomas Fire serves as a historical reference for similar incidents caused by utility lines.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It’s going to go out when it runs out of fuel, or when the weather stops,” said John Lentini, owner of Scientific Fire Analysis.</blockquote>
<p>The situation remains critical, with the fires continuing to spread and further investigations underway to determine the exact causes.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-what-sparked-the-blaze-investigators-explore-multiple-causes-101736555274054.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/california-wildfires-what-sparked-the-blaze-investigators-explore-multiple-causes-101736555274054.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 01:45:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California fire live updates: At least 11 dead in one of the deadliest Los Angeles blaze - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Wildfires: NFL Donates $5 Million for Relief Efforts</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/11/550x309/CALIFORNIA_WILDFIRES_1736558442715_1736558442951.JPG" alt="An aerial view shows debris from burned properties in Los Angeles" title="An aerial view shows debris from burned properties following the Palisades Fire in the Pacific Palisades neighbourhood in Los Angeles, California, US."><figcaption>An aerial view shows debris from burned properties following the Palisades Fire in the Pacific Palisades neighbourhood in Los Angeles, California, US.</figcaption><p>The report discusses the devastating impact of the ongoing wildfires in Los Angeles, with the NFL pledging $5 million to aid communities affected by the fires.</p><ul><li>At least 10 people have died due to the wildfires in California.</li><li>Over 10,000 homes and structures have been destroyed.</li><li>About 400 firefighters are actively working to combat the fires.</li><li>180,000 people are currently under evacuation orders.</li><li>AccuWeather estimates the financial loss from the fires to reach $135-$150 billion.</li></ul><blockquote>“Looting is a despicable crime,” said Los Angeles district attorney Nathan Hochman.</blockquote><p>The situation remains critical as the fires continue to rage, prompting urgent efforts for relief and recovery.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/california-wildfire-live-updates-los-angeles-united-states-death-toll-destruction-evacuation-10-january-2025-holywood-101736500460840.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/california-wildfire-live-updates-los-angeles-united-states-death-toll-destruction-evacuation-10-january-2025-holywood-101736500460840.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:09:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biden grants deportation protection to 900,000 immigrants just before Trump’s inauguration - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Grants Deportation Protection to 900,000 Immigrants Just Before Trump's Inauguration</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/New-Orleans-Car-Into-Crowd-Biden-19_1736331756435_1736543057996.jpg" alt="President Joe Biden speaks during an interfaith prayer service for the victims of the deadly New Years truck attack, at St. Louis Cathedral in New Orleans, Monday, Jan. 6, 2025. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)(AP)" title="President Joe Biden speaks during an interfaith prayer service for the victims of the deadly New Years truck attack, at St. Louis Cathedral in New Orleans, Monday, Jan. 6, 2025. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)(AP)"><figcaption>President Joe Biden speaks during an interfaith prayer service for the victims of the deadly New Years truck attack, at St. Louis Cathedral in New Orleans, Monday, Jan. 6, 2025. (AP Photo/Gerald Herbert)(AP)</figcaption><p>President Joe Biden’s administration has extended Temporary Protected Status (TPS) for 600,000 Venezuelans and over 200,000 Salvadorans, allowing them to remain in the US for an additional 18 months just before Donald Trump’s inauguration.</p><ul><li>The decision was made by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) citing ‘inhumane’ conditions under Venezuela's government.</li><li>Protections were also granted for about 100,000 people from Ukraine and 1,900 from Sudan.</li><li>This extension fulfills Biden's promise to protect vulnerable immigrant populations.</li><li>TPS has become a subject of controversy among Republicans regarding its broad application.</li><li>About 1 million people from various countries currently benefit from TPS in the US.</li></ul><blockquote>“TPS is intended to provide foreigners already in the US with protections from deportation amid political strife, natural disasters or armed conflict in their home countries.”</blockquote><p>The Biden administration's move underscores a protective stance towards immigrants amid impending policy changes expected from the Trump administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/biden-grants-deportation-protection-to-900-000-immigrants-just-before-trump-s-inauguration-101736542894893.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/biden-grants-deportation-protection-to-900-000-immigrants-just-before-trump-s-inauguration-101736542894893.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:05:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Air-to-air missile takes down a Ukrainian MiG-29 aircraft - Bulgarian Military]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOUkZsN2kyNENDcU5LSXhuWUl1SEd1aHlab3B0eWtFaVNrOVZmYzJOVGt4ak5OQTZWOEloaHpPeXhhenRiNWJzMWFpallxeEloQ2dRZS1YVkgzQTlhOU5Zamh4R1A2NklrUmQyYkxuWHZpNXNrenpZNnYwMnQzenJWbFRKZEtNSGF2eWdiNmZrc2t0LTl6Nk5tcUNJNDBLa2Vf0gGgAUFVX3lxTE5SRmw3aTI0Q0NxTktJeG5ZSXVIR3VoeVpvcHR5a0VpU2s5VmZjMk5Ua3hqTk5BNlY4SWhoek95eGF6dGI1YnMxYWlqWXF4SWhDZ1FlLVhWSDNBOWE5TllqaHhHUDY2SWtSZDJiTG5Ydmk1c2t6elk2djAydDN6clZsVEpkS01IYXZ5Z2I2Zmtza3QtOXo2Tm1xQ0k0MEtrZV8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMioAFBVV95cUxOUkZsN2kyNENDcU5LSXhuWUl1SEd1aHlab3B0eWtFaVNrOVZmYzJOVGt4ak5OQTZWOEloaHpPeXhhenRiNWJzMWFpallxeEloQ2dRZS1YVkgzQTlhOU5Zamh4R1A2NklrUmQyYkxuWHZpNXNrenpZNnYwMnQzenJWbFRKZEtNSGF2eWdiNmZrc2t0LTl6Nk5tcUNJNDBLa2Vf0gGgAUFVX3lxTE5SRmw3aTI0Q0NxTktJeG5ZSXVIR3VoeVpvcHR5a0VpU2s5VmZjMk5Ua3hqTk5BNlY4SWhoek95eGF6dGI1YnMxYWlqWXF4SWhDZ1FlLVhWSDNBOWE5TllqaHhHUDY2SWtSZDJiTG5Ydmk1c2t6elk2djAydDN6clZsVEpkS01IYXZ5Z2I2Zmtza3QtOXo2Tm1xQ0k0MEtrZV8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 20:55:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California fire live updates: Los Angeles fire larger than Manhattan - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California Fire Live Updates: Los Angeles Fire Larger Than Manhattan</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 11, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/CALIFORNIA-WILDFIRES--86_1736521271776_1736521291258.JPG" alt="Firefighters battle fire in the Angeles National Forest" title="Firefighters battle fire in the Angeles National Forest"><figcaption>Firefighters battle the fire in the Angeles National Forest near Mount Wilson as the wildfires burn in the Los Angeles area.</figcaption><p>California wildfires have resulted in at least 10 deaths and destroyed more than 10,000 structures, including homes and local landmarks. The fires have forced around 180,000 people to evacuate, with significant damage reported.</p><ul><li>The Kenneth fire started close to a school serving as an evacuation shelter.</li><li>The Eaton fire near Pasadena has burned over 5,000 structures.</li><li>The fires have consumed areas larger than Manhattan, affecting nearly 45 square miles.</li><li>Schools across the Los Angeles Unified School District are closed due to heavy smoke.</li><li>AccuWeather estimates property damage and economic loss could range from $135 billion to $150 billion.</li></ul><blockquote>“Looting is a despicable crime,” said LA district attorney Nathan Hochman.</blockquote><p>The wildfires continue to pose a significant threat to communities across Los Angeles, with efforts to contain the fires ongoing.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/california-wildfire-live-updates-los-angeles-united-states-death-toll-destruction-evacuation-10-january-2025-holywood-101736500460840.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/california-wildfire-live-updates-los-angeles-united-states-death-toll-destruction-evacuation-10-january-2025-holywood-101736500460840.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 19:45:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deadline to Apply for a Student Loan with FAFSA in 2025 - Here's Why You Shouldn't Wait Any Longer - BSEB Inter Org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Deadline to Apply for a Student Loan with FAFSA in 2025 - Here's Why You Shouldn't Wait Any Longer</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><img src="https://bsebinter.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Deadline-to-Apply-for-a-Student-Loan-with-FAFSA-in-2025-Heres-Why-You-Shouldnt-Wait-Any-Longer-1024x683.jpg" alt="Deadline to Apply for a Student Loan with FAFSA in 2025 - Here's Why You Shouldn't Wait Any Longer"><figcaption>Image depicting the deadline for FAFSA applications for 2025.</figcaption><p>The FAFSA application is now open, and the deadline to apply is June 30, 2025. Timely submission is crucial as funding is allocated on a first-come, first-served basis.</p><ul><li>FAFSA deadline is June 30, 2025, for AY 2025-2026.</li><li>Submitting the FAFSA early increases chances of receiving federal aid.</li><li>Processing times: paper version takes 7–10 days; online version takes 3–5 days.</li><li>Eligibility is dependent on the Expected Family Contribution (EFC).</li><li>Potential consequences for missing the deadline include loss of access to federal aid.</li></ul><blockquote>“Punctuality is a must when completing the FAFSA.”</blockquote><p>It's essential to complete your FAFSA promptly to secure necessary financial aid for college.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bsebinter.org/deadline-to-apply-for-a-student-loan-with-fafsa-in-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bsebinter.org/deadline-to-apply-for-a-student-loan-with-fafsa-in-2025/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 19:06:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US hits Russian oil with toughest sanctions yet in bid to give Ukraine, Trump leverage - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-hits-russian-oil-toughest-sanctions-yet-bid-give-ukraine-trump-leverage-2025-01-10/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/biden-hits-russian-oil-toughest-sanctions-yet-bid-give-ukraine-trump-leverage-2025-01-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:40:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Despicable charade, no merit’ says Donald Trump after unconditional discharge in hush money case - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Claims 'Witch Hunt' After Being Discharged in Hush Money Case</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 11, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/USA-TRUMP-NEW-YORK-91_1736533761930_1736533984969.JPG" alt="Donald Trump was sentenced to an unconditional discharge on Friday after being convicted of 34 felony counts(Jane Rosenberg/REUTERS)" /><figcaption>Donald Trump was sentenced to an unconditional discharge on Friday after being convicted of 34 felony counts(Jane Rosenberg/REUTERS)</figcaption></figure><p>Donald Trump expressed his outrage over the Biden-Harris administration's actions against him, labeling it a 'witch hunt' after receiving an unconditional discharge in his hush money trial despite 34 felony counts.</p><ul><li>Trump was convicted of 34 felony counts but received an unconditional discharge, avoiding jail time and fines.</li><li>He condemned the charges as baseless and claimed they were a result of political oppression.</li><li>Trump announced plans to appeal the case, which he called a 'hoax' and a 'scam'.</li><li>The case involved a $130,000 payment to an adult film star to prevent an affair from being disclosed during his presidential campaign.</li></ul><blockquote>“That result alone proves that, as all Legal Scholars and Experts have said, THERE IS NO CASE, THERE WAS NEVER A CASE, and this whole Scam fully deserves to be DISMISSED,” said Trump.</blockquote><p>This case highlights the ongoing legal battles Trump faces and has reignited his claims of being unjustly targeted by political opponents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/despicable-charade-no-merit-says-donald-trump-after-unconditional-discharge-in-hush-money-case-101736531648235.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/despicable-charade-no-merit-says-donald-trump-after-unconditional-discharge-in-hush-money-case-101736531648235.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:40:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Please don't disable': LA County apologizes for wrong evacuation alerts; Social media asks if anyone in - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>LA County Apologizes for Wrong Evacuation Alerts</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent<br><strong>Source:</strong> Local News</p><p>The Los Angeles County authorities have issued an apology following incorrect evacuation alerts that caused confusion among residents. Social media users have expressed frustration and questioned the management of these emergency notifications.</p><ul><li>Incorrect evacuation alerts were sent out to residents, causing panic.</li><li>The County acknowledged the error and is reviewing its alert system.</li><li>Social media reactions highlight the concerns regarding reliability in emergency communications.</li></ul><blockquote>“We sincerely apologize for the distress this has caused to our community.” - LA County Official</blockquote><p>This incident underscores the importance of accurate communication during emergencies and raises questions about the efficiency of the alert system in place.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/please-dont-disable-la-county-apologizes-for-wrong-evacuation-alerts-social-media-asks-if-anyone-in-charge-of-anything/articleshow/117128804.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/please-dont-disable-la-county-apologizes-for-wrong-evacuation-alerts-social-media-asks-if-anyone-in-charge-of-anything/articleshow/117128804.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oil prices rally 3% as US hits Russian oil with tougher sanctions By Reuters - Investing.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxNQ2d2QnRiaHgxdlBVbFJMQU5fanNPOVVIRTYxeS1YM3pZTTRNVHg1NEk4UV9NUUNhRlJoVDBiWFo0NEVVVWtFT0w1Y19EU3NQQWtxYVlETWNfQ3NFR2JUWjY0TkJtSE5xaktHM1dSSF9ULTJUanIzRVJvSnJEV2JNVTF3NTlncXI0SFZ2ejRvNTAtZXFmOHZpM1B1eUFhU1QtYlhUSHIyRXVkY1pNVFRWd0puTTFNUmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxNQ2d2QnRiaHgxdlBVbFJMQU5fanNPOVVIRTYxeS1YM3pZTTRNVHg1NEk4UV9NUUNhRlJoVDBiWFo0NEVVVWtFT0w1Y19EU3NQQWtxYVlETWNfQ3NFR2JUWjY0TkJtSE5xaktHM1dSSF9ULTJUanIzRVJvSnJEV2JNVTF3NTlncXI0SFZ2ejRvNTAtZXFmOHZpM1B1eUFhU1QtYlhUSHIyRXVkY1pNVFRWd0puTTFNUmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 18:04:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia reacts to Trump's claim of setting up talks with Putin: ‘Looks like things…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kremlin acknowledges Trump's claims of a meeting with Putin, suggesting mutual interest in dialogue. They believe progress will commence after his inauguration.</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/FILES_1732892427973_1736527039064.jpg" alt="Vladimir Putin showers praises on Donald Trump in a tone that is in stark contrast to past rhetoric (Photo by Yuri KADOBNOV / AFP)(AFP)"><figcaption>Vladimir Putin showers praises on Donald Trump in a tone that is in stark contrast to past rhetoric (Photo by Yuri KADOBNOV / AFP)(AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>The Kremlin has responded positively to President-Elect Donald Trump’s claims of a potential meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin, indicating a mutual interest in dialogue as Trump prepares for his inauguration on January 20.</p><ul><li>Kremlin confirms Trump’s claims of a meeting with Putin.</li><li>Russia expresses openness to talk without preconditions.</li><li>Dmitry Peskov emphasizes the need for a mutual desire to engage in dialogue.</li><li>Trump claims they are setting up a meeting to discuss the Ukraine-Russia war.</li><li>Ukrainian officials express concerns over potential U.S. aid cuts under Trump.</li></ul><blockquote>“President Putin wants to meet. He has said that even publicly and we have to get that war over with. That's a bloody mess.” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>This development suggests potential diplomatic engagement between the U.S. and Russia, highlighting the significance of international relations in the upcoming administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/russia-reacts-to-trumps-claim-of-setting-up-talks-with-putin-looks-like-things-101736523958999.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/russia-reacts-to-trumps-claim-of-setting-up-talks-with-putin-looks-like-things-101736523958999.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 17:01:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IDF strikes targets in Yemen as Israel threatens to hunt down Houthi leaders - The Times of Israel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>20 Israeli jets attack two ports and a power plant used by Houthis in Yemen</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of Israel</p>
<img src="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2025/01/dd722d8a-0d94-4d4e-be35-46356ac20523-640x400.jpg" alt="IAF F-16I fighter jets prepare to take off" width="600" height="375">
<figcaption>IAF F-16I fighter jets prepare to take off from the Ramon Airbase in southern Israel for strikes against the Houthis in Yemen, January 10, 2025. (Israel Defense Forces)</figcaption>
<p>The Israeli Air Force conducted significant airstrikes against Houthi targets in Yemen, targeting key sites including ports and a power plant, and issued warnings to the group over its ongoing missile and drone attacks.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Over 20 Israeli aircraft were involved in the strikes, dropping around 50 munitions.</li>
  <li>Main targets included the Hodeidah and Ras Isa ports, and the Hezyaz power plant.</li>
  <li>The IDF stated the power plant was crucial for the Houthi military operations.</li>
  <li>Israeli leaders warned of further action if attacks on Israel persisted.</li>
  <li>Netanyahu emphasized the need to counter Iranian influence via the Houthis.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"As we promised, the Houthis are paying, and will continue to pay, a heavy price for their aggression against us." - Benjamin Netanyahu</blockquote>
<p>The Israeli airstrikes represent a continuing escalation in the conflict, reflecting the regional tension stemming from Iran's involvement and the threat posed to Israel.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesofisrael.com/idf-strikes-targets-in-yemen-as-israel-threatens-to-hunt-down-houthi-leaders/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesofisrael.com/idf-strikes-targets-in-yemen-as-israel-threatens-to-hunt-down-houthi-leaders/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 16:48:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kenneth Fire arsonist suspect claims he was using blowtorch to smoke marijuana; detained by locals in dra - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kenneth Fire arsonist suspect claims he was using blowtorch to smoke marijuana; detained by locals in dramatic video</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>In a dramatic incident captured on video, a suspect accused of starting a fire in Kenneth claims he was merely using a blowtorch to smoke marijuana. Local residents intervened and detained him.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The incident involves a suspect who allegedly ignited a fire.</li>
  <li>Locals detained the suspect, showcasing a community response to the crisis.</li>
  <li>The suspect claims his intention was to use the blowtorch for smoking marijuana.</li>
  <li>The video of the event has circulated widely, highlighting the dramatic nature of the situation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I was just trying to smoke, man!” – The suspect's statement during the confrontation.</blockquote>
<p>This incident raises questions about fire safety and community vigilance in addressing potential threats. The dramatic nature of the detainment emphasizes the role of local involvement in crisis situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/kenneth-fire-arsonist-suspect-claims-he-was-using-blowtorch-to-smoke-marijuana-detained-by-locals-in-dramatic-video/articleshow/117125535.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/kenneth-fire-arsonist-suspect-claims-he-was-using-blowtorch-to-smoke-marijuana-detained-by-locals-in-dramatic-video/articleshow/117125535.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump 1st US President To Be Sentenced As Felon, But Avoids Jail, Penalty - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Becomes First US President Sentenced as Felon, Escapes Jail Time</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>January 25, 2025 | <strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p><div><img alt="Stormy Daniels had testified in vivid detail about her alleged encounter with Trump in a hotel in Navada." src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2025-01/d29oiflk_stormy-daniels-reuters_625x300_10_January_25.jpg"><figcaption>Stormy Daniels had testified in vivid detail about her alleged encounter with Trump in a hotel in Navada.</figcaption></div><p>Donald Trump has made history by becoming the first felon in the White House, as a US court upholds his conviction in a hush money case. Although he was sentenced to an 'unconditional discharge', he will not serve jail time due to his position as President-elect.</p><ul><li>Trump was convicted of falsifying business records related to payments made to Stormy Daniels.</li><li>He faced potential jail time of four years but was spared due to presidential immunity.</li><li>Judge Juan Merchan described the circumstances as unique and remarked on the legal implications of sentencing a sitting president.</li><li>Trump did not attend the court session in person and instead appeared virtually.</li><li>He characterized the legal proceedings as damaging to his reputation and a setback for the New York court system.</li></ul><blockquote>"This court has determined that the only lawful sentence that permits entry of a judgement of conviction without encroaching on the highest office of the land, is an unconditional discharge." - Judge Juan Merchan</blockquote><blockquote>"It was done to damage my reputation, just so that I may lose the election." - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>In a significant ruling, this event illustrates the complexities of legal accountability at the highest levels of government, setting a precedent for the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-becomes-1st-us-president-to-be-sentenced-as-a-felon-avoids-jail-time-7445027</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-becomes-1st-us-president-to-be-sentenced-as-a-felon-avoids-jail-time-7445027</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:24:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US to impose sanctions on Russian oil fleet and traders, document shows - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/new-us-sanctions-russian-tankers-hit-oil-supplies-india-refining-sources-say-2025-01-10/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/new-us-sanctions-russian-tankers-hit-oil-supplies-india-refining-sources-say-2025-01-10/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:24:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hush money case: US judge sentences Donald Trump, declines to impose jail term, fine - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Sentenced in Hush Money Case</h1><p><strong>Date: January 10, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/USA-TRUMP-NEW-YORK-49_1736522354982_1736522376464.JPG" alt="Todd Blanche, attorney for former US President Donald Trump, and US President-elect Donald Trump at Manhattan criminal court in New York." title="Todd Blanche, attorney for former US President Donald Trump, and US President-elect Donald Trump at Manhattan criminal court in New York."><figcaption>Todd Blanche, attorney for former US President Donald Trump, and US President-elect Donald Trump are seen on the screen at Manhattan criminal court in New York.(Reuters)</figcaption><p>A US judge sentenced President-elect Donald Trump over a criminal conviction related to hush money paid to a porn star. The verdict marks the first felony conviction for a US president, but Trump will not face jail or a fine.</p><ul><li>The judge imposed the mildest criminal sanction available: an unconditional discharge.</li><li>Judge Juan M Merchan cited unique circumstances surrounding the case.</li><li>Trump was convicted on 34 counts of falsifying business records.</li><li>He claims the conviction is intended to sabotage his presidential campaign.</li></ul><blockquote>"Never before has this court been presented with such a unique and remarkable set of circumstances." - Judge Juan M Merchan</blockquote><p>The case revolves around a payment of $130,000 to Stormy Daniels, made to suppress disclosure about an alleged encounter during Trump's 2016 campaign. Trump denied the encounter and claimed the verdict was politically motivated.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/hush-money-case-us-judge-sentences-donald-trump-declines-to-impose-jail-fine-101736522223806.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/hush-money-case-us-judge-sentences-donald-trump-declines-to-impose-jail-fine-101736522223806.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:17:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gnanasara: Controversial Sri Lankan monk jailed for insulting Islam - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gnanasara: Controversial Sri Lankan monk jailed for insulting Islam</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>A hardline Sri Lankan monk, Galagodaatte Gnanasara, has been sentenced to nine months in prison for insulting Islam and inciting religious hatred during remarks made in 2016.</p><ul><li>Convicted by the Colombo Magistrate's Court, marking his second jail term over hate speech.</li><li>Previously received a presidential pardon in 2019 for a six-year sentence related to intimidation.</li><li>Gnanasara was also fined 1,500 Sri Lankan rupees (approximately $5) by the court.</li><li>He has filed an appeal against this sentence and was denied bail during the appeal process.</li><li>During his previous tenure, he was closely allied with former president Gotabaya Rajapaksa.</li></ul><blockquote>“All citizens, regardless of religion, are entitled to the freedom of belief under the Constitution.”</blockquote><p>This ruling represents a rare conviction for a Buddhist monk in Sri Lanka, signaling a potential shift in handling hate speech related to religious intolerance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce8jdy8j41lo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce8jdy8j41lo</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:15:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Porn star hush money case: Trump avoids jail term, Judge imposes unconditional discharge - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Porn star hush money case: Trump avoids jail term, Judge imposes unconditional discharge</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p><p>Former President Donald Trump has managed to avoid serving time in connection with the hush money payments made during the 2016 election campaign, as a judge sentenced him to an unconditional discharge.</p><ul><li>Trump was involved in a legal dispute concerning payments made to silence allegations of an affair.</li><li>The judge ruled favorably for Trump, leading to no jail time.</li><li>This case continues to generate substantial media coverage and public interest.</li></ul><blockquote>"This case illustrates the complexities of politics and legal obligations around financial settlements in campaigns."</blockquote><p>Despite avoiding jail, the case raises important questions about campaign finance and ethical conduct in political spheres.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/hush-money-case-donald-trump-sentenced-to-unconditional-discharge/articleshow/117124963.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/hush-money-case-donald-trump-sentenced-to-unconditional-discharge/articleshow/117124963.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘California in exchange’: Trudeau says he once made a counteroffer to Trump over US-Canada merger suggestion - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trudeau Jokingly Offered Trade to Trump Over US-Canada Merger Proposal</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 10, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/10/550x309/Canada-US-Trump-Tariffs-0_1733889652905_1736514836520.jpg" alt="Justin Trudeau explained that the President-elect's comment about Canada's merger with the US was merely a tactic to divert attention. (AP Photo/File)(AP)" title="Justin Trudeau explained that the President-elect's comment about Canada's merger with the US was merely a tactic to divert attention. (AP Photo/File)(AP)">
<figcaption>Justin Trudeau explained that the President-elect's comment about Canada's merger with the US was merely a tactic to divert attention. (AP Photo/File)(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau recently reflected on a humorous exchange with US President-elect Donald Trump regarding a merger of Canada and the United States. Trudeau stated he jokingly offered to trade Vermont and California in response to Trump's suggestion that Canada become the 51st state.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trudeau described Trump's merger proposal as a tactic to divert attention from his tariff plans.</li>
  <li>Trump's proposed 25% tariff on Canadian imports may lead to inflation in the US, according to Trudeau.</li>
  <li>Trudeau emphasized there is no chance Canada will become part of the US, asserting national sovereignty.</li>
  <li>Trump is reportedly considering declaring a national economic emergency for tariff implementation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote> Trudeau stated, "There isn't a snowball's chance in hell that Canada would become part of the United States." </blockquote>
<p>In summary, Trudeau's lighthearted counteroffer highlights the serious underlying tensions regarding trade and tariffs between the two nations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/give-us-california-vermont-justin-trudeau-recalls-counter-offer-to-trump-over-us-canada-merger-101736514550279.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/give-us-california-vermont-justin-trudeau-recalls-counter-offer-to-trump-over-us-canada-merger-101736514550279.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:57:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: Massive fire erupts in New York apartment, 7 injured - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Massive Fire in New York Apartment Leaves 7 Injured</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Local News Network</p><p>A significant fire broke out in a residential apartment building in New York, resulting in injuries to seven people. Eyewitness reports describe the scene as chaotic, with emergency services responding rapidly to contain the flames.</p><ul><li>The fire erupted late at night, causing an immediate evacuation of residents.</li><li>Seven individuals were treated for smoke inhalation and other injuries.</li><li>Firefighters battled the blaze for several hours before bringing it under control.</li><li>The cause of the fire is currently under investigation.</li></ul><blockquote>“This was a terrifying experience,” said one resident. “I never thought I’d have to escape a fire from my apartment.”</blockquote><p>Emergency services continue to assess the damage and provide support to those affected.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/video-massive-fire-erupts-in-new-york-apartment-7-injured/articleshow/117124676.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/video-massive-fire-erupts-in-new-york-apartment-7-injured/articleshow/117124676.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>