<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:24:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:24:35 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Girl, you are no longer Canada's governor': Elon Musk's scathing dig at Justin Trudeau - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Girl, you are no longer Canada's governor: Elon Musk's scathing dig at Justin Trudeau</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250108114303_m.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Elon Musk and Justin Trudeau"/><figcaption>Elon Musk and Justin Trudeau, influential figures in their respective countries.</figcaption><p>Elon Musk recently took a jab at Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, who announced his resignation earlier this week. This comes in response to Trudeau's firm stance against suggestions that Canada could become an American territory.</p><ul><li>Musk referred to Trudeau as a "girl" in his critique on social media.</li><li>Trudeau firmly stated there is "no chance in hell" Canada would become part of the United States.</li><li>This back-and-forth arose from ongoing tensions regarding cross-border relations and trade.</li></ul><blockquote>“Girl, you’re not the governor of Canada anymore, so doesn’t matter what you say.” - Elon Musk</blockquote><p>This exchange highlights the ongoing political rivalry and discussions around national sovereignty and identity in the context of international relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/girl-you-no-longer-canada-s-governor-elon-musk-s-scathing-dig-at-justin-trudeau-12905977.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/girl-you-no-longer-canada-s-governor-elon-musk-s-scathing-dig-at-justin-trudeau-12905977.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:43:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump mulls a national emergency declaration to allow for new tariff program - report - ForexLive]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Considers National Emergency to Implement New Tariff Program</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p>
<p>This article discusses former President Trump's consideration of declaring a national economic emergency to impose new tariffs on various countries, potentially impacting international trade relations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump may declare a national economic emergency.</li>
  <li>This would allow him to impose tariffs under the International Economic Emergency Powers Act.</li>
  <li>No final decision has been made yet, but all options remain on the table.</li>
  <li>Markets are reacting, with USD showing mixed movements against other currencies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Nothing is off the table." - Sources on Trump's considerations.</blockquote>
<p>This potential move could significantly alter market dynamics and international trade relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forexlive.com/news/trump-mulls-a-national-emergency-declaration-to-allow-for-new-tariff-program-report-20250108/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forexlive.com/news/trump-mulls-a-national-emergency-declaration-to-allow-for-new-tariff-program-report-20250108/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk 'calls' Canada's outgoing PM Justin Trudeau: Girl, you’re not the .... - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk 'calls' Canada's outgoing PM Justin Trudeau: Girl, you’re not the ....</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>N/A</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>N/A</p><div><p>An unexpected phone call from Elon Musk to outgoing Prime Minister Justin Trudeau raised eyebrows, featuring surprising remarks that have sparked discussions online.</p></div><ul><li>Elon Musk took the initiative to call Justin Trudeau.</li><li>Speculation surrounds the nature of their conversation.</li><li>The call has gone viral on social media platforms.</li><li>Public response includes a mix of surprise and criticism.</li></ul><blockquote>“Girl, you’re not the president of the world.”</blockquote><p>This event highlights the evolving dynamics between influential figures and political leaders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-calls-canadas-former-pm-justin-trudeau-girl-youre-not-the-/articleshow/117054636.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-calls-canadas-former-pm-justin-trudeau-girl-youre-not-the-/articleshow/117054636.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Canadian Official Counters Trump's 51st State Proposal: "How About We Buy..." - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-official-counters-trumps-51st-state-proposal-how-about-we-buy-7427423</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-official-counters-trumps-51st-state-proposal-how-about-we-buy-7427423</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:48:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ukraine claims attack on oil depot serving air base for Russian nuclear bombers - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOT1pYQ25tVU1uZThKNG9PQmlFYXdnMjVtTUQ4SkNkUlM4TUs5OERfT212LVFucDlpNWVkSUd6aXhyX3N2VFRMV05uNk9kT3gzYzljVjhSUXFMRUZHNzV6ZVM4bElrVE1aQ0hYOEt6bU5kQmNrWUM3TXNVNDZIaXhWbnRWMGNfMk1vRFBGWlZCMkNreXpITTZtZnpjczI4aGd3ZmtzeEpNRmowcUJocnpuemM0aFpsMW9jRkRRQW1HSVJoOEU4bjlDQg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOT1pYQ25tVU1uZThKNG9PQmlFYXdnMjVtTUQ4SkNkUlM4TUs5OERfT212LVFucDlpNWVkSUd6aXhyX3N2VFRMV05uNk9kT3gzYzljVjhSUXFMRUZHNzV6ZVM4bElrVE1aQ0hYOEt6bU5kQmNrWUM3TXNVNDZIaXhWbnRWMGNfMk1vRFBGWlZCMkNreXpITTZtZnpjczI4aGd3ZmtzeEpNRmowcUJocnpuemM0aFpsMW9jRkRRQW1HSVJoOEU4bjlDQg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:47:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump Says He Wants No Wind Turbines Built During Administration - Energy Connects]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxOVXlVdG1NRjJMb3lzRmRWVnlkbjhNNXhvWE9nakRlSWR5WGJmems4ZnFFUjVXVWItMllEZy1KMWk1TTVrelY2MUNIUDVIOWtjOEFiZkY2eGY1cGpraC1QRXNHbnI0RUxnVlNkNFlub2lwbXVHZDNreXVqbktPdFRZT3JCVGpMb1lrcjliWmNNamc1cWVfWHhQcEo1TnVBbEQ2N1Bnal9VV2pXX1EzX3oyNGE3RHNzWXVoay1nT2IxT0pKUHM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxOVXlVdG1NRjJMb3lzRmRWVnlkbjhNNXhvWE9nakRlSWR5WGJmems4ZnFFUjVXVWItMllEZy1KMWk1TTVrelY2MUNIUDVIOWtjOEFiZkY2eGY1cGpraC1QRXNHbnI0RUxnVlNkNFlub2lwbXVHZDNreXVqbktPdFRZT3JCVGpMb1lrcjliWmNNamc1cWVfWHhQcEo1TnVBbEQ2N1Bnal9VV2pXX1EzX3oyNGE3RHNzWXVoay1nT2IxT0pKUHM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:31:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Lights, car engines left on': Monster wildfire sparks panicked evacuations in Los Angeles - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lights, car engines left on: Monster wildfire sparks panicked evacuations in Los Angeles</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>This article discusses a significant wildfire that has prompted widespread evacuations in Los Angeles, causing panic among residents as they flee the advancing flames.</p><ul><li>The wildfire has quickly spread, leading to emergency responses.</li><li>Authorities have issued evacuation orders for multiple neighborhoods.</li><li>Residents reported scenes of chaos, with people leaving their vehicles running in their haste to escape.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was terrifying; you could see the flames getting closer,” said one resident.</blockquote><p>The wildfire in Los Angeles poses a serious threat to life and property, urging immediate action from residents and responders alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/lights-car-engines-left-on-monster-wildfire-sparks-panicked-evacuations-in-los-angeles/articleshow/117050034.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/lights-car-engines-left-on-monster-wildfire-sparks-panicked-evacuations-in-los-angeles/articleshow/117050034.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mercedes Benz goes on rampage against teen cyclists, they corner driver and destroy car. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Teen Cyclists Assault Driver After Mercedes Benz Rampage in Los Angeles</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/car_1736328803639_1736328812701.png" alt="The terrifying clip shows the white car zipping past cyclists and dodging them while speeding away.(X/@NewsM101)"><figcaption>The terrifying clip shows the white car zipping past cyclists and dodging them while speeding away.(X/@NewsM101)</figcaption><p>In a troubling incident in Los Angeles, a group of teenage cyclists confronted a driver of a speeding Mercedes Benz, leading to an aggressive altercation.</p><ul><li>A Mercedes Benz driver sped through a group of cyclists, narrowly avoiding them.</li><li>Teen cyclists, angered by the driver's actions, attacked his car after he attempted to leave the scene.</li><li>The attack included vandalizing the car and smashing its windows.</li><li>Local residents reported that large groups of cyclists are common in the area, often receiving support from bystanders.</li><li>Reactions on social media were mixed, with arguments for both the driver's recklessness and the cyclists' response.</li></ul><blockquote>"Driving too hard into upcoming traffic, reckless endangerment of others." - Social media user</blockquote><p>The incident raises questions about road safety and the behavior of all parties involved, highlighting the tensions that can arise in shared road spaces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/mercedes-benz-goes-on-rampage-against-teen-cyclists-they-corner-driver-and-destroy-car-watch-101736327550180.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/mercedes-benz-goes-on-rampage-against-teen-cyclists-they-corner-driver-and-destroy-car-watch-101736327550180.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:35:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Sheikh Hasina, now Khaleda Zia leaves Bangladesh...what is the reason behind her sudden decision? - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Khaleda Zia Leaves Bangladesh for Medical Treatment</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Sheikh-hasina-and-Khaleda-Zia.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="After Sheikh Hasina, now Khaleda Zia leaves Bangladesh...what is the reason behind her sudden decision?"><figcaption></figcaption><p>Former Bangladeshi Prime Minister Khaleda Zia departed for London aboard an air ambulance for medical treatment, accompanied by party leaders. Her departure adds to the political uncertainty in Bangladesh, especially with upcoming general elections.</p><ul><li>Khaleda Zia is undergoing treatment for liver cirrhosis, heart disease, and kidney issues.</li><li>Sheikh Hasina, another significant political figure, has already fled to India amid political turmoil.</li><li>The political landscape in Bangladesh is unstable with elections approaching.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bangladesh is presently grappling with political instability.”</blockquote><p>Khaleda Zia's departure could significantly impact the future of both her party and the nation's political dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/after-sheikh-hasina-now-khaleda-zia-leaves-bangladesh-what-is-the-reason-behind-her-sudden-decision-7523027/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/after-sheikh-hasina-now-khaleda-zia-leaves-bangladesh-what-is-the-reason-behind-her-sudden-decision-7523027/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:24:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 political bombs Trump dropped in his marathon press conference - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Political Bombs Trump Dropped in His Marathon Press Conference</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> AP</p>
<img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2025/01/Trump-2025-01-1ae0f506c97203bd7a31ccde2d29cb70-1200x675.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Trump Press Conference" title="Trump Press Conference">
<figcaption>President-elect Donald Trump speaks during a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday, Jan. 7, 2025, in Palm Beach, Fla.</figcaption>
<p>In a marathon press conference in Florida, Donald Trump dropped political bombs, dismissing climate concerns and making bold claims about territorial expansion.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump expressed interest in acquiring Greenland, claiming it was in the U.S. national interest.</li>
  <li>He made provocative comments about Canada and the Panama Canal, drawing sharp rebukes from both countries.</li>
  <li>Trump threatened NATO allies and downplayed the January 6 Capitol riots.</li>
  <li>He aimed to take credit for peace talks in West Asia involving Israel and Hamas.</li>
  <li>Trump labeled climate change as a hoax and criticized the Biden administration's environmental policies.</li>
  <li>He praised Elon Musk amid controversy surrounding Musk's comments on global political issues.</li>
  <li>Trump reiterated his views on pardoning supporters related to the Capitol attack.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“All hell is going to break loose in the Middle East if they are not back before I take office.”</blockquote>
<p>The press conference exemplified Trump's characteristic rhetoric, signaling a contentious and unpredictable second term ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/world/7-political-bombs-trump-dropped-in-his-marathon-press-conference-13850916.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/world/7-political-bombs-trump-dropped-in-his-marathon-press-conference-13850916.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US is giving billions of dollars to Pakistan's enemy, Pakistan army and ISI are...., the enemy is... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Sends Billions to Taliban, Raising Concerns for Pakistan</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><p>Pakistan is facing increasing tensions as the U.S. reportedly funnels billions to the Taliban, raising alarms in Islamabad. This funding reportedly empowers the Taliban and threatens Pakistan's security.</p><ul><li>U.S. Congressional report claims Biden administration sends USD 40 million weekly to the Taliban, totaling approximately USD 3.5 billion.</li><li>Concerns raised over foreign aid causing unintended support for the Taliban amidst ongoing military threats to Pakistan.</li><li>Elon Musk and other public figures express outrage on social media regarding U.S. taxpayer money supporting the Taliban.</li></ul><blockquote>“Can you imagine that these terrorists are receiving USD 40 million of our tax money every week?” — Lara Logan</blockquote><p>This funding allows the Taliban to bolster their military capabilities, posing a direct threat to Pakistan and its military.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/us-is-giving-billions-of-dollars-to-pakistans-enemy-pakistan-army-and-isi-are-in-trouble-worried-the-enemy-is-taliban-in-afghanistan-sigar-report-7522199/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/us-is-giving-billions-of-dollars-to-pakistans-enemy-pakistan-army-and-isi-are-in-trouble-worried-the-enemy-is-taliban-in-afghanistan-sigar-report-7522199/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:58:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EU warns of 'serious blow' from Trump on climate change - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/eu-warns-serious-blow-trump-climate-change-2025-01-08/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/eu-warns-serious-blow-trump-climate-change-2025-01-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Oh Canada’: Trump shares map with 51 US states - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump's Controversial Map: Is America Now 51 States?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> The Times</p><p>Donald Trump recently sparked attention by sharing a map that depicts the United States as having 51 states. This surprising act has raised eyebrows and generated discussions regarding its implications.</p><ul><li>Trump shared a map on social media suggesting the USA has 51 states.</li><li>The map's origins and reasoning behind the addition of a new state are unclear.</li><li>This image has generated a mix of amusement and concern among the public.</li><li>Reactions from political figures and Twitter users have varied widely.</li></ul><blockquote>'It's more of a faux pas than a policy statement,' said one political analyst.</blockquote><p>The incident highlights the often-blurred lines between social media and official political discourse.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/oh-canada-trump-shares-map-with-51-us-states/articleshow/117042228.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/oh-canada-trump-shares-map-with-51-us-states/articleshow/117042228.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 05:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Is Trump Threatening To Take Greenland, Panama Canal, Canada? His Imperialist Agenda Explained - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-is-trump-threatening-to-take-greenland-panama-canal-canada-his-imperialist-agenda-explained-9181542.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/explainers/why-is-trump-threatening-to-take-greenland-panama-canal-canada-his-imperialist-agenda-explained-9181542.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Oh Canada!’: Donald Trump shares distorted unified US-Canada map, Justin Trudeau's Liberal Party responds - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump shares distorted map showing Canada as part of the United States</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US_1736311434165_1736311434433.jpg" alt="Donald Trump shares distorted unified US-Canada map" />
<figcaption>Donald Trump shares distorted unified US-Canada map (Photo by SCOTT OLSON / GETTY IMAGES NORTH AMERICA / Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption>
<p>Donald Trump posted a distorted map suggesting Canada should be part of the US alongside a caption on Truth Social. This has drawn a swift response from Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's Liberal Party.</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump's post referenced a distorted vision of a unified US and Canada.</li>
<li>The Canadian Liberal Party posted a response distinguishing the US from Canada.</li>
<li>Trump has previously expressed interest in integrating Canada as the 51st state.</li>
<li>He suggested using "economic force" rather than military to pursue this ambition.</li>
<li>Trudeau firmly rejected the notion, stating there's no chance Canada would join the US.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There isn’t a snowball’s chance in hell that Canada would become part of the United States.” - Justin Trudeau</blockquote>
<p>This incident underscores the ongoing tensions and differing views regarding US-Canada relations, highlighting Trump's controversial approach to foreign policy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-distorted-unified-us-canada-map-justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-responds-101736311061282.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-distorted-unified-us-canada-map-justin-trudeaus-liberal-party-responds-101736311061282.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:47:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles: Pacific Palisades wildfire destroys cars and houses, forcing 30,000 to evacuate | Updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Los Angeles: Pacific Palisades Wildfire Destroys Cars and Houses, Forcing 30,000 to Evacuate</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-70_1736307148546_1736307193321.jpg" alt="Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)" title="Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)">
<figcaption>Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>A dangerous wildfire is raging in Pacific Palisades, Los Angeles, devastating nearly 3,000 acres and forcing over 30,000 residents to evacuate. The fire is exacerbated by hurricane-force winds.</p>
<ul>
<li>A wildfire in Los Angeles raged across an upscale section amid a fierce windstorm hitting Southern California.</li>
<li>The fire erupted midmorning and swelled quickly, taking many residents by surprise.</li>
<li>The fire came as the area was being hit by seasonal Santa Ana winds, with gusts up to 100 miles (160 kilometres) an hour expected.</li>
<li>The fire swiftly consumed nearly 2 square miles (just over 5 square kilometres) of land.</li>
<li>Hundreds of firefighters are on site, tackling the blaze from both ground and air.</li>
<li>Los Angeles Fire Department Chief Kristin Crowley confirmed there were no immediate reports of casualties.</li>
<li>The American city has declared a state of emergency over the fire.</li>
<li>As a result of strong winds, 28,300 households are without power.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Despite the frantic evacuations...over 30,000 people were ordered to evacuate the region.” - Los Angeles Fire Department Chief Kristin Crowley</blockquote>
<p>The wildfire has led to significant disruptions as residents evacuate and infrastructure is compromised, highlighting the ongoing challenges posed by climate-related disasters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:30:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles: Pacific Palisades destroys cars and houses, forcing 30,000 to evacuate | Updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wildfire in Pacific Palisades Forces Mass Evacuations in Los Angeles</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src='https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-70_1736307148546_1736307193321.jpg' alt='Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)'><figcaption>Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)</figcaption><p>A dangerous wildfire in Pacific Palisades has devastated nearly 3,000 acres and forced over 30,000 residents to evacuate amid fierce windstorms.</p><ul><li>The blaze leveled homes and forced mass evacuations.</li><li>Strong winds are complicating firefighting efforts, leading to widespread panic.</li><li>Firefighters are working to contain the fire from both ground and air.</li><li>No immediate reports of deaths or injuries have been reported.</li><li>Federal aid has been approved to assist with firefighting efforts.</li></ul><blockquote>“Despite the chaotic evacuation, there were no immediate reports of any deaths or injuries.” - Los Angeles Fire Department Chief Kristin Crowley</blockquote><p>The ongoing wildfire represents a significant threat to residents and property, and immediate efforts are underway to combat and contain the flames.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:30:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles wildfire: Pacific Palisades declares emergency, President Joe Biden approves aid | Updates - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wildfire in Pacific Palisades Forces 30,000 to Evacuate</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US-WEATHER-FIRE-70_1736307148546_1736307193321.jpg" alt="Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)" title="Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)"><figcaption>Los Angeles wildfire: The blaze further engulfed an area packed with multimillion-dollar homes in the Santa Monica Mountains.(AFP)</figcaption></figure><p>A dangerous wildfire has ravaged the Pacific Palisades area of Los Angeles, destroying nearly 3,000 acres of land and forcing over 30,000 residents to evacuate. The situation has been exacerbated by hurricane-force winds.</p><ul><li>The fire erupted midmorning amid seasonal Santa Ana winds.</li><li>Firefighters are working on the ground and from the air to contain the blaze.</li><li>As of Tuesday evening, over 28,300 households were without power.</li></ul><blockquote>“There are no immediate reports of any deaths or injuries.” - Kristin Crowley, Chief of Los Angeles Fire Department</blockquote><p>This wildfire marks a significant emergency in the region, prompting federal aid approval from President Joe Biden.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-city-declares-emergency-president-joe-biden-approves-aid-updates-101736306822695.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:30:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump warns ‘all hell will break out’ if hostages in Gaza are not freed - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump warns ‘all hell will break out’ if hostages in Gaza are not freed</h1>
<p><strong>Published: 08 January 2025, Source: Deccan Herald</strong></p>
<p>President-elect Donald Trump issued a stern warning regarding the hostages held by Hamas during a news conference at his Mar-a-Lago estate, stating that severe repercussions will follow if they are not released by Inauguration Day.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump emphasized that if hostages are not released by his inauguration, “all hell will break out in the Middle East.”</li>
  <li>There are approximately 100 hostages, including Americans, currently held captive since October 7, 2023.</li>
  <li>Negotiations for the release of these hostages have been ongoing, with both Biden's and Trump's teams expressing a unified front.</li>
  <li>Trump did not specify potential actions he might take if hostages are not released.</li>
  <li>Experts express skepticism regarding the efficacy of Trump’s threats against Hamas.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Bluster is the worst form of policy.” - Daniel Kurtzer, former US ambassador to Israel</blockquote>
<p>The implications of Trump's comments raise questions about the dynamics of negotiations in light of the upcoming administration. While both Biden's and Trump's teams are striving towards the same goal, the path forward remains complex amidst existing tensions in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/trump-warns-all-hell-will-break-out-if-hostages-in-gaza-are-not-freed-3-3345938</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/trump-warns-all-hell-will-break-out-if-hostages-in-gaza-are-not-freed-3-3345938</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:50:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Highly Dangerous’ Los Angeles Wildfire Forces 30,000 To Evacuate, Emergency Declared - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Highly Dangerous’ Los Angeles Wildfire Forces 30,000 To Evacuate, Emergency Declared</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Los Angeles Wildfire: The Pacific Palisades fire grew to nearly 3,000 acres following which California Governor Gavin Newsom and the City of Los Angeles declared a state of emergency."><figcaption>Los Angeles Wildfire: The Pacific Palisades fire grew to nearly 3,000 acres following which California Governor Gavin Newsom and the City of Los Angeles declared a state of emergency.</figcaption><p>A fast-moving brush fire in Los Angeles has led to the evacuation of approximately 30,000 residents as officials declare a state of emergency. The Pacific Palisades fire threatened more than 10,000 homes and has rapidly expanded.</p><ul><li>Evacuation orders in place for around 30,000 residents.</li><li>More than 10,000 homes threatened by the fire.</li><li>The fire has grown to nearly 3,000 acres.</li><li>Governor Gavin Newsom warns of extreme fire risks due to windstorms.</li><li>The Getty Villa, a museum in Malibu, is threatened but its collection is safe.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is a highly dangerous windstorm that’s creating extreme fire risk – and we’re not out of the woods.” - Governor Gavin Newsom</blockquote><p>Authorities urge residents to stay vigilant and prepare evacuation plans, as fire danger alerts remain in effect across Southern California.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/highly-dangerous-los-angeles-wildfire-forces-30000-to-evacuate-emergency-declared-9181487.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/highly-dangerous-los-angeles-wildfire-forces-30000-to-evacuate-emergency-declared-9181487.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:44:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tibet earthquake aftermath: Thousands of homes destroyed, 126 killed as rescue efforts continue - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tibet earthquake aftermath: Thousands of homes destroyed, 126 killed as rescue efforts continue</h1><p><strong>Published: January 08, 2025 08:53 am IST</strong></p><p><strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/v6jbl5/article69075120.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/tibet.jpg" alt="Rescue efforts in Tibet" /><figcaption>Rescue efforts in Tibet</figcaption><p>A powerful 7.1 magnitude earthquake struck Tibet, leading to significant destruction and loss of life, with multiple rescue operations ongoing to find survivors trapped under rubble.</p><ul><li>The earthquake occurred on January 7, 2025, with its epicenter in Tingri, Tibet, about 80 km north of Mount Everest.</li><li>More than 400 people have been rescued from trapped locations, with over 30,000 residents relocated.</li><li>At least 126 casualties have been reported, with 188 injured on the Tibetan side of the border.</li><li>3,609 homes were destroyed, impacting a population of around 800,000 in the Shigatse region.</li><li>Rescue teams face challenges due to freezing temperatures dropping to minus 18 degrees Celsius.</li><li>An extensive aftershock sequence has been noted, with over 500 aftershocks recorded post-earthquake.</li></ul><blockquote>"More than 500 aftershocks with magnitudes of up to 4.4 had followed the quake…"</blockquote><p>The ongoing rescue efforts and relief operations are crucial in addressing the aftermath of this devastating earthquake and ensuring the safety of affected residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/tibet-earthquake-several-killed-houses-destroyed-updates-january-8/article69074939.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/tibet-earthquake-several-killed-houses-destroyed-updates-january-8/article69074939.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thousands of homes destroyed, 126 killed as rescue efforts continue after earthquake in Tibet - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Tibet earthquake aftermath: Thousands of homes destroyed, 126 killed as rescue efforts continue</h1><p><strong>Published: January 08, 2025 08:53 am IST</strong></p><p><strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/v6jbl5/article69075120.ece/alternates/FREE_1200/tibet.jpg" alt="Rescue efforts in Tibet" /><figcaption>Rescue efforts in Tibet</figcaption><p>A powerful 7.1 magnitude earthquake struck Tibet, leading to significant destruction and loss of life, with multiple rescue operations ongoing to find survivors trapped under rubble.</p><ul><li>The earthquake occurred on January 7, 2025, with its epicenter in Tingri, Tibet, about 80 km north of Mount Everest.</li><li>More than 400 people have been rescued from trapped locations, with over 30,000 residents relocated.</li><li>At least 126 casualties have been reported, with 188 injured on the Tibetan side of the border.</li><li>3,609 homes were destroyed, impacting a population of around 800,000 in the Shigatse region.</li><li>Rescue teams face challenges due to freezing temperatures dropping to minus 18 degrees Celsius.</li><li>An extensive aftershock sequence has been noted, with over 500 aftershocks recorded post-earthquake.</li></ul><blockquote>"More than 500 aftershocks with magnitudes of up to 4.4 had followed the quake…"</blockquote><p>The ongoing rescue efforts and relief operations are crucial in addressing the aftermath of this devastating earthquake and ensuring the safety of affected residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/tibet-earthquake-several-killed-houses-destroyed-updates-january-8/article69074939.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/tibet-earthquake-several-killed-houses-destroyed-updates-january-8/article69074939.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Oh Canada!’: Donald Trump shares distorted map showing Canada part of US, Justin Trudeau’s party clears ‘confusion’ - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-new-map-showing-canada-part-of-us-11736306229715.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-new-map-showing-canada-part-of-us-11736306229715.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:17:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump shares distorted map showing Canada part of US, Justin Trudeau’s party clears ‘confusion’ - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Oh Canada!’: Donald Trump shares distorted map showing Canada part of US, Justin Trudeau’s party clears ‘confusion’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>US President-elect Donald Trump shared a distorted map on social media suggesting Canada is part of the United States, prompting a swift response from Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau’s Liberal Party.</p><ul><li>Trump posted the map on TRUTH, calling it 'Oh Canada!'.</li><li>The Liberal Party clarified the US-Canada border with an image on social media.</li><li>Trump reiterated his position that Canada should be the '51st State'.</li><li>Trudeau rebuffed Trump's comments, emphasizing Canada's sovereignty.</li><li>Trump expressed his intent to acquire Canada using 'economic force'.</li></ul><blockquote>“There isn’t a snowball’s chance in hell that Canada would become part of the United States.” — Justin Trudeau</blockquote><p>The incident highlights ongoing tensions surrounding Trump's comments about Canada as he prepares to take office again.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-new-map-showing-canada-part-of-us-11736306229715.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/oh-canada-donald-trump-shares-new-map-showing-canada-part-of-us-11736306229715.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:17:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israeli PULS “Defeats” U.S. HIMARS In Another European Deal; Here’s Why Israeli Rockets Are Zooming Ahead - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Germany Acquires Israeli PULS Rocket Systems, Outpacing HIMARS</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: October 2023</strong> | <strong>Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/9a/%D7%A8%D7%A7%D7%98%D7%A9_%D7%9B%D7%99%D7%93%D7%95%D7%9F_%D7%A7%D7%A1%D7%95%D7%9D.jpg/1920px-%D7%A8%D7%A7%D7%98%D7%AA_%D7%9B%D7%99%D7%93%D7%95%D7%9F_%D7%A7%D7%A1%D7%95%D7%9D.jpg" alt="PULS Rocket System" width="1920" height="1204"><figcaption>PULS (Precise & Universal Launching System): Wikipedia</figcaption></figure>
<p>Germany has secured approval to purchase five PULS rocket systems from Israeli defense contractor Elbit Systems, as part of a shift towards modernizing its military capabilities.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The deal is valued at €65 million (US$68 million) and follows a competitive selection against Lockheed Martin's HIMARS system.</li>
  <li>PULS offers versatility in munitions, potentially including GMLRS rockets pending U.S. approval.</li>
  <li>Germany joins other European nations like Serbia and the Netherlands in investing in Israeli PULS systems.</li>
  <li>The PULS system can launch a greater quantity of rockets in less time compared to HIMARS.</li>
  <li>Germany’s acquisition reflects ongoing concerns over security dynamics following Russia's invasion of Ukraine.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“PULS’s affordability, flexibility, and ability to carry out a wide array of missions have made it an attractive alternative to HIMARS for European countries.” - Sébastien Roblin</blockquote>
<p>This procurement signals a strategic shift for Germany, seeking new artillery solutions amid rising geopolitical tensions in Europe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/after-arrow-air-defense-system-germany-approved/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/after-arrow-air-defense-system-germany-approved/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:04:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘All hell will break…’: Donald Trump warns Hamas as he sets deadline for hostages' release - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Issues Stark Warning to Hamas Over Hostages Ahead of Inauguration</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Jan 08, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/US-PRESIDENT-ELECT-TRUMP-HOLDS-PRESS-CONFERENCE-AT_1736303409052_1736303409570.jpg" alt="Donald Trump also refused to rule out the use of military force to take control of the Panama Canal(Getty Images via AFP)" title="Donald Trump also refused to rule out the use of military force to take control of the Panama Canal(Getty Images via AFP)">
<figcaption>Donald Trump also refused to rule out the use of military force to take control of the Panama Canal(Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption>
<p>US President-elect Donald Trump delivered a stern warning during a press conference in Florida, stating “all hell will break out in the Middle East” if Hamas does not release its hostages in Gaza before his inauguration on January 20.</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump's warning highlights the escalating tensions in the Middle East regarding the hostage situation.</li>
<li>He expressed that the situation would be detrimental not only to Hamas but to everyone involved.</li>
<li>Trump appointed Steve Witkoff as special envoy to the Middle East, who noted a cautiously optimistic view on ceasefire talks.</li>
<li>The Biden administration officials are reportedly leading negotiations, with Trump’s team being kept informed.</li>
<li>Trump also hinted at the potential use of military force regarding territorial claims over the Panama Canal and Greenland.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It will not be good for Hamas and it will not be good, frankly, for anyone. All hell will break out.” - Donald Trump</blockquote>
<p>The press conference reflects Trump's aggressive stance on foreign policy and his ongoing involvement in international negotiations prior to taking office.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/all-hell-will-break-donald-trump-warns-hamas-as-he-sets-deadline-for-hostages-release-january-20-inauguration-101736303112432.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/all-hell-will-break-donald-trump-warns-hamas-as-he-sets-deadline-for-hostages-release-january-20-inauguration-101736303112432.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:03:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump says “there isn’t a snowball’s chance in hell” on Canada-US merger, Justin Trudeau responds - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-says-he-will-use-economic-force-against-canada-trudeau-responds/article69074888.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-says-he-will-use-economic-force-against-canada-trudeau-responds/article69074888.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘All Hell Will Break Out In Middle East...’: Trump's Deadline For Hamas To Return Hostages - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Issues Deadline for Hamas to Return Hostages</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="US President-elect Donald Trump was convicted of all felony counts in the hush money case. (AP image)"><figcaption>US President-elect Donald Trump was convicted of all felony counts in the hush money case. (AP image)</figcaption><p>Donald Trump warns of severe consequences if Hamas does not release hostages by his inauguration date.</p><ul><li>Trump sets January 20 as the deadline for Hamas to return hostages.</li><li>He warned that “all hell will break out” in the Middle East if hostages are not released.</li><li>Trump expressed frustration about the ongoing hostage crisis and criticized Hamas for their actions.</li></ul><blockquote>“All hell will break out. If those hostages aren’t back... all hell will break out in the Middle East.” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>Trump's statements have amplified concerns about the hostage situation and potential Middle Eastern tensions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-warns-hamas-all-hell-will-break-out-if-hostages-not-released-by-jan-20-9181418.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-warns-hamas-all-hell-will-break-out-if-hostages-not-released-by-jan-20-9181418.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:14:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump warns Hamas that all hell will break out if hostages not released before his inauguration - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Warns Hamas that All Hell Will Break Out if Hostages Not Released Before His Inauguration</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/o9b9a/article69074875.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-22T185749Z_1682455386_RC2HUBAJW3SP_RTRMADP_3_USA-TRUMP.JPG" alt="File picture of U.S. President-elect Donald Trump">
<figcaption>File picture of U.S. President-elect Donald Trump | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption>
<p>U.S. President-elect Donald Trump warned Hamas that “all hell will break out” if hostages are not released before his inauguration on January 20, 2025.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump emphasized the importance of hostage release during a press conference at Mar-a-Lago, Florida.</li>
  <li>He warned that failure to return hostages by his swearing-in would escalate tensions in the Middle East.</li>
  <li>Trump's Special Envoy to the Middle East, Steven Charles Witkoff, indicated progress was being made in negotiations for the hostages’ release.</li>
  <li>Trump criticized Hamas for their previous actions and questioned their treatment of hostages.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“All hell will break out. If those hostages aren’t back, I don’t want to hurt your negotiation, if they’re not back by the time I get into office...” - Donald Trump</blockquote>
<p>Trump reiterated the urgency of the situation, affirming his commitment to the issue and the lives at stake.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-warns-hamas-that-all-hell-will-break-out-if-hostages-not-released-before-his-inauguration/article69074873.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-warns-hamas-that-all-hell-will-break-out-if-hostages-not-released-before-his-inauguration/article69074873.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indonesia places a $28bn bet on free school meals - Financial Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTE5zNC1lZUVETmZ1RlZFMXVmNXNoUVk1Vkg5T3VydlBfdUZkcV9MYU5qNERWTTM5Z1N2V2ZwcENRQ1BMQmFyVE50VlA1b2VOdzdaOW9KOS1HUFFNQUVQR3M2NEd0eFMweGlrRjFEbExZbnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMicEFVX3lxTE5zNC1lZUVETmZ1RlZFMXVmNXNoUVk1Vkg5T3VydlBfdUZkcV9MYU5qNERWTTM5Z1N2V2ZwcENRQ1BMQmFyVE50VlA1b2VOdzdaOW9KOS1HUFFNQUVQR3M2NEd0eFMweGlrRjFEbExZbnM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 02:03:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>