<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 04:21:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 04:21:03 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WHO Global Internship Programme: Check eligibility, objectives and where to apply here - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxNZWJTTDhRWlhaVkF0RWZONFZuTEZqZXdSUDNlMVY2VXU2NDJYVXAzY29VY0llN2ZQczVlQmd5Z1N2RHJyNTl5U1pRaGxRU0JPT3ltTjlra2o0dXMxRlVwVE1DOGZCVllLUXVjYW10VkpXZ1BaU0Z0bE1IcXdkX3dBVjhpNnZoQTViTVZmcFJ6MndRdGRiZ1RvM0RfSTdFY29VOEdNX1lFdXJ1bXdNNGVNaGdlYVZpVnZIOUtnMmJJSXE1V2VmZkQ5bGtTQWQtTlJUTDBpOC15blNlU2tBVkRjb21zOGRNWTRwZ0REWFdEM081Y1pF0gH6AUFVX3lxTFA0SHBJMW03S0Vhanp2eWFEdVd2Sk1VOUxPUHBoN3RqZ3ZQSUJKMnJsU3NtMzVxU0hOMUdFbjNGb3FxNDk2QndycnFJMHZXcXJfMl8xX09Tal8weTk2N0VxOGhZelpMci12Z3lOeVBoUjRQWVI0QThJcGVZQ3RuZkU4dFNOSTRXSDBMWTFLZGU2a3l1LUxGV1ZwYXpHQmE1bmJwZmx4aGk3WVlIM2wwQU1nWjJrN1M4dVFPUkpRSk82bkFpek5kT3NlV3RDbHo2SmpfM3ZyVGM4TDZzVWpUNW1Jd0dQVkN6aFUzRHpQRUh0LWdHOXNjYWR6VkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxNZWJTTDhRWlhaVkF0RWZONFZuTEZqZXdSUDNlMVY2VXU2NDJYVXAzY29VY0llN2ZQczVlQmd5Z1N2RHJyNTl5U1pRaGxRU0JPT3ltTjlra2o0dXMxRlVwVE1DOGZCVllLUXVjYW10VkpXZ1BaU0Z0bE1IcXdkX3dBVjhpNnZoQTViTVZmcFJ6MndRdGRiZ1RvM0RfSTdFY29VOEdNX1lFdXJ1bXdNNGVNaGdlYVZpVnZIOUtnMmJJSXE1V2VmZkQ5bGtTQWQtTlJUTDBpOC15blNlU2tBVkRjb21zOGRNWTRwZ0REWFdEM081Y1pF0gH6AUFVX3lxTFA0SHBJMW03S0Vhanp2eWFEdVd2Sk1VOUxPUHBoN3RqZ3ZQSUJKMnJsU3NtMzVxU0hOMUdFbjNGb3FxNDk2QndycnFJMHZXcXJfMl8xX09Tal8weTk2N0VxOGhZelpMci12Z3lOeVBoUjRQWVI0QThJcGVZQ3RuZkU4dFNOSTRXSDBMWTFLZGU2a3l1LUxGV1ZwYXpHQmE1bmJwZmx4aGk3WVlIM2wwQU1nWjJrN1M4dVFPUkpRSk82bkFpek5kT3NlV3RDbHo2SmpfM3ZyVGM4TDZzVWpUNW1Jd0dQVkN6aFUzRHpQRUh0LWdHOXNjYWR6VkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 03:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australia: Man killed by shark while fishing with family - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/australia-man-killed-by-shark-while-fishing-with-family/articleshow/116757013.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/australia-man-killed-by-shark-while-fishing-with-family/articleshow/116757013.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 02:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea news LIVE: Plane with 181 people crashes at Muan Airport, 29 dead; fire department says ‘tally could rise..’ | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/south-korea-news-plane-carrying-175-passengers-six-crew-members-crashes-after-driving-off-runway-at-muan-airport-11735432937148.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/south-korea-news-plane-carrying-175-passengers-six-crew-members-crashes-after-driving-off-runway-at-muan-airport-11735432937148.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 02:16:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s a great program: Trump appears to side with Musk in H-1B visa row - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Supports H-1B Visas Amid Controversy with Musk and Tech Industry</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 29, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> New York Post</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/pyu453/article69025831.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-23T215136Z_525061291_RC2GUBA1RFQ9_RTRMADP_3_USA-TRUMP-TIMELINE.JPG" alt="Donald Trump has in the past criticised the H-1B visas, calling them “very bad” and “unfair” for U.S. workers. File" title="Donald Trump has in the past criticised the H-1B visas, calling them “very bad” and “unfair” for U.S. workers. File"><figcaption>Donald Trump has in the past criticised the H-1B visas, calling them “very bad” and “unfair” for U.S. workers. File | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>In a recent interview, President-elect Donald Trump expressed support for H-1B visas, siding with Elon Musk and tech enthusiasts, amidst ongoing disputes about their impact on American jobs.</p><ul><li>Trump praised H-1B visas as essential for attracting skilled foreign workers.</li><li>He acknowledged a past of criticizing the program, citing it as 'very bad' for U.S. workers.</li><li>His previous administration focused on limiting visa usage to prioritize high-skilled applicants.</li><li>Despite criticisms, Trump indicated his businesses have utilized H-1B visas.</li><li>The debate over H-1B visas has caused a rift among his conservative base, particularly online.</li></ul><blockquote>“I have always liked the visas, I have always been in favor of the visas. That’s why we have them.” – Donald Trump</blockquote><p>In conclusion, Trump's recent statements signal a shift in his stance towards H-1B visas, conflicting with the hardline immigration policies that formed a key part of his campaign.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/its-a-great-program-trump-appears-to-side-with-musk-in-h-1b-visa-row/article69039158.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/its-a-great-program-trump-appears-to-side-with-musk-in-h-1b-visa-row/article69039158.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 01:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biden reportedly regrets dropping out of US presidential race. Could he have beaten Trump? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Reportedly Regrets Dropping Out of US Presidential Race: Could He Have Beaten Trump?</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In a reflective turn, President Biden is reportedly regretting his decision to withdraw from the 2024 presidential race, contemplating whether he could have won against Donald Trump.</p><ul><li>Biden's withdrawal from the race may have been premature.</li><li>Speculations arise around his chances against Trump.</li><li>This sentiment reflects the political landscape and potential voter dynamics.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's a tough call whether I could have won.”</blockquote><p>The sentiments from Biden highlight the complexities of electoral decisions and their long-term impacts on political career trajectories.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/biden-reportedly-regrets-dropping-out-of-us-presidential-race-could-he-have-beaten-trump/articleshow/116755876.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/biden-reportedly-regrets-dropping-out-of-us-presidential-race-could-he-have-beaten-trump/articleshow/116755876.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 01:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea news LIVE: Plane crash at Muan Airport kills 62, flights cancelled – know latest updates here | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Plane Crash at Muan Airport Leaves 85 Dead</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> [Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p>
<p>A Jeju Air flight with 175 passengers crashed at Muan International Airport while returning from Thailand, leading to a tragic death toll of at least 85. All flights have been canceled in the wake of the incident.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Flight 7C2216 crashed into a wall after driving off the runway.</li>
  <li>Initial reports confirmed 62 deaths, which later rose to 85.</li>
  <li>All domestic and international flights from South Korea have been canceled.</li>
  <li>Two Thai nationals were reported to be aboard the flight.</li>
  <li>Eyewitnesses shared videos of the crash, showing the aircraft without visible landing gear before impact.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I would like to express my condolences to the families of the deceased and injured.” - Thailand's Prime Minister Paetongtarn Shinawatra</blockquote>
<p>This incident marks a significant air disaster in South Korea's recent history, prompting immediate investigations and responses from both South Korean and foreign officials.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/world/south-korea-news-plane-carrying-175-passengers-six-crew-members-crashes-after-driving-off-runway-at-muan-airport-11735432937148.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/world/south-korea-news-plane-carrying-175-passengers-six-crew-members-crashes-after-driving-off-runway-at-muan-airport-11735432937148.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:46:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel finds massive Hezbollah weapon cache at ‘military base disguised as village’ in Lebanon - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Discovers Large Hezbollah Weapons Cache Disguised as Civilian Infrastructure</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 29, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> HT News</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/29/550x309/ISRAEL-LEBANON-PALESTINIAN-CONFLICT-10_1735430910453_1735430939343.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: Documents, letters and photographs the Israeli army says belonged to the Lebanese militant group Hezbollah, and were seized by the army during its ground operation in south Lebanon, are displayed to the media on December 23, 2024, in a northern Israeli military base.(AFP)" title="FILE PHOTO: Documents, letters and photographs the Israeli army says belonged to the Lebanese militant group Hezbollah, and were seized by the army during its ground operation in south Lebanon, are displayed to the media on December 23, 2024, in a northern Israeli military base.(AFP)">
<figcaption>FILE PHOTO: Documents, letters and photographs the Israeli army says belonged to the Lebanese militant group Hezbollah, and were seized by the army during its ground operation in south Lebanon, are displayed to the media on December 23, 2024, in a northern Israeli military base.(AFP)</figcaption>
<p>The Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) have uncovered a significant cache of weapons hidden within civilian infrastructure in southern Lebanon, highlighting concerns about Hezbollah's military operations within civilian areas.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Findings included a truck mounted with 40 rocket launcher barrels near Naqoura.</li>
  <li>Additional weapons were discovered inside a pharmacy, including explosives and RPG missiles.</li>
  <li>Hezbollah is reportedly preparing for further conflict and has resumed reconstruction efforts.</li>
  <li>The IDF conducted an airstrike targeting Hezbollah's weapons smuggling unit.</li>
  <li>Growing tensions between the IDF and UNIFIL regarding ceasefire agreements.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Those aren't villages with some military infrastructure, this is a military base disguised as a civilian area.” - Sarit Zahavi, president of the Alma Research Center</blockquote>
<p>The IDF's discovery underscores ongoing instability in the region, with potential long-term implications for both Israel and Lebanon.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israel-finds-massive-hezbollah-weapon-cache-at-military-base-disguised-as-village-in-lebanon-101735430610623.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israel-finds-massive-hezbollah-weapon-cache-at-military-base-disguised-as-village-in-lebanon-101735430610623.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:27:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYC teacher 'Arthur Dent' sexually abused student in ‘escape room’ and home ‘bat cave’ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NYC teacher 'Arthur Dent' sexually abused student in ‘escape room’ and home ‘bat cave’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified<strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>An NYC teacher, known as Arthur Dent, is facing serious allegations of sexually abusing a student both in an escape room and at his residence, which he referred to as a 'bat cave'.</p><ul><li>Allegations involve multiple incidents of sexual abuse.</li><li>Events took place in unconventional settings, raising concerns about safety and trust in educational environments.</li><li>The case is currently under investigation.</li></ul><blockquote>"These allegations are deeply troubling and must be taken seriously to protect students."</blockquote><p>The ongoing investigation highlights the need for strict safeguarding measures in schools to prevent such incidents from occurring in the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/nyc-teacher-arthur-dent-sexually-abused-student-in-escape-room-and-home-bat-cave/articleshow/116753005.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/nyc-teacher-arthur-dent-sexually-abused-student-in-escape-room-and-home-bat-cave/articleshow/116753005.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 22:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disturbing Bodycam Footage Shows US Cops Brutally Beating Handcuffed Inmate To Death - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/disturbing-bodycam-footage-shows-us-cops-brutally-beating-handcuffed-inmate-to-death-9171059.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/disturbing-bodycam-footage-shows-us-cops-brutally-beating-handcuffed-inmate-to-death-9171059.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 22:32:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump sides with Elon Musk in H-1B visa debate, says he's always been in favor of the program - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Supports H-1B Visa Program Amid Debate with Elon Musk</h1><p><strong>Published on 28 December 2024, IST</strong> by a reputable news source.</p><p>President-elect Donald Trump openly sided with Elon Musk in a debate over the H-1B visa program, indicating his support for the program in the face of opposition from some of his supporters.</p><ul><li>Trump expressed his longstanding support for the H-1B visa program, which allows foreign tech workers to work in the U.S.</li><li>This stance comes after Musk vowed to defend the program amid criticism from far-right activists.</li><li>Trump previously moved to restrict H-1B visas during his first presidency.</li><li>The controversy arose following Trump's choice of an Indian American adviser on AI, prompting backlash from some of his supporters.</li><li>Musk highlighted the need for skilled foreign workers, mentioning Tesla's use of 724 H-1B visas this year.</li></ul><blockquote>"I have many H-1B visas on my properties. I've been a believer in H-1B. I have used it many times. It's a great program." - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>The ongoing debate emphasizes the dichotomy within Trump's supporters regarding immigration policies, especially in the tech sector, which relies heavily on H-1B visas.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/trump-sides-with-elon-musk-in-h-1b-visa-debate-says-hes-always-been-in-favor-of-the-program-3335153</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/trump-sides-with-elon-musk-in-h-1b-visa-debate-says-hes-always-been-in-favor-of-the-program-3335153</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 21:57:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AT&T Says Its Network Is Now Clear After Salt Typhoon Hack | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>AT&T Says Its Network Is Now Clear After Salt Typhoon Hack</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Recent</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p><p>AT&T Inc. reported that it was targeted in the Salt Typhoon hacking operation linked to China, but asserts that its network is now secure. The telecom giant is collaborating with authorities and notifying individuals whose information may have been compromised.</p><ul><li>The hackers aimed to gather information on foreign intelligence.</li><li>AT&T has reported no current activity by nation-state actors in its networks.</li><li>The company has complied with notification obligations in cooperation with law enforcement.</li><li>AT&T and Verizon were among the telecom carriers affected by the Salt Typhoon intrusion.</li><li>The White House confirmed that nine telecom companies were breached.</li><li>US officials are still assessing the extent of the targeted individuals.</li><li>The Biden administration held a closed-door session with telecom industry leaders to discuss vulnerabilities.</li></ul><blockquote>“We detect no activity by nation-state actors in our networks at this time.” - AT&T</blockquote><p>In conclusion, AT&T is taking measures to secure its network and enhance customer data protection following the breach, while the investigation continues into the Salt Typhoon incident.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/att-says-its-network-is-now-clear-after-salt-typhoon-hack-11735421813142.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/att-says-its-network-is-now-clear-after-salt-typhoon-hack-11735421813142.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 21:36:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh journalists 'sacked on students' demand', media associations in India flag 'mob threat' - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh journalists 'sacked on students' demand', media associations in India flag 'mob threat'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi, Date Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> ThePrint</p><p>The Foreign Correspondents’ Club of South Asia, Press Club of India, and the Indian Association of Foreign Affairs Correspondents have expressed concern over the sacking of five journalists from Somoy TV in Bangladesh, following protests led by student leaders.</p><ul><li>Five veteran journalists were dismissed after Hasnat Abdullah, a student leader, protested their presence on social media.</li><li>These dismissals have raised alarms about press freedom in Bangladesh.</li><li>The journalists claimed they were asked to resign for the 'greater good' of the channel.</li><li>The situation reflects increasing pressure on media outlets amid rising student-led protests.</li></ul><blockquote>“Hasnat Abdullah’s visit to a TV channel’s newsroom demanding favourable coverage is nothing but news censorship and policing of information through the threat of mob action.”</blockquote><p>Concerns about media repression have escalated, with calls for the journalists' reinstatement and for the government to uphold press freedoms.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/diplomacy/bangladesh-journalists-sacked-on-students-demand-media-associations-in-india-flag-mob-threat/2423285/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/diplomacy/bangladesh-journalists-sacked-on-students-demand-media-associations-in-india-flag-mob-threat/2423285/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 19:17:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump breaks silence on H-1B row, supports Elon-Vivek: 'It's a great program' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump breaks silence on H-1B row, supports Elon-Vivek: 'It's a great program'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Trump supports H-1B program"><figcaption>Trump discusses the H-1B visa program, saying it is beneficial.</figcaption><p>In a recent statement, Donald Trump expressed his support for the H-1B visa program, siding with tech leaders Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy amidst a controversy about immigration and job competition.</p><ul><li>Trump affirmed the value of the H-1B program as a vital resource for the US economy.</li><li>His comments come in the context of public backlash regarding the current immigration policies.</li><li>Musk and Ramaswamy have been vocal proponents of the program, emphasizing its importance in the tech industry.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's a great program,” Trump stated, highlighting its positive impact on America’s workforce.</blockquote><p>Trump's remarks reflect ongoing debates about the future of immigration in the US, particularly concerning skilled labor from abroad.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-breaks-silence-on-h-1b-row-supports-elon-vivek-its-a-great-program/articleshow/116750940.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-breaks-silence-on-h-1b-row-supports-elon-vivek-its-a-great-program/articleshow/116750940.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 19:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China makes another move to assert territorial claim, creates new county with large parts of India's Aksai Chin - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Creates New Counties in Aksai Chin, Escalating Territorial Disputes with India</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 28 December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p><p>China has recently established two new counties, one of which encompasses a significant portion of Aksai Chin, an area claimed by India. This move comes shortly after boundary negotiations between the two nations were restarted.</p><ul><li>China created He’an County and Hekang County in the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region.</li><li>He'an County reportedly covers 38,000 sq. km of territory claimed by India.</li><li>This decision follows a meeting between Indian and Chinese special representatives for boundary talks.</li><li>India has yet to officially respond to China's unilateral action regarding the territorial dispute.</li></ul><blockquote>New Delhi has taken note of the latest move initiated by Beijing on India's land illegally occupied by China.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, China's establishment of new administrative regions in disputed territories reflects its ongoing claims over Aksai Chin, complicating the fragile relationship with India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/china-makes-another-move-to-assert-territorial-claim-creates-new-county-with-large-parts-of-indias-aksai-chin-3335098</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/china-makes-another-move-to-assert-territorial-claim-creates-new-county-with-large-parts-of-indias-aksai-chin-3335098</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 18:34:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk backs AfD party in German newspaper opinion piece - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxNTWNRa3NXc0FrenphdXo3anY1WFhKSjVlcEdXa3lzMU9CenoxVV9QNld3bERqMExuMHViSU43NW9TcG84Z1RXOUNrYXpuNUdiZ0hqUGtQUXhycGxYSVlqYUxOc0FTTmRqNVByVEc4QlF6OGdTbW9hZkotcTQxLUZwQnctdEdkX3huNjNQNGJOTHVXZzh2cE04UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxNTWNRa3NXc0FrenphdXo3anY1WFhKSjVlcEdXa3lzMU9CenoxVV9QNld3bERqMExuMHViSU43NW9TcG84Z1RXOUNrYXpuNUdiZ0hqUGtQUXhycGxYSVlqYUxOc0FTTmRqNVByVEc4QlF6OGdTbW9hZkotcTQxLUZwQnctdEdkX3huNjNQNGJOTHVXZzh2cE04UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:35:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frequent GPS interference, including ‘spoofing’, near India’s border with Pakistan, Myanmar - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Frequent GPS interference, including ‘spoofing’, near India’s border with Pakistan, Myanmar</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/nwxg99/article69038042.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-28T131005Z_422148835_RC25VBANNJAL_RTRMADP_3_KAZAKHSTAN-CRASH-RUSSIA.JPG" alt="A file photo of the Azerbaijan Airlines crash on December 25 in which 38 people onboard were killed" title="A file photo of the Azerbaijan Airlines crash on December 25 in which 38 people onboard were killed"><figcaption>A file photo of the Azerbaijan Airlines crash on December 25 in which 38 people onboard were killed | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>The rise of GPS interference, especially ‘spoofing’, is alarming as it poses risks to passenger aircraft near conflict zones, notably on India's borders with Pakistan and Myanmar.</p><ul><li>GPS interference incidents are rising globally with India’s borders among the top areas affected.</li><li>Spoofing can mislead navigation systems with false signals, particularly in conflict zones.</li><li>A recent report indicated daily spoofing in the Delhi Flight Information Region.</li><li>The number of flights impacted by spoofing increased significantly from January to August 2024.</li><li>The Directorate General of Civil Aviation issued an advisory for airlines to manage these occurrences.</li></ul><blockquote>“Spoofing the GPS could also result in errors in the speed display, or trigger a terrain warning.”</blockquote><p>The growing frequency of GPS spoofing presents a serious challenge for aviation safety, demanding immediate attention and robust solutions from authorities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/frequent-gps-interference-including-spoofing-near-indias-border-with-pakistan-myanmar/article69037483.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/frequent-gps-interference-including-spoofing-near-indias-border-with-pakistan-myanmar/article69037483.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Scorched beyond recognition' NYC subway horror victim still unidentified. What's next? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scorched beyond recognition' NYC subway horror victim still unidentified. What's next?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The article discusses the tragic incident occurring in the NYC subway where a victim, severely burned, remains unidentified. The focus is on the implications of this event and what steps are being undertaken for identification and justice.</p><ul><li>Victim was found in a horrific condition.</li><li>Authorities are seeking leads to identify the victim.</li><li>Concerns about safety in subway transit are raised.</li></ul><blockquote>“The situation is dire and needs immediate attention,” said a police spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights ongoing safety issues in public transport systems and the community's need for vigilance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/scorched-beyond-recognition-nyc-subway-horror-victim-still-unidentified-whats-next/articleshow/116748315.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/scorched-beyond-recognition-nyc-subway-horror-victim-still-unidentified-whats-next/articleshow/116748315.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: In A First, Israel Uses US Anti-Missile THAAD system To Counter Houthi Attack - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Uses US THAAD System for the First Time Against Houthi Missile Attack</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Israel uses THAAD system to intercept missile fired by Houthi rebels (Screengrab)" title="Israel uses THAAD system to intercept missile fired by Houthi rebels (Screengrab)"><figcaption>Israel uses THAAD system to intercept missile fired by Houthi rebels (Screengrab)</figcaption></figure><p>Israel successfully used the US-made Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) system to intercept a ballistic missile launched from Yemen by Houthi rebels. This marks a significant first in Israel's defense strategy.</p><ul><li>THAAD was deployed in Israel by the US in October.</li><li>Footage captured an interceptor being launched with an American soldier expressing his long-awaited anticipation.</li><li>The missile interception is part of escalating attacks from the Houthi group targeting Israel.</li><li>The THAAD system’s capabilities extend to intercepting threats both inside and outside the atmosphere.</li><li>The recent attack was the fifth by the Houthis in eight days, prompting Israeli military responses.</li></ul><blockquote>“Eighteen years I’ve been waiting for this.”</blockquote><p>This successful interception highlights the growing military cooperation between Israel and the US, especially in the face of increasing regional threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/video-in-a-first-israel-uses-us-anti-missile-thaad-system-to-counter-houthi-attack-9170958.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/video-in-a-first-israel-uses-us-anti-missile-thaad-system-to-counter-houthi-attack-9170958.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:41:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['F**k Yourself': Elon Musk's Response To MAGA Supporter In Heated H-1B/Immigration Debate - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'F**k Yourself': Elon Musk's Response To MAGA Supporter In Heated H-1B/Immigration Debate</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2024/12/img-2-2024-12-10t114148.300-2024-12-e321ae417145dab8514c2248981961b2.png?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Billionaire entrepreneur Elon Musk | File Image" /><figcaption>Billionaire entrepreneur Elon Musk | File Image</figcaption></figure><p>Elon Musk provided a fierce response to a MAGA supporter in a heated debate over the H-1B visa, highlighting the importance of the visa for the tech industry and calling out anti-immigration rhetoric.</p><ul><li>Musk's response was sparked by a Twitter comment regarding the H-1B visa.</li><li>He emphasized that many individuals who contribute to tech companies in the U.S. immigrated on H-1B visas.</li><li>The discussion relates to broader debates around immigration policy and the impact of such policies on the tech sector.</li></ul><blockquote>The reason I’m in America along with so many critical people who built SpaceX, Tesla and hundreds of other companies that made America strong is because of H1B. Take a big step back and FUCK YOURSELF in the face. I will go to war on this issue the likes of which you cannot… — Elon Musk (@elonmusk) December 28, 2024</blockquote><p>Musk's comments reflect a significant viewpoint in the ongoing debates regarding immigration reform in the United States, especially in the tech sector.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/elon-musk-f-k-yourself-response-to-maga-supporter-as-immigration-debate-h1b-visa-9171363.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/elon-musk-f-k-yourself-response-to-maga-supporter-as-immigration-debate-h1b-visa-9171363.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:40:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus suggests lowering voting age to 17 in Bangladesh, BNP says could ‘delay’ elections - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Muhammad Yunus suggests lowering voting age to 17 in Bangladesh, BNP says could ‘delay’ elections</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 19, 2024&nbsp;|&nbsp;<strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/10/Muhammad-Yunus-2_20241019203032.jpg?w=640" alt="Bangladesh Chief Adviser Yunus" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Interim government's chief adviser, Dr Muhammad Yunus.</figcaption><p>Bangladesh’s Chief Adviser, Muhammad Yunus proposed on Friday that the minimum voting age in Bangladesh should be lowered to 17 years. Yunus believes that this change would empower youth and give them a stronger role in shaping their future.</p><ul><li>Yunus stated that having a voting age of 17 would engage more young people in the electoral process.</li><li>BNP expressed concerns that the proposal could burden the Election Commission and delay elections.</li><li>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir criticized the suggestion, urging Yunus to have consulted stakeholders first.</li><li>Yunus indicated he would accept the recommendation of the Election Reform Commission.</li><li>The expected timeline for elections is between late 2025 and early 2026 after updating the voter list.</li></ul><blockquote>“The youth gives them strength,” Yunus remarked during the dialogue.</blockquote><p>The debate around the voting age highlights differing views on electoral engagement in Bangladesh, as political parties vie for influence in the impending elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/muhammad-yunus-bangladesh-lowering-voting-age-to-17-delay-elections-bnp-9749136/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/muhammad-yunus-bangladesh-lowering-voting-age-to-17-delay-elections-bnp-9749136/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:54:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Supporters Are No Longer Fans Of Elon Musk. Reason? Immigration - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Supporters Turn Against Elon Musk Over Immigration Views</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Donald Trump and Elon Musk (AP Image)"><figcaption>Donald Trump and Elon Musk (AP Image)</figcaption><p>Supporters of US President-elect Donald Trump are reacting negatively to comments made by Elon Musk regarding immigration. Musk’s advocacy for merit-based immigration reforms has conflicted with the anti-immigration stance of Trump supporters.</p><h3>Main Points:</h3><ul><li>Elon Musk supports attracting global talent to maintain US technological dominance.</li><li>Trump supporters oppose Musk’s pro-immigration comments.</li><li>The controversy arose following the appointment of Sriram Krishnan to lead AI policy.</li><li>Social media reactions have included vocally critical viewpoints from far-right commentators.</li></ul><h3>Notable Quotes:</h3><blockquote>“If you want your TEAM to win the championship, you need to recruit top talent wherever they may be.” - Elon Musk</blockquote><blockquote>“There is nothing wrong with American workers or American culture.” - Nikki Haley</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the clash between Musk’s immigration views and the preferences of Trump supporters highlights a significant divide over immigration policy and its implications for the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-supporters-are-no-longer-fans-of-elon-musk-reason-immigration-9170742.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-supporters-are-no-longer-fans-of-elon-musk-reason-immigration-9170742.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:34:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Azerbaijan Plane Crash: Is A.I-Enabled Pantsir Missile Behind Shootdown Of Flight 8432? Putin Says Sorry For ‘Tragic Incident’ - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Azerbaijan Airlines Flight 8432 Crash: Possible Missile Involvement</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date]</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/WhatsApp-Image-2024-12-26-at-1.33.27-AM.jpeg" alt="Wreckage of the Azerbaijan airline that crashed in Aktau, Kazakhstan." width="800" height="450"><figcaption>Wreckage of the Azerbaijan airline that crashed in Aktau, Kazakhstan.</figcaption><p>The Azerbaijan Airlines plane that crashed in Kazakhstan was reportedly shot down by a Russian missile, raising significant concerns over aviation safety in conflict zones.</p><ul><li>Flight 8432, with 67 people on board, was hit by a missile from a Russian surface-to-air system during drone activity.</li><li>38 passengers and crew members lost their lives due to the incident, described as a tragic accident.</li><li>President Putin expressed condolences, hinting at possible Russian air defense involvement.</li><li>Experts have pointed to damage consistent with missile shrapnel on the aircraft.</li><li>This incident adds to a troubling history of civilian aircraft being mistakenly targeted in conflict zones.</li></ul><blockquote>“(President) Vladimir Putin apologized for the tragic incident that occurred in Russian airspace and once again expressed his deep and sincere condolences to the families of the victims.”</blockquote><p>This incident underlines the risks faced by civilian flight operations in areas of heightened military activity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/war-haze-when-passenger-jets-became/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/war-haze-when-passenger-jets-became/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:29:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kamal Adwan Hospital out of service following a raid yesterday and repeated attacks since October - World Health Organization]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxNdlMyNmlFcnVwREowbTJBM1ViaWI0TmhKT0xzUXE1Z0U1TW1pM1U0QURYbVo1b0NrRFVYMTc1eGc1Vl9nSnNpZWlBSmRsYWpwd1hJbWktbnRrVU9VYk83SjJ1Vm1jUUZHQ1NTTG10UEJlNXpyV2FJaVRmNWhLUU53SGV1aTFFOFFZVlJPaHRWajF3VXlaMlZvSnZqa3h3NXpuRFAzU0RQSjViVEljRzlWa2VycUNpRDA3dlp5VXRBQktJQW44bko0YTFWSmI2STQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMizwFBVV95cUxNdlMyNmlFcnVwREowbTJBM1ViaWI0TmhKT0xzUXE1Z0U1TW1pM1U0QURYbVo1b0NrRFVYMTc1eGc1Vl9nSnNpZWlBSmRsYWpwd1hJbWktbnRrVU9VYk83SjJ1Vm1jUUZHQ1NTTG10UEJlNXpyV2FJaVRmNWhLUU53SGV1aTFFOFFZVlJPaHRWajF3VXlaMlZvSnZqa3h3NXpuRFAzU0RQSjViVEljRzlWa2VycUNpRDA3dlp5VXRBQktJQW44bko0YTFWSmI2STQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:40:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi Finds Alternative To F-35; Could Become 2nd Country To Acquire Non-American Stealth Fighters: Reports - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saudi Finds Alternative To F-35; Could Become 2nd Country To Acquire Non-American Stealth Fighters: Reports</h1><p><strong>Date: Unknown, Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.lockheedmartin.com/content/dam/lockheed-martin/aero/photo/F-35/22-08928-ADSW_JASSM-LRASM-F-35_AFA_Column-Wrap-V2-1280.jpg.pc-adaptive.full.medium.jpg" alt="F-35 Lightning II | Lockheed Martin" width="1280" height="750" aria-hidden="false"><figcaption>F-35 Lightning II</figcaption></figure><p>Saudi Arabia has been trying to acquire the F-35 fighter jet for years but is now seeking alternatives due to delays and obstacles from the U.S. government, including concerns over human rights violations and military cooperation with China.</p><ul><li>Saudi Arabia's interest in F-35 stealth aircraft dates back to 2017.</li><li>The U.S. military sales are influenced by Israel's qualitative military edge.</li><li>Alternatives being considered include the Chinese J-35 stealth fighter and the Turkish KAAN jets.</li><li>Saudi Arabia has not explicitly expressed interest in Russian or Chinese fighters due to pressure from the U.S.</li><li>High-level talks have been reported regarding acquiring the Turkish KAAN fighter jet.</li></ul><blockquote>“This aircraft is better than the (US’s) F-35.” - Temel Kotil, Turkish Aerospace Industries General Manager</blockquote><p>The search for alternatives to the F-35 underscores Saudi Arabia's desire to strengthen its military capabilities amid evolving regional threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/with-f-35-elusive-saudi-arabia-is-looking/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/with-f-35-elusive-saudi-arabia-is-looking/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:20:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UAE records mild earthquake; no impact reported - Khaleej Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQbWJVMTg5Z1dPZ0p0aE1rVWFzTUZLdU5xdVNJWi1IYlR4M01TYXJ0V255bkFwQlE2bDF1VlJoUEFEdW91enVWUWtsSG41MEg3NHQ5bGZBRzQtQWE0UkhPaFJQVk5Tc3RxZDNIWTN3NWQyc09hWDhSMnhwVU1vTUFoNmJhNDQyd9IBjgFBVV95cUxNYm83SGI5T09Hc1RTZ0JzRmFrS1hDVi1LQW0tVFRzaEtQemIyM0FBcTQxUTJPd3RJVlFTT1pkOWllb1VjazNYYnBIbm14WThZLUZfc0kzcWxQQ3VHQlBPb3ItcU5oWFlwWWJnRGttLWpGTUFMUGxkQm1wRFpEcHVmR2NVQUVzM0p5Mm5HWEFR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQbWJVMTg5Z1dPZ0p0aE1rVWFzTUZLdU5xdVNJWi1IYlR4M01TYXJ0V255bkFwQlE2bDF1VlJoUEFEdW91enVWUWtsSG41MEg3NHQ5bGZBRzQtQWE0UkhPaFJQVk5Tc3RxZDNIWTN3NWQyc09hWDhSMnhwVU1vTUFoNmJhNDQyd9IBjgFBVV95cUxNYm83SGI5T09Hc1RTZ0JzRmFrS1hDVi1LQW0tVFRzaEtQemIyM0FBcTQxUTJPd3RJVlFTT1pkOWllb1VjazNYYnBIbm14WThZLUZfc0kzcWxQQ3VHQlBPb3ItcU5oWFlwWWJnRGttLWpGTUFMUGxkQm1wRFpEcHVmR2NVQUVzM0p5Mm5HWEFR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:16:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024: Express Entry year in review - Canada Immigration News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>2024: Express Entry Year in Review</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 24, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CanadaVisa</p><p>This article reviews the major changes to Canada’s Express Entry system throughout 2024, highlighting trends and what to expect in the coming year.</p><h2>Key Points:</h2><ul><li>98,803 invitations to apply (ITAs) issued in 52 draws.</li><li>Focus shifted to Provincial Nominee Program (PNP), Canadian Experience Class (CEC), and French language proficiency candidates.</li><li>221,310 candidate profiles in the Express Entry pool as of December 2024.</li><li>Changes in the minimum Comprehensive Ranking System (CRS) cut-off scores across various categories.</li><li>Significant policy changes expected to influence the system in 2025.</li></ul><h2>Notable Changes Include:</h2><blockquote>“In December of 2024, Minister of Immigration Marc Miller announced his intention to remove CRS points awarded for valid job offers.”</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cicnews.com/2024/12/2024-express-entry-year-in-review-1249932.html#gs.jf56aa</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cicnews.com/2024/12/2024-express-entry-year-in-review-1249932.html#gs.jf56aa</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:00:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Melbourne weather forecast December 29: What are the chances of rain on Day 4 of 4th BGT 2024-25 Test? - Sportskeeda]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Melbourne Weather Forecast for December 29: Rain Chances on Day 4 of 4th BGT 2024-25 Test</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 29, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Sportskeeda</p><h2>Weather forecast for Melbourne on December 29</h2><p>As Day 4 of the Boxing Day Test unfolds, the weather in Melbourne is expected to be partly sunny and pleasant throughout the day.</p><ul><li>Morning: Low precipitation probability at 3%, 55% cloud cover, 57% humidity.</li><li>Afternoon: Precipitation probability remains at 3%, cloud cover increases to 76%, 46% humidity.</li><li>Evening: Clear skies with 3% precipitation probability, low cloud cover at 7%, 71% humidity.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.sportskeeda.com/cricket/news-melbourne-weather-forecast-december-29-what-chances-rain-day-4-4th-bgt-2024-25-test</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sportskeeda.com/cricket/news-melbourne-weather-forecast-december-29-what-chances-rain-day-4-4th-bgt-2024-25-test</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:49:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Putin apologises for downing Azerbaijan Airlines plane, says Russia was repelling Ukranian drone attacks - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Putin Apologizes for Azerbaijan Airlines Plane Crash Amidst Ukrainian Drone Attacks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/2024-12-25T180312Z_1847302196_RC25VBAVUAUX_RTRMADP_3_KAZAKHSTAN-CRASH.jpg?w=640' alt='azerbaijan plane crashes, kazakhastan Russia'><figcaption>A drone view shows emergency specialists working at the crash site of an Azerbaijan Airlines passenger plane near the city of Aktau, Kazakhstan December 25, 2024. (Reuters)</figcaption><p>The Kremlin acknowledged that the Russian air defense forces were responding to Ukrainian drone attacks when an Azerbaijan Airlines plane attempted to land in Grozny, resulting in a tragic crash that claimed 38 lives.</p><ul><li>The plane was on a scheduled flight from Baku to Grozny on Christmas Day.</li><li>It crashed near Aktau in Kazakhstan after losing control due to apparent interference.</li><li>President Putin expressed condolences to Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev, calling the incident tragic.</li><li>The US had indicated that the Russian air defense may be responsible for the downing of the aircraft.</li><li>Azerbaijan's presidential office reported that the plane faced external physical interference in Russian airspace.</li></ul><blockquote>“(President) Vladimir Putin apologised for the tragic incident that occurred in Russian airspace.”</blockquote><p>The incident raises significant concerns regarding air safety in conflict zones, particularly in light of ongoing tensions between Russia and Ukraine.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/russia-air-defence-reponsible-for-azerbaijan-airlines-flight-crash-9748976/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/russia-air-defence-reponsible-for-azerbaijan-airlines-flight-crash-9748976/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Russian air defence active when plane crashed': Russian President Putin 'apologises' to Azerbaijan count - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russian air defence active when plane crashed: Russian President Putin 'apologises' to Azerbaijan counterpart Aliyev</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 10, 2023</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has expressed his regrets to Azerbaijan's President Ilham Aliyev following a plane crash that occurred during a period of active Russian air defense operations.</p><ul><li>The incident raised questions about the effectiveness and communication protocols of air defense systems.</li><li>Putin's apology aims to maintain diplomatic relations following the unfortunate event.</li><li>A high-level investigation has been promised to assess the circumstances of the crash.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will thoroughly investigate the circumstances that led to this unfortunate incident,” said Putin.</blockquote><p>This event underscores the complexities of air defense operations in conflict areas and the importance of international diplomacy in crisis situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/russian-air-defence-active-when-plane-crashed-russian-president-putin-to-azerbaijan-counterpart-ilham-aliyev/articleshow/116744006.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/russian-air-defence-active-when-plane-crashed-russian-president-putin-to-azerbaijan-counterpart-ilham-aliyev/articleshow/116744006.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Dangerous attack': WHO chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus shares video of narrow escape from Israeli attac - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dangerous attack: WHO chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus shares video of narrow escape from Israeli attack on Yemen</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p>
<p><img src="[Image URL]" alt="Image Description"><figcaption>[Image Caption]</figcaption></p>
<p>In a recent incident, WHO Chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus shared a video capturing his near miss from an Israeli attack in Yemen, highlighting the dangers faced by humanitarian workers in conflict zones.</p>
<ul>
  <li>WHO chief documented his narrow escape from an airstrike in Yemen.</li>
  <li>The video aims to raise awareness about the risks humanitarian organizations face.</li>
  <li>This incident underscores ongoing violence affecting vulnerable populations in the region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is a dangerous situation not just for aid workers, but for the people we serve.” - Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus</blockquote>
<p>This critical moment serves as a reminder of the perilous conditions under which humanitarian efforts operate amidst conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/dangerous-attack-who-chief-tedros-adhanom-ghebreyesus-shares-video-of-narrow-escape-from-israeli-attack-on-yemen/articleshow/116743188.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/dangerous-attack-who-chief-tedros-adhanom-ghebreyesus-shares-video-of-narrow-escape-from-israeli-attack-on-yemen/articleshow/116743188.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>