<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:25:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 06:25:03 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Consistently called for release of hostages': India issues statement on Israel-Hamas ceasefire in Gaza - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>India Calls for Release of Hostages Amid Israel-Hamas Ceasefire Discussions</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>India has issued a statement urging for the release of hostages in Gaza as ceasefire negotiations continue between Israel and Hamas.</p><ul><li>India emphasizes the importance of humanitarian considerations in the conflict.</li><li>The statement highlights India's call for peaceful resolution and assistance to affected civilians.</li><li>Diplomatic channels are being engaged to facilitate discussions.</li></ul><blockquote>"We consistently call for the release of all hostages to ensure peace in the region." - Indian Government Statement</blockquote><p>This statement underscores India's commitment to supporting peace efforts in ongoing conflicts and aligns with international calls for resolution.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/consistently-called-for-release-of-hostages-india-issues-statement-on-israel-hamas-ceasefire-in-gaza/articleshow/117285777.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/consistently-called-for-release-of-hostages-india-issues-statement-on-israel-hamas-ceasefire-in-gaza/articleshow/117285777.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 05:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel-Hamas ceasefire live updates: Israel escalates bombardment on Gaza amid truce deal announcement - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel-Hamas Ceasefire Live Updates: Escalation of Bombardment Amid Truce Deal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 16, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><div><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Mideast-Wars-Takeaways-0_1736979812844_1736979824147.jpg" alt="Israel-Hamas ceasefire live updates" title="Israel-Hamas ceasefire live updates: Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the final details are being worked out." loading="lazy" decoding="async"><figcaption>Israel-Hamas ceasefire live updates: Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the final details are being worked out.</figcaption></div><p>The United States, Egypt, and Qatar have been mediating an end to the war sparked by Hamas' attack on Israel in October 2023. While a significant ceasefire agreement is announced, Israeli bombardment on Gaza continues.</p><ul><li>A ceasefire agreement is reportedly close, but final details are being worked out by Israeli PM Netanyahu.</li><li>Qatar's PM confirmed a ceasefire in Gaza will begin soon, with 33 Israeli hostages released in the first phase.</li><li>The war has resulted in significant casualties: 46,707 deaths in Gaza, predominantly civilians, and 1,210 deaths in Israel, mostly civilians.</li><li>ISRAEL launched airstrikes resulting in 13 Palestinian casualties in recent hours.</li></ul><blockquote>“It is critical that everybody – that the outgoing Biden administration lays the groundwork for the incoming Trump administration...” - Jon Polin, family member of a hostage.</blockquote><p>The situation remains tense as both sides prepare for potential ceasing of hostilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-live-updates-benjamin-netanyahu-gaza-ceasefire-hostage-deal-latest-news-today-101736958511131.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-live-updates-benjamin-netanyahu-gaza-ceasefire-hostage-deal-latest-news-today-101736958511131.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 04:40:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bryan Johnson, are you taking notes? 124-year-old Chinese woman shares secrets to longevity - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>124-Year-Old Chinese Woman Shares Secrets to Longevity</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 1, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Qiu_Chaishi_1736934545736_1736934550292.png" alt="Qiu Chaishi was born in 1901.(X)" title="Qiu Chaishi was born in 1901.(X)"><figcaption>Qiu Chaishi was born in 1901.(X)</figcaption><p>Qiu Chaishi, who recently celebrated her 124th birthday, shares her insights on longevity and a fulfilling life. Residing in Nanchong, Sichuan Province, her life story reflects China's historical changes and her personal resilience.</p><ul><li>Born in 1901, Qiu has lived through significant periods in Chinese history.</li><li>Her family boasts six generations, underscoring her long-lasting legacy.</li><li>Qiu follows a strict daily routine, including meals and exercises like walking after each meal.</li><li>She attributes her longevity to a positive attitude and a balanced diet.</li><li>Living with her granddaughter, she maintains independence despite some age-related challenges.</li></ul><blockquote>“My siblings, husband, and son passed away long ago. The King of Hell must have forgotten about me and will not take me!” - Qiu Chaishi</blockquote><p>Her story encourages many, emphasizing a peaceful mindset as crucial for a long life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/124yearold-woman-in-china-inspires-millions-shares-secrets-of-longevity-my-siblings-son-passed-away-101736930466498.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/124yearold-woman-in-china-inspires-millions-shares-secrets-of-longevity-my-siblings-son-passed-away-101736930466498.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 04:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Prime Minister got down on one knee for Giorgia Meloni, surprised her with scarf on birthday. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Albanian Prime Minister Edi Rama Surprises Giorgia Meloni on Her 48th Birthday</h1><p><strong>Date: Jan 16, 2025 | Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/Albanian_Prime_Minister_Giorgia_Meloni_Birthday_1737001782865_1737001788876.jpg" alt="Albanian Prime Minister Edi Rama and his counterpart, Italy's Giorgia Meloni. (AFP)" title="Albanian Prime Minister Edi Rama and his counterpart, Italy's Giorgia Meloni. (AFP)"><figcaption>Albanian Prime Minister Edi Rama and his counterpart, Italy's Giorgia Meloni. (AFP)</figcaption><p>Albanian Prime Minister Edi Rama surprised Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni by presenting her with a scarf and singing to her on her 48th birthday during the World Future Energy Summit in Abu Dhabi.</p><ul><li>Rama went down on one knee to hand over the gift and serenade Meloni.</li><li>The scarf was designed by an Italian designer who has moved to Albania.</li><li>Despite their differing political backgrounds, the two leaders maintain a strong working relationship.</li><li>They have collaborated on migration issues, including an agreement to send some migrants to detention centers in Albania.</li><li>Italy, Albania, and the UAE signed a €1 billion deal for renewable energy at the summit.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tanti auguri” (happy birthday) - Edi Rama</blockquote><p>This celebratory gesture exemplifies the camaraderie between the two leaders and their shared commitment to collaboration on energy and migration issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/albanian-prime-minister-gets-down-on-one-knee-for-giorgia-meloni-surprises-her-with-scarf-on-birthday-watch-101737001060554.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/albanian-prime-minister-gets-down-on-one-knee-for-giorgia-meloni-surprises-her-with-scarf-on-birthday-watch-101737001060554.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 04:32:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Media Outlet Obtains Telegram Message Between Min Hee Jin And NewJeans Member’s Uncle - Koreaboo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Media Outlet Obtains Telegram Message Between Min Hee Jin And NewJeans Member’s Uncle</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> <time datetime="2025-01-16T03:29:36+00:00">2 hours ago</time> | <strong>Source:</strong> <span>Koreaboo</span></p>
<img loading="eager" src="https://img.koreaboo.com/tr:n-thumb_mega/2025/01/post1-2025-01-16T132705.085.jpg" width="900" height="439">
<figcaption>| <em>News1</em></figcaption>
<p>Min Hee Jin, the former CEO of ADOR, had a conversation with the uncle of a NewJeans member via Telegram about a complaint filed against the group regarding workplace bullying.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The conversation took place around the time Hanni, a member of NewJeans, was allegedly bullied at work.</li>
  <li>The Telegram message revealed possible violations of contract regulations by Min regarding the discussion of sensitive topics.</li>
  <li>Media outlets interpret Min's words to decipher her knowledge of the petition related to the Ministry of Employment and Labor.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Mr. A:</strong> The Ministry of Employment and Labor has started. Please call me.</p>
  <p><strong>Min Hee Jin:</strong> I’m currently getting an IV. I’ll call you in the afternoon.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This development raises questions about potential interventions by Min in light of the bullying accusations made by fans.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.koreaboo.com/news/media-outlet-obtains-telegram-message-min-hee-jin-regarding-ministry-employment-labor/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.koreaboo.com/news/media-outlet-obtains-telegram-message-min-hee-jin-regarding-ministry-employment-labor/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 04:29:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Generation Beta is here! From Gen Z to Silent Generation - Meet the stars from every era - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Generation Beta is Here: Meet the Stars from Every Era</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/collagegen_1736949453297_1736949479625.jpg" alt="Jeh with Kareena Kapoor Khan, Salman Khan, Alia Bhatt">
<figcaption>Jeh with Kareena Kapoor Khan, Salman Khan, Alia Bhatt</figcaption>
<p>As 2025 begins, a new generation, dubbed Generation Beta, enters the world. This article explores multiple generations, showcasing the stars associated with each.</p>
<ul>
<li>Generation Beta is set to grow up in a world heavily influenced by AI.</li>
<li>Generation Alpha includes celebrity children like Taimur and Jehangir.</li>
<li>Generation Z, also known as Zoomers, are marked by their strong opinions and digital nativity.</li>
<li>Millennials, or Gen Y, grew with the internet and prioritize living in the present.</li>
<li>Generation X experienced significant economic reforms and diverse cultural shifts.</li>
<li>Baby Boomers were characterized by optimism following India’s independence.</li>
<li>The Silent Generation witnessed India's struggle for independence and is defined by hard work.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The newest kids on the block will grow up immersed in AI and environments that promote inclusivity and creativity.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the emergence of Generation Beta adds a new chapter to the narrative of cultural and generational evolution in celebrity culture.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/generation-beta-is-here-from-gen-z-to-silent-generation-meet-the-stars-from-every-era-101736943110687.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/htcity/cinema/generation-beta-is-here-from-gen-z-to-silent-generation-meet-the-stars-from-every-era-101736943110687.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 04:29:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With Gaza deal, IMEC Corridor can become reality: Biden - The Siasat Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>With Gaza Deal, IMEC Corridor Can Become Reality: Biden</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Wednesday, October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Siasat Daily</p><figure><img src="https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IMEC-780x470.jpg" alt="Israel, US to benefit most by India-Middle East-Europe Corridor" width="1200" height="900"><figcaption>IMEC</figcaption></figure><p>US President Joe Biden announced that the recent ceasefire agreement between Israel and Hamas creates opportunities for the India-Middle East-Europe Corridor (IMEC) to become a reality. This corridor aims to enhance transportation and communication links between Europe and Asia.</p><ul><li>The IMEC Corridor extends from India to Europe through the Middle East, signed by eight countries.</li><li>It serves as an alternative to China's One Belt, One Road Initiative.</li><li>The project was affected by recent tensions in the region, specifically the Hamas attack on Israel.</li><li>The initiative positions India strategically in global supply chains.</li><li>Biden highlighted the significance of this corridor for regional economic integration.</li></ul><blockquote>“By offering an alternative to China’s Belt and Road Initiative, this project underscores New Delhi’s proactive approach to regional economic integration and infrastructure development.”</blockquote><p>This agreement marks a potential shift in regional collaboration and economic strategy, with lasting implications for international relations and trade.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.siasat.com/with-gaza-deal-imec-corridor-can-become-reality-biden-3165410/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.siasat.com/with-gaza-deal-imec-corridor-can-become-reality-biden-3165410/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 02:28:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden warns of dangerous 'oligarchy', ‘extreme wealth’ in dark farewell speech - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Joe Biden Warns of ‘Oligarchy’ and Extreme Wealth in Farewell Speech</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/USA-BIDEN--69_1736992545749_1736992571786.JPG" alt="US President Joe Biden delivers his farewell address to the nation from the Oval Office of the White House in Washington, DC.(REUTERS)" title="US President Joe Biden delivers his farewell address to the nation from the Oval Office of the White House in Washington, DC.(REUTERS)"><figcaption>US President Joe Biden delivers his farewell address to the nation from the Oval Office of the White House in Washington, DC.(REUTERS)</figcaption><p>In his farewell address, President Joe Biden raised alarms about a dangerous concentration of power and wealth in America, citing concerns about an emerging oligarchy and a tech-industrial complex.</p><ul><li>Biden highlights a worrying trend of extreme wealth concentration threatening democracy.</li><li>He warns of a tech-industrial complex infringing on democratic rights.</li><li>Biden invokes Eisenhower’s warnings about military-industrial complexes, expanding to current tech concerns.</li><li>Mentions the affluent supporting Trump's political rise.</li><li>Calls for constitutional amendments to limit presidential immunity.</li></ul><blockquote>“Today, an oligarchy is taking shape in America of extreme wealth, power and influence that literally threatens our entire democracy.” - Joe Biden</blockquote><p>This speech serves as a stark warning about the growing divide and the implications for the future of American democracy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/us-president-joe-biden-warns-of-dangerous-oligarchy-extreme-wealth-in-dark-farewell-speech-101736992473344.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/us-president-joe-biden-warns-of-dangerous-oligarchy-extreme-wealth-in-dark-farewell-speech-101736992473344.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 02:18:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden farewell speech live updates: President warns 'oligarchy of ultra-wealthy taking shape in America' - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQZHJVdVMzelRmNDNpcWJ4VzFJOWswOS1SWVFIYlBMZl9Zd3pxRVJRZl93d0k0SnFWTVpzcTFEdTIzRDU3d21wUUJ5dkdDaV84ME5rOFFpVmgwa3BBNHRucG55Wk10U3ZGa1BhZjdnRWREZktkM08xekFpaVNfazFsdW8xa3RLd3dRMHNhQjFFc1hISFdqeVU3SGZ5TmsxRk5MWkxDN1dyWVhhS3FBQjVKbzh3dWdPQ1hraWJNcXlTdFNnQnQ0YUg3RFhEZU5HZ2g5Uk1hX0Iyd2VFd2JyQTBNaUtfSWhOSVN5aVpNM2p4ZjlTN2VhMXhoddIB_gFBVV95cUxORzhSMkQzNzhDbExJRTltX3hfMW12Z0lCdWl4UHZQblhjSC1wZ1VJSFhodm9EMDdiYXpkeld5aHI1VUZNT0hwTkFnazY2dWNMcTM4QUFqNG1ua3dXNExmbC1rNDFKemdhcHNQc1BtbHhDa0xrTW1BTWtsQkJqejlITmNaclhjXy1mUlRSal8yN1ItZlZDNUpuR2FPM2ktYXBKQnlkbTlQaEhIQ1VKb3lUX05KX2Z6MGZfaUhwTTJ1ZDBYQjlqX1R3cUljdDhlaGx1OFlrVldTS0picVRmX0R0QlhnQ1hQcVVqcWtmNk5zdVJhOEVYU1o3LXlTV1V0UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxQZHJVdVMzelRmNDNpcWJ4VzFJOWswOS1SWVFIYlBMZl9Zd3pxRVJRZl93d0k0SnFWTVpzcTFEdTIzRDU3d21wUUJ5dkdDaV84ME5rOFFpVmgwa3BBNHRucG55Wk10U3ZGa1BhZjdnRWREZktkM08xekFpaVNfazFsdW8xa3RLd3dRMHNhQjFFc1hISFdqeVU3SGZ5TmsxRk5MWkxDN1dyWVhhS3FBQjVKbzh3dWdPQ1hraWJNcXlTdFNnQnQ0YUg3RFhEZU5HZ2g5Uk1hX0Iyd2VFd2JyQTBNaUtfSWhOSVN5aVpNM2p4ZjlTN2VhMXhoddIB_gFBVV95cUxORzhSMkQzNzhDbExJRTltX3hfMW12Z0lCdWl4UHZQblhjSC1wZ1VJSFhodm9EMDdiYXpkeld5aHI1VUZNT0hwTkFnazY2dWNMcTM4QUFqNG1ua3dXNExmbC1rNDFKemdhcHNQc1BtbHhDa0xrTW1BTWtsQkJqejlITmNaclhjXy1mUlRSal8yN1ItZlZDNUpuR2FPM2ktYXBKQnlkbTlQaEhIQ1VKb3lUX05KX2Z6MGZfaUhwTTJ1ZDBYQjlqX1R3cUljdDhlaGx1OFlrVldTS0picVRmX0R0QlhnQ1hQcVVqcWtmNk5zdVJhOEVYU1o3LXlTV1V0UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:54:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[President Joe Biden warns of dangers of ‘oligarchy’ running the U.S. in farewell address to nation - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>President Joe Biden warns of dangers of ‘oligarchy’ running the U.S. in farewell address to nation</h1><p><strong>Published on: January 16, 2025</strong></p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/z22g9y/article69103301.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Biden_79486.jpg" alt="President Joe Biden speaks from the Oval Office of the White House as he gives his farewell address on January 15, 2025, in Washington." title="President Joe Biden speaks from the Oval Office of the White House as he gives his farewell address on January 15, 2025, in Washington."><figcaption>Photo Credit: AP</figcaption><p>In his farewell address, President Biden expressed concerns about the rise of an oligarchy in the U.S. and warned against a growing tech-industrial complex that threatens democracy.</p><ul><li>Biden highlighted the concentration of wealth and power in the hands of a few, calling it a threat to democracy.</li><li>He drew parallels to Eisenhower's warnings about the military-industrial complex, indicating concerns over the tech-industrial complex.</li><li>The president addressed the need for vigilance to protect freedoms amid rapid technological and economic changes.</li><li>Biden emphasized the importance of a peaceful transfer of power as he prepares to leave office on January 20.</li><li>He reflected on his five-decade political career, marking the end of his presidency and legacy.</li></ul><blockquote>“Today, an oligarchy is taking shape in America... Dangerous consequences if their abuse of power is left unchecked.”</blockquote><p>Biden's speech underscores the challenges ahead as he concludes his term amidst a divided political landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/joe-biden-farewell-address-us-oligarchy-final-speech-as-president-donald-trump/article69103300.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/joe-biden-farewell-address-us-oligarchy-final-speech-as-president-donald-trump/article69103300.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In farewell address to nation, Biden warns of dangers of ‘oligarchy’ running the U.S. - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden's Farewell Address: Warning Against an Oligarchy in America</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/z22g9y/article69103301.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Biden_79486.jpg" alt="President Joe Biden speaks from the Oval Office of the White House as he gives his farewell address on January 15, 2025, in Washington." />
<figcaption>President Joe Biden speaks from the Oval Office of the White House as he gives his farewell address on January 15, 2025, in Washington. | Photo Credit: AP</figcaption>
<p>In his farewell address, President Joe Biden warns of an emerging oligarchy in the U.S. and a tech-industrial complex that threatens democracy and citizens' rights.</p>
<ul>
<li>Biden highlights the concentration of wealth and power among a small elite as a threat to democracy.</li>
<li>He raises concerns about a potential tech-industrial complex similar to the military-industrial complex warned about by Eisenhower.</li>
<li>The address serves as a model for a peaceful transfer of power as he prepares to hand over to President-elect Donald Trump.</li>
<li>Biden mentions significant achievements during his presidency while acknowledging the challenges ahead.</li>
<li>Calls for a constitutional amendment to end presidential immunity after Supreme Court rulings that could protect Trump.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Today, an oligarchy is taking shape in America of extreme wealth, power and influence that literally threatens our entire democracy.” - Joe Biden</blockquote>
<p>This farewell address not only highlighted Biden's immediate concerns but also reflected on his long political career, concluding five decades of public service.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/joe-biden-farewell-address-us-oligarchy-final-speech-as-president-donald-trump/article69103300.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/joe-biden-farewell-address-us-oligarchy-final-speech-as-president-donald-trump/article69103300.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden administration thanks Donald Trump after Israel-Hamas hostage deal: ‘Crucial’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Administration Acknowledges Trump's Role in Israel-Hamas Hostage Deal</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/16/550x309/AP12-23-2024-000005B-0_1736538936843_1736987758683.jpg" alt="President-elect Donald Trump was in the centre of news after Israel, Hamas deal.(AP)" title="President-elect Donald Trump was in the centre of news after Israel, Hamas deal.(AP)"><figcaption>President-elect Donald Trump was in the centre of news after Israel, Hamas deal.(AP)</figcaption><p>The Biden administration has publicly thanked President-elect Donald Trump for his team's involvement in brokering a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, which has been plagued by conflict since October 2023.</p><ul><li>The US State Department stated that Trump's team played a critical role in facilitating the truce.</li><li>The deal involves a three-phase agreement aimed at releasing hostages and allowing humanitarian aid into Gaza.</li><li>The ceasefire is expected to pause fighting for an initial six weeks, during which negotiations will continue.</li><li>46,000 lives have been claimed by the ongoing war, highlighting its devastating impact.</li></ul><blockquote>“It shows that when Americans are willing to work together across partisan lines… a lot can get done.” - Matthew Miller, State Department spokesperson</blockquote><p>In closing, the involvement of both administrations underscores the significance of bipartisan cooperation in achieving peace in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/joe-biden-administration-thanks-donald-trump-after-israel-hamas-hostage-deal-crucial-101736987302200.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/joe-biden-administration-thanks-donald-trump-after-israel-hamas-hostage-deal-crucial-101736987302200.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 01:32:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel-Hamas ceasefire live updates: Netanyahu thanked US President-elect Donald Trump in a call after Gaza truce deal - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel-Hamas ceasefire live updates: Netanyahu thanked US President-elect Donald Trump in a call after Gaza truce deal</h1><p><strong>Date: January 16, 2025</strong> <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Mideast-Wars-Takeaways-0_1736979812844_1736979824147.jpg" alt="Israel-Hamas ceasefire updates" title="Israel-Hamas ceasefire updates: Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the final details are being worked out."><figcaption>Israel-Hamas ceasefire updates: Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the final details are being worked out.</figcaption><p>The article discusses the ongoing ceasefire discussions between Israel and Hamas, mediated by the United States, Egypt, and Qatar.</p><ul><li>Netanyahu announced that the ceasefire agreement is still being finalized.</li><li>A ceasefire in Gaza is set to begin on Sunday, with the first phase involving the release of 33 Israeli hostages.</li><li>The 15-month conflict, sparked by Hamas' October 2023 attack, resulted in significant casualties on both sides.</li><li>The article includes comments from various leaders, including Donald Trump and Bernie Sanders, emphasizing the need for humanitarian assistance.</li><li>Public reactions in Tel Aviv show citizens celebrating the potential end to hostilities.</li></ul><blockquote>“Both sides must honor the deal and implement it as quickly as possible. The senseless killing must stop.” - Bernie Sanders</blockquote><p>The ceasefire represents a crucial step towards peace in the region, but its long-term sustainability remains to be seen.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-live-updates-benjamin-netanyahu-gaza-ceasefire-hostage-deal-latest-news-today-101736958511131.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-live-updates-benjamin-netanyahu-gaza-ceasefire-hostage-deal-latest-news-today-101736958511131.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:04:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US: Trump Considers Executive Order To Stop ‘TikTok Ban’ - Gulte]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Considers Executive Order to Delay TikTok Ban</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> 4:13 am, 16 January 2025</p>
<img width="1200" height="900" src="https://cdn.gulte.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/TikTok.jpg" alt="" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>An image related to the TikTok ban.</figcaption>
<p>US President-elect Donald Trump is reportedly considering an executive order that would stop the enforcement of the TikTok ban for 60 to 90 days.</p>
<ul>
  <li>TikTok will be banned in the US on January 19 unless the Supreme Court accepts a legal bid from its Chinese Owner ByteDance.</li>
  <li>The ban will restrict app stores such as Google PlayStore and Apple App Store from allowing downloads of TikTok.</li>
  <li>Current users will retain access to the app, but no new updates will leave it unusable over time.</li>
  <li>Concerns about data privacy and national security are driving the US government's actions against TikTok.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The user data collected by TikTok could be accessed by the Chinese government.”</blockquote>
<p>This potential executive order may provide temporary relief for TikTok users while legal battles continue in the Supreme Court.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.gulte.com/trends/335135/us-trump-considers-executive-order-to-stop-tiktok-ban</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gulte.com/trends/335135/us-trump-considers-executive-order-to-stop-tiktok-ban</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 22:43:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Michelle Obama is skipping Trump's inauguration because she is not 'phoney'. 'Who is she taking dig at?' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/michelle-obama-is-skipping-trumps-inauguration-because-she-is-not-phoney-who-is-she-taking-dig-at/articleshow/117277450.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/michelle-obama-is-skipping-trumps-inauguration-because-she-is-not-phoney-who-is-she-taking-dig-at/articleshow/117277450.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 21:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How US sanctions on Russia shadow fleet may impact India oil imports - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How US sanctions on Russia shadow fleet may impact India oil imports</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>The United States recently announced significant sanctions against Russia's oil trade, particularly targeting its shadow fleet, which may have considerable implications for India's crude oil imports.</p><ul><li>US sanctions encompass 183 tankers and target major Russian oil companies and insurers.</li><li>Russia is now India's largest crude oil supplier following significant discounts offered after the war in Ukraine.</li><li>Indian refiners can still accept cargoes from sanctioned vessels booked prior to sanctions until March 12.</li><li>Experts anticipate a shift toward West Asian suppliers as the availability of tankers for Russian oil decreases.</li><li>Russia may need to sell oil below the Western price cap of $60 per barrel to mitigate sanctions effects.</li></ul><blockquote>"India is not part of the sanctions regime against Russia, but it has generally tried to avoid falling foul of them to prevent secondary US sanctions."</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while the new sanctions are unlikely to halt Indian oil imports, they may prompt a shift towards alternative suppliers, affecting the pricing and availability of Russian oil in the near future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/us-sanctions-russias-oil-trade-indias-crude-imports-9779906/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-economics/us-sanctions-russias-oil-trade-indias-crude-imports-9779906/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 21:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel, Hamas seal ceasefire agreement; end 15-month-long Gaza war - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel and Hamas Reach Ceasefire Agreement Ending 15-Month Conflict</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 16, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/15/550x309/Gaza_1736955284805_1736955285245.jpg" alt="A Palestinian looks at a damaged residential building following an overnight Israeli strike in Deir al-Balah, Gaza Strip, on Jan. 8, 2025.(AP)"><figcaption>A Palestinian looks at a damaged residential building following an overnight Israeli strike in Deir al-Balah, Gaza Strip, on Jan. 8, 2025.(AP)</figcaption><p>The ceasefire agreement between Israel and Hamas signals the end of a 15-month conflict that escalated after Hamas attacked Israel in October 2023. The agreement was reached after mediation efforts by the United States, Egypt, and Qatar.</p><ul><li>Ceasefire will begin on Sunday.</li><li>33 Israeli hostages will be released in the first phase.</li><li>Hamas conducted a deadly attack on Israel on October 7, 2023, resulting in 1,210 Israeli deaths.</li><li>46,707 Palestinians have been killed during the conflict, mostly civilians.</li><li>The talks had previously faced last-minute obstacles but were resolved by Qatari mediation.</li></ul><blockquote>“The ceasefire agreement marks the end of a 15-month-long conflict between Israel and Hamas.”</blockquote><p>This ceasefire is a significant development in the ongoing conflict, reflecting the complex political dynamics in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-updates-benjamin-netanyahu-gaza-ceasefire-latest-news-today-101736955045661.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-updates-benjamin-netanyahu-gaza-ceasefire-latest-news-today-101736955045661.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Armenia to tow Indo-French artillery gun system - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxQdTBlb3pVQ01MUElmbnhaNzFFWTBya0ZxZWdDbFNfY25WSnRLTTJfbDZxR2JPU3NZSEFNVVdjRjdFWkV0d1ZXUWcycTJ4X1Y3QUg4Q3VRZDYycGRTX25HZHpzTzl0NW1jTlB3TE91aFIyblAxTVk3U1Y5MklGSHJ0UWNOWkxhWF9qbWpjYUpCR2cxUWFYbXVhMUJvZ1cxQlpBbGNHU2FuWGplTHMwZkNDcHU0QWzSAboBQVVfeXFMTXIyT2ZNQUIyZVpuYmVUUDFCTklha3hRT0RYRnlLNS11aXQ5S2ZoY2hKYjNFWnJxSzhSRG5iOFFkUDFKYkNsNTJMOC1tYWFsLVZuZnZobzlpelByNndpVFVoN29hRllJRFhTMFpQTXpuN3hkQXNWSlpkclRCUlJUZy1JLXpOUHREdkF1Qzd6ZTVJSjkzMFZVUmVGMXh6Y0JJcE9Ga2h5NTBoWGZhRnRmTlhIVTc2N3J5eUNR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxQdTBlb3pVQ01MUElmbnhaNzFFWTBya0ZxZWdDbFNfY25WSnRLTTJfbDZxR2JPU3NZSEFNVVdjRjdFWkV0d1ZXUWcycTJ4X1Y3QUg4Q3VRZDYycGRTX25HZHpzTzl0NW1jTlB3TE91aFIyblAxTVk3U1Y5MklGSHJ0UWNOWkxhWF9qbWpjYUpCR2cxUWFYbXVhMUJvZ1cxQlpBbGNHU2FuWGplTHMwZkNDcHU0QWzSAboBQVVfeXFMTXIyT2ZNQUIyZVpuYmVUUDFCTklha3hRT0RYRnlLNS11aXQ5S2ZoY2hKYjNFWnJxSzhSRG5iOFFkUDFKYkNsNTJMOC1tYWFsLVZuZnZobzlpelByNndpVFVoN29hRllJRFhTMFpQTXpuN3hkQXNWSlpkclRCUlJUZy1JLXpOUHREdkF1Qzd6ZTVJSjkzMFZVUmVGMXh6Y0JJcE9Ga2h5NTBoWGZhRnRmTlhIVTc2N3J5eUNR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:20:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel-Hamas war live updates: Netanyahu's office says ‘ceasefire deal still not reached, details being sorted out’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxOeFFLc1AzV3BHUVFLdWVRb3lNOWNIMGdya19lT0NJcjNrT2Z0T2ZFVFdSR0l1cWxjd2JnR001cnYwMkRXckVIQUwwakYyOTZDdjJyZm5nVzhxV2lnZjZDc2JXQUI1blBXckhjSW1oNWxtSU1qZHJKLTk3cXBaVGZCUXJQT01TZ3U4MUJ1T3lZWktyR2loZGNhWW9MNXByWG9NYTZ6TjdNLUVxZGVzQlBrajJoZ25ldlBQQ1BERGxXSjE3aHlVaDFtZTJ5c3N4M29uN1lwNlQzRW14U3JXand1dE1mQW5QQTFpWUZsRWV30gHzAUFVX3lxTE55RDZMWGdiQUg4QlptOHJSUkhWcm5GWGxtMEc3aFJpVXZKd2RtQURkTVFZQ3A4VTJxM2p1NzdWcDlmNjRfQWQzWjZrU2tabDdhT1pVS3BoRG5IN2lnUXFja1E1V3FjZXhNVGxrWVgzWm1UeThoeXVsOG9sUTQzVGJCZHBKcnZqVUliRHduTUNQbmVyX3FXSU5KLWxFM1NTalhuaXRMOG54TXE1bzFWbFNsOGRUUGhWcEcwcVQzS0RELXFpRkVSQXoxd3I2S0lhakV3Wm55SzhkbEp6cVB0OENkbEFSWmxzZ2wtdkpPZER5bU1vQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi7gFBVV95cUxOeFFLc1AzV3BHUVFLdWVRb3lNOWNIMGdya19lT0NJcjNrT2Z0T2ZFVFdSR0l1cWxjd2JnR001cnYwMkRXckVIQUwwakYyOTZDdjJyZm5nVzhxV2lnZjZDc2JXQUI1blBXckhjSW1oNWxtSU1qZHJKLTk3cXBaVGZCUXJQT01TZ3U4MUJ1T3lZWktyR2loZGNhWW9MNXByWG9NYTZ6TjdNLUVxZGVzQlBrajJoZ25ldlBQQ1BERGxXSjE3aHlVaDFtZTJ5c3N4M29uN1lwNlQzRW14U3JXand1dE1mQW5QQTFpWUZsRWV30gHzAUFVX3lxTE55RDZMWGdiQUg4QlptOHJSUkhWcm5GWGxtMEc3aFJpVXZKd2RtQURkTVFZQ3A4VTJxM2p1NzdWcDlmNjRfQWQzWjZrU2tabDdhT1pVS3BoRG5IN2lnUXFja1E1V3FjZXhNVGxrWVgzWm1UeThoeXVsOG9sUTQzVGJCZHBKcnZqVUliRHduTUNQbmVyX3FXSU5KLWxFM1NTalhuaXRMOG54TXE1bzFWbFNsOGRUUGhWcEcwcVQzS0RELXFpRkVSQXoxd3I2S0lhakV3Wm55SzhkbEp6cVB0OENkbEFSWmxzZ2wtdkpPZER5bU1vQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 18:16:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘We have a deal’: Donald Trump shares big update on hostages after Israel-Hamas truce - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxPelV0ODlqOGJveHJqcWpNMTZScTAtTEMtU2lKSG94a2JpVU84V25MZU9BQTNWMWluLThjbVNsdmtzdmlEbUpUV0J2RExsZEhZeDJLNmJhWHBMZm5YX0RaR3FVZ1dUa29oX0pLVXFTWUhJendZOHpLaXF1ZTVXZmc1bHAwRG8wVG1YcDczcmNzR0JLM1RGUTNOcHJ3WHI0Sm95dGZyYmNyX1FNX0Zzdll4TExUX2pQV1FKLXRBdXFhQndsOHVLek9ka2w4aHhtVFdvM1FGeU1XWTV2YXl3M2fSAeMBQVVfeXFMT1U1ZDJNRlN0Z3gzYURfVkFtOXR3OGg1a0dDY3Jnek8zTmxhcjR3ZXNMa1BYVUZwckV2M3lrdDktb3loc1BHMDE2Y0l1WllPUG8xYS1hNmUydUlQT3U5aFlBZm9UdVZsdlJLSTk1emNxcEllQ2FncHdOSkp2cFYwYmU4WFo1bjBlQmY1bHZYdXNnME85b3FmV3pGUkNJN1dURmVwdVlKSFV1ZXBjT1ZEMEpaekVJOVpZMXRnSTh3eVU2eVFXSlJfeE04SXFHWHRQZ1VsZzJzRnIzaTVMVXpHV0VvZTg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi3gFBVV95cUxPelV0ODlqOGJveHJqcWpNMTZScTAtTEMtU2lKSG94a2JpVU84V25MZU9BQTNWMWluLThjbVNsdmtzdmlEbUpUV0J2RExsZEhZeDJLNmJhWHBMZm5YX0RaR3FVZ1dUa29oX0pLVXFTWUhJendZOHpLaXF1ZTVXZmc1bHAwRG8wVG1YcDczcmNzR0JLM1RGUTNOcHJ3WHI0Sm95dGZyYmNyX1FNX0Zzdll4TExUX2pQV1FKLXRBdXFhQndsOHVLek9ka2w4aHhtVFdvM1FGeU1XWTV2YXl3M2fSAeMBQVVfeXFMT1U1ZDJNRlN0Z3gzYURfVkFtOXR3OGg1a0dDY3Jnek8zTmxhcjR3ZXNMa1BYVUZwckV2M3lrdDktb3loc1BHMDE2Y0l1WllPUG8xYS1hNmUydUlQT3U5aFlBZm9UdVZsdlJLSTk1emNxcEllQ2FncHdOSkp2cFYwYmU4WFo1bjBlQmY1bHZYdXNnME85b3FmV3pGUkNJN1dURmVwdVlKSFV1ZXBjT1ZEMEpaekVJOVpZMXRnSTh3eVU2eVFXSlJfeE04SXFHWHRQZ1VsZzJzRnIzaTVMVXpHV0VvZTg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:37:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia uses 'fake nuke' Kh-55SM missiles to strike Ukraine - Bulgarian Military]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia Deploys Kh-55SM Missiles in Strategic Air Strike Against Ukraine</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Bulgarian Military</p><figure><img src="https://bulgarianmilitary.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Russia-uses-fake-nuke-Kh-55SM-missiles-to-strike-Ukraine.jpg" alt="Russia uses 'fake nuke' Kh-55SM missiles to strike Ukraine"><figcaption>Photo credit: DSNS</figcaption></figure><p>Russia launched a complex air strike against Ukraine, utilizing Kh-55SM missiles equipped with non-explosive mock warheads as decoys.</p><ul><li>The strike included 30 missiles and 47 enemy UAVs intercepted by Ukrainian forces.</li><li>The Kh-55SM missiles are part of a broader military strategy and were launched from the Volgograd region.</li><li>Ukrainian air defense systems had an 85% interception rate against conventional missiles.</li><li>The primary target was Ukraine’s gas infrastructure, with limited damage reported.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ukrainian air defense forces shot down 30 missiles and 47 enemy UAVs, while 27 others failed to reach their targets.” — Maria Drutska 🇺🇦</blockquote><p>This air strike reflects ongoing Russian military strategies and highlights the challenges faced by Ukrainian air defenses amidst advanced missile tactics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bulgarianmilitary.com/2025/01/15/russia-uses-fake-nuke-kh-55sm-missiles-to-strike-ukraine/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bulgarianmilitary.com/2025/01/15/russia-uses-fake-nuke-kh-55sm-missiles-to-strike-ukraine/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:27:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['We Have A Deal...': Trump Becomes First World Leader To Announce Gaza Accord - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxNcGVBYjhjN0RKOG1mdjRzS2QtOW9INE9wNVpRdUtUOGlUdENsbGpFQkhZTDQwODF4eFloRDY4UTlQa1dYY0R5VWxnbVpqdjViNnNXdDczVUQyQTI5WkRtcV9abGY0R2JYQ1BoZGhXZTZaTU1uZHVkVjNFQ3FCbWp1aDlQWFI0WVAwQlFCRmdvR1VEQlRfdFpiNXRPWFNpeUJERldlQWQ5T00xdDRRUHJRVnBjb21OVVRiNEhLUFBPZ3pmZHJt0gHKAUFVX3lxTE9kcHhwQURMUWd4STFEVG05eWxpMU0xS3VhaXdsR1Z5RGlIZXZBVktPWlBrdm12OXY3WGZORWx2Z3E3QkFXRmRLcEo1NmNPMXUyV0RmQzVXV0VGSklQQU5LS1dVeDhjS2RCUVdueTJuMUN1XzV1REFJUDFCZmVuNllJOVRIQVhqV1dxd2oxdUkxWHVtMW1RQzBzd2c1TjdSUDRwbl84SXhaRXRhU0RvUWxUUVFQMHI3WVRVZktTOFpLbGgwalZNTzFOVGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixAFBVV95cUxNcGVBYjhjN0RKOG1mdjRzS2QtOW9INE9wNVpRdUtUOGlUdENsbGpFQkhZTDQwODF4eFloRDY4UTlQa1dYY0R5VWxnbVpqdjViNnNXdDczVUQyQTI5WkRtcV9abGY0R2JYQ1BoZGhXZTZaTU1uZHVkVjNFQ3FCbWp1aDlQWFI0WVAwQlFCRmdvR1VEQlRfdFpiNXRPWFNpeUJERldlQWQ5T00xdDRRUHJRVnBjb21OVVRiNEhLUFBPZ3pmZHJt0gHKAUFVX3lxTE9kcHhwQURMUWd4STFEVG05eWxpMU0xS3VhaXdsR1Z5RGlIZXZBVktPWlBrdm12OXY3WGZORWx2Z3E3QkFXRmRLcEo1NmNPMXUyV0RmQzVXV0VGSklQQU5LS1dVeDhjS2RCUVdueTJuMUN1XzV1REFJUDFCZmVuNllJOVRIQVhqV1dxd2oxdUkxWHVtMW1RQzBzd2c1TjdSUDRwbl84SXhaRXRhU0RvUWxUUVFQMHI3WVRVZktTOFpLbGgwalZNTzFOVGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:27:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LIVE: Israel, Hamas agree for Gaza ceasefire, hostage release - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Qatari Prime Minister says Israel and Hamas agree to ceasefire deal to pause Gaza war and release some hostages, reports AP.</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 15, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/wuneyu/article69102176.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2025-01-15T171500Z_1535064749_RC2HACA5AR8E_RTRMADP_3_ISRAEL-PALESTINIANS-GAZA-HOSTAGES-PROTEST.JPG" alt="Protest for Hostage Release in Gaza"><figcaption>Supporters of Israeli hostages, who were kidnapped during the deadly October 7 2023 attack by Hamas, attend a protest to demand a deal to bring every hostage home at once.</figcaption><p>Israel and Hamas have reached a deal for a ceasefire in Gaza, following negotiations in Qatar, marking an end to a 15-month war and the release of hostages.</p><ul><li>Ceasefire to go into effect on Sunday.</li><li>Deal includes phases for the release of hostages and Palestinian prisoners.</li><li>Humanitarian aid to be flooded into Gaza as part of the agreement.</li><li>Crowds celebrate the news across Gaza.</li></ul><blockquote>“This deal will halt the fighting in Gaza, surge much needed humanitarian assistance to Palestinian civilians, and reunite the hostages with their families after more than 15 months in captivity.” — President Joe Biden</blockquote><p>The ceasefire agreement represents a significant development towards peace in the region and aims to alleviate the humanitarian crisis in Gaza.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/israel-hamas-ceasefire-agreement-on-january-15-2025/article69102175.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/israel-hamas-ceasefire-agreement-on-january-15-2025/article69102175.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fed Up Of Paying Rs 1 Lakh In Rent, Woman Moves Into Boat With Dog - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxQOVpFeVpoTDE1SEgweUtVdkFhdjlGRDJ4dFdjcHhySHB0WnJPTnNRcVhMNlBEcHBxVXhRRHBOWjRKLUpEaFh5N0djWngtUFQzb0J0NHJEdDNUcTFNTkFMNzlHaUVuS1FiYml6enhadF9mOWVsUEVaY0JlWFhrNm56V1Z2Q2htc09ySjdqbzhCbDkzUks2MEtRQnc2RjAzb1QtOVU3V0FwdGw5aDE0RnUzZDR4bmdYZGdJ0gG-AUFVX3lxTE00d05JTU4wSzFmS2NENzdWUVZZOW1QSklkS0ZyZTRWQmU4Y1V3WG9SY1hpUVRTamJJSGtlNEJPTUtqMFhQZFFPbEgtUFZlV3M0bmlVTmVpRWg4VUxsN01FaU9DZHFJckgzRHFZR0EwN2k1TEdMTk5RUFhRRzMweDlyRURSdXJ6d1pRVXBBSjk2SjROV2ctVDVPN0toQmtPTUVDV1dmSnk1bEpsZFZ5ZlEtSkhDbS1OczRPdDdLNFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxQOVpFeVpoTDE1SEgweUtVdkFhdjlGRDJ4dFdjcHhySHB0WnJPTnNRcVhMNlBEcHBxVXhRRHBOWjRKLUpEaFh5N0djWngtUFQzb0J0NHJEdDNUcTFNTkFMNzlHaUVuS1FiYml6enhadF9mOWVsUEVaY0JlWFhrNm56V1Z2Q2htc09ySjdqbzhCbDkzUks2MEtRQnc2RjAzb1QtOVU3V0FwdGw5aDE0RnUzZDR4bmdYZGdJ0gG-AUFVX3lxTE00d05JTU4wSzFmS2NENzdWUVZZOW1QSklkS0ZyZTRWQmU4Y1V3WG9SY1hpUVRTamJJSGtlNEJPTUtqMFhQZFFPbEgtUFZlV3M0bmlVTmVpRWg4VUxsN01FaU9DZHFJckgzRHFZR0EwN2k1TEdMTk5RUFhRRzMweDlyRURSdXJ6d1pRVXBBSjk2SjROV2ctVDVPN0toQmtPTUVDV1dmSnk1bEpsZFZ5ZlEtSkhDbS1OczRPdDdLNFE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:17:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump 2.0: With A Whopping $21B In Arms Backlog, U.S. To Expedite Weapons Delivery To Taiwan: Waltz - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump 2.0: U.S. to Expedite Weapons Delivery to Taiwan Amid $21B Arms Backlog</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 14, 2024 | Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Untitled-1290-x-650-px-2.png" alt="US President-elect Donald Trump" width="1290" height="650">
<figcaption>US President-elect Donald Trump (Image for Representation)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Donald Trump aims to expedite the delivery of arms to Taiwan, reducing a backlog exceeding $20 billion, to enhance Taiwan's combat readiness against increasing Chinese military threats.</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump plans to clear a backlog of arms sales to Taiwan that currently totals $21 billion.</li>
<li>Mike Waltz, the incoming US national security advisor, emphasized the need for timely delivery of these military supplies.</li>
<li>China's military activities in the Taiwan Strait heighten the urgency of enhancing Taiwan's defense capabilities.</li>
<li>Trump's military strategies include selling advanced weaponry to Taiwan, which may face delays due to supply chain issues.</li>
<li>The continuous military support aims to deter potential Chinese aggression towards Taiwan.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We have over a $20 billion backlog of things that they paid for and that we need to work hard to free up.” - Mike Waltz</blockquote>
<p>The acceleration of arms deliveries is critical in light of rising tensions in East Asia, showcasing the U.S. commitment to Taiwan's defense.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/trump-2-0-with-a-whopping-21b-in-arms/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/trump-2-0-with-a-whopping-21b-in-arms/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:43:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unforgiving Trump says to ERS is American - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Delivers Strong Message to ERS on American Identity</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Trump Image"><figcaption>Trump at a rally</figcaption><p>In a recent statement, former President Donald Trump emphasized the significance of American identity and values during his address to the ERS. His comments have sparked discussions about citizenship and national pride.</p><ul><li>Trump's address to the ERS focused on the importance of American values.</li><li>He underscored the need for unity in the face of division.</li><li>The speech was met with both support and criticism from various political circles.</li></ul><blockquote>“We must stand strong together as Americans, preserve our values, and not lose sight of what makes our nation great,” Trump stated.</blockquote><p>This speech highlights ongoing debates about nationalism and identity politics in America today.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/unforgiving-trump-says-to-ers-is-american/articleshow/117273825.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/unforgiving-trump-says-to-ers-is-american/articleshow/117273825.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rubio, pro-Israel hawk set to be Trump’s top diplomat, vows ‘America First’ - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/15/rubio-pro-israel-hawk-set-to-be-trumps-top-diplomat-vows-america-first</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/15/rubio-pro-israel-hawk-set-to-be-trumps-top-diplomat-vows-america-first</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh commission proposes dropping ‘secularism’, ‘socialism’ from Constitution - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh commission proposes dropping ‘secularism’, ‘socialism’ from Constitution</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p>
<img src="https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/962c56e/2147483647/strip/true/crop/5527x3684+0+0/resize/599x399!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2F5e%2F57%2F7eaa0e6115a3ff2d5c4116cd1222%2F8c6a353bb5084586841ed98e416634ea" alt="Men run past a burning vehicle inside the Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University Hospital" />
<figcaption>Men run past a burning vehicle inside the Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University Hospital during a protest rally in Dhaka, Bangladesh.</figcaption>
<p>The Constitution Reform Commission in Bangladesh has proposed significant changes including removing the state principles of secularism, socialism, and nationalism from the constitution. This comes in light of the country’s recent political upheaval following the ousting of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The commission proposes to introduce a bicameral parliament structure.</li>
    <li>Only 'democracy' will remain among the four fundamental principles of state policy.</li>
    <li>A new set of state principles proposed includes equality, human dignity, and social justice.</li>
    <li>Recommendations also include limiting the prime minister's tenure to two terms.</li>
    <li>A National Constitutional Council is suggested to establish checks and balances.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our party supports the need for reforms and has submitted its proposals, but these should be implemented by an elected government, not the interim administration,” said Shama Obaed, BNP organizing secretary.</blockquote>
<p>The proposed changes could reshape the political landscape in Bangladesh and may provoke public response regarding their legality and necessity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-secularism-socialism-constitution-9780874/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/india/bangladesh-secularism-socialism-constitution-9780874/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:23:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deepfakes Are Becoming More Convincing: How to Spot Them - Softonic EN]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Deepfakes Are Becoming More Convincing: How to Spot Them</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Softonic</p>
<figure><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="984" src="https://articles-img.sftcdn.net/t_articles/auto-mapping-folder/sites/3/2025/01/avast-deepfake-inside-15012025.jpg" alt="Deepfake Image"><figcaption>Deepfake illustration showing the rise of this technology.</figcaption></figure>
<p>With deepfakes on the rise, understanding how to detect them is essential. These manipulations, made possible by advanced AI techniques, can generate highly realistic videos and audio recordings of public figures, leading to potential exploitation.</p>
<ul>
<li>Deepfakes target public figures like actors and politicians.</li>
<li>Created using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) and deep learning algorithms.</li>
<li>Misuse includes spreading false information and damaging reputations.</li>
<li>Cybersecurity firms are developing detection tools to combat deepfake technology.</li>
</ul>
<h2>How to Tell If a Video Has Been Altered:</h2>
<ol>
<li>Pay close attention to the face for inconsistencies.</li>
<li>Check the cheeks and forehead for unnatural skin textures.</li>
<li>Observe the eyes and eyebrows for proper shadowing.</li>
<li>Look at reflections and glare in glasses.</li>
<li>Evaluate the realism of facial hair.</li>
<li>Check for natural blinking.</li>
<li>Assess lip movements for synchronicity.</li>
<li>Pay attention to the quality of sound and voice realism.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>“If something seems off, or if what the celebrity is saying appears completely unrealistic, illogical, or inflammatory, be skeptical.”</blockquote>
<p>As deepfakes become increasingly sophisticated, staying informed and vigilant is crucial to navigating today's digital landscape.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://en.softonic.com/articles/deepfakes-are-becoming-more-convincing-how-to-spot-them</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.softonic.com/articles/deepfakes-are-becoming-more-convincing-how-to-spot-them</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:22:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pam Bondi is asked whether she will enforce an 'enemies list' like Kash Patel announced. Her reply is... - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxQWVI1VWU1Z1VhRHJKWm05R2FhY2Z3NEtTUlVsd3JqbGpLaElUSUszQ1BiZFJpdW5IRmJaY0JaaE5acmRGWUFjQkxmQV9vVlBJdHFJNDYxUTJzNWdXbm9ka29qT01DdGRNRy1xbTBhRGNsbHJzbG4yVmxmRmlTdTdYbUJLbjEwMFNXVmI2MHVSaVNzY2h6NlRNMjFFQU1LTm9scGNfMVFLQ09VenNUd0YtQWR5QlNoTHk2bVQxTzZDOGhNODl2X3NkaHhJQWh6akRMOEdTX2xnaTV5MlhhbTk0WWo3bUlTazJjdWRkMmhxOEJ6OFdLd3pSaHdtMEowZmfSAYQCQVVfeXFMTkNnaXgxUzZ2VDFQUmYtQWpmSDNNaW01WWtaYTlxdmNIck5CZ2IxdWJMOVloWGlJaDRfb1FVd181UmdmRkFUSzVCQTlUNGMxZGJuMUhQRWRkbDBLcUl4eU1aSzEtbnB0QVE3dERzLWdMT0pZZHhSa295cmFId0tvOVpEc21FMGs5dEFndmVRMktnd0I3M1J0ZGlPWjhtWFJQNnlKam1SN2dqa1RuLW1VWU9Wdy04VlVpeDBvbllvckljZk8ydDd0OUlqaTVyZFUxZEN6T1lTemlQQzZ2R0l2bDdaampzNEFNR3JFZnRtM0pDZXNFRFVzWmducnB3eUl0c1VDb0g?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi_wFBVV95cUxQWVI1VWU1Z1VhRHJKWm05R2FhY2Z3NEtTUlVsd3JqbGpLaElUSUszQ1BiZFJpdW5IRmJaY0JaaE5acmRGWUFjQkxmQV9vVlBJdHFJNDYxUTJzNWdXbm9ka29qT01DdGRNRy1xbTBhRGNsbHJzbG4yVmxmRmlTdTdYbUJLbjEwMFNXVmI2MHVSaVNzY2h6NlRNMjFFQU1LTm9scGNfMVFLQ09VenNUd0YtQWR5QlNoTHk2bVQxTzZDOGhNODl2X3NkaHhJQWh6akRMOEdTX2xnaTV5MlhhbTk0WWo3bUlTazJjdWRkMmhxOEJ6OFdLd3pSaHdtMEowZmfSAYQCQVVfeXFMTkNnaXgxUzZ2VDFQUmYtQWpmSDNNaW01WWtaYTlxdmNIck5CZ2IxdWJMOVloWGlJaDRfb1FVd181UmdmRkFUSzVCQTlUNGMxZGJuMUhQRWRkbDBLcUl4eU1aSzEtbnB0QVE3dERzLWdMT0pZZHhSa295cmFId0tvOVpEc21FMGs5dEFndmVRMktnd0I3M1J0ZGlPWjhtWFJQNnlKam1SN2dqa1RuLW1VWU9Wdy04VlVpeDBvbllvckljZk8ydDd0OUlqaTVyZFUxZEN6T1lTemlQQzZ2R0l2bDdaampzNEFNR3JFZnRtM0pDZXNFRFVzWmducnB3eUl0c1VDb0g?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 16:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>