<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 18:27:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 18:27:08 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brazil: Aircraft crashes into shops in tourist city of Gramado, all 10 passengers feared dead - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Aircraft Crashes into Shops in Gramado, Brazil, Leaving All Passengers Feared Dead</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Dec 22, 2024</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>HT News Desk</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Brazil_crash_1734881998702_1734881998918.png" alt="The plane reportedly first struck the chimney of a building, then the second floor of a house, before crashing into a furniture store(X Screengrab/ Defesa Civil Nacional)" title="The plane reportedly first struck the chimney of a building, then the second floor of a house, before crashing into a furniture store(X Screengrab/ Defesa Civil Nacional)"><figcaption>The plane reportedly first struck the chimney of a building, then the second floor of a house, before crashing into a furniture store(X Screengrab/ Defesa Civil Nacional)</figcaption></figure><p>A small aircraft carrying 10 passengers crashed into shops in Gramado, Brazil, with all passengers expected to be deceased. The incident seems particularly devastating as it happened just days before Christmas, a major tourist period for the city.</p><ul><li>The aircraft struck a building's chimney before hitting a furniture store.</li><li>Governor Eduardo Leite has been monitoring the situation and mobilizing municipal resources for rapid response.</li><li>Fifteen people unrelated to the crash suffered injuries from smoke inhalation related to the subsequent fire.</li><li>The crash follows a year marked by devastating floods in the region that already caused significant disruption.</li></ul><blockquote>“Unfortunately, initial information indicates that the occupants of the aircraft did not survive,” - Governor Eduardo Leite.</blockquote><p>This tragic incident underscores the ongoing challenges faced by the region, particularly during one of its busiest tourist seasons.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/brazil-aircraft-crashes-into-shops-in-tourist-city-of-gramado-all-10-passengers-feared-dead-101734880110977.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/brazil-aircraft-crashes-into-shops-in-tourist-city-of-gramado-all-10-passengers-feared-dead-101734880110977.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:42:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Burn In Hell': Teacher Who Raped 12-Year-Old, Got Pregnant With His Child, Jailed For 25 Years - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxOR09wbEx1d1pnM05QcDl0UFJrRDFkV01ZSmNleG9MaTFjRTBONUdfT0ZNRFpIN2RzNXZBeXlYRTVWX0Z2eUk4MUlXR3JKN0JtWktHanF5QlI4SWR4NlY3NXVkWnVnejF3M29ha1BEalEySkNHNEY3d1ZqeEdZSnlldTBhQkd3VG1qVjhpU29LMklYZklpRmNjb1hVLXRqYWw5cDVfZHE4TzNHYTk0azlPaDhQZFZWNHdmS0xIbFJJZ1dtak1FZHJYVk9IN1pDWmZxdDFr0gHYAUFVX3lxTE1qNW1xcEszenE3SlFzb1RWeTlIZEY2ZXVSeDlLNzBObTBjZGVFWV8zVlhvMXpxYkllSHduTV9vdjFJRXFrdWpvZEc5eFhiaklvNWREbEgtTGpnU2t1amFraU1tTlVKMGx4SXlzX0Jlc0FwZHF3WWlrYlpLZEVXbTdkZG8wWXhtODFoeUQwclhFWjhabmVBR0ZPZEo5akFxZTYwSzNxR2VOa2lEQ1pVTU5RUFcyME1BNEVGTGU0eXRYUktGRHM4TW0wY2JfeXpJdEM1RllwRl8tdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi0wFBVV95cUxOR09wbEx1d1pnM05QcDl0UFJrRDFkV01ZSmNleG9MaTFjRTBONUdfT0ZNRFpIN2RzNXZBeXlYRTVWX0Z2eUk4MUlXR3JKN0JtWktHanF5QlI4SWR4NlY3NXVkWnVnejF3M29ha1BEalEySkNHNEY3d1ZqeEdZSnlldTBhQkd3VG1qVjhpU29LMklYZklpRmNjb1hVLXRqYWw5cDVfZHE4TzNHYTk0azlPaDhQZFZWNHdmS0xIbFJJZ1dtak1FZHJYVk9IN1pDWmZxdDFr0gHYAUFVX3lxTE1qNW1xcEszenE3SlFzb1RWeTlIZEY2ZXVSeDlLNzBObTBjZGVFWV8zVlhvMXpxYkllSHduTV9vdjFJRXFrdWpvZEc5eFhiaklvNWREbEgtTGpnU2t1amFraU1tTlVKMGx4SXlzX0Jlc0FwZHF3WWlrYlpLZEVXbTdkZG8wWXhtODFoeUQwclhFWjhabmVBR0ZPZEo5akFxZTYwSzNxR2VOa2lEQ1pVTU5RUFcyME1BNEVGTGU0eXRYUktGRHM4TW0wY2JfeXpJdEM1RllwRl8tdw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:27:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 dead after plane crashes into shops in southern Brazil, 'no survivors', say authorities - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>10 dead after plane crashes into shops in southern Brazil, 'no survivors', say authorities</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 4, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Plane crash in Brazil" /><figcaption>Scene of the tragic plane crash in southern Brazil.</figcaption><p>A tragic incident occurred in southern Brazil where a plane crashed into shops, resulting in the death of all ten individuals on board. Authorities have confirmed that there are no survivors from the crash.</p><ul><li>The incident took place during a busy shopping period, increasing human impact.</li><li>Authorities are investigating the cause of the crash.</li><li>This has raised concerns regarding air traffic safety and regulations.</li></ul><blockquote>“There are no survivors,” said a local official responding to the tragic event.</blockquote><p>This tragedy has shocked the local community and raised urgent questions about aviation safety measures in Brazil.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/nine-dead-after-plane-crashes-in-southern-brazil-says-authorities/articleshow/116570313.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/nine-dead-after-plane-crashes-in-southern-brazil-says-authorities/articleshow/116570313.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Playing with fire': China warns US over supplying arms to Taiwan - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Playing with fire': China warns US over supplying arms to Taiwan</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Playing with fire" /><figcaption>China warns the US about consequences of arms supply to Taiwan</figcaption><p>China has issued a stern warning to the United States regarding its continued arms supplies to Taiwan, emphasizing the potential risks involved.</p><ul><li>China considers the arms supply to Taiwan as provocative and destabilizing.</li><li>The Chinese government insists that such actions could lead to severe repercussions for US-China relations.</li><li>This warning comes amid heightened tensions in the Taiwan Strait and regional security concerns.</li></ul><blockquote>"Playing with fire will get you burned," stated a Chinese spokesperson, highlighting the grave concerns over US actions.</blockquote><p>The ongoing situation indicates an escalating tension between China and the US, particularly concerning Taiwan's sovereignty and military support.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/playing-with-fire-china-warns-us-over-supplying-arms-to-taiwan/articleshow/116569293.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/playing-with-fire-china-warns-us-over-supplying-arms-to-taiwan/articleshow/116569293.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 14:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No J-10C Fighters For Bangladesh; Chinese Aircraft’s “Drawbacks” May Outweigh All Its Capabilities: OPED - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh's Consideration of J-10C Fighter Jets: Opportunities and Challenges</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> OPED by Air Marshal Anil Khosla (R)</p><figure><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/J-10C-China.jpg" alt="J-10C China" width="696" height="445"><figcaption>File: J-10C China.</figcaption></figure><p>Bangladesh is exploring the acquisition of Chinese J-10C fighter jets as part of its military modernization efforts, amidst a backdrop of geopolitical tensions in South Asia.</p><ul><li>Bangladesh aims to modernize its armed forces and expressed interest in acquiring fighter jets and helicopters during a recent visit to China.</li><li>The J-10C fighter jet boasts advanced capabilities but faces criticism over its reliance on older technologies and potential reliability issues.</li><li>Challenges include financial considerations and the political implications of deepening defense ties with China amid complex regional dynamics.</li><li>India is closely monitoring Bangladesh's military acquisitions due to concerns over shifting power balances in South Asia.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bangladesh’s potential acquisition of Chinese J-10C fighter jets represents both an opportunity and a risk.”</blockquote><p>In conclusion, while the J-10C may enhance the Bangladesh Air Force’s capabilities, a careful evaluation of the associated risks and challenges is essential for informed decision-making.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/no-j-10c-fighters-for-bangladesh-chinese-aircrafts/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/no-j-10c-fighters-for-bangladesh-chinese-aircrafts/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 12:52:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From US, Russia and France: List of top international awards conferred to PM Modi over the years - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>List of International Awards Conferred to PM Modi</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>This article highlights the various prestigious international awards that Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi has received over the years.</p><ul><li>Overview of major awards conferred to PM Modi from countries like the US, Russia, and France.</li><li>Details of the significance of these awards in enhancing India's global presence.</li><li>List of notable awards with a brief description of each.</li></ul><blockquote>“These awards signify the recognition of India’s development initiatives on the world stage.”</blockquote><p>The article concludes with an emphasis on the importance of international accolades in fostering diplomatic relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/from-us-russia-and-france-list-of-top-international-awards-conferred-to-pm-modi-over-the-years/articleshow/116567970.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/from-us-russia-and-france-list-of-top-international-awards-conferred-to-pm-modi-over-the-years/articleshow/116567970.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 12:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man dressed up as Santa to surprise wife and kids, then killed them: Christmas murders that shook Texas - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Christmas Tragedy: Man Dressed as Santa Kills Six Family Members Before Suicide</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Dec 22, 2024 06:17 PM IST<br>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Untitled-148_1734870813668_1734871011467.png" alt="Aziz Yazdanpanah showed up at his estranged wife's apartment on December 25, 2011 in a Santa suit."><figcaption>Aziz Yazdanpanah showed up at his estranged wife's apartment on December 25, 2011 in a Santa suit.</figcaption>
<p>The festive spirit of Christmas was shattered by a horrifying murder-suicide carried out by Aziz Yazdanpanah, a 56-year-old Iranian-born man who dressed up as Santa Claus. In Grapevine, Texas, known as the Christmas Capital of Texas, Aziz killed his estranged wife, their two teenage children, his wife’s sister, her husband, and their niece during a family Christmas gathering.</p>
<ul>
<li>Aziz arrived at the house dressed as Santa, with his niece texting her boyfriend about his unexpected presence.</li>
<li>Aziz killed six family members before calling 911 and confessing to the murders. He then took his own life.</li>
<li>The motive behind the killings is believed to be Aziz's marital and financial troubles.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>In a chilling 911 call, Aziz said, "I am shooting people."</blockquote>
<p>This tragic event remains the deadliest crime in the history of Grapevine.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/man-dressed-up-as-santa-to-surprise-wife-and-kids-then-killed-them-christmas-murders-that-shook-texas-101734869157446.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/man-dressed-up-as-santa-to-surprise-wife-and-kids-then-killed-them-christmas-murders-that-shook-texas-101734869157446.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 12:47:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘We must take back our cities’: Protesters in Germany seek mass deportations after Christmas market attack by Saudi man | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxPNVEzREhmSlh6MGhXVUJCQTZvb1dXWjFLQjV6OEROX3g3ZUlaTC1tY3lFNElXenZTamh4NmlZcTFlZkgtNlV1ai1jMV85enBKRVhLNFVPM04yQTBCdlh3OXpLd2JieFBqRXZ4OXhxQnlNQTVhMkNqalhySDNOSnVZd05SY3VwdV9sbEs2LW40ZlYxMFBwU1J6cUkwZXVDbVRacTU0MjJwazFBVXQ1NXB4WS1LZ1pjRDFQc3dLNVdjVFNSc3BOOHphLWxDb2QyMkZJcDNzTVZnZ2RDeW4wdW1iVktKSzRWSGNsOHdfelZNX0dVN2PSAfgBQVVfeXFMT2Vsc1ZxMl9VNXBtUlJDOXhlXzJreDVuVUlyZEYtZ0NFRDA5SG5ydEsxWDNPTU15RklQVUw0RUoyUEYyTTZVdUhlOGpBb0tTYjRnYV9GTEMzNDRHT0RIekVUYWR6eWxtRVF5cWJHUzN1TTYycGdSV2F4MjRyRUMtV09WVTJDQnA2cjZ4Q2JZdlk4eFlRVTJldnF5QWlxR1I1bWtIYjhYNGFXOExPd29LNk5oaVdTbmR1Y0poYUJWYmUzd2lzckFfMDQ4Uk04TkxMS3dqSmRicHpHeUZRd0dsZHpzbDlyVHAyeTI4ajJ0STRPZzhsWndmM1k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi8wFBVV95cUxPNVEzREhmSlh6MGhXVUJCQTZvb1dXWjFLQjV6OEROX3g3ZUlaTC1tY3lFNElXenZTamh4NmlZcTFlZkgtNlV1ai1jMV85enBKRVhLNFVPM04yQTBCdlh3OXpLd2JieFBqRXZ4OXhxQnlNQTVhMkNqalhySDNOSnVZd05SY3VwdV9sbEs2LW40ZlYxMFBwU1J6cUkwZXVDbVRacTU0MjJwazFBVXQ1NXB4WS1LZ1pjRDFQc3dLNVdjVFNSc3BOOHphLWxDb2QyMkZJcDNzTVZnZ2RDeW4wdW1iVktKSzRWSGNsOHdfelZNX0dVN2PSAfgBQVVfeXFMT2Vsc1ZxMl9VNXBtUlJDOXhlXzJreDVuVUlyZEYtZ0NFRDA5SG5ydEsxWDNPTU15RklQVUw0RUoyUEYyTTZVdUhlOGpBb0tTYjRnYV9GTEMzNDRHT0RIekVUYWR6eWxtRVF5cWJHUzN1TTYycGdSV2F4MjRyRUMtV09WVTJDQnA2cjZ4Q2JZdlk4eFlRVTJldnF5QWlxR1I1bWtIYjhYNGFXOExPd29LNk5oaVdTbmR1Y0poYUJWYmUzd2lzckFfMDQ4Uk04TkxMS3dqSmRicHpHeUZRd0dsZHpzbDlyVHAyeTI4ajJ0STRPZzhsWndmM1k?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 12:00:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Suicidal Empathy’: Elon Musk Reacts To Reports On Germany Refusing To Extradite Saudi Suspect - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk Criticizes Germany's Extradition Decision Following Deadly Market Attack</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Billionaire entrepreneur Elon Musk | File Image" title="Billionaire entrepreneur Elon Musk | File Image" loading="eager"><figcaption>Billionaire entrepreneur Elon Musk | File Image</figcaption></figure><p>In response to Germany’s refusal to extradite a Saudi suspect linked to a deadly Christmas market attack, Elon Musk has called the decision 'suicidal empathy' and demanded the resignation of German Chancellor Olaf Scholz.</p><ul><li>Musk criticized Germany's human rights considerations for not extraditing the suspect, Taleb A.</li><li>The attack in Magdeburg saw five fatalities and over 60 injuries, sparking national outrage.</li><li>The suspect, a 50-year-old Saudi doctor, is awaiting trial for multiple charges, including murder.</li><li>Musk's social media remarks have amplified the public's reaction to the incident.</li></ul><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Europe must walk away from its “suicidal empathy" policy.— Visegrád 24 (@visegrad24) December 21, 2024</p></blockquote><p>The tragic event has led to increased security measures at Christmas markets across Germany following similar past attacks, raising concerns about safety during the holiday season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/elon-musk-saudi-arabian-suspect-germany-christmas-market-attack-2-dead-extradite-suicidal-empathy-9164656.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/elon-musk-saudi-arabian-suspect-germany-christmas-market-attack-2-dead-extradite-suicidal-empathy-9164656.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 11:00:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xi Jinping’s anti-corruption drive targets record number of ‘tigers’ this year - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Xi Jinping’s Anti-Corruption Drive Targets Record Number of ‘Tigers’ This Year</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>This year, Xi Jinping's government has intensified its anti-corruption campaign, aiming to hold a record number of high-ranking officials accountable.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The campaign targets a significant increase in the number of 'tigers'—senior officials involved in corruption.</li>
  <li>Officials at various levels are being scrutinized, reflecting a broader political strategy.</li>
  <li>This approach aims to enhance the integrity of the Communist Party and restore public trust.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Our efforts will not wane until we achieve our anti-corruption objectives,” an official remarked.</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing drive signifies a critical moment for governance in China, as it seeks to prove its commitment to transparency and accountability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/xi-jinpings-anti-corruption-drive-targets-record-number-of-tigers-this-year/articleshow/116564279.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/xi-jinpings-anti-corruption-drive-targets-record-number-of-tigers-this-year/articleshow/116564279.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 10:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suspect in German Christmas market attack held on murder charges after night of grief, scuffles - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/suspect-in-german-christmas-market-attack-held-on-murder-charges-after-night-of-grief-scuffles-3328585</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/suspect-in-german-christmas-market-attack-held-on-murder-charges-after-night-of-grief-scuffles-3328585</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 10:05:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump threatens to take back control of Panama Canal over ‘ridiculous fees’ - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/22/trump-threatens-to-take-back-control-of-panama-canal-over-ridiculous-fees</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/22/trump-threatens-to-take-back-control-of-panama-canal-over-ridiculous-fees</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 09:57:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Turkey: Four killed after helicopter crashes into hospital - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Helicopter Crash in Turkey Claims Four Lives</h1><p><strong>December 22, 2024; Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/22/550x309/Turkey_1734860246868_1734860254915.jpg" alt="The chopper fell to the ground after colliding with the fourth storey of a hospital during take-off. ((Gonca Köksal/X))"><figcaption>The chopper fell to the ground after colliding with the fourth storey of a hospital during take-off. ((Gonca Köksal/X))</figcaption><p>At least four people were killed on Sunday after a helicopter crashed into a hospital in southwestern Turkey during takeoff amidst poor visibility.</p><ul><li>The helicopter collided with the fourth story of a hospital in Mugla.</li><li>The victims included two pilots, a doctor, and a hospital employee.</li><li>This incident follows a previous mid-air collision of military helicopters on December 9, which resulted in six fatalities.</li></ul><blockquote>“The helicopter took off amid poor visibility from the roof of Mugla's hospital en route to the city of Antalya.”</blockquote><p>This tragic event underscores the dangers associated with aviation in poor weather conditions and has prompted further investigations into the incidents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/turkey-four-killed-after-helicopter-crashes-into-hospital-101734859180694.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/turkey-four-killed-after-helicopter-crashes-into-hospital-101734859180694.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 09:52:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PTI hails govt's formation of negotiation committee as 'positive' move - Geo News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PTI hails govt's formation of negotiation committee as 'positive' move</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Geo News</p>
<img src="https://www.geo.tv/assets/uploads/updates/2024-12-22/580964_233325_updates.jpg" alt="PTI Chairman Barrister Gohar Ali Khan and Opposition Leader Omar Ayub Khan are seen during a presser in this still taken from a video. — YouTube/Geo News Live" width="700" height="400">
<figcaption>PTI Chairman Barrister Gohar Ali Khan and Opposition Leader Omar Ayub Khan are seen during a presser in this still taken from a video. — YouTube/Geo News Live</figcaption>
<p>Following a significant political development, the Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) has expressed support for the establishment of a negotiation committee by the government, describing it as a 'positive' step towards constructive dialogue.</p>
<ul>
  <li><b>We consider committee's formation constructive step:</b> Gohar</li>
  <li><b>Demands meaningful dialogue based on positive intentions.</b></li>
  <li><b>PTI needs to see whether govt's body has authority, says Ayub.</b></li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Our demands have already been presented to the government. If they make a formal request, we will consider it.” – Omar Ayub Khan</blockquote>
<p>This move by Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif to create a high-level body aims to engage the PTI amid calls for civil disobedience, with both parties stressing the importance of a defined and serious approach to negotiations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.geo.tv/latest/580964-pti-hails-govts-formation-of-negotiation-committee-as-positive-move</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.geo.tv/latest/580964-pti-hails-govts-formation-of-negotiation-committee-as-positive-move</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 09:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four killed as Helicopter crashes into Turkish hospital amid thick fog - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Four killed as Helicopter crashes into Turkish hospital amid thick fog</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 20, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The tragic incident of a helicopter crash occurred at a hospital in Turkey, resulting in four fatalities. The crash, attributed to heavy fog, has raised concerns about aviation safety in poor weather conditions.</p><ul><li>The helicopter crashed into the roof of a hospital, causing significant damage.</li><li>Four individuals were confirmed dead at the scene.</li><li>Emergency services responded promptly to the disaster.</li><li>The incident has led to discussions on air traffic regulations during adverse weather.</li></ul><blockquote>"This is a devastating reminder of the risks involved in flying during poor weather conditions." - Aviation expert comment</blockquote><p>This incident underscores the importance of adhering to safety protocols in aviation, especially during adverse weather conditions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/four-killed-as-helicopter-crashes-into-turkish-hospital-amid-thick-fog/articleshow/116563342.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/four-killed-as-helicopter-crashes-into-turkish-hospital-amid-thick-fog/articleshow/116563342.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 09:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Navy ship shoots down its own jet in friendly fire incident over Red Sea; pilots eject to safety - ThePrint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Navy ship shoots down its own jet in friendly fire incident over Red Sea; pilots eject to safety</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> New Delhi</p><p>The US Navy experienced a friendly fire incident late Saturday evening when the USS Gettysburg mistakenly shot down an F/A-18 F Super Hornet that was flying off the USS Harry S. Truman. Both pilots ejected safely.</p><ul><li>The guided-missile cruiser USS Gettysburg accidentally fired on the F/A-18.</li><li>The pilots were recovered safely, with one sustaining minor injuries.</li><li>An investigation into the incident is currently underway.</li><li>The USS Harry S. Truman Carrier Strike Group came under Central Command’s control on December 15.</li><li>Central Command had conducted precision airstrikes in Yemen just before the incident.</li><li>The incident relates to broader operations against Houthi forces disrupting shipping in the Red Sea.</li></ul><blockquote>“CENTCOM forces conducted the deliberate strikes to disrupt and degrade Houthi operations...” - CENTCOM Statement</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the complexity and risks involved in military operations, particularly in regions with ongoing conflicts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://theprint.in/world/us-navy-ship-shoots-down-its-own-jet-in-friendly-fire-incident-over-red-sea-pilots-eject-to-safety/2415174/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theprint.in/world/us-navy-ship-shoots-down-its-own-jet-in-friendly-fire-incident-over-red-sea-pilots-eject-to-safety/2415174/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 09:22:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Cruelty is terrorists hiding behind children': Israel hits out at Pope Francis over Gaza airstrikes rema - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cruelty is terrorists hiding behind children: Israel hits out at Pope Francis over Gaza airstrikes remark</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>The article discusses Israel's strong reaction to remarks made by Pope Francis regarding airstrikes in Gaza, labeling the comments as misguided and accusing terrorists of using children as shields.</p><ul><li>Israel's government condemned Pope Francis's statement.</li><li>Criticism focused on the Pope's portrayal of the conflict in Gaza.</li><li>Israeli officials emphasized the complexities of military operations in urban areas.</li></ul><blockquote>"Cruelty is terrorists hiding behind children" - Israeli official response to Pope Francis.</blockquote><p>The ongoing conflict in Gaza remains a contentious issue, drawing varied international responses.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/cruelty-is-terrorists-hiding-behind-children-israel-hits-out-at-pope-francis-over-gaza-airstrikes-remark/articleshow/116563131.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/cruelty-is-terrorists-hiding-behind-children-israel-hits-out-at-pope-francis-over-gaza-airstrikes-remark/articleshow/116563131.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 09:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia-Ukraine war: List of key events, day 1,032 - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/22/russia-ukraine-war-list-of-key-events-day-1032</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/22/russia-ukraine-war-list-of-key-events-day-1032</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:56:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Playing with fire': China warns US over military aid to Taiwan - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Playing with fire': China warns US over military aid to Taiwan</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>China has expressed serious warnings to the United States regarding its military aid to Taiwan, describing the situation as playing with fire.</p><ul><li>China firmly opposes US arms sales to Taiwan.</li><li>The warnings come amidst heightened tensions in US-China relations.</li><li>Military aid is seen as undermining China's sovereignty and territorial integrity.</li></ul><blockquote>"The US is playing with fire and will get burned."</blockquote><p>The rising military support from the US could have significant implications for cross-strait relations and regional stability.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/playing-with-fire-china-warns-us-over-military-aid-to-taiwan/articleshow/116559263.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/china/playing-with-fire-china-warns-us-over-military-aid-to-taiwan/articleshow/116559263.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 07:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan was blackmailing US to act against India, started developing Washington killer missile after..., and - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan's Missile Development Tensions with the US</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pakistan-missile-us-shaheen.png?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Pakistan missile us shaheen">
<figcaption>Pakistan was blackmailing US to act against India, started developing Washington killer missile after..., and then...</figcaption>
<p>The article discusses escalating tensions between Pakistan and the United States over missile development initiatives. The U.S. has rejected Pakistan's attempts to influence its stance on India's missile capabilities.</p>
<ul>
<li>Pakistan allegedly attempted to blackmail the U.S. regarding India's missile capabilities.</li>
<li>The U.S. Deputy National Security Advisor revealed Pakistan's development of nuclear missiles aimed at the U.S.</li>
<li>Pakistan has intensified missile development in response to U.S. rejections.</li>
<li>Pakistan's Shaheen-III missile can target all parts of India, while efforts are now focused on missiles that can reach the U.S.</li>
<li>Tensions are heightened due to U.S. sanctions on companies associated with Pakistan's missile program.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The missile issue could remain contentious even under the Trump administration.” - Former Pakistani ambassador to the UN, Maleeha Lodhi</blockquote>
<p>The revelations about Pakistan's missile capabilities may continue to create friction in US-Pakistan relations moving forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/pakistan-was-blackmailing-us-to-act-against-india-started-developing-washington-killer-missile-after-and-then-7484384/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/pakistan-was-blackmailing-us-to-act-against-india-started-developing-washington-killer-missile-after-and-then-7484384/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:52:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Decoding 2024: An Indian's guide to moving abroad as the world looks for 'better' immigrants - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxPbExkREVJajZnRHFvNngxSUY4MzNSbXFCcHZmdGVGQVNEMFN0R3FiYUV1c3dpcmd6MF9pQm8zTUtJZDdMNGdvcHhFQ3ktNmFnQkVHRU14ZzlsQ1FWeEM4ZVZIZG1uV2gxb1gzeWJQdHBReGRXVHNIeEJUQWNLTlZza1dKbTdFQ1hPd0dnb1FGZWowcU5fUjQ2NDJ5Z3pqeWRUX0w5OVdQd0JyYlZka2lVX2ZwQXFvZFRyTWMzNjktMFBKQXF4cS0zbFlhY0Fnd3ZycU9WS2RNcnB3RGxOM25XMTU2VFlqdWEtWEHSAe8BQVVfeXFMTjJlc09NSllIa2lkeEczMEU2SnVLa1Qtb0w5eVREeVJvWF9PT3E4WURFZ0ZnUFVsNDNwNEdFZTYtX2xTbFExaXVLNFd5eHZGSU9UQVMzV0c1S3JUNmNWdVd6T1lpVFg4QWdzQ1N4WXRfbnRkUkFWMkZ2WFkwaGJ2eHRUdFJCQkxlSkJnLVlfYng5OHBRa0pkekVmY2hjelE3RmtzQlFnUHluMWNuWUktZU90ZVRtWFI4UUVKWU5IUTlnak1YaXdFSjQ0aUZrVFh4aEJkUGN3bGNmTEdxSkRMODhOMnJEdTJNRm5DZDdJNU0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6gFBVV95cUxPbExkREVJajZnRHFvNngxSUY4MzNSbXFCcHZmdGVGQVNEMFN0R3FiYUV1c3dpcmd6MF9pQm8zTUtJZDdMNGdvcHhFQ3ktNmFnQkVHRU14ZzlsQ1FWeEM4ZVZIZG1uV2gxb1gzeWJQdHBReGRXVHNIeEJUQWNLTlZza1dKbTdFQ1hPd0dnb1FGZWowcU5fUjQ2NDJ5Z3pqeWRUX0w5OVdQd0JyYlZka2lVX2ZwQXFvZFRyTWMzNjktMFBKQXF4cS0zbFlhY0Fnd3ZycU9WS2RNcnB3RGxOM25XMTU2VFlqdWEtWEHSAe8BQVVfeXFMTjJlc09NSllIa2lkeEczMEU2SnVLa1Qtb0w5eVREeVJvWF9PT3E4WURFZ0ZnUFVsNDNwNEdFZTYtX2xTbFExaXVLNFd5eHZGSU9UQVMzV0c1S3JUNmNWdVd6T1lpVFg4QWdzQ1N4WXRfbnRkUkFWMkZ2WFkwaGJ2eHRUdFJCQkxlSkJnLVlfYng5OHBRa0pkekVmY2hjelE3RmtzQlFnUHluMWNuWUktZU90ZVRtWFI4UUVKWU5IUTlnak1YaXdFSjQ0aUZrVFh4aEJkUGN3bGNmTEdxSkRMODhOMnJEdTJNRm5DZDdJNU0?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:42:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['It's an open secret he's a predator': Wild sexual allegations surface against Jeffrey Maddrey after NYPD - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Wild Allegations Against NYPD Chief Jeffrey Maddrey Surface After Resignation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><p>In the wake of the NYPD chief's resignation, disturbing allegations of sexual misconduct against Jeffrey Maddrey have emerged, casting a shadow over the police department.</p><ul><li>Several former and current members of the NYPD have come forward with accusations.</li><li>The allegations include systematic harassment and inappropriate behavior.</li><li>These revelations have sparked outrage and calls for greater accountability within the NYPD.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s an open secret he’s a predator,” stated a former officer.</blockquote><p>The situation raises serious questions about the culture within the NYPD and its handling of such grave issues.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/its-an-open-secret-hes-a-predator-wild-sexual-allegations-surface-against-jeffrey-maddrey-after-nypd-chiefs-resignation/articleshow/116557160.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/its-an-open-secret-hes-a-predator-wild-sexual-allegations-surface-against-jeffrey-maddrey-after-nypd-chiefs-resignation/articleshow/116557160.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From Gujarat to America: Perils of illegal migration.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>From Gujarat to America: Perils of illegal migration as Trump plans crackdown</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br /><strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/trump_21734848747.jpg" alt="From Gujarat to America: Perils of illegal migration"><figcaption>Image caption for the article</figcaption><p>US President-elect Donald Trump pledges to oversee a large-scale deportation operation, reigniting the debate on illegal immigration in the US, particularly highlighting the influx of illegal immigrants from Gujarat, India.</p><ul><li>Over 11 million undocumented immigrants currently reside in the US.</li><li>In FY 2024, 90,415 illegal crossings from India recorded, with almost half from Gujarat.</li><li>From October 2023 to September 2024, 29 lakh illegal immigrants apprehended, with 43,764 Indians at the Canadian border.</li><li>The tragic Dingucha case illustrates the dangers of illegal immigration, with the Patel family freezing to death attempting to cross the border.</li><li>Gujarat Police filed an FIR against 14 immigration agents involved in a fraudulent migration scheme.</li><li>The US is an attractive destination for Gujaratis, who represent a significant part of the Indian community in America.</li></ul><blockquote>“The journey is perilous, with many families borrowing significant sums for what are often dangerous attempts to reach the US.”</blockquote><p>Trump's proposed mass deportations could have severe implications for undocumented Gujaratis, who may face uncertain futures in the US.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/india-news/from-gujarat-to-america-perils-of-illegal-migration-142914</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/politics/india-news/from-gujarat-to-america-perils-of-illegal-migration-142914</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 06:25:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Navy warship shoots down 2 fighter jet pilots in 'friendly fire' during Red Sea operations against Ho - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Navy warship shoots down 2 fighter jet pilots in 'friendly fire' during Red Sea operations against Houthis</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date Here] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source Here]</p>
<img src="[Insert Image URL Here]" alt="US Navy operation image">
<figcaption>[Insert Caption Here]</figcaption>
<p>This article discusses a tragic incident involving a US Navy warship that mistakenly shot down two fighter jet pilots during operations in the Red Sea, aimed at countering the Houthi threats.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Incident occurred during military operations in the Red Sea.</li>
  <li>Involved a US Navy warship and resulted in the deaths of two pilots.</li>
  <li>Highlights the risks of 'friendly fire' in complex military engagements.</li>
  <li>Raises questions about communication and identification protocols in warfare.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This tragic incident underscores the dangers inherent in military operations and the need for improved communication protocols to prevent such occurrences in the future."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, this event serves as a sobering reminder of the complexities of modern warfare and the importance of precise communication to avert casualties among allied forces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/us-navy-warship-shoots-down-2-fighter-jet-pilots-in-friendly-fire-during-red-sea-operations-against-houthis/articleshow/116556277.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/us-navy-warship-shoots-down-2-fighter-jet-pilots-in-friendly-fire-during-red-sea-operations-against-houthis/articleshow/116556277.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 05:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australia Permanent Residency: New opportunities for foreign workers, migrants and students in 2025 - The Financial Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Australia's 2025 Migration Policies: Opportunities for Foreign Workers and Students</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Financial Express</p>
<img src="https://www.financialexpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/REUTERS-USA.jpg?w=300" alt="permanent residency in US, US naturalization rule, citizenship, USCIS Policy Manual, lawful permanent resident, eligibility conditions" />
<figcaption>US provides clarity on rules for foreigners seeking permanent residency</figcaption>
<p>Australia is set to transform its migration policies by 2025, aiming to enhance economic growth, social cohesion, and regional development. For Indian nationals, these changes create new migration opportunities, particularly in skilled sectors.</p>
<ul>
<li>The permanent Migration Program will have 185,000 places, with 70% for skilled migration.</li>
<li>Employer-sponsored visas will rise to 44,000, making it easier for skilled workers to obtain permanent residency.</li>
<li>Regional visas will increase to 33,000, promoting workforce development outside urban areas.</li>
<li>A new National Innovation Visa will replace the Global Talent Visa, attracting exceptional talents in key industries.</li>
<li>Mobility Arrangement for Talented Early-Professionals Scheme will allow 3,000 Indian graduates to work in Australia for 2 years starting November 2024.</li>
<li>International student intake will be capped at 270,000 with raised English proficiency requirements.</li>
<li>Temporary Skill Shortage visa experience requirement will be reduced from two years to one.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Australia’s shift towards innovation-centric migration signals its intent to become a global hub for technology and advanced research.”</blockquote>
<p>The new migration policies underscore Australia’s commitment to a skilled and innovative workforce while providing significant opportunities for Indian migrants.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.financialexpress.com/business/investing-abroad-australia-immigration-2025-what-foreign-workers-migrants-and-students-need-to-know-for-work-study-or-permanent-residency-3696769/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.financialexpress.com/business/investing-abroad-australia-immigration-2025-what-foreign-workers-migrants-and-students-need-to-know-for-work-study-or-permanent-residency-3696769/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 04:24:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. Navy’s F/18 Super Hornet Shot Down Over Red Sea In Friendly Fire; Both Pilots Recovered - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>U.S. Navy's F/18 Super Hornet Shot Down Over Red Sea In Friendly Fire; Both Pilots Recovered</h1><p><strong>Date: December 22, Source: U.S. Central Command</strong></p><p>According to a statement from U.S. Central Command, two U.S. Navy pilots ejected safely over the Red Sea during the early morning hours of December 22 when their F/A-18 fighter aircraft was shot down in an apparent case of friendly fire.</p><ul><li>The USS Gettysburg mistakenly fired on the F/A-18 while it was flying off the USS Harry S. Truman.</li><li>Both pilots were safely recovered, with initial assessments indicating one crew member sustained minor injuries.</li><li>The incident was not the result of hostile fire, and a full investigation is underway.</li></ul><blockquote>This is a developing story…</blockquote><p>The U.S. Navy is currently investigating the friendly fire incident and its implications for operational safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/u-s-navys-f-18-super-hornet-shot-down-over/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/u-s-navys-f-18-super-hornet-shot-down-over/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:54:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Putin weighs in on the Syrian situation - Indian Punchline -]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE9Sd21zYVZwaEJ5SHhLOFp1aXFTaDZLNmRVTE14V1ptZXFXbmtBUUZhMUhSZGRSVmVCX0MyZ0xpbDJ1Ymk0ZFpCOExMZ0J3U0prRldXVTBtXzZwM2Noems4Z3FxWDNWZWx1NEdRRDhiZEhYZHctZ19RWERvalM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE9Sd21zYVZwaEJ5SHhLOFp1aXFTaDZLNmRVTE14V1ptZXFXbmtBUUZhMUhSZGRSVmVCX0MyZ0xpbDJ1Ymk0ZFpCOExMZ0J3U0prRldXVTBtXzZwM2Noems4Z3FxWDNWZWx1NEdRRDhiZEhYZHctZ19RWERvalM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:26:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump threatens to take back control of Panama Canal - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Demands Return of Control Over the Panama Canal</h1>
<p><strong>Published Date:</strong> December 22, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ect8b1/article69014970.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-22T022521Z_2056153836_RC2DE9AGH33T_RTRMADP_3_USA-TRUMP-PANAMA.JPG" alt="Donald Trump slammed what he called unfair fees for U.S. ships passing through the Panama Canal. File" />
<figcaption>Donald Trump slammed what he called unfair fees for U.S. ships passing through the Panama Canal. File | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption>
<p>Donald Trump has criticized the fees imposed on U.S. ships using the Panama Canal and has threatened to reclaim control of the waterway if Panama does not manage it efficiently.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump labeled the fees for U.S. ships as "unfair" and "ridiculous." </li>
  <li>He indicated concerns about China's influence over the canal.</li>
  <li>He threatened to demand the Panama Canal be returned to U.S. control if Panama fails its responsibilities.</li>
  <li>The Panama Canal was returned to Panama in 1999 after a deal signed in 1977.</li>
  <li>The canal is crucial, with an estimated 5% of global maritime traffic passing through it.</li>
  <li>The Panama Canal Authority reported record revenues of nearly $5 billion for the last fiscal year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Our Navy and Commerce have been treated in a very unfair and injudicious way. The fees being charged by Panama are ridiculous." - Donald Trump</blockquote>
<p>Trump's statements reflect his ongoing influence even before officially taking office, positioning himself as a defender of U.S. business interests.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-threatens-to-take-back-control-of-panama-canal/article69014967.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-threatens-to-take-back-control-of-panama-canal/article69014967.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US fighter shot down in 'apparent case of friendly fire' over Red Sea - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Fighter Plane Shot Down in Friendly Fire Incident Over Red Sea</h1><p><strong>Published: 22 December 2024, 03:07 IST</strong></p><p>The US military mistakenly shot down one of its own F/A-18 Hornet fighter aircraft over the Red Sea during an incident described as 'friendly fire.' Both pilots were rescued, with one sustaining minor injuries.</p><ul><li>The fighter jet was operating from the aircraft carrier Harry S. Truman.</li><li>The cruiser Gettysburg mistakenly fired on the aircraft.</li><li>The Red Sea has seen escalating military activity due to conflicts involving the Iran-backed Houthi militia.</li></ul><blockquote>"This incident is an apparent case of friendly fire, which is currently under investigation." - US Central Command</blockquote><p>The incident raises concerns over safety protocols amid heightened military operations in a volatile region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/us-fighter-shot-down-in-apparent-case-of-friendly-fire-over-red-sea-3328422</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/us-fighter-shot-down-in-apparent-case-of-friendly-fire-over-red-sea-3328422</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 03:07:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gaza ceasefire agreement nearly finalised: Palestinian source - The Siasat Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Gaza Ceasefire Agreement Nearly Finalised: Palestinian Source</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Xinhua News Agency</p>
<img src="https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Gaza-1.jpg" alt="Gaza faces 'most intense' civilian bombardment since WWII: UNRWA" width="1200" height="900" fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption> Photo: Anadolu Agency </figcaption>
<p>A ceasefire agreement in the Gaza Strip is imminent, with most terms already agreed upon, according to a senior official from the Palestinian Islamic Jihad. The agreement focuses on a gradual cessation of hostilities, the withdrawal of Israeli forces, a comprehensive prisoner-for-hostage exchange, and a permanent end to the conflict.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The ceasefire discussions are mediated by Egypt, Qatar, and the US.</li>
    <li>Ongoing negotiations aim to finalize the deal before the year ends, pending no new conditions from Israel.</li>
    <li>The political will exists from all parties involved to achieve a lasting resolution.</li>
    <li>Leaders from three Palestinian factions claim the agreement is closer than ever if Israel halts new demands.</li>
    <li>The conflict has lasted over 14 months, since the Hamas attack on southern Israel on October 7, 2023, which resulted in a significant number of casualties.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If Israel stops setting new conditions, a ceasefire agreement in the Gaza Strip is closer than ever.” - Hamas</blockquote>
<p>The recent meetings among Palestinian factions underscore a collective effort to end the ongoing violence and discuss post-war management of Gaza.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.siasat.com/gaza-ceasefire-agreement-nearly-finalised-palestinian-source-3152152/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.siasat.com/gaza-ceasefire-agreement-nearly-finalised-palestinian-source-3152152/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 02:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>