<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 19:14:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 19:14:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kenya investigates 1,000 kg rocket debris crash amid space junk concerns - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kenya Investigates Rocket Debris Crash Amid Growing Space Junk Concerns</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Jan 4, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> indiatorglobal</p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/space-debris-in-kenya-035932315-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=f31Vu9DCfOX4B9uJyz20ecIOBMaHLZgy&amp;size=690:388" alt="Space debris in Kenya">
<figcaption>A KSA official said the partially burnt metallic object is most likely a fragment from a rocket. (AP Photo)</figcaption>
<p>A metallic ring, believed to be rocket debris, crashed in Makueni County, Kenya, raising concerns about space junk and safety.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The debris is approximately 1,100 pounds with an 8-foot diameter.</li>
  <li>Kenya Space Agency (KSA) officials are investigating its origin.</li>
  <li>The object is not considered a safety threat, according to KSA.</li>
  <li>The situation highlights increasing incidents of falling space debris due to rising space traffic.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We want to assure the public that the object poses no immediate threat to safety," the Kenya Space Agency stated.</blockquote>
<p>This incident underscores the growing issue of space debris and its potential risks as space traffic increases.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/kenya-investigates-1000-kg-rocket-debris-crash-amid-space-junk-concerns-glbs-2659509-2025-01-04</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/kenya-investigates-1000-kg-rocket-debris-crash-amid-space-junk-concerns-glbs-2659509-2025-01-04</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 18:40:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A double dose of nasty winter is about to smack much of the US with snow, ice and biting cold - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>A double dose of nasty winter is about to smack much of the US with snow, ice and biting cold</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> Associated Press</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/18/550x309/World_4_1734523380663_1734523416539.jpg" alt="A double dose of nasty winter is about to smack much of the US with snow, ice and biting cold" title="A double dose of nasty winter is about to smack much of the US with snow, ice and biting cold"><figcaption>A double dose of nasty winter is about to smack much of the US with snow, ice and biting cold</figcaption></img><p>Millions across the eastern two-thirds of the U.S. are bracing for a significant winter storm bringing heavy snow and dangerous ice, forecasted to disrupt lives and possibly lead to power outages.</p><ul><li>A strong storm will affect areas from Kansas City to Washington, with some regions expecting up to 8 inches of snow.</li><li>Ice accumulation poses serious risks, particularly in southern Kansas, Missouri, Illinois, Indiana, Kentucky, and West Virginia.</li><li>Wind gusts could reach 50 mph, increasing the potential for blizzard conditions in the Central Plains.</li><li>The cold snap may lead to temperatures dropping 12 to 25 degrees Fahrenheit below normal, impacting the entire eastern U.S.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s going to be a mess, a potential disaster,” said private meteorologist Ryan Maue.</blockquote><p>This impending weather event is a stark reminder of the unpredictability of winter and the effects of climate change, as warming trends in the Arctic influence weather patterns worldwide.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/a-double-dose-of-nasty-winter-is-about-to-smack-much-of-the-us-with-snow-ice-and-biting-cold-101735921564518.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/a-double-dose-of-nasty-winter-is-about-to-smack-much-of-the-us-with-snow-ice-and-biting-cold-101735921564518.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 16:26:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kenya space junk: Experts investigate huge ring that crashed into village - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kenya space junk: Experts investigate huge ring that crashed into village</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>Not specified, <strong>Source: </strong><a href="http://bbcafrica.com/">BBCAfrica.com</a></p><p><img src="" alt="" /><figcaption>No caption available.</figcaption></p><p>Experts from Kenya's space agency are investigating a 500kg metal ring that crashed to Earth in Mukuku village, located 50km southeast of Nairobi. Fortunately, no injuries were reported.</p><ul><li>The ring is believed to be a separation ring from a launch vehicle.</li><li>These rings are designed to burn up upon re-entry or fall in unoccupied areas.</li></ul><blockquote>“Initial assessment showed that the huge object was a separation ring from a launch vehicle.”</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the potential risks associated with space debris and the need for improved safety measures during rocket launches.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/cx2vzql8zndo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/cx2vzql8zndo</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 16:03:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Germany: Airport border controls hit by IT outage - DW (English)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPTkU0RFpuZl9oMWNSSmtSOEVrelZ4NFBucTFhd1FPWFotYWczQkxIRWNCcC1aVFRQcU1zWTFwY3Z6S1NBckNjNmYwZ0h6Q0ZyQUdaNW5PeC1zWTZidUNIWl9EX2tUUmpVQTN3MjV1ZFpOZjg0bS1YSjI0X1c0N2hIYjc3eGxUT3NDanNWWVJ2RXpJQzQ3NHJ4TERRZGJ2eURjaVBEU1pyU1FsX3UtdENoSmZUWWZsVDRjS3lIUDFhRlFrd3p5cGfSAcYBQVVfeXFMUHdLRDk4aFpEdHllM1BTWEJkZkRwZGxmWVh5ZUlha05HbXkxMnA1V3kxbDItcG9NSm9PdW9zU2ZDR215WVRRcUwzdUZiQjI2R0MtRmJsOW9pLXVVR3puOFpnRTFPSlpnNDdnY2tJNndZUWotYkx2cHgtNzF3SXZEbmltRV9KZFU4Wkw0T1gxZjhvbmwwN2tkUFhIVld4cm1SekQtZzNoZE03azdXaTFQR2xHNkJHWTU5ekVmelZYYW5BX3lucnd3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxPTkU0RFpuZl9oMWNSSmtSOEVrelZ4NFBucTFhd1FPWFotYWczQkxIRWNCcC1aVFRQcU1zWTFwY3Z6S1NBckNjNmYwZ0h6Q0ZyQUdaNW5PeC1zWTZidUNIWl9EX2tUUmpVQTN3MjV1ZFpOZjg0bS1YSjI0X1c0N2hIYjc3eGxUT3NDanNWWVJ2RXpJQzQ3NHJ4TERRZGJ2eURjaVBEU1pyU1FsX3UtdENoSmZUWWZsVDRjS3lIUDFhRlFrd3p5cGfSAcYBQVVfeXFMUHdLRDk4aFpEdHllM1BTWEJkZkRwZGxmWVh5ZUlha05HbXkxMnA1V3kxbDItcG9NSm9PdW9zU2ZDR215WVRRcUwzdUZiQjI2R0MtRmJsOW9pLXVVR3puOFpnRTFPSlpnNDdnY2tJNndZUWotYkx2cHgtNzF3SXZEbmltRV9KZFU4Wkw0T1gxZjhvbmwwN2tkUFhIVld4cm1SekQtZzNoZE03azdXaTFQR2xHNkJHWTU5ekVmelZYYW5BX3lucnd3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 16:01:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PM Modi's $20,000 diamond was the most expensive gift to Biden family in 2023 - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>PM Modi's $20,000 diamond was the most expensive gift to Biden family in 2023</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023<br/><strong>Source:</strong> US State Department Report</p><p>During a private dinner at the White House in June 2023, Prime Minister Narendra Modi gifted a 7.5 carat, $20,000 diamond to First Lady Jill Biden, marking it as the most expensive gift presented to the Biden family by a foreign leader that year.</p><ul><li>The diamond was valued at approximately ₹17,15,158.</li><li>Modi's gifts also included a carved sandalwood box, a book, a statue, and an oil lamp, totaling an estimated $6,232.</li><li>Jill Biden's diamond was retained for official use in the East Wing.</li><li>The diamond symbolizes India's 75 years of independence and was created using advanced technology in Gujarat.</li><li>Modi has previously gifted Biden a painting worth $1,000.</li><li>Other gifts included $850 and $125 items to US officials.</li></ul><blockquote>“Jill Biden’s diamond is likely to remain a notable symbol of India’s diplomatic ties with the US.”</blockquote><p>In summary, the extravagant gifting during Modi's visit underscores the significance of diplomatic relations and the cultural symbolism associated with such exchanges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/pm-modi-usd-20000-diamond-was-the-most-expensive-gift-to-biden-family-in-2023-19534321.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/pm-modi-usd-20000-diamond-was-the-most-expensive-gift-to-biden-family-in-2023-19534321.htm</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:56:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan hits JACKPOT, discovers huge gold reserves worth billions in..., but cannot use it due to.... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan discovers huge gold reserves worth billions in Punjab's Indus River, but cannot utilise because…</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><figure><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/QT-pak-gold-BEFUN.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Gold reserves in Indus River"><figcaption>(Representational image)</figcaption></figure><p>Pakistan has struck gold as massive reserves and deposits of gold have been discovered along the Indus River in Punjab’s Attock region, estimated at 2.8 million tolas (approximately 32.6 metric tons) worth around Rs 600 billion (Pakistani rupee).</p><ul><li>The reserves stretch across a 32-kilometer area.</li><li>Discovery revealed through research by the Geological Survey of Pakistan.</li><li>Gold is mainly visible during winter when water levels recede.</li><li>Controversy over the exploration and development of the gold resources.</li><li>Illegal excavation has led to government bans on unauthorized gold extraction.</li></ul><blockquote>“After completion of necessary formalities and approval of amendments required in PMC Rules, 2002 to conduct the auction of placer gold, seeking environmental approvals from the Punjab Environment Department, the administrative department is fully determined to start the auctions of placer gold deposits by December this year.”</blockquote><p>Despite the significant finding, proper exploration and development remain stymied by bureaucratic resistance, leading to illegal mining practices.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/pakistan-discovers-huge-gold-reserves-worth-billions-in-punjabs-indus-river-but-cannot-utilise-because-7512641/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/pakistan-discovers-huge-gold-reserves-worth-billions-in-punjabs-indus-river-but-cannot-utilise-because-7512641/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:12:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan discovers huge gold reserves worth billions in Punjab's Indus River, but cannot utilise because… - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistan Discovers Billions Worth of Gold Reserves Along Indus River</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p>
<img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/QT-pak-gold-BEFUN.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Gold Reserves Discovery" />
<figcaption>(Representational image)</figcaption>
<p><strong>Islamabad:</strong> Pakistan has struck gold, literally, as massive reserves estimated at 32.6 metric tons have been discovered along the Indus River in Punjab’s Attock region.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The gold reserves are estimated to be worth Rs 600 billion.</li>
  <li>Gold deposits extend across a 32-kilometer area identified by the Geological Survey of Pakistan.</li>
  <li>The gold is primarily visible during winter months when the river's water levels recede.</li>
  <li>Albert reserves are affected by illegal excavations, prompting government bans on unauthorized extraction.</li>
  <li>Officials are reportedly prioritizing other mining operations over gold exploration.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“After completion of necessary formalities and approval of amendments required in PMC Rules, 2002 to conduct the auction of placer gold...”</blockquote>
<p>The discovery of gold reserves presents significant potential for Pakistan's economy, though mismanagement and illegal activities pose challenges for proper utilization.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/pakistan-discovers-huge-gold-reserves-worth-billions-in-punjabs-indus-river-but-cannot-utilise-because-7512641/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/pakistan-discovers-huge-gold-reserves-worth-billions-in-punjabs-indus-river-but-cannot-utilise-because-7512641/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 14:12:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cut my finger but I won't vote for Mike Johnson: Kentucky Republican Thomas Massie says he has no 'F's to - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kentucky Republican Thomas Massie Declares Intentions on Voting Amid Personal Injury</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Thomas Massie" />
<figcaption>Thomas Massie, Republican Congressman from Kentucky</figcaption>
<p>In a recent statement, Kentucky Republican Thomas Massie indicated that despite sustaining an injury, he will not be voting for Mike Johnson.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Massie expressed a strong opinion against Mike Johnson, stating he has no interest in supporting him.</li>
  <li>Massie humorously likened the situation to being unimpressed by minor setbacks like a finger injury.</li>
  <li>His remarks reflect a broader sentiment among some GOP members regarding the party's leadership.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“I cut my finger but I won’t vote for Mike Johnson. I have no ‘F’s to give,” Massie emphasized.</blockquote>
<p>This statement underscores ongoing tensions within the Republican party as they navigate leadership choices ahead of the elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/cut-my-finger-but-i-wont-vote-for-mike-johnson-kentucky-republican-thomas-massie-says-he-has-no-fs-to-give/articleshow/116918976.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/cut-my-finger-but-i-wont-vote-for-mike-johnson-kentucky-republican-thomas-massie-says-he-has-no-fs-to-give/articleshow/116918976.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 13:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yemen conducts 2 military operations against Israel - Mehr News Agency - English Version]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxPWGZtY0ZQYjBJbklfZXF6Tzl5dXM5VjZQaGhUTXVwd3BkQnpBTC0yWXdmMS1qZmhLa25ySVNVN0JlenVFOUx3Sm14TWl3cU12ZnRRRFpXdGxCSlVsTzFNZEN1Z3ZaVmZRQXpEVmdfZUc1NEZLNWwzSVN0eHRMTXlTd2Zoc1VxYnB2cXFKYXpxM2PSAUtBVV95cUxOWm5TOGVaMUEwbjFRbVk3Q1FUenNxdWlvZ3FuanB6bGxvajJpTDI1eHVJMDN5QXMwNTZXLWs5Slh6ZUowZU1JeUM2alE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxPWGZtY0ZQYjBJbklfZXF6Tzl5dXM5VjZQaGhUTXVwd3BkQnpBTC0yWXdmMS1qZmhLa25ySVNVN0JlenVFOUx3Sm14TWl3cU12ZnRRRFpXdGxCSlVsTzFNZEN1Z3ZaVmZRQXpEVmdfZUc1NEZLNWwzSVN0eHRMTXlTd2Zoc1VxYnB2cXFKYXpxM2PSAUtBVV95cUxOWm5TOGVaMUEwbjFRbVk3Q1FUenNxdWlvZ3FuanB6bGxvajJpTDI1eHVJMDN5QXMwNTZXLWs5Slh6ZUowZU1JeUM2alE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 13:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biden blocks Japan firm’s bid to acquire US steelmaker: why this is a shortsighted decision, what could happen now - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Blocks Nippon Steel's Acquisition of US Steel</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 3, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><p>This article discusses President Biden's executive decision to block a $14.9 billion takeover of US Steel by Japan's Nippon Steel, citing national security risks. The decision has sparked debates on the implications for the US economy and foreign investment.</p><ul><li>Biden exercised executive power to block the acquisition, emphasizing the need for a strong domestic steel industry.</li><li>The acquisition raised concerns over national security and potential job losses in key battleground states.</li><li>The United Steelworkers union opposed the deal, reflecting bipartisan worries over foreign ownership of American firms.</li><li>Biden’s decision is described as a significant deviation from the U.S. culture of open investment.</li><li>Critics argue the decision may deter foreign investment in sensitive U.S. industries.</li></ul><blockquote>“I am taking action to block this deal. It is my solemn responsibility as President to ensure that, now and long into the future, America has a strong domestically owned and operated steel industry.” – President Biden</blockquote><p>The blocking of this deal highlights the tension between national security interests and foreign investment, raising questions about the future of U.S. economic policy in sensitive sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/biden-block-nippon-japan-steel-takeover-9758563/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/biden-block-nippon-japan-steel-takeover-9758563/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['T for terrorism': MEA's dig at Pakistan foreign minister's 'two to tango' comment on bilateral ties - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/t-for-terrorism-meas-dig-at-pakistan-foreign-ministers-two-to-tango-comment-on-bilateral-ties/articleshow/116918363.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/t-for-terrorism-meas-dig-at-pakistan-foreign-ministers-two-to-tango-comment-on-bilateral-ties/articleshow/116918363.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MAGA impressed by Cybertruck bomber; Matt Gaetz calls 'Vegas dude' real 'CHAD' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>MAGA Impressed by Cybertruck Bomber; Matt Gaetz Calls 'Vegas Dude' Real 'CHAD'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p>The article discusses the reactions of MAGA supporters to a recent event involving a Cybertruck and Matt Gaetz's comments about an individual referred to as the 'Vegas dude'.</p>
<ul>
  <li>MAGA supporters show excitement over a Cybertruck event.</li>
  <li>Matt Gaetz praises an individual, dubbing him a 'real CHAD'.</li>
  <li>Social media reactions reflect varying opinions on the situation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This guy is the real deal, a true CHAD!” - Matt Gaetz</blockquote>
<p>This incident illustrates the intersection of technology and pop culture within the political realm.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/maga-impressed-by-cybertruck-bomber-matt-gaetz-calls-vegas-dude-real-chad/articleshow/116918082.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/maga-impressed-by-cybertruck-bomber-matt-gaetz-calls-vegas-dude-real-chad/articleshow/116918082.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German, French foreign ministers meet Syria's new rulers in Damascus - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/germanys-foreign-minister-heads-damascus-one-day-trip-2025-01-03/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/germanys-foreign-minister-heads-damascus-one-day-trip-2025-01-03/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:31:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jill Biden's most expensive gift in 2023, a $20,000 diamond from PM Modi - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Jill Biden's most expensive gift in 2023, a $20,000 diamond from PM Modi</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 03, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/03/550x309/modi_jill_joe_biden_1735905196302_1735905212676.jpg" alt="The diamond gifted by PM Modi will be transferred to the US National Archives once Joe Biden leaves office. (AFP/File)" title="The diamond gifted by PM Modi will be transferred to the US National Archives once Joe Biden leaves office. (AFP/File)">
<figcaption>The diamond gifted by PM Modi will be transferred to the US National Archives once Joe Biden leaves office. (AFP/File)</figcaption>
<p>In 2023, Jill Biden received a stunning $20,000 diamond from Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi, marking it as the most expensive gift to any member of the first family that year.</p>
<ul>
<li>The diamond is a 7.5-carat stone, reflecting the value of diplomatic gifts.</li>
<li>Jill Biden also received a $14,063 brooch from the Ukrainian ambassador and various gifts from Egyptian officials worth $4,510.</li>
<li>President Biden was given numerous expensive gifts, including a commemorative photo album worth $7,100 from South Korea's former president.</li>
<li>All gifts over $480 must be declared per US federal law.</li>
<li>The diamond will be transferred to the National Archives once Biden leaves office.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The diamond will be turned over to the archives once Biden leaves the office later this month.” - Vanessa Valdivia, spokesperson for Jill Biden</blockquote>
<p>This significant gift highlights the norms of international diplomacy and the regulations surrounding gifts to officials.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/jill-bidens-most-expensive-gift-in-2023-a-20-000-diamond-from-pm-modi-joe-biden-us-101735904287742.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/jill-bidens-most-expensive-gift-in-2023-a-20-000-diamond-from-pm-modi-joe-biden-us-101735904287742.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:05:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pravasi Bharatiya Samman Awards-2025 - Ministry of External Affairs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxQLUd1ZjBHVzY3TnlWVEdJNTN2UVZFRlJKZHVCT0NzVGlNRnRTWXNxcWJHVGYzR2N1YmxIWDVDOWJKODRFSVhxYjB3bDdrN1k1S0llWVRDcnVHanBrOG9vcXM4eWhxVUFjeEttRm5KLUJmcHVtY2c3NU1iTFdVQ1VVRXUwUUQ3NjBqd1dkSmxGSl8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxQLUd1ZjBHVzY3TnlWVEdJNTN2UVZFRlJKZHVCT0NzVGlNRnRTWXNxcWJHVGYzR2N1YmxIWDVDOWJKODRFSVhxYjB3bDdrN1k1S0llWVRDcnVHanBrOG9vcXM4eWhxVUFjeEttRm5KLUJmcHVtY2c3NU1iTFdVQ1VVRXUwUUQ3NjBqd1dkSmxGSl8?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 12:00:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Relevant T-Word Is Terrorism, Not Tango': India Responds To Pakistan Minister's Remark On Ties - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/cant-be-one-way-pakistans-deputy-pm-on-improving-ties-with-india-9176365.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/cant-be-one-way-pakistans-deputy-pm-on-improving-ties-with-india-9176365.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 11:07:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['US Is Laughing Stock': Donald Trump Blames 'Open Borders' After New Orleans, Las Vegas Attacks - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Blames Open Borders for New Orleans and Las Vegas Attacks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 03, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Donald Trump called America a 'disaster' and 'laughing stock all over the world'. (AP image)"><figcaption>Donald Trump called America a 'disaster' and 'laughing stock all over the world'. (AP image)</figcaption><p>Following a tragic truck attack in New Orleans, President-elect Donald Trump attributes the violence to "open borders" and criticizes current leadership, asserting the US is viewed as a laughing stock globally.</p><ul><li>A truck attack in New Orleans left 14 dead and at least 35 injured during New Year's celebrations.</li><li>The attacker, identified as Shamsud-Din Jabbar, was purportedly inspired by ISIS.</li><li>Trump condemned the perceived ineffectiveness of various US law enforcement agencies.</li><li>Another incident occurred in Las Vegas, involving a Tesla Cybertruck explosion outside Trump International Hotel.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is what happens when you have OPEN BORDERS, with weak, ineffective, and virtually nonexistent leadership.”</blockquote><p>Trump urges for stronger leadership and action to combat ongoing threats to safety and national security.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/us-becomes-laughing-stock-donald-trump-blames-open-borders-after-new-orleans-las-vegas-attacks-9175935.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/us-becomes-laughing-stock-donald-trump-blames-open-borders-after-new-orleans-las-vegas-attacks-9175935.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:56:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bomb-Making Materials And Open Quran: What FBI Found In New Orleans Attacker Shamsud-Din Jabbar's Home - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/bomb-making-materials-and-open-quran-what-fbi-found-in-new-orleans-attacker-shamsud-din-jabbars-home-9175951.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/bomb-making-materials-and-open-quran-what-fbi-found-in-new-orleans-attacker-shamsud-din-jabbars-home-9175951.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:47:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel Conducts 'Operation Many Ways' In Syria, Destroys Underground Missile Facility - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Conducts 'Operation Many Ways' In Syria, Destroys Underground Missile Facility</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 03, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Israel conducts raid in Syria (Photo: Israeli Air Force)"><figcaption>Israel conducts raid in Syria (Photo: Israeli Air Force)</figcaption></figure><p>The Israeli military conducted a successful operation on September 8, 2024, targeting an Iranian-funded underground missile production site in Masyaf, Syria, as revealed on January 3, 2025.</p><ul><li>The operation involved over a hundred Kingfisher fighters.</li><li>It resulted in the destruction of critical missile production machinery and documents.</li><li>The operation was described as essential for Israel's security by Air Force Commander Major General Tomer Bar.</li></ul><blockquote>“Now that we are on the ground in peace for a moment, having accomplished the mission, we can be proud.” - Major General Tomer Bar</blockquote><p>This operation reflects ongoing tensions in the region and Israel's proactive stance against Iranian influence in Syria.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/israeli-military-operation-many-ways-israeli-raid-syria-missile-production-9176006.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/israeli-military-operation-many-ways-israeli-raid-syria-missile-production-9176006.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 10:38:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Virgin Australia staff not detained in Fiji after theft, sexual assault complaint, says government - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/virgin-australia-staff-not-detained-fiji-after-theft-sexual-assault-complaint-2025-01-03/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/virgin-australia-staff-not-detained-fiji-after-theft-sexual-assault-complaint-2025-01-03/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 08:05:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tesla Cybertruck Driver Broke Up With Wife Days Before Explosion, Left Home After Argument: Report - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxPdWNVaTdyZllEcWtXZUZITVlEa1A0U2FQbnotMl8ycG1XX3hQRDhSTnVVT0xOZ2x3TTNlU2IwWXEzcXVGSzBSYkM5U3RwWGNYd09FQXRWbWIwaTdvOERhR2xVNVgwdGVTVE01RGl4WjNROXBPQXZTNTNnTjFDWmZaRzQ3WFFTMVhWdG5yYi10WDR6ZGZ0MTJIX2hPSzZ2SlpoZ2FUcHQwUldaQ2lTSXN4Yzc5eWYtWUpfQ1pRS1BtREVaVjNBSnZNUXM5S28xeHFTU0IwMklndnRyaWNFR2lHOXpKYWJHZDZp0gHuAUFVX3lxTE01aUdZQ2d3cXNVRmx6MWktQkhUbUZ3dVRqNG1pT09tcDY1NEdmVEJ6T2tGa0lLdGJoV2RkeU9kdktzWFZpYWtCeU1ISmRNdWZ4bHdZamVtNDNiMDJROXVVTm04ZFdIaXZKRmUtVkNHbXp5c0ozSU5pUV9fX3ZFRTVGVlFtMmRGQ09XZGgtWGZOSHdLRVVpUFZiQWlwbEx3LTQxZnhraHhIVzFXWWJibXJuT19IY01GVmRHSmxZS3hEbHR4bXdjdWtETm93ZlNqZnlILXJ2NFc5Y0JiSUNXVG53aVFDbkF6RU5tanF2SGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxPdWNVaTdyZllEcWtXZUZITVlEa1A0U2FQbnotMl8ycG1XX3hQRDhSTnVVT0xOZ2x3TTNlU2IwWXEzcXVGSzBSYkM5U3RwWGNYd09FQXRWbWIwaTdvOERhR2xVNVgwdGVTVE01RGl4WjNROXBPQXZTNTNnTjFDWmZaRzQ3WFFTMVhWdG5yYi10WDR6ZGZ0MTJIX2hPSzZ2SlpoZ2FUcHQwUldaQ2lTSXN4Yzc5eWYtWUpfQ1pRS1BtREVaVjNBSnZNUXM5S28xeHFTU0IwMklndnRyaWNFR2lHOXpKYWJHZDZp0gHuAUFVX3lxTE01aUdZQ2d3cXNVRmx6MWktQkhUbUZ3dVRqNG1pT09tcDY1NEdmVEJ6T2tGa0lLdGJoV2RkeU9kdktzWFZpYWtCeU1ISmRNdWZ4bHdZamVtNDNiMDJROXVVTm04ZFdIaXZKRmUtVkNHbXp5c0ozSU5pUV9fX3ZFRTVGVlFtMmRGQ09XZGgtWGZOSHdLRVVpUFZiQWlwbEx3LTQxZnhraHhIVzFXWWJibXJuT19IY01GVmRHSmxZS3hEbHR4bXdjdWtETm93ZlNqZnlILXJ2NFc5Y0JiSUNXVG53aVFDbkF6RU5tanF2SGc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 07:33:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. Aircraft Shot Down! Report Claims China Arming Houthis For ‘Free Passage’ In The Red Sea - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>U.S. Aircraft Shot Down! Report Claims China Arming Houthis For 'Free Passage' In The Red Sea</h1>
<p><strong>Date & Source:</strong> January 1, 2024 - EurAsian Times</p>
<img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Su-57-1290-x-650-px-16.png" alt="" width="1290" height="650">
<figcaption>Image Credits: Gulf International Forum.</figcaption>
<p>Since the outbreak of the Israel-Hamas war in October 2023, the Houthis, a Yemeni armed group, have intensified conflicts against Israel and the U.S., claiming support from China for acquiring advanced weaponry.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Houthis are part of a wider Iran-led resistance in the region, fiercely opposing Israeli and U.S. influence.</li>
  <li>Claims suggest China is supplying the Houthis with advanced weapons through a covert partnership.</li>
  <li>U.S. intelligence indicates a complex weapons supply network connecting the Houthis and Chinese manufacturers.</li>
  <li>Despite numerous airstrikes, the Houthis maintain control over significant regions in Yemen.</li>
  <li>Attacks from the Houthis on Israeli targets have escalated since October 2023, amidst a broader regional conflict.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We are committed to continuing our military operation in support of Gaza, and we will not stop until the genocide crimes and the siege on Gaza stop.” - Mohammed al-Bukhaiti, Houthi political official</blockquote>
<p>The situation remains volatile as the future of U.S. and Israeli operations against the Houthis may face persistent challenges, as hinted by ongoing arms supply and military engagements.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/u-s-aircraft-shot-down-report-claims-china/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/u-s-aircraft-shot-down-report-claims-china/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 06:43:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Let's protect Yoon': How South Korea's impeached president defied arrest - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Let's protect Yoon: How South Korea's impeached president defied arrest</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p><p>Despite being impeached, South Korea's former president Yoon Suk-yeol has evaded arrest, prompting significant public discourse on the implications of this defiance.</p><ul><li>Yoon’s impeachment has fueled debates about political accountability in South Korea.</li><li>Public demonstrations have emerged, both in support of and against Yoon.</li><li>The legal ramifications of his defiance are still unfolding, leading to potential constitutional crises.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will protect Yoon at all costs,” said a supporter during a recent rally.</blockquote><p>This incident raises important questions about the balance of power and the rule of law in South Korea, marking a pivotal moment for the nation’s democratic institutions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/lets-protect-yoon-how-south-koreas-impeached-president-defied-arrest/articleshow/116904597.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/lets-protect-yoon-how-south-koreas-impeached-president-defied-arrest/articleshow/116904597.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 06:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump: Tariffs will make America wealthy again - ForexLive]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump: Tariffs will make America wealthy again</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Unknown | <strong>Source:</strong> Unknown</p><img src="https://images.forexlive.com/Content/Authors/Justin-Low.jpg" alt="Justin Low" /><figcaption>Justin Low</figcaption><p>Donald Trump reaffirms his belief that tariffs are essential for America's wealth in a series of recent tweets, outlining his agenda for when he takes office.</p><ul><li>Trump claims that tariffs contributed significantly to America's wealth in the past.</li><li>He vows to prioritize tariffs to improve the economy and pay off national debt.</li><li>Trump criticizes the current administration's border policies, linking them to national security issues.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Tariffs, and Tariffs alone, created this vast wealth for our Country... Tariffs will pay off our debt and, MAKE AMERICA WEALTHY AGAIN!”</blockquote><p>Trump's strong stance on tariffs outlines his economic strategy for his upcoming term, emphasizing a return to policies he believes will restore America's economic power.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forexlive.com/news/trump-tariffs-will-make-america-wealthy-again-20250103/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forexlive.com/news/trump-tariffs-will-make-america-wealthy-again-20250103/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 05:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Germany launches online visa applications via consular services portal - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Germany Launches Online Visa Applications via Consular Services Portal</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Economic Times</p>
<img src="https://img.etimg.com/thumb/width-513,height-50,msid-115075348/growfast.jpg" alt="Growfast" />
<figcaption>Growfast advertisement</figcaption>
<p>Germany has launched the Consular Services Portal, a global online platform allowing applicants to submit German visa applications digitally. This marks a significant shift from traditional paperwork to a streamlined digital process.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The system supports 28 categories of national visas, including for employment, education, training, and family reunification.</li>
  <li>Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock emphasized the need for modernization in the visa process to address the skilled worker shortage.</li>
  <li>The digital overhaul aims to improve efficiency and reduce waiting times, benefiting both applicants and businesses in need of skilled labor.</li>
  <li>The Federal Foreign Office is planning further enhancements, like enabling joint family applications.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Every year, Germany is short of at least 400,000 skilled workers... We need a national visa process that is state-of-the-art – modern, digital, and secure.” – Annalena Baerbock</blockquote>
<p>This reform is seen as a “real administrative revolution” and aligns with modern immigration laws, strengthening Germany's competitive position globally.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/nri/migrate/germany-launches-online-visa-applications-via-consular-services-portal/articleshow/116903184.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/nri/migrate/germany-launches-online-visa-applications-via-consular-services-portal/articleshow/116903184.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 05:26:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: Plane crashes into roof of building in California; 2 dead, 18 hurt - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQS1ZJQWRqNDhoWm1qcmZ1VFJKby1KVG83eVVmeDVpTEZBQ0M5QW1iZ216Wk9zU1diTEVoRlZUNkQxajEwUmN2b2xTTEVNWVEyMWJrZExXbmc5NVhrQnJubVF0U1A0SklXUlpjTzhQeld2UlBGdGh1WW5STnh3amRmZS0zbGdCcmpTNlBENG9Zc0tjM2IxMmFTTmxFV01EeXN3X0p3aldneDZGUzBaRHdXbkVBd244TEJvQ2xz0gG_AUFVX3lxTE5BeVoxOTVEaC1XbWRkRkZGbnVnNEZ4T1pMdlQzSkY5dndIa1NiQjd6d1ZQajFZWThnNW05ck1mb0FxQThEUE1tRU4tM1EyZUZqUlYxblJaekVOYnFkT0pzUVVTT0J1Xy14U3QtZlpIdmZqaDJFb1RWYzZVVXkwSlZFWjV6QnBPXzJXcDc1V2ZMOTQ5Mk05WjJBeFZtM3pPbFhldlhsVmNUNjJ2MG1laGJycUx1SWJicTMzdWlRUTV3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQS1ZJQWRqNDhoWm1qcmZ1VFJKby1KVG83eVVmeDVpTEZBQ0M5QW1iZ216Wk9zU1diTEVoRlZUNkQxajEwUmN2b2xTTEVNWVEyMWJrZExXbmc5NVhrQnJubVF0U1A0SklXUlpjTzhQeld2UlBGdGh1WW5STnh3amRmZS0zbGdCcmpTNlBENG9Zc0tjM2IxMmFTTmxFV01EeXN3X0p3aldneDZGUzBaRHdXbkVBd244TEJvQ2xz0gG_AUFVX3lxTE5BeVoxOTVEaC1XbWRkRkZGbnVnNEZ4T1pMdlQzSkY5dndIa1NiQjd6d1ZQajFZWThnNW05ck1mb0FxQThEUE1tRU4tM1EyZUZqUlYxblJaekVOYnFkT0pzUVVTT0J1Xy14U3QtZlpIdmZqaDJFb1RWYzZVVXkwSlZFWjV6QnBPXzJXcDc1V2ZMOTQ5Mk05WjJBeFZtM3pPbFhldlhsVmNUNjJ2MG1laGJycUx1SWJicTMzdWlRUTV3?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 05:07:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea Political Crisis: How impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol defied arrest warrant after hours of standoff - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Political Crisis: How impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol defied arrest warrant after hours of standoff</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/yoon-2.jpg?resize=600,338' alt='yoon, south korea, arrest warrant'><figcaption>Pro-Yoon protesters lie on the ground outside of impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol’s official residence as police officers attempt to disperse them. (Reuters Photo)</figcaption><p>The political crisis in South Korea has escalated as investigators attempted to arrest impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol over his declaration of martial law. Despite facing fierce resistance, Yoon remained defiant as the nation watched the unfolding events.</p><ul><li>Yoon stood firm against an attempted arrest amidst protests from his supporters.</li><li>Investigators faced significant resistance from presidential security at the residence.</li><li>The crisis follows Yoon's controversial imposition of martial law and subsequent impeachment proceedings.</li><li>Thousands of police were deployed as tensions escalated outside the presidential compound.</li></ul><blockquote>“I will fight to the end.” - President Yoon Suk Yeol</blockquote><p>The crisis in South Korea reflects severe political tensions as President Yoon's actions challenge the rule of law.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-crisis-investigators-attempt-arrest-president-yoon-9757708/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-crisis-investigators-attempt-arrest-president-yoon-9757708/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 04:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea Political Crisis: Investigators suspend attempt to arrest impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol after standoff - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Political Crisis: Impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol Defies Arrest Warrant</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/yoon-2.jpg?resize=600,338" alt="Yoon Suk Yeol Standoff"><figcaption>Pro-Yoon protesters lie on the ground outside of impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol’s official residence as police officers attempt to disperse them. (Reuters Photo)</figcaption><p>The political crisis in South Korea deepens as impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol defies attempts to arrest him following his controversial imposition of martial law, sparking widespread protests and a significant standoff with police and supporters.</p><ul><li>Yoon Suk Yeol faces a warrant for arrest related to his declaration of martial law.</li><li>Security forces prevented investigators from entering the presidential residence to execute the arrest.</li><li>Protests erupted outside the residence, with supporters rallying in freezing temperatures.</li><li>Yoon's legal team claims the arrest warrant is invalid and illegal.</li><li>The political situation escalates as impeachment proceedings gain momentum.</li></ul><blockquote>“I will fight to the end.” – Yoon Suk Yeol, in a New Year’s message</blockquote><p>The current political turmoil in South Korea not only highlights the challenges facing the administration but also raises questions about the future of governance in the country amid deepening divisions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-crisis-investigators-attempt-arrest-president-yoon-9757708/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-crisis-investigators-attempt-arrest-president-yoon-9757708/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 04:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korea crisis deepens as investigators attempt to arrest impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korea Political Crisis: Investigators suspend attempt to arrest impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol after standoff</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/yoon-2.jpg?resize=600,338" alt="Pro-Yoon protesters lie on the ground outside of impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol’s official residence." /><figcaption>Pro-Yoon protesters lie on the ground outside of impeached South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol’s official residence. (Reuters Photo)</figcaption><p>South Korea faces a severe political crisis with the impeachment of President Yoon Suk Yeol, leading to a failed attempt by investigators to arrest him amid a tense standoff outside the presidential residence.</p><ul><li>Investigators arrived with a warrant for Yoon's arrest amidst accusations of his martial law declaration.</li><li>Resistance from Yoon's security detail led to a standoff, with police and supporters gathered outside.</li><li>Yoon declared his intention to fight the arrest, claiming the warrant was invalid.</li><li>Previous actions by Yoon, including declaring martial law, have escalated tensions and led to opposition responses.</li></ul><blockquote>“I will fight to the end.” - Yoon Suk Yeol</blockquote><p>The situation in South Korea remains volatile as the nation watches the unfolding political drama, with implications for its governance and democracy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-crisis-investigators-attempt-arrest-president-yoon-9757708/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/south-korea-crisis-investigators-attempt-arrest-president-yoon-9757708/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 04:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Las Vegas Cybertruck explosion: 'Wife left Matthew Livelsberger days before blast' — Was it political mot - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Las Vegas Cybertruck explosion: 'Wife left Matthew Livelsberger days before blast' — Was it political motive or personal struggles?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>In a shocking incident in Las Vegas, a Cybertruck exploded, raising questions about possible political motives or personal struggles behind the event.</p><ul><li>The explosion occurred shortly after the individual's wife left him.</li><li>Authorities are investigating both personal and political angles as possible motives.</li><li>The incident has drawn widespread media attention, leading to discussions on social media.</li></ul><blockquote>"The timing of the explosion raises many questions about the motivations behind it," stated a local investigator.</blockquote><p>This incident has generated significant public interest and will likely continue to fuel discussions about the intersection of personal issues and broader motives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/las-vegas-cybertruck-explosion-wife-left-matthew-livelsberger-days-before-blast-was-it-political-motive-or-personal-struggles/articleshow/116898874.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/las-vegas-cybertruck-explosion-wife-left-matthew-livelsberger-days-before-blast-was-it-political-motive-or-personal-struggles/articleshow/116898874.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 04:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>