<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 21:17:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 21:17:05 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump's '51st state' dream hits a wall: Even MAGA’s favorite Canadian Pierre Poilievre says no - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump's '51st State' Dream Hits a Wall: Even MAGA’s Favorite Canadian Pierre Poilievre Says No</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [insert date here] | <strong>Source:</strong> [insert source here]</p><p>This article discusses former President Trump's aspirations for a '51st state' and highlights the unexpected repudiation from popular Canadian politician Pierre Poilievre, who aligns with Trump's supporters.</p><ul><li>Trump’s proposal for a 51st state gains mixed reactions.</li><li>Polls indicate that a significant portion of Trump's base supports the idea.</li><li>Pierre Poilievre states his opposition to the proposal, despite his MAGA connections.</li><li>The implications of this rejection could affect Trump's influence in Canada.</li></ul><blockquote>“It’s not going to happen,” said Poilievre, reaffirming his stance against the notion of a 51st state.</blockquote><p>The article concludes that Trump's dream of expanding the United States may face significant hurdles not only domestically but also from allies abroad.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/trumps-51st-state-dream-hits-a-wall-even-magas-favorite-canadian-pierre-poilievre-says-no/articleshow/117060923.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/trumps-51st-state-dream-hits-a-wall-even-magas-favorite-canadian-pierre-poilievre-says-no/articleshow/117060923.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 19:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles firefighters running out of water as Southern California wildfires rage - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Los Angeles firefighters running out of water as Southern California wildfires rage</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/CALIFORNIA-WILDFIRES--4_1736351576868_1736351593165.JPG" alt="A hose is used from outside the window of a building, as the Eaton Fire burns in Pasadena, California, U.S. January 7, 2025. REUTERS/Mario Anzuoni(REUTERS)" title="A hose is used from outside the window of a building, as the Eaton Fire burns in Pasadena, California, U.S. January 7, 2025. REUTERS/Mario Anzuoni(REUTERS)"><figcaption>A hose is used from outside the window of a building, as the Eaton Fire burns in Pasadena, California, U.S. January 7, 2025. REUTERS/Mario Anzuoni(REUTERS)</figcaption></figure><p>As wildfires continue to ravage Southern California, Los Angeles firefighters are facing a critical water shortage, with reports of hydrants drying up and emergency evacuations underway in areas such as Pacific Palisades.</p><ul><li>Firefighters report dwindling water supply as wildfires burn through homes and neighborhoods.</li><li>California Governor Gavin Newsom has declared a state of emergency due to worsening conditions.</li><li>At least 30,000 residents have been evacuated, with an additional 52,000 under evacuation orders.</li><li>Wind gusts of up to 100 mph are intensifying the fire conditions.</li></ul><blockquote>“There’s no water in the fire hydrants,” said billionaire developer Rick Caruso, confirming reports of the water crisis.</blockquote><p>The situation highlights the urgent need for resources as numerous areas remain affected by the raging wildfires.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-firefighters-running-out-of-water-as-southern-california-wildfires-rage-101736348724882.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-firefighters-running-out-of-water-as-southern-california-wildfires-rage-101736348724882.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:55:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump asks Supreme Court to block sentencing in his hush money case in New York - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Asks Supreme Court to Block Sentencing in His Hush Money Case in New York</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/ygxdt3/article69077658.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/IMG_U.S._President-elect_2_1_H6DQQRLC.jpg" alt="U.S. President-elect Donald Trump. File" />
<figcaption>U.S. President-elect Donald Trump. File | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption>
<p>President-elect Donald Trump is requesting the Supreme Court to intervene and cancel the sentencing scheduled for January 10, 2025, in his hush money case, after New York courts refused to postpone it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump's lawyers have filed an appeal, citing potential harm to the Presidency.</li>
<li>The Supreme Court has requested a response from New York prosecutors.</li>
<li>Judge Juan M. Merchan indicated there would be no jail time, fines, or probation for Trump.</li>
<li>Trump’s legal team argues for presidential immunity from criminal prosecution.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“To prevent grave injustice and harm to the institution of the Presidency and the operations of the federal government.”</blockquote>
<p>This development continues the ongoing legal battles surrounding Trump as he navigates his recent conviction.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-asks-supreme-court-to-block-sentencing-in-hush-money-case/article69076914.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-asks-supreme-court-to-block-sentencing-in-hush-money-case/article69076914.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Los Angeles wildfire: Over 30,000 evacuated, Elon Musk blames ‘nonsense’ regulations| 10 points - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Los Angeles wildfire: Over 30,000 evacuated, Elon Musk blames ‘nonsense’ regulations</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not provided | <strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Los_Angeles_fire_1736347168154_1736347168448.jpg" alt="Firefighters battle the Palisades Fire in the Pacific Palisades neighborhood of Los Angeles, California. (Kyle Grillot/Bloomberg)" title="Firefighters battle the Palisades Fire in the Pacific Palisades neighborhood of Los Angeles, California. (Kyle Grillot/Bloomberg)">
<figcaption>Firefighters battle the Palisades Fire in the Pacific Palisades neighborhood of Los Angeles, California. (Kyle Grillot/Bloomberg)</figcaption>
<p>More than 30,000 people, including celebrities, were forced to evacuate their homes as wildfires spread through Los Angeles, impacting both the city and surrounding areas.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Elon Musk criticized California regulations for contributing to the fires, stating they could be avoided.</li>
  <li>National Weather Service reported winds up to 80 mph, with red flag warnings for critical fire conditions.</li>
  <li>Actor Steve Guttenberg emphasized the importance of prioritizing evacuation over personal property.</li>
  <li>Approximately 100 residents from a Pasadena nursing home were evacuated.</li>
  <li>A new blaze, the Hurst Fire, prompted evacuations in Sylmar, rapidly growing in size.</li>
  <li>Firefighting efforts included aircraft dropping water and clearing roads for emergency vehicles.</li>
  <li>Getty Villa sustained some damage, but its collection remained safe due to preventive measures.</li>
  <li>President Biden's plans were affected by the winds, grounding Air Force One.</li>
  <li>Actor James Woods shared his evacuation experience as flames approached his home.</li>
  <li>Firefighters experienced water shortages in the Palisades region amidst significant fire spread.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“These fires are easily avoidable, but nonsense regulations in California prevent action being taken.” - Elon Musk</blockquote>
<p>The wildfires in Los Angeles have created a dire situation for residents and emergency responders, leading to widespread evacuations and raising concerns about regulatory measures surrounding fire prevention.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-over-30-000-evacuated-elon-musk-blames-nonsense-regulations-10-points-101736347172714.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/los-angeles-wildfire-over-30-000-evacuated-elon-musk-blames-nonsense-regulations-10-points-101736347172714.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Canadian leader makes 'counter-offer' to Trump: 'How about if we buy Alaska?’ - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Canadian Leader Makes 'Counter-Offer' to Trump: 'How About If We Buy Alaska?'</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250108150806_Doug-Ford.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=770&amp;height=431" alt="‘How about if we buy Alaska?’ Canadian official fires back over Trump's '51st state' proposal" title="‘How about if we buy Alaska?’ Canadian official fires back over Trump's '51st state' proposal" width="770" height="431"><figcaption>Ontario Premier Doug Ford retaliated to Donald Trump's threat. (Image: Reuters)</figcaption><p>In a bold response to US President-elect Donald Trump's comments about making Canada the 51st American state, Ontario Premier Doug Ford proposed instead that Canada buy Alaska.</p><ul><li>Trump has made multiple remarks suggesting Canada could be absorbed into the US.</li><li>Ford humorously suggested purchasing Alaska and even adding Minnesota and Minneapolis to the deal.</li><li>Ford made it clear that he takes Trump's comments seriously and doesn't see them as merely jokes.</li></ul><blockquote>Ford stated, "To the president, I'll make him a counteroffer. How about if we buy Alaska? And we'll throw in Minnesota and Minneapolis at the same time?"</blockquote><p>Ford emphasized that under his leadership, the absorption of Canada will never happen.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/how-about-if-we-buy-alaska-canadian-official-fires-back-over-trump-s-51st-state-proposal-12906117.html#goog_rewarded</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/how-about-if-we-buy-alaska-canadian-official-fires-back-over-trump-s-51st-state-proposal-12906117.html#goog_rewarded</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:09:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Father set on fire by daughters after rape in Pakistan - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/father-set-on-fire-by-daughters-after-rape-in-pakistan/articleshow/117059627.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/father-set-on-fire-by-daughters-after-rape-in-pakistan/articleshow/117059627.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California wildfire apocalypse: No water for firefighters in Los Angeles? Crying, screaming residents fle - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>California wildfire apocalypse: No water for firefighters in Los Angeles? Crying, screaming residents flee in chaos</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <br> <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="California Wildfire" />
<figcaption>The wildfire has already caused significant damage in Los Angeles.</figcaption>
<p>A destructive wildfire is wreaking havoc in Los Angeles, leading to water shortages for firefighters and panic among local residents.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Firefighters are struggling with limited water supply to combat raging flames.</li>
  <li>Residents are reported to be fleeing in chaos, creating scenes of desperation.</li>
  <li>Many homes and properties are at risk of being engulfed by the wildfire.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“It feels like the end of the world, with every passing moment bringing uncertainty and fear.”</blockquote>
<p>The situation remains critical, with emergency services working hard to manage the blaze while residents seek safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/california-wildfire-apocalyptic-scenes-firefighters-in-los-angeles-battle-without-water-as-crying-screaming-residents-flee-in-chaos/articleshow/117058696.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/california-wildfire-apocalyptic-scenes-firefighters-in-los-angeles-battle-without-water-as-crying-screaming-residents-flee-in-chaos/articleshow/117058696.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ukraine says it attacked oil depot serving air base for Russian nuclear bombers - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOT1pYQ25tVU1uZThKNG9PQmlFYXdnMjVtTUQ4SkNkUlM4TUs5OERfT212LVFucDlpNWVkSUd6aXhyX3N2VFRMV05uNk9kT3gzYzljVjhSUXFMRUZHNzV6ZVM4bElrVE1aQ0hYOEt6bU5kQmNrWUM3TXNVNDZIaXhWbnRWMGNfMk1vRFBGWlZCMkNreXpITTZtZnpjczI4aGd3ZmtzeEpNRmowcUJocnpuemM0aFpsMW9jRkRRQW1HSVJoOEU4bjlDQg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOT1pYQ25tVU1uZThKNG9PQmlFYXdnMjVtTUQ4SkNkUlM4TUs5OERfT212LVFucDlpNWVkSUd6aXhyX3N2VFRMV05uNk9kT3gzYzljVjhSUXFMRUZHNzV6ZVM4bElrVE1aQ0hYOEt6bU5kQmNrWUM3TXNVNDZIaXhWbnRWMGNfMk1vRFBGWlZCMkNreXpITTZtZnpjczI4aGd3ZmtzeEpNRmowcUJocnpuemM0aFpsMW9jRkRRQW1HSVJoOEU4bjlDQg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 14:20:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump appeals to Supreme Court to halt sentencing in New York hush money case - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-appeals-to-supreme-court-to-halt-sentencing-in-new-york-hush-money-case/articleshow/117057705.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-appeals-to-supreme-court-to-halt-sentencing-in-new-york-hush-money-case/articleshow/117057705.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israeli strikes kill dozens in Gaza amid stepped up ceasefire push - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israeli Strikes Result in High Casualties in Gaza as Ceasefire Efforts Intensify</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Reuters</p><img src="https://www.reutersagency.com/en/licensereuterscontent/?utm_medium=rcom-article-media&utm_campaign=rcom-rcp-lead" alt="Mourners react during the funeral in Khan Younis" /><figcaption>Mourners react during the funeral of Palestinians killed in Israeli strikes, amid the Israel-Hamas conflict, in Khan Younis, Gaza Strip.</figcaption><p>This article discusses recent Israeli military strikes in Gaza which resulted in significant casualties amidst ongoing international efforts to establish a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas.</p><ul><li>Israeli airstrikes killed at least 22 people across Gaza.</li><li>The US, Qatar, and Egypt are intensifying efforts for a ceasefire.</li><li>Hamas demands an end to the war and withdrawal of Israeli troops for hostage release.</li><li>Israel states they will not cease operations until they dismantle Hamas.</li><li>Warning from the Gaza Health Ministry about potential hospital closures due to fuel shortages.</li></ul><blockquote>“Things are better than ever before, but there is no deal yet.”</blockquote><p>The ongoing conflict has caused extensive humanitarian issues, with a large part of the population displaced and facing severe shortages of essential resources.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-strikes-kill-dozens-gaza-us-pushes-ceasefire-2025-01-08/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-strikes-kill-dozens-gaza-us-pushes-ceasefire-2025-01-08/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 13:26:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Girl, you're not...': Elon Musk's sassy reply to Justin Trudeau over US-Canada merger post - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk Responds to Justin Trudeau's Rejection of US-Canada Merger</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/Elon_Musk_1661156439232_1736338581213.JPG" alt="Elon Musk, a Donald Trump confidant, has in the past endorsed his idea of Canada merging with the US.(Reuters)">
<figcaption>Elon Musk, a Donald Trump confidant, has in the past endorsed his idea of Canada merging with the US.(Reuters)</figcaption>
<p>Tech billionaire and Tesla boss Elon Musk took a jab at outgoing Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau after Trudeau rejected the Canada-US merger proposed by US President-elect Donald Trump.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Musk targeted Trudeau on social media after Trudeau dismissed any notion of a merger, emphasizing Canada's independence.</li>
  <li>Trudeau stated, "There isn’t a snowball’s chance in hell that Canada would become part of the United States," highlighting the beneficial partnership between the two nations.</li>
  <li>Musk replied, "Girl, you’re not the governor of Canada anymore, so doesn’t matter what you say," in a sassy retort.</li>
  <li>Trump previously endorsed the idea of Canada becoming the 51st state, suggesting military action was not necessary, but rather economic influence.</li>
  <li>Conservative leader Pierre Poilievre echoed Trudeau's sentiment, affirming Canada’s independence.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Canada will never be the 51st state. Period. We are a great and independent country." - Pierre Poilievre</blockquote>
<p>The ongoing dialogue surrounding the proposed merger reflects deeper political tensions and differing perspectives on national identity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/girl-youre-not-elon-musks-sassy-reply-to-justin-trudeau-over-us-canada-merger-post-101736338420081.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/girl-youre-not-elon-musks-sassy-reply-to-justin-trudeau-over-us-canada-merger-post-101736338420081.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:21:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No one cares, girl ...: Elon Musk brutally trolls Canada's Justin Trudeau after fiery exchange over Trump - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk Mocks Justin Trudeau Over Trump's 51st State Idea</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Times</p><p>In a fiery exchange, Elon Musk trolled Canada's Prime Minister Justin Trudeau after Trudeau reacted to Trump's suggestion of making Canada the 51st state of the U.S.</p><ul><li>Musk's tweet ignited laughter and controversy on social media.</li><li>Trudeau defended Canada's sovereignty while addressing the humorous aspect of Trump's idea.</li><li>The exchange highlights the ongoing tension in U.S.-Canada relations, especially surrounding political humor.</li></ul><blockquote>“No one cares, girl,” Musk tweeted in response to Trudeau's remarks.</blockquote><p>This incident underscores how political figures leverage humor in their public discourse to engage with audiences and navigate international relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-calls-justin-trudeau-a-girl-amid-fiery-exchange-over-trumps-canada-takeover-idea/articleshow/117055803.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-calls-justin-trudeau-a-girl-amid-fiery-exchange-over-trumps-canada-takeover-idea/articleshow/117055803.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 12:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Girl, you are no longer Canada's governor': Elon Musk's scathing dig at Justin Trudeau - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Girl, you are no longer Canada's governor: Elon Musk's scathing dig at Justin Trudeau</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 08, 2025 / <strong>Source:</strong> Moneycontrol</p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/01/20250108114303_m.jpg?impolicy=website&width=770&height=431" alt="Elon Musk and Justin Trudeau"/><figcaption>Elon Musk and Justin Trudeau, influential figures in their respective countries.</figcaption><p>Elon Musk recently took a jab at Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, who announced his resignation earlier this week. This comes in response to Trudeau's firm stance against suggestions that Canada could become an American territory.</p><ul><li>Musk referred to Trudeau as a "girl" in his critique on social media.</li><li>Trudeau firmly stated there is "no chance in hell" Canada would become part of the United States.</li><li>This back-and-forth arose from ongoing tensions regarding cross-border relations and trade.</li></ul><blockquote>“Girl, you’re not the governor of Canada anymore, so doesn’t matter what you say.” - Elon Musk</blockquote><p>This exchange highlights the ongoing political rivalry and discussions around national sovereignty and identity in the context of international relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/girl-you-no-longer-canada-s-governor-elon-musk-s-scathing-dig-at-justin-trudeau-12905977.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/world/girl-you-no-longer-canada-s-governor-elon-musk-s-scathing-dig-at-justin-trudeau-12905977.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:43:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is FAFSA? 2025-2026 Form Available Now, Deadline and All You Need to Know - BSEB Inter Org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FAFSA 2025-2026 Form Available Now: Deadlines and Essential Information</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<img src="https://bsebinter.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/What-is-FAFSA-2025-2026-Form-Available-Now-Deadline-and-All-You-Need-to-Know-1024x683.jpg" alt="What is FAFSA? 2025-2026 Form Available Now, Deadline and All You Need to Know">
<figcaption>What is FAFSA? 2025-2026 Form Available Now, Deadline and All You Need to Know</figcaption>
<p>The FAFSA for the 2025-2026 academic year is now available, allowing students to begin their applications for financial aid. It is essential to file early due to schools awarding aid on a first-come, first-served basis. This article outlines key deadlines and requirements for completing the FAFSA.</p>
<ul>
<li>The FAFSA form must be submitted online at studentaid.gov.</li>
<li>Key materials include your Social Security number, tax information, and FSA ID.</li>
<li>The FAFSA officially opened on November 21, following a beta release for testing.</li>
<li>Financial aid eligibility is assessed annually through FAFSA submissions.</li>
<li>Deadlines vary by state, with June 30, 2026, as the final deadline for federal aid applications.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Families must be ready to move swiftly once the form is available to prevent missing deadlines."</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, completing the FAFSA is a crucial step for students seeking financial aid for college, with deadlines that require prompt action to secure funding opportunities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bsebinter.org/what-is-fafsa-2025-2026-form-available-now/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bsebinter.org/what-is-fafsa-2025-2026-form-available-now/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:39:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump mulls a national emergency declaration to allow for new tariff program - report - ForexLive]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Considers National Emergency to Implement New Tariff Program</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 8, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> CNN</p>
<p>This article discusses former President Trump's consideration of declaring a national economic emergency to impose new tariffs on various countries, potentially impacting international trade relations.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump may declare a national economic emergency.</li>
  <li>This would allow him to impose tariffs under the International Economic Emergency Powers Act.</li>
  <li>No final decision has been made yet, but all options remain on the table.</li>
  <li>Markets are reacting, with USD showing mixed movements against other currencies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Nothing is off the table." - Sources on Trump's considerations.</blockquote>
<p>This potential move could significantly alter market dynamics and international trade relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forexlive.com/news/trump-mulls-a-national-emergency-declaration-to-allow-for-new-tariff-program-report-20250108/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forexlive.com/news/trump-mulls-a-national-emergency-declaration-to-allow-for-new-tariff-program-report-20250108/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk 'calls' Canada's outgoing PM Justin Trudeau: Girl, you’re not the .... - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk 'calls' Canada's outgoing PM Justin Trudeau: Girl, you’re not the ....</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>N/A</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>N/A</p><div><p>An unexpected phone call from Elon Musk to outgoing Prime Minister Justin Trudeau raised eyebrows, featuring surprising remarks that have sparked discussions online.</p></div><ul><li>Elon Musk took the initiative to call Justin Trudeau.</li><li>Speculation surrounds the nature of their conversation.</li><li>The call has gone viral on social media platforms.</li><li>Public response includes a mix of surprise and criticism.</li></ul><blockquote>“Girl, you’re not the president of the world.”</blockquote><p>This event highlights the evolving dynamics between influential figures and political leaders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-calls-canadas-former-pm-justin-trudeau-girl-youre-not-the-/articleshow/117054636.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/technology/tech-news/elon-musk-calls-canadas-former-pm-justin-trudeau-girl-youre-not-the-/articleshow/117054636.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 11:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Canadian Official Counters Trump's 51st State Proposal: "How About We Buy..." - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-official-counters-trumps-51st-state-proposal-how-about-we-buy-7427423</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-official-counters-trumps-51st-state-proposal-how-about-we-buy-7427423</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:48:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ukraine claims attack on oil depot serving air base for Russian nuclear bombers - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOT1pYQ25tVU1uZThKNG9PQmlFYXdnMjVtTUQ4SkNkUlM4TUs5OERfT212LVFucDlpNWVkSUd6aXhyX3N2VFRMV05uNk9kT3gzYzljVjhSUXFMRUZHNzV6ZVM4bElrVE1aQ0hYOEt6bU5kQmNrWUM3TXNVNDZIaXhWbnRWMGNfMk1vRFBGWlZCMkNreXpITTZtZnpjczI4aGd3ZmtzeEpNRmowcUJocnpuemM0aFpsMW9jRkRRQW1HSVJoOEU4bjlDQg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxOT1pYQ25tVU1uZThKNG9PQmlFYXdnMjVtTUQ4SkNkUlM4TUs5OERfT212LVFucDlpNWVkSUd6aXhyX3N2VFRMV05uNk9kT3gzYzljVjhSUXFMRUZHNzV6ZVM4bElrVE1aQ0hYOEt6bU5kQmNrWUM3TXNVNDZIaXhWbnRWMGNfMk1vRFBGWlZCMkNreXpITTZtZnpjczI4aGd3ZmtzeEpNRmowcUJocnpuemM0aFpsMW9jRkRRQW1HSVJoOEU4bjlDQg?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:47:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will use military: Why is Trump keen on taking control of Greenland? - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump's Controversial Interest in Greenland: Military or Economic Control?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 20, 2021 <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p><p>In a surprising statement, President-elect Donald Trump expressed his desire to take control of Greenland, suggesting potential military or economic action against Denmark.</p><ul><li>Greenland's leader is meeting with the Danish king amid tensions over the island's status.</li><li>Trump's comments coincide with a visit from his son, Donald Trump Jr., to the resource-rich island.</li><li>Greenland has a population of 57,000 and has been under Danish control for 600 years.</li><li>The island's Prime Minister insists that Greenland is not for sale and is pursuing greater independence.</li></ul><blockquote>“The island is not for sale,” said Greenland's Prime Minister Mute Egede.</blockquote><p>The conflict over Greenland’s status highlights ongoing issues rooted in its colonial past and current desires for autonomy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/world/will-use-military-why-is-trump-keen-on-taking-control-of-greenland/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/world/will-use-military-why-is-trump-keen-on-taking-control-of-greenland/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:33:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump Says He Wants No Wind Turbines Built During Administration - Energy Connects]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxOVXlVdG1NRjJMb3lzRmRWVnlkbjhNNXhvWE9nakRlSWR5WGJmems4ZnFFUjVXVWItMllEZy1KMWk1TTVrelY2MUNIUDVIOWtjOEFiZkY2eGY1cGpraC1QRXNHbnI0RUxnVlNkNFlub2lwbXVHZDNreXVqbktPdFRZT3JCVGpMb1lrcjliWmNNamc1cWVfWHhQcEo1TnVBbEQ2N1Bnal9VV2pXX1EzX3oyNGE3RHNzWXVoay1nT2IxT0pKUHM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxOVXlVdG1NRjJMb3lzRmRWVnlkbjhNNXhvWE9nakRlSWR5WGJmems4ZnFFUjVXVWItMllEZy1KMWk1TTVrelY2MUNIUDVIOWtjOEFiZkY2eGY1cGpraC1QRXNHbnI0RUxnVlNkNFlub2lwbXVHZDNreXVqbktPdFRZT3JCVGpMb1lrcjliWmNNamc1cWVfWHhQcEo1TnVBbEQ2N1Bnal9VV2pXX1EzX3oyNGE3RHNzWXVoay1nT2IxT0pKUHM?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:31:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New year brings little new hope for children in Gaza, with at least 74 children reportedly killed in first week of 2025 - UNICEF]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.unicef.org/press-releases/new-year-brings-little-new-hope-children-gaza-least-74-children-reportedly-killed</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unicef.org/press-releases/new-year-brings-little-new-hope-children-gaza-least-74-children-reportedly-killed</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:29:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New year brings little new hope for children in Gaza, with at least 74 children reportedly killed in first week of 2025 - UNICEF]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.unicef.org/press-releases/new-year-brings-little-new-hope-children-gaza-least-74-children-reportedly-killed</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unicef.org/press-releases/new-year-brings-little-new-hope-children-gaza-least-74-children-reportedly-killed</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 10:29:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Lights, car engines left on': Monster wildfire sparks panicked evacuations in Los Angeles - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Lights, car engines left on: Monster wildfire sparks panicked evacuations in Los Angeles</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] | <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>This article discusses a significant wildfire that has prompted widespread evacuations in Los Angeles, causing panic among residents as they flee the advancing flames.</p><ul><li>The wildfire has quickly spread, leading to emergency responses.</li><li>Authorities have issued evacuation orders for multiple neighborhoods.</li><li>Residents reported scenes of chaos, with people leaving their vehicles running in their haste to escape.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was terrifying; you could see the flames getting closer,” said one resident.</blockquote><p>The wildfire in Los Angeles poses a serious threat to life and property, urging immediate action from residents and responders alike.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/lights-car-engines-left-on-monster-wildfire-sparks-panicked-evacuations-in-los-angeles/articleshow/117050034.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/lights-car-engines-left-on-monster-wildfire-sparks-panicked-evacuations-in-los-angeles/articleshow/117050034.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Anita Anand replace Trudeau? the race for Canadas next PM begins - The Tribune India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>The Race for Canada's Next Prime Minister Begins After Trudeau's Resignation</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Tuesday, Date Unspecified | <strong>Source:</strong> The Tribune</p>
<p>The race to succeed Justin Trudeau as Canadian Prime Minister commenced following his resignation amid political turmoil and trade tensions with the US. The Liberal Party faces the challenge of rebuilding amidst low poll standings.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trudeau's resignation creates an opportunity for Liberal Party leadership candidates.</li>
  <li>Polls indicate the party is likely to lose upcoming elections, impacting candidate interest.</li>
  <li>Potential candidates include Chrystia Freeland, Mark Carney, Anita Anand, François-Philippe Champagne, Melanie Joly, Dominic LeBlanc, and Christy Clark.</li>
  <li>Freeland's resignation was seen as a catalyst for Trudeau stepping down.</li>
  <li>Mark Carney is perceived as a strong candidate but lacks political experience.</li>
  <li>Anita Anand has held significant cabinet roles during the pandemic and military scrutiny.</li>
  <li>Christy Clark is a notable contender with past premier experience but faces language barriers.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“As a lifelong Liberal I look forward to joining tens of thousands of Canadians to choose our next leader.” - Christy Clark</blockquote>
<p>The leadership race injects uncertainty into Canada's political landscape as the Liberal Party strives to establish new leadership before Parliament reopens in March.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/world/will-anita-anand-replace-trudeau-the-race-for-canadas-next-pm-begins/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tribuneindia.com/news/world/will-anita-anand-replace-trudeau-the-race-for-canadas-next-pm-begins/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:36:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mercedes Benz goes on rampage against teen cyclists, they corner driver and destroy car. Watch - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Teen Cyclists Assault Driver After Mercedes Benz Rampage in Los Angeles</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 08, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/08/550x309/car_1736328803639_1736328812701.png" alt="The terrifying clip shows the white car zipping past cyclists and dodging them while speeding away.(X/@NewsM101)"><figcaption>The terrifying clip shows the white car zipping past cyclists and dodging them while speeding away.(X/@NewsM101)</figcaption><p>In a troubling incident in Los Angeles, a group of teenage cyclists confronted a driver of a speeding Mercedes Benz, leading to an aggressive altercation.</p><ul><li>A Mercedes Benz driver sped through a group of cyclists, narrowly avoiding them.</li><li>Teen cyclists, angered by the driver's actions, attacked his car after he attempted to leave the scene.</li><li>The attack included vandalizing the car and smashing its windows.</li><li>Local residents reported that large groups of cyclists are common in the area, often receiving support from bystanders.</li><li>Reactions on social media were mixed, with arguments for both the driver's recklessness and the cyclists' response.</li></ul><blockquote>"Driving too hard into upcoming traffic, reckless endangerment of others." - Social media user</blockquote><p>The incident raises questions about road safety and the behavior of all parties involved, highlighting the tensions that can arise in shared road spaces.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/mercedes-benz-goes-on-rampage-against-teen-cyclists-they-corner-driver-and-destroy-car-watch-101736327550180.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/mercedes-benz-goes-on-rampage-against-teen-cyclists-they-corner-driver-and-destroy-car-watch-101736327550180.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 09:35:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Sheikh Hasina, now Khaleda Zia leaves Bangladesh...what is the reason behind her sudden decision? - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Khaleda Zia Leaves Bangladesh for Medical Treatment</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2025</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Sheikh-hasina-and-Khaleda-Zia.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="After Sheikh Hasina, now Khaleda Zia leaves Bangladesh...what is the reason behind her sudden decision?"><figcaption></figcaption><p>Former Bangladeshi Prime Minister Khaleda Zia departed for London aboard an air ambulance for medical treatment, accompanied by party leaders. Her departure adds to the political uncertainty in Bangladesh, especially with upcoming general elections.</p><ul><li>Khaleda Zia is undergoing treatment for liver cirrhosis, heart disease, and kidney issues.</li><li>Sheikh Hasina, another significant political figure, has already fled to India amid political turmoil.</li><li>The political landscape in Bangladesh is unstable with elections approaching.</li></ul><blockquote>“Bangladesh is presently grappling with political instability.”</blockquote><p>Khaleda Zia's departure could significantly impact the future of both her party and the nation's political dynamics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/after-sheikh-hasina-now-khaleda-zia-leaves-bangladesh-what-is-the-reason-behind-her-sudden-decision-7523027/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/after-sheikh-hasina-now-khaleda-zia-leaves-bangladesh-what-is-the-reason-behind-her-sudden-decision-7523027/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 08:24:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel, Turkey “Direct Confrontation”: Netanyahu Asked To Boost Military With More F-15s, Refuellers, Drones & Satellites - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel and Turkey on the Brink of Military Confrontation</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 6, 2025 | Source: Eurasian Times</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://www.eurasiantimes.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Su-57-1290-x-650-px-8.png" alt="Turkey Vs Israel" width="1290" height="650"><figcaption>Turkey Vs Israel. Edited Image.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Turkey and Israel are edging closer to direct military confrontation amidst the complexities of the Syrian civil conflict, influenced by a surge in anti-Israeli sentiment from Turkey's leadership.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Turkey has escalated its military presence in Syria, particularly targeting Kurdish groups protected by U.S. forces.</li>
  <li>The Nagel Committee warns that the threat from Syria could surpass that posed by Iran, suggesting urgent upgrades to Israel's military capabilities.</li>
  <li>Recent events following the downfall of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad further intensify tensions as both nations vie for influence in the region.</li>
  <li>Israel is advised to bolster its defense budget significantly and enhance military equipment, including acquiring more F-15 jets and advanced drones.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There is a chance of a future military confrontation between Israel and Turkey,” - Prof. Efrat Aviv.</blockquote>
<p>This report highlights the profound shifts in Middle Eastern geopolitics and emphasizes the need for strategic re-evaluations by Israel to prepare for potential hostilities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/israel-turkey-direct-confrontation-netanyahu/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/israel-turkey-direct-confrontation-netanyahu/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:19:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 political bombs Trump dropped in his marathon press conference - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>7 Political Bombs Trump Dropped in His Marathon Press Conference</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 <strong>Source:</strong> AP</p>
<img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2025/01/Trump-2025-01-1ae0f506c97203bd7a31ccde2d29cb70-1200x675.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Trump Press Conference" title="Trump Press Conference">
<figcaption>President-elect Donald Trump speaks during a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday, Jan. 7, 2025, in Palm Beach, Fla.</figcaption>
<p>In a marathon press conference in Florida, Donald Trump dropped political bombs, dismissing climate concerns and making bold claims about territorial expansion.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump expressed interest in acquiring Greenland, claiming it was in the U.S. national interest.</li>
  <li>He made provocative comments about Canada and the Panama Canal, drawing sharp rebukes from both countries.</li>
  <li>Trump threatened NATO allies and downplayed the January 6 Capitol riots.</li>
  <li>He aimed to take credit for peace talks in West Asia involving Israel and Hamas.</li>
  <li>Trump labeled climate change as a hoax and criticized the Biden administration's environmental policies.</li>
  <li>He praised Elon Musk amid controversy surrounding Musk's comments on global political issues.</li>
  <li>Trump reiterated his views on pardoning supporters related to the Capitol attack.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“All hell is going to break loose in the Middle East if they are not back before I take office.”</blockquote>
<p>The press conference exemplified Trump's characteristic rhetoric, signaling a contentious and unpredictable second term ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/world/7-political-bombs-trump-dropped-in-his-marathon-press-conference-13850916.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/world/7-political-bombs-trump-dropped-in-his-marathon-press-conference-13850916.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump’s Inauguration Day 2025: When is swearing-in ceremony? Know date, timings, tickets, venue, how to watch - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump's Inauguration Day 2025: Date, Timing, and How to Watch</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 20, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/01/Trump-at-white-house-AP.jpg?w=640" alt="Donald Trump Inauguration Day 2025" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Trump has promised several plans for the first day in office, including imposing import tariffs on Canada, Mexico, and China and pardoning the accused of January 6 Capitol Hill riots. (AP)</figcaption><p>On January 20, 2025, US President-elect Donald Trump will officially take office again, marking a significant event in American politics, coinciding with Martin Luther King Jr. Day.</p><ul><li>Inauguration Day is on January 20, 2025.</li><li>The swearing-in ceremony starts at 12 PM Eastern Time.</li><li>Tickets for the event are limited and available only through Congress members.</li><li>Inauguration Day program includes a variety of ceremonies and celebrations featuring numerous events.</li></ul><blockquote>“Tickets are free and allow you to watch in person on the grounds of the US Capitol as the president and vice president are sworn in on Jan. 20, 2025.”</blockquote><p>The event is highly anticipated, and many are eager to witness this pivotal moment in American history.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/donald-trump-inauguration-day-2025-swearing-in-ceremony-9766449/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/donald-trump-inauguration-day-2025-swearing-in-ceremony-9766449/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 07:03:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two men, dog trapped in home surrounded by Palisades Fire. Terrifying viral video - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Two Men and Dog Trapped as Palisades Fire Engulfs Home: Viral Video Sparks Concern</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Jan 8, 2025<br><strong>Source: </strong>India Today</p><img fetchpriority="high" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202501/two-men--dog-trapped-in-home-surrounded-by-palisades-fire-photo-sia-kordestanix-084907288-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=fDB0lr5GdxwF9LAkPdFO4G.PnxxBZ.oW&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Two men dog trapped in home surrounded by Palisades Fire " title="Two men, dog trapped in home surrounded by Palisades Fire (Photo: Sia Kordestani/X) " height="388"><figcaption>Two men, dog trapped in home surrounded by Palisades Fire (Photo: Sia Kordestani/X)</figcaption><p>A harrowing viral video shows two men and a dog trapped in a home engulfed by the Palisades Fire in Los Angeles, raising concerns for their safety.</p><ul><li>Massive walls of fire surrounded the house, creating a dire situation.</li><li>Social media users expressed confusion as to why the group did not evacuate earlier.</li><li>Updates confirmed that the men and the dog were able to safely evacuate.</li><li>The wildfire has prompted mandatory evacuations for over 30,000 residents in the Pacific Palisades area.</li></ul><blockquote>This is by far the craziest video from the fire in Los Angeles. This guy is filming huge walls of fire surrounding a house they're in, and there's another person and a dog. I have no idea why they didn't evacuate or what happened to them. Let's hope they're okay. — Sia Kordestani (@SiaKordestani) January 8, 2025</blockquote><p>This incident highlights the dangers faced by residents as massive wildfires threaten their homes and safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/trending-news/story/two-men-dog-trapped-in-home-surrounded-by-palisades-fire-terrifying-viral-video-2661415-2025-01-08</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/trending-news/story/two-men-dog-trapped-in-home-surrounded-by-palisades-fire-terrifying-viral-video-2661415-2025-01-08</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 06:54:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>