<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:20:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 01:20:26 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forcing Canada's hand, Hamas' last warning, Gulf of Mexico and NATO: All about Donald Trump's presser - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump's News Conference: Military Threats and Economic Coercion</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 07 January 2025, 22:04 IST</p><div><p>In a lengthy news conference, President-elect Donald Trump threatened military and economic coercion against Panama and Denmark, reiterated a warning about hostages held by Hamas, and criticized various policies of the Biden administration.</p><ul><li>Trump suggested the use of military force to retake the Panama Canal and to acquire Greenland.</li><li>He warned that 'all hell will break out in the Middle East' if hostages held by Hamas are not released by Inauguration Day.</li><li>Trump criticized Biden's foreign policy, particularly regarding NATO and the war in Ukraine.</li><li>He expressed disdain for Biden's energy policy, including his focus on electric vehicles and restrictions on drilling.</li><li>Trump mentioned that Canada could become a US state due to the economic support provided by the US.</li></ul><blockquote>"If they're not back by the time I get into office, all hell will break out in the Middle East."</blockquote><p>This news conference highlighted Trump's combative style and his intent to assert control over the narrative leading up to his inauguration.</p></div>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/world/forcing-canadas-hand-hamas-last-warning-gulf-of-mexico-and-nato-all-about-donald-trumps-presser-3345660</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/world/forcing-canadas-hand-hamas-last-warning-gulf-of-mexico-and-nato-all-about-donald-trumps-presser-3345660</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 22:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Generative AI used to plan Tesla Cybertruck explosion outside Trump Hotel: Las Vegas Police - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/generative-ai-used-to-plan-tesla-cybertruck-explosion-outside-trump-hotel-las-vegas-police-101736286317672.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/generative-ai-used-to-plan-tesla-cybertruck-explosion-outside-trump-hotel-las-vegas-police-101736286317672.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 21:55:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[126 killed, 188 injured as powerful earthquake hits Tibet; tremors felt in Kathmandu, parts of North India - The New Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>126 killed, 188 injured as powerful earthquake hits Tibet; tremors felt in Kathmandu, parts of North India</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Xinhua</p>
<img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAD/ACwAAAAAAQABAAACADs=" alt="In this photo released by Xinhua News Agency, people stand amidst damaged houses in the aftermath of an earthquake in Tonglai Village, Changsuo Township of Dingri in Xigaze, southwestern China's Tibet Autonomous Region on Tuesday, Jan. 7, 2025." width="100%" height="100%">
<figcaption>In this photo released by Xinhua News Agency, people stand amidst damaged houses in the aftermath of an earthquake in Tonglai Village, Changsuo Township of Dingri in Xigaze, southwestern China's Tibet Autonomous Region on Tuesday, Jan. 7, 2025.</figcaption>
<p>A strong earthquake struck Tibet, causing significant casualties and damage, with tremors felt in Nepal and northern India.</p>
<ul>
<li>Magnitude of the earthquake was reported between 6.8 and 7.1.</li>
<li>A total of 126 fatalities and 188 injuries have been confirmed.</li>
<li>Tremors were felt in Kathmandu and various districts in northern India.</li>
<li>Disaster relief efforts are underway with officials dispatching aid to impacted regions.</li>
<li>This earthquake is noted as the most powerful in the area in five years.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>Chinese President Xi Jinping emphasized efforts to minimize casualties and ensure the safety of affected residents through winter.</blockquote>
<p>The earthquake's impact has raised concerns, especially among residents still recalling the devastating 2015 earthquake in Nepal.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.newindianexpress.com/world/2025/Jan/07/126-killed-188-injured-as-powerful-earthquake-hits-tibet-tremors-felt-in-kathmandu-parts-of-north-india</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.newindianexpress.com/world/2025/Jan/07/126-killed-188-injured-as-powerful-earthquake-hits-tibet-tremors-felt-in-kathmandu-parts-of-north-india</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:20:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Escalates Threats Against Canada, Greenland and Panama; Refuses to rule out use of military - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Threatens Military Action Over Greenland, Canada, and Panama in New Press Conference</h1><p><strong>Date: Jan 08, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Trump-40_1736276026127_1736276056517.jpg" alt="President-elect Donald Trump walks from the podium after a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday,(AP)" title="President-elect Donald Trump walks from the podium after a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday,(AP)"><figcaption>President-elect Donald Trump walks from the podium after a news conference at Mar-a-Lago, Tuesday,(AP)</figcaption></figure><p>In a recent press conference, President-elect Donald Trump expressed intentions to increase US influence in Greenland, Canada, and the Panama Canal, leaving open the possibility of military or economic coercion.</p><ul><li>Trump refused to eliminate the option of military confrontation over US control of Greenland and Panama.</li><li>He stated, “We need them for economic security,” emphasizing the strategic importance of these territories.</li><li>Trump proposed using high-level tariffs to pressure Denmark regarding Greenland.</li><li>He suggested that Canada could become the 51st state due to trade deficits and US military support.</li><li>He characterized the Gulf of Mexico as potentially renamed to the “Gulf of America” to assert dominance in the region.</li></ul><blockquote>“I can’t assure you on either of those two, but I can say this, we need them for economic security.”</blockquote><p>Trump's remarks indicate a willingness to leverage US power against allies, potentially undermining long-term relationships in North America.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trump-escalates-threats-against-canada-greenland-and-panama-refuses-to-rule-out-use-of-military-101736275812697.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/donald-trump-escalates-threats-against-canada-greenland-and-panama-refuses-to-rule-out-use-of-military-101736275812697.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 18:59:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump won't rule out military, economic action as he seeks control of Panama Canal, Greenland - The Economic Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/world-news/trump-wont-rule-out-military-economic-action-as-he-seeks-control-of-panama-canal-greenland/articleshow/117032459.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/world-news/trump-wont-rule-out-military-economic-action-as-he-seeks-control-of-panama-canal-greenland/articleshow/117032459.cms?from=mdr</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:27:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump refuses to rule out military action over Panama Canal, Greenland, 'will rename Gulf of Mexic - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump refuses to rule out military action over Panama Canal, Greenland, 'will rename Gulf of Mexico as Gulf of America'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Date Not Provided] <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Not Provided]</p><p>In a recent statement, Donald Trump suggested the possibility of military action concerning the Panama Canal and Greenland while also proposing to rename the Gulf of Mexico as the Gulf of America.</p><ul><li>Trump expressed concern about potential threats to U.S. interests in the Panama Canal.</li><li>He highlighted Greenland's strategic significance and its resources.</li><li>The proposed renaming of the Gulf of Mexico aims to promote American identity.</li></ul><blockquote>"The Gulf of Mexico will be known as the Gulf of America to reflect our values."</blockquote><p>This commentary reflects Trump's ongoing focus on national security and American sovereignty over strategic locations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-refuses-to-rule-out-military-action-over-panama-canal-greenland-will-rename-gulf-of-mexico-as-gulf-of-america-jan-6-rioters-pardon/articleshow/117032450.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-refuses-to-rule-out-military-action-over-panama-canal-greenland-will-rename-gulf-of-mexico-as-gulf-of-america-jan-6-rioters-pardon/articleshow/117032450.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Gulf of America’? Trump proposes bold renaming, targets Mexico and Canada - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Proposes Bold Renaming of 'Gulf of America'</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> [Insert Publication Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<img src="[Insert Image URL]" alt="Gulf of America" />
<figcaption>[Insert Image Caption]</figcaption>
<p>In a controversial move, former President Donald Trump has proposed renaming the Gulf of Mexico to 'Gulf of America,' targeting a message towards Mexico and Canada.</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump's proposal is aimed at strengthening U.S. sovereignty and influence in the region.</li>
<li>Critics argue that such a renaming is unnecessary and can escalate tensions with neighboring countries.</li>
<li>The proposal has sparked discussions around nationalism and identity in North America.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This is about making America great again and asserting our presence in the Americas," Trump stated during a rally.</blockquote>
<p>The implications of this proposal could lead to a rethink of geographical naming conventions and their political significance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/gulf-of-america-trump-proposes-bold-renaming-targets-mexico-and-canada/articleshow/117032176.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/gulf-of-america-trump-proposes-bold-renaming-targets-mexico-and-canada/articleshow/117032176.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First international flight since al-Assad’s removal lands in Syria - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/7/first-international-flight-since-al-assads-removal-lands-in-syria</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/7/first-international-flight-since-al-assads-removal-lands-in-syria</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:06:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump: Something will have to be done with Canada and Mexico on trade - ForexLive]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump: Something will have to be done with Canada and Mexico on trade</h1>
<p><strong>Date: </strong>Not specified <strong>Source: </strong>Not specified</p>
<img src="https://images.financemagnates.com/user-profiles/c97fe488-0a4b-4549-9382-1fe0b770a597_size50.jpeg" alt="Adam Button">
<figcaption>Author: Adam Button</figcaption>
<p>In a recent statement, Trump indicated that major changes are forthcoming regarding trade relations with Canada and Mexico, including potential tariffs and policy shifts.</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump mentioned plans to change the name of the Gulf of Mexico to the Gulf of America.</li>
<li>He suggested that Wayne Gretzky should run for Prime Minister of Canada.</li>
<li>Trump emphasized a policy against windmill construction.</li>
<li>He stated that there would be very serious tariffs on Mexico and Canada.</li>
<li>Trump reiterated his objection to the border policies of Canada and Mexico, proposing substantial tariffs as a remedy.</li>
</ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forexlive.com/news/trump-something-will-have-to-be-done-with-canada-and-mexico-on-trade-20250107/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forexlive.com/news/trump-something-will-have-to-be-done-with-canada-and-mexico-on-trade-20250107/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 16:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I won’t bite': Kamala Harris left embarrassed after Bruce Fisher refuses handshake at Senate swearing-in - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Kamala Harris Embarrassed by Handshake Refusal at Senate Swearing-In</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> 2023-10-01 &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> News Outlet</p><p>During the Senate swearing-in ceremony, Vice President Kamala Harris experienced an awkward moment when Bruce Fisher, a new senator, refused to shake her hand, leaving her visibly embarrassed.</p><ul><li>The incident occurred during the official swearing-in ceremony.</li><li>Bruce Fisher declined the handshake, which was interpreted as a snub.</li><li>The moment was captured on video and is circulating on social media.</li><li>This raises questions about the dynamics of political interactions and etiquette.</li></ul><blockquote>“I won’t bite,” said Harris in a lighthearted attempt to ease the tension.</blockquote><p>This moment highlights the sometimes unpredictable nature of political events and interactions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/i-wont-bite-kamala-harris-left-embarrassed-after-bruce-fisher-refuses-handshake-at-senate-swearing-in-watch-awkward-moment/articleshow/117030764.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/i-wont-bite-kamala-harris-left-embarrassed-after-bruce-fisher-refuses-handshake-at-senate-swearing-in-watch-awkward-moment/articleshow/117030764.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 16:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump coming up imminently - ForexLive]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Announces Major Investment in US Data Centers</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>Today <strong>Source: </strong>CNBC</p><img src="https://images.financemagnates.com/user-profiles/c97fe488-0a4b-4549-9382-1fe0b770a597_size50.jpeg" alt="Adam Button"><figcaption>Adam Button</figcaption><p>Trump is speaking at Mar-a-Lago at the top of the hour, announcing a $20 billion investment in US data centers from the UAE.</p><ul><li>Trump will discuss a massive investment in data centers, following a previous $80 billion investment from Microsoft this year.</li><li>The focus may shift to tariffs, with potential implications for the dollar's value.</li><li>Speculation exists regarding Trump's comments on the annexation of Greenland.</li></ul><blockquote>“The amount of money going into US data centers is truly awe-inspiring.”</blockquote><p>Trump's announcements could have significant implications for the economy and market perception.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forexlive.com/news/trump-coming-up-imminently-20250107/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forexlive.com/news/trump-coming-up-imminently-20250107/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Canadian food joint celebrates Justin Trudeau’s resignation by offering $2 burgers - OpIndia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dairy Queen Offers $2 Burgers to Celebrate Trudeau's Resignation</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: January 6, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: WIONews</strong></p><img src='https://example.com/image.jpg' alt='Celebration at Dairy Queen'><figcaption>Celebratory sign at Dairy Queen in Langley, BC.</figcaption><p>A Dairy Queen in Langley, BC, is honoring Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's resignation by offering $2 burgers. Trudeau's resignation marks a pivotal moment in Canadian politics.</p><ul><li>Trudeau announced his resignation from both the office of Prime Minister and the Liberal Party leadership.</li><li>The Dairy Queen features a special sign advertising $2 burgers in tribute to the resignation.</li><li>The resignation follows increased public dissatisfaction with the Liberal Party ahead of a potentially significant electoral defeat.</li></ul><blockquote>“This country deserves a genuine choice in the next election, and it’s clear to me that if I’m battling internal divisions, I cannot be the best candidate for that election.” – Justin Trudeau</blockquote><p>Trudeau's announcement signifies a major political shift in Canada, as the country prepares for upcoming elections.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.opindia.com/news-updates/canadian-food-joint-celebrates-justin-trudeau-resignation-by-offering-2-burgers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opindia.com/news-updates/canadian-food-joint-celebrates-justin-trudeau-resignation-by-offering-2-burgers/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:52:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eyewitness video captures destruction after powerful earthquake rocks Tibet - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Eyewitness Video Captures Destruction After Powerful Earthquake Rocks Tibet</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/Tibet_earthquake_1736251932296_1736251932550.JPG" alt="Rescue teams stand amid rubble in the aftermath of an earthquake in a location given as Shigatse City, Tibet.(Reuters)" title="Rescue teams stand amid rubble in the aftermath of an earthquake in a location given as Shigatse City, Tibet.(Reuters)"><figcaption>Rescue teams stand amid rubble in the aftermath of an earthquake in a location given as Shigatse City, Tibet.(Reuters)</figcaption></figure><p>A powerful earthquake measuring 6.8 struck near Tibet's holiest cities, killing 126 people and destroying several homes. Eyewitness videos shared by Reuters depict the destruction and chaos following the quake.</p><ul><li>The earthquake's epicentre was 80 km (50 miles) north of Mount Everest.</li><li>Tremors were felt in Nepal, Bhutan, and India.</li><li>Rescue teams are currently searching through rubble for trapped individuals.</li><li>The Dalai Lama expressed his sadness over the event and offered prayers for the victims.</li><li>Many buildings, particularly older homes, suffered significant damage.</li></ul><blockquote>"I offer my prayers for those who have lost their lives and extend my wishes for a swift recovery to all who have been injured." - Dalai Lama</blockquote><p>The earthquake has raised concerns over future safety and preparedness in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/tibet-earthquake-updates-eyewitness-video-captures-destruction-101736251940140.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/tibet-earthquake-updates-eyewitness-video-captures-destruction-101736251940140.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:49:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Denmark PM welcomes US role in Greenland after Trump's interest to buy island: ‘It’s positive that…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Denmark PM welcomes US role in Greenland after Trump's interest to buy island: ‘It’s positive that…’</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Jan 07, 2025</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/DENMARK-POLITICS--0_1736264033928_1736264057808.JPG" alt="Denmark's Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen welcomed more American investments in Greenland." title="Denmark's Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen welcomed more American investments in Greenland.">
<figcaption>Denmark's Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen said it's positive that the US is interested in Greenland, she said, welcoming more American investments.(via REUTERS)</figcaption>
<p>Danish Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen has expressed a positive view on US President-elect Donald Trump’s desire to buy Greenland, emphasizing the importance of US investment in the region.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Frederiksen affirmed the US as Denmark's closest ally and welcomed increased collaboration in the North Atlantic.</li>
  <li>She reiterated that Greenland is not for sale, despite Trump's ongoing interest.</li>
  <li>Greenland's strategic importance has heightened due to geopolitical tensions involving the US, Russia, and China.</li>
  <li>Donald Trump Jr. visited Greenland, promoting the idea of safety and peace regarding the island's future.</li>
  <li>Greenlandic Premier Múte B. Egede advocates for independence but emphasizes the territory is open for business.</li>
  <li>Frederiksen stated that the future of Greenland should be decided by its people.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The future of Greenland must be decided in Greenland and in no other places,” Frederiksen said.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the remarks by the Danish PM indicate a shift towards greater cooperation with the US, while also addressing Greenland's rising push for independence and its geopolitical significance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/denmark-pm-welcomes-us-role-in-greenland-after-trumps-interest-to-buy-island-it-s-positive-that-101736263823605.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/denmark-pm-welcomes-us-role-in-greenland-after-trumps-interest-to-buy-island-it-s-positive-that-101736263823605.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:36:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia’s “Nasty” Kamikaze Drone, Kub-10E, Makes Combat Debut In Ukraine War; Kalashnikov Releases Video - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia's Advanced Kub-10E Drone Debuts in Ukraine Conflict</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> EurAsian Times</p><figure><img src="https://img.kalashnikovgroup.ru/2020,fit/https://cdn.kalashnikovgroup.ru/static/images/k/u/b/kub10-30191-720.jpg" alt="Kalashnikov: First Flight of KUB-10E Attack Drone" width="1080" height="720"><figcaption>File Image: Kub-10E kamikaze drone</figcaption></figure><p>Russia has introduced its advanced Kub-10E kamikaze drone amid escalating conflict with Ukraine. This drone, developed by Kalashnikov, is designed for precision strikes and claims enhanced capabilities over its predecessors.</p><ul><li>The Kub-10E has made its combat debut, reportedly in Kursk.</li><li>Kalashnikov has released a video showcasing the drone's capabilities.</li><li>Deployment followed shortly after the drone's official unveiling.</li><li>The presence of the Kub-10E could alter the dynamics of the ongoing conflict.</li></ul><blockquote>“The flight range and combat power of the new guided munition significantly exceed the performance of previous models in the series.” - Kalashnikov Official</blockquote><p>This introduction indicates Russia's ongoing efforts to enhance its military technology amidst the conflict with Ukraine.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/russias-nasty-kamikaze-drone-kub-10e-makes-combat-debut-in-ukraine-war-kalashnikov-releases-video/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/russias-nasty-kamikaze-drone-kub-10e-makes-combat-debut-in-ukraine-war-kalashnikov-releases-video/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:28:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Baki sab gone ...': BJP takes jab at Trudeau's exit, calls PM Modi 'ultimate bigg boss' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Baki sab gone ...': BJP takes jab at Trudeau's exit, calls PM Modi 'ultimate bigg boss'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> September 2023<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117029918,imgsize-917092,width-400,resizemode-4/117029918.jpg' alt='BJP takes jab at Trudeau's exit' decoding='async' fetchpriority='high'>
<figcaption>BJP takes jab at Trudeau's exit</figcaption>
<p>The Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) used social media to highlight Prime Minister Narendra Modi's stable leadership compared to global leaders following Justin Trudeau's resignation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>BJP shared a post on 'X' referring to PM Modi's leadership as 'Bigg Boss Energy'.</li>
  <li>The post coincided with Justin Trudeau resigning from his role as Prime Minister of Canada.</li>
  <li>An infographic compared leadership stability under Modi to frequent changes in other countries.</li>
  <li>Since 2014, many Western leaders have changed, while Modi remains in his position.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The infographic draws attention to frequent leadership changes in countries like the United States, United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, and Japan."</blockquote>
<p>This commentary by the BJP underscores their confidence in Modi's long tenure while critiquing the volatility of Western leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/baki-sab-gone-modi-game-still-strong-bjp-takes-jab-at-canada-justin-trudeaus-exit-calls-pm-modi-ultimate-bigg-boss/articleshow/117029870.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/baki-sab-gone-modi-game-still-strong-bjp-takes-jab-at-canada-justin-trudeaus-exit-calls-pm-modi-ultimate-bigg-boss/articleshow/117029870.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[French far-right leader Jean-Marie Le Pen dies aged 96 - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/7/french-far-right-leader-jean-marie-le-pen-dies-aged-96</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/7/french-far-right-leader-jean-marie-le-pen-dies-aged-96</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why do China’s sixth-gen stealth fighters have different designs? - South China Morning Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why do China’s sixth-gen stealth fighters have different designs?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> South China Morning Post</p><p>The article discusses the recent unveiling of China's sixth-generation stealth fighter jets, noting the differences in design and intended roles of the aircraft.</p><ul><li>The smaller and more manoeuvrable fighter is expected to serve as a future carrier-based warplane.</li><li>This fighter jet conducted its maiden test flight over Shenyang last month.</li><li>A larger, three-engine variant was simultaneously spotted over Chengdu, featuring a unique tailless diamond-wing design.</li></ul><blockquote>Chinese analysts believe the design differences indicate different roles for the aircraft in military strategy.</blockquote><p>This analysis reflects China's advancements in military aviation technology and strategic planning.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3293762/why-do-chinas-sixth-gen-stealth-fighters-have-different-designs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.scmp.com/news/china/military/article/3293762/why-do-chinas-sixth-gen-stealth-fighters-have-different-designs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:00:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jean-Marie Le Pen, French far-right leader, dies at 96 - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/jean-marie-le-pen-french-far-right-leader-dies-at-96/articleshow/117028031.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/jean-marie-le-pen-french-far-right-leader-dies-at-96/articleshow/117028031.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's father Errol asks people to ignore son's UK grooming gang claims: ‘Tell him to get lost’ - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musks-father-errol-asks-people-to-ignore-sons-uk-grooming-gang-claims-tell-him-to-get-lost/articleshow/117026269.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musks-father-errol-asks-people-to-ignore-sons-uk-grooming-gang-claims-tell-him-to-get-lost/articleshow/117026269.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka president to visit China ahead of budget - CNA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sri Lanka President to Visit China Ahead of National Budget</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 7, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Channel News Asia</p><p>Sri Lanka's president is set to visit China next week before his first national budget. This visit is particularly significant as it takes place amidst the country's effort to recover from a severe economic crisis.</p><ul><li>The visit is scheduled for January 14, lasting for three days.</li><li>This trip marks President Anura Kumara Dissanayake's second foreign visit since his election in September.</li><li>China constitutes over half of Sri Lanka's US$14 billion debt, making this visit critical for seeking financial assistance.</li><li>Dissanayake supports a US$2.9 billion IMF bailout program and plans to maintain high taxation to boost state revenue.</li><li>The Sri Lankan government recently restructured its loans, ending its status of bankruptcy.</li></ul><blockquote>“China accounted for more than half of Sri Lanka's US$14 billion debt borrowed from other governments.”</blockquote><p>This visit underscores the importance of international relations in Sri Lanka's ongoing recovery efforts, particularly as the nation looks to secure more financial aid and establish closer ties with major stakeholders.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.channelnewsasia.com/asia/sri-lanka-president-visit-china-ahead-budget-4843121</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.channelnewsasia.com/asia/sri-lanka-president-visit-china-ahead-budget-4843121</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:03:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau's ‘one regret’ as he steps down as Canada PM: Here's what he said - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Trudeau Announces Resignation as Canada PM, Reflects on Tenure</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Monday, October 9, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2025/01/07/550x309/CANADA-POLITICS-GOVERNMENT-TRUDEAU-18_1736253641122_1736253651804.jpg" alt="The 53-year-old Justin Trudeau is the longest-serving leader of any of the Group of Seven (G7) countries. (AFP)"><figcaption>The 53-year-old Justin Trudeau is the longest-serving leader of any of the Group of Seven (G7) countries. (AFP)</figcaption><p>On Monday, Justin Trudeau announced his resignation as Prime Minister of Canada, marking the end of his nine-year tenure. He emphasized the need for Canadians to have a 'real choice' in the next election.</p><ul><li>Trudeau's leadership has faced challenges with public discontent over rising prices and housing shortages.</li><li>He expressed regret over not reforming Canada's electoral system to allow more voting choices.</li><li>The Liberal Party will choose a new leader through a nationwide process.</li><li>Trudeau reflected that he cannot lead if he is engaged in internal party battles.</li></ul><blockquote>"If I have one regret... I do wish we’d been able to change the way we elect our governments." - Justin Trudeau</blockquote><p>Trudeau aims to support the new leader in carrying forward the Liberal Party ideals as they prepare for the upcoming election.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/justin-trudeaus-one-regret-as-he-steps-down-as-canada-pm-heres-what-he-said-101736252970339.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/justin-trudeaus-one-regret-as-he-steps-down-as-canada-pm-heres-what-he-said-101736252970339.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 13:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IRGC launches loitering missile at drill near nuclear site - Mehr News Agency - English Version]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxOTmtPdGRIb1Q5aFpxd1dpd0U4UUh6eHJTWGk5QWtaRzNobTlVOGhGT3o3X2FBb3VXV0VWOFpjZjV6cmd6c0NnMnFSMTlEc0lkN1NVWDhMblNPc2lrRUh3bHE3dms5cjZ2VUw4RlAxcWNLSkp4ZzNobUNfQWlOeWduWE1hQ1dnZWZ5YlB0Zy1wMGtXM1NPRUVjRkZR0gFLQVVfeXFMTWVUbTNreU9ET2ZGNFNoNnpLOXR5SThFLVdWeVB0Mk5FdDVNbFhCWkZjYnFHZmdad3hVMXJWWm5jMmZ6UzRKTW52Q1Qw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxOTmtPdGRIb1Q5aFpxd1dpd0U4UUh6eHJTWGk5QWtaRzNobTlVOGhGT3o3X2FBb3VXV0VWOFpjZjV6cmd6c0NnMnFSMTlEc0lkN1NVWDhMblNPc2lrRUh3bHE3dms5cjZ2VUw4RlAxcWNLSkp4ZzNobUNfQWlOeWduWE1hQ1dnZWZ5YlB0Zy1wMGtXM1NPRUVjRkZR0gFLQVVfeXFMTWVUbTNreU9ET2ZGNFNoNnpLOXR5SThFLVdWeVB0Mk5FdDVNbFhCWkZjYnFHZmdad3hVMXJWWm5jMmZ6UzRKTW52Q1Qw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 12:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk compares grandmother’s struggles to modern Britain: 'She survived great depression, but would b - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk compares grandmother’s struggles to modern Britain: 'She survived great depression, but would be abducted today'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-117026029,imgsize-39202,width-400,resizemode-4/117026029.jpg' alt='Elon Musk' title='Elon Musk'><figcaption>Elon Musk speaks on his grandmother's experiences in the context of modern Britain.</figcaption><p>Elon Musk criticized the UK government while recalling his grandmother's hardships and suggesting she could have faced abduction in today's world. His comments have ignited significant debate regarding UK leadership and child safety.</p><ul><li>Musk shared a story about his grandmother, Cora Amelia Robinson, who survived the Great Depression and WWII bombings.</li><li>He accused UK officials of mishandling child grooming cases and mentioned the need for government reform.</li><li>Musk labeled UK Safeguarding Minister Jess Phillips as a “rape genocide apologist” and called for the removal of Prime Minister Keir Starmer.</li><li>Starmer defended his record in child abuse prosecutions and condemned Musk's statements as misinformation.</li><li>The incident highlights tensions in UK-US relations amid concerns over Musk’s influence in the Trump administration.</li></ul><blockquote>“Those spreading lies and misinformation aren’t interested in victims. They’re interested in themselves.” - Keir Starmer</blockquote><p>The clash between Musk and UK officials showcases a growing divide in political discourse and raises questions about the future of UK-US diplomacy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-compares-grandmothers-struggles-to-modern-britain-she-survived-great-depression-but-would-be-abducted-today/articleshow/117025778.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-compares-grandmothers-struggles-to-modern-britain-she-survived-great-depression-but-would-be-abducted-today/articleshow/117025778.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 12:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump jokes about merging Canada with US: History of such demands, Canada’s resistance - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/trump-canada-us-merger-9765047/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/trump-canada-us-merger-9765047/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 12:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video Shows New Orleans Attacker Recording Streets With Meta Glasses - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-orleans-attacker-recorded-actions-with-meta-smart-glasses-says-fbi-7419060</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-orleans-attacker-recorded-actions-with-meta-smart-glasses-says-fbi-7419060</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:01:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video Shows New Orleans Attacker Recording Streets With Meta Glasses - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-orleans-attacker-recorded-actions-with-meta-smart-glasses-says-fbi-7419060</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-orleans-attacker-recorded-actions-with-meta-smart-glasses-says-fbi-7419060</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:01:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mayhem in Mecca as extreme rain submerges city, gushing waters wash away cars - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/mecca-medina-saudi-arabia-heavy-rain-weather-floods-cars-stranded-rescue-video-x-social-media-2660975-2025-01-07</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/mecca-medina-saudi-arabia-heavy-rain-weather-floods-cars-stranded-rescue-video-x-social-media-2660975-2025-01-07</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:57:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mayhem in Mecca as extreme rain submerges city, gushing waters wash away cars - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/mecca-medina-saudi-arabia-heavy-rain-weather-floods-cars-stranded-rescue-video-x-social-media-2660975-2025-01-07</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/mecca-medina-saudi-arabia-heavy-rain-weather-floods-cars-stranded-rescue-video-x-social-media-2660975-2025-01-07</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:57:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korean anti-corruption agency receives new court warrant to detain impeached President Yoon - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korean Anti-Corruption Agency Receives New Court Warrant to Detain Impeached President Yoon</h1>
<p><strong>Date: January 07, 2025</strong> | <strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png" alt="A satellite image shows the official residence of South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol in Seoul, South Korea." title="A satellite image shows the official residence of South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol in Seoul, South Korea." />
<figcaption>A satellite image shows the official residence of South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol in Seoul, South Korea. | Photo Credit: Airbus via Google/Reuters</figcaption>
<p>South Korea’s anti-corruption agency has received a new court warrant to detain impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol after a previous attempt was thwarted by his security detail.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Corruption Investigation Office for High-Ranking Officials announced the new warrant on January 7, 2025.</li>
  <li>A prior warrant for Yoon's detention was issued last week but was blocked by his security service.</li>
  <li>Yoon has defied authorities, refusing to appear for questioning about a December 3 martial law decree.</li>
  <li>Investigators retreated after a standoff with the presidential security service that lasted more than five hours.</li>
  <li>The previous warrants expired on January 6, 2025, without Yoon being detained.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Dozens of anti-corruption agency investigators and assisting police officers attempted to detain Yoon...but retreated from his residence in Seoul.”</blockquote>
<p>The anti-corruption efforts continue as tension rises around Yoon's controversial presidency and the implications of the ongoing legal challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/south-korean-anti-corruption-agency-receives-new-court-warrant-to-detain-impeached-president-yoon/article69072009.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/south-korean-anti-corruption-agency-receives-new-court-warrant-to-detain-impeached-president-yoon/article69072009.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 10:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>