<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 15:25:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 15:25:44 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CNN's 'prisoner' from Syrian facility was torturer for Assad regime: Local fact-checker - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>CNN's 'prisoner' from Syrian facility was torturer for Assad regime: Local fact-checker</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src='https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms' alt='TOI logo' width='300' height='24'>
<figcaption>Image Source: Times of India</figcaption>
<p>A recent fact-check has unveiled that a man presented by CNN as a prisoner from a Syrian facility is actually a known torturer for the Assad regime. This revelation has ignited discussions about media integrity and the portrayal of individuals in conflict zones.</p>
<ul>
<li>The individual in question was highlighted in a CNN report.</li>
<li>Local fact-checkers found significant evidence of his involvement in torture.</li>
<li>This exposes potential lapses in the verification processes of major news organizations.</li>
<li>Consequences of misleading narratives on public perception and policy decisions are highlighted.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Misinformation in war can fuel further violence and suffering." - Local Fact-Checker</blockquote>
<p>The exposure of the man's true identity emphasizes the importance of rigorous fact-checking in journalism, especially in sensitive and volatile regions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/cnns-prisoner-from-syrian-prison-was-torturer-for-assad-regime/articleshow/116372777.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/cnns-prisoner-from-syrian-prison-was-torturer-for-assad-regime/articleshow/116372777.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Indians found dead at restaurant in Georgia's mountain resort of Gudauri: Indian Mission - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxPVHZiUzZXcnBPektwbHdvNng5aVJmSnlIb2FQSmYwVGlORWxjcnFkVUktbHMzZDZjVU9OSDBGRjYwcklnWUQ3OTJXandyV05rbmdOR0Z4V2ZWdjdjN3NNRDhITHo5eFk1T0xBaXdyMnJOZjJONFBSYjFDMXliY0dRWWVUUV9yZGdEbmZuYVpsRkxJUTJsUFZ2VU12OFF3RjFGN2JWc1J6aURZLTdDWno4RC1wc1VQaHpJYjV1dFlIa3dvX0dmV1NkOElkTWp5eDdfS0RfTTRtbjFEbWlyS0dleU130gHoAUFVX3lxTE4wMUNvRUJXeHdMTjFuUmZicmJDcDZWZkIzeWZGbEdneUY1ellVRWowVTM5aVYtZW1SLVd4ZEhuZnFBdTVKcVk4NDZxY1R0S0d3MXB5UTBBR1BpNHdSTk14aEJNWUpYQ3paWjZEdWNWSVpwVFREalZwLUFmQzY2WExnU0VsMVlWQ1pycVF3aDFfMXlsNDgtQ1J4dk93ZTE0YUl6eks0MzFIUU5BZEdWdUxaV29MVTE3TkVoNUVjNkgwQlJseWxZRE1pSDdFekJYYnl1Q1ZKSDcwZk9aMHBYaVNwanhMck9uSjE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi4gFBVV95cUxPVHZiUzZXcnBPektwbHdvNng5aVJmSnlIb2FQSmYwVGlORWxjcnFkVUktbHMzZDZjVU9OSDBGRjYwcklnWUQ3OTJXandyV05rbmdOR0Z4V2ZWdjdjN3NNRDhITHo5eFk1T0xBaXdyMnJOZjJONFBSYjFDMXliY0dRWWVUUV9yZGdEbmZuYVpsRkxJUTJsUFZ2VU12OFF3RjFGN2JWc1J6aURZLTdDWno4RC1wc1VQaHpJYjV1dFlIa3dvX0dmV1NkOElkTWp5eDdfS0RfTTRtbjFEbWlyS0dleU130gHoAUFVX3lxTE4wMUNvRUJXeHdMTjFuUmZicmJDcDZWZkIzeWZGbEdneUY1ellVRWowVTM5aVYtZW1SLVd4ZEhuZnFBdTVKcVk4NDZxY1R0S0d3MXB5UTBBR1BpNHdSTk14aEJNWUpYQ3paWjZEdWNWSVpwVFREalZwLUFmQzY2WExnU0VsMVlWQ1pycVF3aDFfMXlsNDgtQ1J4dk93ZTE0YUl6eks0MzFIUU5BZEdWdUxaV29MVTE3TkVoNUVjNkgwQlJseWxZRE1pSDdFekJYYnl1Q1ZKSDcwZk9aMHBYaVNwanhMck9uSjE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ousted Syrian leader Assad says he had planned to keep fighting but Russians evacuated him - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/ousted-syrian-leader-assad-says-he-had-planned-to-keep-fighting-but-the-russians-evacuated-him/articleshow/116371578.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/ousted-syrian-leader-assad-says-he-had-planned-to-keep-fighting-but-the-russians-evacuated-him/articleshow/116371578.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza war: Hamas-run ministry says Israeli strikes kill 50 - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel-Gaza war: Hamas-run ministry says Israeli strikes kill 50</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> BBC News</p>
<img src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/480/cpsprodpb/ebb6/live/161c69d0-bbaa-11ef-acb0-1fafa3fb8111.jpg.webp" alt="AFP Palestinians inspect damage following an Israeli air strike on a school housing displaced families in Khan Younis, southern Gaza (16 December 2024)">
<figcaption>Many of those killed on Sunday were in a school-turned-shelter in the southern city of Khan Younis.</figcaption>
<p>More than 50 people were killed in Israeli attacks across the Gaza Strip, with reports including children and a journalist among the deceased. The ongoing violence has brought the total Palestinian death toll to over 45,000 since the conflict began.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Israeli attacks targeted sites associated with Hamas and Palestinian Islamic Jihad.</li>
  <li>Casualties included a cameraman from Al Jazeera and members of the Civil Defence agency.</li>
  <li>The death toll from the war has been controversial, with different figures reported by Hamas and the Israeli government.</li>
  <li>The attacks included strikes on a UN-run school serving as a shelter for displaced families.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"People were safe, staying in their homes after they prayed the dinner prayer. They were sitting, sleeping, and staying put in their places." - Manal Tafesh</blockquote>
<p>The humanitarian situation in Gaza is dire, exacerbated by continuous strikes and widespread displacement among civilians. The conflict shows no signs of abating, raising serious concerns about the protection of civilians and humanitarian workers.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0rnvy1zn10o</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0rnvy1zn10o</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:18:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Istanbul Airport Beats Rivals to Become Busiest Airport in Europe - Aviation A2z]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://aviationa2z.com/index.php/2024/12/16/istanbul-busiest-airport-in-europe/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://aviationa2z.com/index.php/2024/12/16/istanbul-busiest-airport-in-europe/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:56:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Istanbul death toll from tainted alcohol jumps to 37: governor - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Istanbul Death Toll from Tainted Alcohol Rises to 37</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>December 4, 2023</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Governor's Office</p><p>The death toll from tainted alcohol in Istanbul has increased to 37, with 17 others still in treatment. A total of 77 individuals have been poisoned since November 1.</p><ul><li>The recent surge in deaths is attributed to alcohol contaminated with methanol, a toxic substance.</li><li>The report indicates that poisonings from adulterated alcohol are common in Turkey due to high taxes on alcoholic beverages.</li><li>A collective fine of 2.6 million Turkish lira was imposed on 32 businesses for supplying fake alcohol.</li><li>The Turkish police arrested 14 individuals and confiscated over 14,700 bottles of suspect liquor.</li></ul><blockquote>“Thirty-seven people died and 17 others are still receiving treatment.”</blockquote><p>Authorities are monitoring the situation and highlight the dangers related to counterfeit alcohol production as incidents have become more frequent due to rising production costs and extensive taxation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1879127/istanbul-death-toll-from-tainted-alcohol-jumps-to-37-governor</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1879127/istanbul-death-toll-from-tainted-alcohol-jumps-to-37-governor</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 12:37:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German Chancellor Scholz to ask parliament to clear way for snap election - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/german-chancellor-scholz-ask-parliament-clear-way-new-elections-2024-12-15/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/german-chancellor-scholz-ask-parliament-clear-way-new-elections-2024-12-15/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:44:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Myanmar junta intimidates aid groups in effort to hide hunger crisis - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/famine-data-myanmar/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/famine-data-myanmar/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Syria: Bashar Assad's Shirtless Pics Go Viral After Rebels Storm His Mansions - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bashar Assad's Viral Shirtless Photos After Rebel Invasion</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 10, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News Agency</p><p>Several photos of ousted Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, some featuring him semi-naked, have gone viral after rebels stormed his mansions. These images reveal a dramatic shift for a leader who ruled with an iron fist for 25 years and fled to Russia amidst civil unrest.</p><ul><li>Photos found in Assad's albums after rebel seizure depict him in casual, informal situations.</li><li>One image captures a shirtless Assad appearing to take a selfie.</li><li>Other images include him on a scooter and flexing in a speedo.</li><li>Found alongside, a photo of his father, Hafez al-Assad, in underwear has also caught public attention.</li></ul><blockquote>"Few more Assad pictures so you can have endless nightmares for days to come" — Saad Abedine</blockquote><p>Public response has ranged from ridicule to curiosity about why such photos exist, with significant critique aimed at the Assad family's portrayal.</p><p>These revelations come against a backdrop of ongoing conflict and humanitarian crisis in Syria, marking a notable twist in the narrative surrounding Assad's leadership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-assads-semi-naked-pics-go-viral-after-rebels-storm-his-mansions-7260264</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-assads-semi-naked-pics-go-viral-after-rebels-storm-his-mansions-7260264</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 09:36:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia to allow visa-free entry for Indian tourists: Here’s what you need to know - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOYmdmakFkWXVscXg0VGU4RzBOQlM2dUlLSGtiX2l2Z25IVG5hVlQ0eHozZlQ4cUxnMXJsTi1kUTJfOTdCYm4xUENaS3JEc3EwOVVPaVUxdEU4bzRTMXFPbDRUZ0RzVkRwT0M4SUxFM1dSU0JpRG1odnlpVXVkU3JWeHhFVkZsTFFkQXA5WmxmMG5ramRPLXBaTl9ZQ09xYWRrZWRIcnIxRmtWYU1lT05sSnpVMGRrdk3SAbwBQVVfeXFMTXJLVUp2NmhiaGdYYVJQUmx5NzdhREZKdllKdG9QZ3AtNFQzTlVZel8yci1UQnVUNHZuYzNwYzhvUHozb1RJSDdQQWFqaGJvNzVEek9zMjZXckhVWGFNS1BpSGJwOUJCZ1FRSVBLZWJlUGVwQmNlaEZGN1doVV9hUmhZbi1XLVB3ZThpYkhMLVlWcVlQb1BVTWhSVnRiS0hrLVZZbXBmUzdlc24wU1ctOGtGdGVTNEJ0OEQzT0o?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxOYmdmakFkWXVscXg0VGU4RzBOQlM2dUlLSGtiX2l2Z25IVG5hVlQ0eHozZlQ4cUxnMXJsTi1kUTJfOTdCYm4xUENaS3JEc3EwOVVPaVUxdEU4bzRTMXFPbDRUZ0RzVkRwT0M4SUxFM1dSU0JpRG1odnlpVXVkU3JWeHhFVkZsTFFkQXA5WmxmMG5ramRPLXBaTl9ZQ09xYWRrZWRIcnIxRmtWYU1lT05sSnpVMGRrdk3SAbwBQVVfeXFMTXJLVUp2NmhiaGdYYVJQUmx5NzdhREZKdllKdG9QZ3AtNFQzTlVZel8yci1UQnVUNHZuYzNwYzhvUHozb1RJSDdQQWFqaGJvNzVEek9zMjZXckhVWGFNS1BpSGJwOUJCZ1FRSVBLZWJlUGVwQmNlaEZGN1doVV9hUmhZbi1XLVB3ZThpYkhMLVlWcVlQb1BVTWhSVnRiS0hrLVZZbXBmUzdlc24wU1ctOGtGdGVTNEJ0OEQzT0o?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 09:07:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baba Vanga's Predictions for 2025: A Deep Dive into the Mysterious Insights - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baba Vanga's Predictions for 2025: A Deep Dive into the Mysterious Insights</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Available &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> Not Available</p><p>In this article, we explore the intriguing predictions made by the late clairvoyant Baba Vanga for the year 2025, investigating their potential implications and relevance in today's world.</p><ul><li>Baba Vanga, known for her prophetic insights, is said to predict significant global events.</li><li>Insights may cover various sectors including politics, environment, and technology.</li><li>The article discusses the interpretation of her predictions and their potential accuracy.</li></ul><blockquote>“The future is not set in stone, but can be influenced by our actions today.”</blockquote><p>Understanding these predictions may offer valuable perspectives on the challenges and opportunities that lie ahead.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/astrology/zodiacs-astrology/baba-vangas-predictions-for-2025-a-deep-dive-into-the-mysterious-insights/articleshow/116361809.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/astrology/zodiacs-astrology/baba-vangas-predictions-for-2025-a-deep-dive-into-the-mysterious-insights/articleshow/116361809.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 08:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyclone Chido, 'worst in a century', devastates France's Mayotte, toll may be in thousands - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cyclone Chido Devastates Mayotte, Death Toll Expected to Reach Thousands</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/FRANCE-WEATHER-MAYOTTE-40_1734336662872_1734336707198.JPG" alt="The wreckage of a car lies outside a home, in the aftermath of Cyclone Chido, within Labattoir, in Mayotte,(REUTERS)">
<figcaption>The wreckage of a car lies outside a home, in the aftermath of Cyclone Chido, within Labattoir, in Mayotte,(REUTERS)</figcaption>
<p>Cyclone Chido, the most powerful storm to hit Mayotte in nearly a century, has caused devastating damages, and the death toll may reach into the thousands according to officials.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The cyclone struck with winds over 200 kph (124 mph), affecting housing, government buildings, and hospitals.</li>
  <li>Prefect Francois-Xavier Bieuville reported that casualties could number in the thousands.</li>
  <li>French President Emmanuel Macron expressed condolences for the victims in Mayotte, calling it a horrific tragedy.</li>
  <li>The cyclone has severely impacted access to essential resources such as food, water, and sanitation.</li>
  <li>Efforts for disaster relief, including an air bridge from Reunion island, have been initiated.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Honestly, what we are experiencing is a tragedy, you feel like you are in the aftermath of a nuclear war… I saw an entire neighborhood disappear." - Mohamed Ishmael, resident of Mamoudzou.</blockquote>
<p>This cyclone challenges the leadership of new Prime Minister Francois Bayrou as authorities assess the extent of the damage and begin recovery efforts.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/cyclone-chido-worst-in-a-century-devastates-frances-mayotte-toll-may-be-in-thousands-101734336233375.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/cyclone-chido-worst-in-a-century-devastates-frances-mayotte-toll-may-be-in-thousands-101734336233375.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 08:38:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mysterious drone sightings spook Americans, spark new theory - India Today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Mysterious drone sightings spook Americans, spark new theory</h1>
<p><strong>Published On:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 <strong>By:</strong> Girish Kumar Anshul</p>
<img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202412/drones-over-new-jersey-162447682-16x9_0.png?VersionId=H.4jv8oPl19d4xLIaPz3oBbKYv_x_mtb&size=690:388" alt="Drones over New Jersey" title="Several drones appear to be flying over New Jersey. (Photo: AP)">
<figcaption>Several drones appear to be flying over New Jersey. (Photo: AP)</figcaption>
<p>A series of unexplained drone sightings over New Jersey and other parts of the East Coast in recent weeks have sparked widespread concern and confusion. While federal authorities, including the FBI and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), maintain there is "no evidence at this time" that the drones pose a threat to national security or public safety, their presence continues to alarm residents.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The mysterious drone sightings started on November 18 in New Jersey and have been reported every night since.</li>
  <li>Drones have been observed flying over residential neighborhoods, restricted areas, and critical infrastructure across at least six states.</li>
  <li>The White House National Security Council stated that the drones are not a public safety risk.</li>
  <li>Theories about the drones' purpose have gained traction, suggesting they might be conducting night-time searches for specific substances.</li>
  <li>Political pressure is increasing, with governors seeking clarity from the federal government on the drone sightings.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is the first video about these drones that has got me genuinely concerned.” – Joe Rogan</blockquote>
<p>As the concern escalates, many Americans continue to wonder whether they are witnessing advanced surveillance technology, industrial activity, or something far more mysterious.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/mysterious-drone-east-coast-new-jersey-new-theories-emerged-us-agency-no-threat-public-safety-joe-rogan-2650389-2024-12-16</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/mysterious-drone-east-coast-new-jersey-new-theories-emerged-us-agency-no-threat-public-safety-joe-rogan-2650389-2024-12-16</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 08:13:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Europe stocks open lower; French stocks slide after Moody's credit downgrade; Broadcaster Canal+ lists in London - CNBC]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>European Stocks Open Lower; French Stock Slide After Moody's Credit Downgrade</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 18, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> CNBC</p><div><p>European markets began the week on a downward trend as traders prepare for significant central bank activities. The CAC 40 index experienced losses following a credit downgrade from Moody's.</p></div><ul><li>European markets opened lower on Monday as traders brace for central bank decisions.</li><li>Moody's downgraded France's credit rating from Aa2 to Aa3, citing concerns over public finances.</li><li>The CAC 40 index fell by 0.36%, while the Stoxx 600 index opened 0.09% lower.</li><li>Francois Bayrou was named France's fourth prime minister this year amidst ongoing political instability.</li><li>Key attention is on upcoming U.S. Federal Reserve and Bank of England meetings, with expectations for rate adjustments.</li></ul><blockquote>“French public finances will be weakened in the coming years by ongoing political instability.” - Moody's report</blockquote><div> <p>The article highlights the ongoing uncertainties in European markets due to political changes and anticipated monetary policy shifts in the coming week.</p> </div>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/16/european-markets-live-updates-stocks-news-data-and-earnings.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/16/european-markets-live-updates-stocks-news-data-and-earnings.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 08:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[At least 30 North Korean soldiers killed and wounded in Russia’s Kursk region: Ukraine - Al Arabiya English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://english.alarabiya.net/News/world/2024/12/16/at-least-30-north-korean-soldiers-killed-and-wounded-in-russia-s-kursk-region-ukraine-</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://english.alarabiya.net/News/world/2024/12/16/at-least-30-north-korean-soldiers-killed-and-wounded-in-russia-s-kursk-region-ukraine-</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:44:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man spends Rs 2.3 lakh fees for 'self-discipline challenge' to win Rs 1.1 crore, fails thrice, sues... - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/man-spends-rs-2-3-lakh-fees-for-self-discipline-challenge-to-win-rs-1-1-crore-fails-thrice-sues-organisers-12890735.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/man-spends-rs-2-3-lakh-fees-for-self-discipline-challenge-to-win-rs-1-1-crore-fails-thrice-sues-organisers-12890735.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:38:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nations step up outreach to Syria’s post-Assad rulers - The Times of Israel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesofisrael.com/nations-step-up-outreach-to-syrias-post-assad-rulers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesofisrael.com/nations-step-up-outreach-to-syrias-post-assad-rulers/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:28:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy's 4-word explanation for why MAGA leaders carry their children to workplaces - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxOSm9jS1ppeXJYaFBBWWJVM0dUOGlSRFdIZXdjNVh1QW5MOE1abmNROWV0ZTRmSTdhR1pTR0hIUV9EblMzZ2U2Q21NWGFZb05DdUdCemZYNUtMSzNicUltbU5tMG94Z3Z4cmd1bHpPM09hUkRsY1V6QnNQMmlYS0MtVnFTS0R4dDE1UW5DNWJPaUFrV2NybURtYzI5VmsxYmM1WWZXbkk1ckdCWHUwMXdQdWZOOGhrMEZkUWNZemJIMnhrT0lNMDl5ZVljNGhndXQtblp1S0ltLV9WUC1IX3Jvc1hUTHhjZnVZU25MNFMtYnFsY0ot0gH6AUFVX3lxTFBGZHhSN29CNXNVRjZJMzVQb1dMNU9hNkFZTWhuWXppOHJOZWd3b1RpdlpsQVE4N0EzRmVmNkNIQkFSOTZ4cE94ckJuQXJPVlZTbnFmalRHZ0x2X1liNVEtN1d4STY5OHkxXzBkNE5pX1EzdmZqb25saVVpcUpDbWwtWkdjNFhTT1ZDbHpzYkpENDNSX2kwS044Wjc1eWNFalFoN1hfT3g4cnBwYW9Fa184VFF0OWNxNnhJTEhOc0FCMjNUTHJsNzhYS3pVYmxqUXZzcFZHYXBSY2JZUDQ0azhfU3lZU3JaNndFc2pOLWNxSDhxVlgxYlF1eXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi9AFBVV95cUxOSm9jS1ppeXJYaFBBWWJVM0dUOGlSRFdIZXdjNVh1QW5MOE1abmNROWV0ZTRmSTdhR1pTR0hIUV9EblMzZ2U2Q21NWGFZb05DdUdCemZYNUtMSzNicUltbU5tMG94Z3Z4cmd1bHpPM09hUkRsY1V6QnNQMmlYS0MtVnFTS0R4dDE1UW5DNWJPaUFrV2NybURtYzI5VmsxYmM1WWZXbkk1ckdCWHUwMXdQdWZOOGhrMEZkUWNZemJIMnhrT0lNMDl5ZVljNGhndXQtblp1S0ltLV9WUC1IX3Jvc1hUTHhjZnVZU25MNFMtYnFsY0ot0gH6AUFVX3lxTFBGZHhSN29CNXNVRjZJMzVQb1dMNU9hNkFZTWhuWXppOHJOZWd3b1RpdlpsQVE4N0EzRmVmNkNIQkFSOTZ4cE94ckJuQXJPVlZTbnFmalRHZ0x2X1liNVEtN1d4STY5OHkxXzBkNE5pX1EzdmZqb25saVVpcUpDbWwtWkdjNFhTT1ZDbHpzYkpENDNSX2kwS044Wjc1eWNFalFoN1hfT3g4cnBwYW9Fa184VFF0OWNxNnhJTEhOc0FCMjNUTHJsNzhYS3pVYmxqUXZzcFZHYXBSY2JZUDQ0azhfU3lZU3JaNndFc2pOLWNxSDhxVlgxYlF1eXc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taliban’s Khalil Ur-Rahman Haqqani killed: Why it matters - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxPSllON0tYbnFoNFYzY1BrTk5JSWFHazJsMVBQcjhsVThILTUzc0otUktQN2hZckFrenZYeG5YMzdFMnI3NnFXcmxNbEtyNXhRRnFNN0lBUlhDYkg5RTdKVWxOMnUzVXk4MXVGNlQ2SjZDV0NmZ2RyYmU0N0tMSWU0enY5Mkk4Ukc0eFk1aW0tRjhybEpBeWtfRHhzNXVZd9IBowFBVV95cUxOMGxMOU5XWFlySlNMM2hfWWVYYVJiSjVMUFRWSllKOWJlUDhmWm5sbF8zc2lBc3dEb2JRb0NDSFl1MlNzVzNrakQ3SGJ3ZXY0MTFhX0pPa1p5RklJc3V5ZG5aTFRmVG5mTmJ6WlBDNzBaaGxBY3NEa1FXN1ctRE9hZ212WXRTNWllTXRLMDE5b1czSjQ4ZUhYb3V1UnpzRnB6anFZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxPSllON0tYbnFoNFYzY1BrTk5JSWFHazJsMVBQcjhsVThILTUzc0otUktQN2hZckFrenZYeG5YMzdFMnI3NnFXcmxNbEtyNXhRRnFNN0lBUlhDYkg5RTdKVWxOMnUzVXk4MXVGNlQ2SjZDV0NmZ2RyYmU0N0tMSWU0enY5Mkk4Ukc0eFk1aW0tRjhybEpBeWtfRHhzNXVZd9IBowFBVV95cUxOMGxMOU5XWFlySlNMM2hfWWVYYVJiSjVMUFRWSllKOWJlUDhmWm5sbF8zc2lBc3dEb2JRb0NDSFl1MlNzVzNrakQ3SGJ3ZXY0MTFhX0pPa1p5RklJc3V5ZG5aTFRmVG5mTmJ6WlBDNzBaaGxBY3NEa1FXN1ctRE9hZ212WXRTNWllTXRLMDE5b1czSjQ4ZUhYb3V1UnpzRnB6anFZ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:51:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kyrgyzstan's president dismisses prime minister - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/kyrgyzstans-president-dismisses-prime-minister-ria-reports-2024-12-16/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/kyrgyzstans-president-dismisses-prime-minister-ria-reports-2024-12-16/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Joe Rogan worried about drone sightings after chilling new theory floats, ‘Genuinely concerned’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Joe Rogan worried about drone sightings after chilling new theory floats, ‘Genuinely concerned’</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/Election-2024-Trump-0_1734329847591_1734329874912.jpg" alt="Joe Rogan worried about drone sightings after chilling new theory floats" title="Joe Rogan worried about drone sightings after chilling new theory floats">
<figcaption>Joe Rogan worried about drone sightings after chilling new theory floats (AP Photo/Gregory Payan, File)(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Joe Rogan has expressed genuine concern over unverified drone sightings in New Jersey after watching a viral TikTok video suggesting they may be searching for harmful substances.</p>
<ul>
<li>Rogan's comments came after observing a theory by John Ferguson, a CEO of a drone company, who speculated that drones might be detecting gas leaks or radioactive materials.</li>
<li>Despite reassurances from government officials that the drones are not a public safety threat, Rogan remains skeptical of these claims.</li>
<li>Various theories about the purpose of the drone sightings have emerged, including suggestions of foreign involvement.</li>
<li>Former President Donald Trump has also weighed in, urging authorities to disclose more information about the sightings and suggesting a more aggressive approach.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is the first video about these drones that has got me genuinely concerned.” – Joe Rogan</blockquote>
<p>Rogan’s reaction highlights the public's interest and concern regarding the safety implications of unidentified drone activity.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/joe-rogan-worried-about-drone-sightings-after-chilling-new-theory-floats-genuinely-concerned-101734329474424.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/joe-rogan-worried-about-drone-sightings-after-chilling-new-theory-floats-genuinely-concerned-101734329474424.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:21:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hundreds feared dead on France’s Mayotte after Cyclone Chido - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Cyclone Chido Causes Devastation in Mayotte, Hundreds Feared Dead</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Al Jazeera</p><img src="/images/mayotte_cyclone.jpg" alt="Destruction in Mayotte after Cyclone Chido"><figcaption>Destruction in Mayotte after Cyclone Chido</figcaption><p>Cyclone Chido, the most powerful storm in nearly a century, has struck Mayotte, leading to fears of several hundred casualties and significant damage to infrastructure.</p><ul><li>The cyclone brought winds surpassing 200 km/h (124 mph), causing widespread destruction.</li><li>Local officials estimate the death toll could reach up to a thousand.</li><li>More than 100,000 undocumented migrants reside in the impoverished region, complicating recovery efforts.</li><li>Concerns about food, water, and sanitation access have been raised following the disaster.</li><li>An air bridge is being established from Reunion Island to aid relief efforts.</li><li>The cyclone also affected northern Mozambique, though the full impact there is still unknown.</li></ul><blockquote>“Honestly, what we are experiencing is a tragedy, you feel like you are in the aftermath of a nuclear war.” - Mohamed Ishmael, local resident</blockquote><p>The situation in Mayotte highlights the ongoing struggles of the territory, including poverty and social unrest, exacerbated by natural disasters.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/gallery/2024/12/16/hundreds-feared-dead-on-mayotte-after-cyclone-chido</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/gallery/2024/12/16/hundreds-feared-dead-on-mayotte-after-cyclone-chido</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:19:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Rare Tornado tears through California, flips cars and uproots trees - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/watch-rare-tornado-tears-through-california-flips-cars-and-uproots-trees/articleshow/116355164.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/watch-rare-tornado-tears-through-california-flips-cars-and-uproots-trees/articleshow/116355164.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Serbian police used Cellebrite to unlock, then plant spyware, on a journalist’s phone - TechCrunch]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Serbian police used Cellebrite to unlock, then plant spyware, on a journalist's phone</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> TechCrunch</p><p>This article discusses the alarming use of Cellebrite’s cellphone-unlocking technology by Serbian authorities to hack into the phones of journalists and activists, demonstrating a troubling trend of state surveillance.</p><ul><li>Serbian journalist Slaviša Milanov and activist Nikola Ristić had their phones hacked by police using Cellebrite.</li><li>The hacking involved not just unlocking but also installing spyware, termed 'NoviSpy'.</li><li>Amnesty International’s report claims this is the first documented case of such spyware infections via Cellebrite.</li><li>Authorities are increasingly relying on direct phone access to conduct surveillance as sophisticated hacking methods become more expensive.</li><li>Milanov discovered unauthorized data extraction of 1.6 GB from his phone while it was in police custody.</li><li>Amnesty found that NoviSpy might have been developed by the Serbian intelligence agency, implicating state-sponsored spying on civil society.</li></ul><blockquote>“I noticed that my mobile data ... are turned off. ... This was the first suspicion that someone entered my mobile phone,” said Milanov.</blockquote><p>This developing situation raises significant concerns regarding privacy rights and the misuse of surveillance technology by the state.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/15/serbian-police-used-cellebrite-to-unlock-then-plant-spyware-on-a-journalists-phone/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/15/serbian-police-used-cellebrite-to-unlock-then-plant-spyware-on-a-journalists-phone/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chinese man, reunited with millionaire parents 25 years after kidnapping, rejects family's wealth - Moneycontrol]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/chinese-man-reunited-with-millionaire-parents-25-years-after-kidnapping-rejects-family-wealth-12890685.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/trends/chinese-man-reunited-with-millionaire-parents-25-years-after-kidnapping-rejects-family-wealth-12890685.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 06:04:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Toppled Syrian President Bashar Al Assad flew $250 million in cash to Moscow: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bashar Al Assad's $250 Million Cash Transfer to Moscow Revealed</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 16, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/16/550x309/Syria-Assad-Inner-Circle-0_1734326585546_1734326629616.jpg" alt="FILE - An image of ousted Syrian President Bashar Assad covers the facade of a provincial government office in the aftermath of the opposition's takeover of Hama, Syria,(AP)" />
<figcaption>FILE - An image of ousted Syrian President Bashar Assad covers the facade of a provincial government office in the aftermath of the opposition's takeover of Hama, Syria,(AP)</figcaption>
<p>The report reveals that ousted Syrian President Bashar Al Assad allegedly transferred $250 million in cash to Moscow between 2018 and 2019, indicating strong financial ties with Russia during the Syrian Civil War.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The cash was primarily in $100 and €500 denominations.</li>
  <li>Transactions occurred in amounts such as $10 million and $20 million at a time.</li>
  <li>The funds were recorded being deposited in Russian banks after flights from the Syrian Central Bank to Moscow.</li>
  <li>The assistance from Russia was crucial for Assad's regime amid the civil war.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"The transactions happened between March 2018 to September 2019, after Russian Forces helped repel rebel forces from Damascus."</blockquote>
<p>This revelation highlights the depth of Assad's reliance on Russia for financial and military support throughout the conflict.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/toppled-syrian-president-bashar-al-assad-flew-250-million-in-cash-to-moscow-report-101734326221297.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/toppled-syrian-president-bashar-al-assad-flew-250-million-in-cash-to-moscow-report-101734326221297.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:53:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh to hold elections in late 2025 or early 2026: Yunus - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bangladesh to Hold Elections in Late 2025 or Early 2026 According to Interim Leader Yunus</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 16, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/lwlihr/article68990983.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/Bdesh.jpg" alt="Muhammad Yunus, Chief Adviser of Bangladesh’s interim government." /><figcaption>Muhammad Yunus, Chief Adviser of Bangladesh’s interim government. | Photo Credit: Special Arrangement</figcaption><p>Bangladesh’s national elections may be held between late 2025 and early 2026, contingent on the implementation of electoral reforms. Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus highlighted the potential impact of these reforms in his address to the nation on December 16, 2024.</p><ul><li>The elections could be possible by late 2025 with minimal reforms focused on an accurate voter list.</li><li>Comprehensive reforms may delay elections by an additional six months.</li><li>Yunus emphasized the necessity for reforms before proceeding with elections.</li><li>Recent discussions with EU ambassadors showcase international support for Bangladesh.</li><li>Yunus addressed concerns regarding Bangladeshi students' visa challenges and the country's economic recovery.</li></ul><blockquote>“I have repeatedly urged for the completion of major reforms before holding the elections.” - Muhammad Yunus</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the electoral timeline remains contingent upon the pace and scope of necessary reforms, reflecting a crucial period for Bangladesh's democratic process.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/bangladesh-to-hold-elections-in-late-2025-or-early-2026-yunus/article68990782.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/bangladesh-to-hold-elections-in-late-2025-or-early-2026-yunus/article68990782.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Europe Needs to Swiftly Fulfil Its Aid Pledges to Ukraine | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxNWjJxeElhbW80ZzE5TzBhcDYxX0E1cVdvQ20zb3M4ajdqMnRJRElxTzNzV1ZmVVhHX09GeXdyRkxqSklwa2xWYnY3T1N0QWNyejkzeG5JdkwwMDZBQ1RfZ1FyRHRpVmpZMkxhdURJU3F2cXBQNWxBbnR6SGVtRHdJTlZack9mQWhka2U3OEdTSW92VHVDVE8zd2R6bVlrY09WWXhTV29nNUM4MEpwMi0wNHdiS0VENXlp0gG-AUFVX3lxTE9CaUdtVUo3OUM3SDJLWnM0RElHSmtpUGRmNUhEYlFvM1VhZmlFY1Q4RjFXYTlWWmhCQjRidDg1TEhBeDVjdjN4VzZBbmZhY2lKbGs1ZzlFak1oMTk0OFFnZ19ZNGpfaXBsQU9lTjNlU1dISHhWdk9aNGt0Y2M3bkxweVhDeE51dVVZNTc3dU5aX2hXQl9OdUdua1hvNmhJZ0E3SGF1SnlGd0U4TE1oSmc2LUk0V2tGMF9FTmVDZUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxNWjJxeElhbW80ZzE5TzBhcDYxX0E1cVdvQ20zb3M4ajdqMnRJRElxTzNzV1ZmVVhHX09GeXdyRkxqSklwa2xWYnY3T1N0QWNyejkzeG5JdkwwMDZBQ1RfZ1FyRHRpVmpZMkxhdURJU3F2cXBQNWxBbnR6SGVtRHdJTlZack9mQWhka2U3OEdTSW92VHVDVE8zd2R6bVlrY09WWXhTV29nNUM4MEpwMi0wNHdiS0VENXlp0gG-AUFVX3lxTE9CaUdtVUo3OUM3SDJLWnM0RElHSmtpUGRmNUhEYlFvM1VhZmlFY1Q4RjFXYTlWWmhCQjRidDg1TEhBeDVjdjN4VzZBbmZhY2lKbGs1ZzlFak1oMTk0OFFnZ19ZNGpfaXBsQU9lTjNlU1dISHhWdk9aNGt0Y2M3bkxweVhDeE51dVVZNTc3dU5aX2hXQl9OdUdua1hvNmhJZ0E3SGF1SnlGd0U4TE1oSmc2LUk0V2tGMF9FTmVDZUE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:24:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Israel has its eyes set on Syria’s Golan Heights - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Why Israel has its eyes set on Syria’s Golan Heights</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Firstpost</p><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/12/2024-12-13T030807Z_2069070847_RC2PNBAJ879P_RTRMADP_3_SYRIA-SECURITY-GOLAN-HEIGHTS-1-2024-12-57a943ba5fc642ab1333a6535addaf97.jpg" alt="israel golan heights "><figcaption><b>An Israeli tank operates in Syria, as seen from Majdal Shams in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights, December 12, 2024. Reuters</b></figcaption><p>Israel is planning to double its population in the occupied Golan Heights, which was captured in the 1967 Six-Day War. Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu cites security concerns following the overthrow of Syrian President Bashar al-Assad as a justification for the expansion.</p><ul><li>Israel is increasing its settlements in the Golan Heights.</li><li>The move is justified by perceived threats from Syria post-Assad's fall.</li><li>The Israeli government approved an $11 million plan for the expansion.</li><li>Netanyahu emphasizes that strengthening the Golan strengthens Israel.</li><li>The Golan Heights is strategically important due to its proximity to Syria.</li></ul><blockquote>“Strengthening the Golan is strengthening the State of Israel... We will continue to hold onto it,” - Netanyahu.</blockquote><p>Israel's actions have drawn criticism internationally, but the government maintains that it seeks security rather than confrontation with Syria.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/explainers/israel-expand-settlement-syria-golan-heights-13844787.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/explainers/israel-expand-settlement-syria-golan-heights-13844787.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:10:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia plans visa-free entry for Indians from 2025, joining 62 countries - Business Standard]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.business-standard.com/finance/personal-finance/russia-plans-visa-free-entry-for-indians-from-2025-joining-62-countries-124121600240_1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.business-standard.com/finance/personal-finance/russia-plans-visa-free-entry-for-indians-from-2025-joining-62-countries-124121600240_1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 05:09:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>