<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:13:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:13:22 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump To Get $15 Million From ABC News In Defamation Suit Over Anchor's 'Rape' Remark - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump To Get $15 Million From ABC News In Defamation Suit Over Anchor's 'Rape' Remark</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 15, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="US President-elect Donald Trump (AP Image)" title="US President-elect Donald Trump (AP Image)">
<figcaption>US President-elect Donald Trump (AP Image)</figcaption>
<p>Donald Trump will receive $15 million from ABC News as part of a settlement in a defamation lawsuit against anchor George Stephanopoulos for an erroneous statement regarding Trump's legal liability regarding writer E. Jean Carroll.</p>
<ul>
    <li>George Stephanopoulos claimed that Trump had been civilly found liable for raping writer E. Jean Carroll during his March 10 show.</li>
    <li>As part of the settlement, ABC News will pay Trump $15 million and $1 million in legal fees to his attorney Alejandro Brito.</li>
    <li>The settlement includes a public regret from ABC News about the remarks made on the "This Week" program.</li>
    <li>The funds will be designated as a charitable contribution towards Trump's presidential library.</li>
    <li>The agreement was signed prior to scheduled depositions, avoiding the need for sworn testimony.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"We are pleased that the two parties have reached an agreement to dismiss the lawsuit on the terms in the court filing." - Jeannie Kedas, ABC News spokesperson</blockquote>
<p>The settlement marks a significant resolution for Trump in light of the accusations, allowing both parties to move forward without further legal proceedings.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-to-get-15-million-from-abc-news-in-defamation-suit-over-anchor-george-stephanopoulos-rape-remark-9156664.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-to-get-15-million-from-abc-news-in-defamation-suit-over-anchor-george-stephanopoulos-rape-remark-9156664.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 02:09:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump to receive $15 million and apology from ABC News over anchor George Stephanopoulos’s ‘rape’ remark - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/abc-news-settles-defamation-lawsuit-with-trump-agrees-to-contribute-15-million-to-presidential-library/articleshow/116327039.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/abc-news-settles-defamation-lawsuit-with-trump-agrees-to-contribute-15-million-to-presidential-library/articleshow/116327039.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 02:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberattack in Rhode Island: Sensitive data breach, hackers demand ransom - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/cyberattack-in-rhode-island-sensitive-data-breach-hackers-demand-ransom/articleshow/116329719.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/cyberattack-in-rhode-island-sensitive-data-breach-hackers-demand-ransom/articleshow/116329719.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 01:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Did Donald Trump salute too soon? US President-elect's gesture during Anthem at Army-Navy game sparks deb - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/did-donald-trump-salute-too-soon-us-president-elects-gesture-during-anthem-at-army-navy-game-sparks-debate/articleshow/116329255.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/did-donald-trump-salute-too-soon-us-president-elects-gesture-during-anthem-at-army-navy-game-sparks-debate/articleshow/116329255.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump trolls Governor Chris Christie with 'Drone Happy Meal' meme amid mystery sightings in New Je - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-trolls-governor-chris-christie-with-drone-happy-meal-meme-amid-mystery-sightings-in-new-jersey/articleshow/116329244.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-trolls-governor-chris-christie-with-drone-happy-meal-meme-amid-mystery-sightings-in-new-jersey/articleshow/116329244.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['I'm safe, but won't return': Missing photographer Hannah Kobayashi breaks silence after disappearance - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/im-safe-but-wont-return-missing-photographer-hannah-kobayashi-breaks-silence-after-disappearance/articleshow/116326119.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/im-safe-but-wont-return-missing-photographer-hannah-kobayashi-breaks-silence-after-disappearance/articleshow/116326119.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five killed in shooting near France's Dunkirk, including migrants and guards - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/five-killed-in-shooting-near-frances-dunkirk-including-migrants-and-guards/articleshow/116326003.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/five-killed-in-shooting-near-frances-dunkirk-including-migrants-and-guards/articleshow/116326003.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Founder of fashion brand Mango, Isak Andic, dies in mountain accident - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Founder of fashion brand Mango, Isak Andic, dies in mountain accident</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 15, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/France-Isak-Andic-Obit-0_1734203623806_1734203651799.jpg" alt="Isak Andic, the founder of Spanish fashion brand Mango, died in a mountain accident(AP)" title="Isak Andic, the founder of Spanish fashion brand Mango, died in a mountain accident(AP)">
<figcaption>Isak Andic, the founder of Spanish fashion brand Mango, died in a mountain accident(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Isak Andic, the Istanbul-born founder and owner of the fashion brand Mango, tragically died in a hiking accident near Barcelona, falling from a 150-metre cliff while hiking with family.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Andic was 71 years old at the time of his death.</li>
    <li>The accident occurred near the Montserrat caves close to Barcelona.</li>
    <li>Mango CEO Toni Ruiz expressed the legacy Andic left behind, stating, “His departure leaves a huge void.”</li>
    <li>Andic founded Mango in 1984 after moving to Catalonia in the 1960s.</li>
    <li>He had a net worth of $4.5 billion, according to Forbes.</li>
    <li>Mango reported a turnover of 3.1 billion euros in 2023, with significant online sales and a presence in over 120 markets.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“He leaves an indelible mark on the Catalan and global fashion sector.” - Salvador Illa, head of the regional government of Catalonia</blockquote>
<p>This loss has sent shockwaves through the fashion industry, as Andic's contributions and vision helped shape Mango into a globally recognized brand.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/founder-of-fashion-brand-mango-isak-andic-dies-in-mountain-accident-101734203386816.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/founder-of-fashion-brand-mango-isak-andic-dies-in-mountain-accident-101734203386816.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 19:33:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Al-Jolani says his group won't engage in fight with Israel - Mehr News Agency - English Version]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Al-Jolani says his group won't engage in fight with Israel</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Saturday</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> MNA</p>
<p>Abu Mohammad al-Jolani stressed that the HTS does not seek confrontation with Israel amidst ongoing airstrikes and regional tensions.</p>
<ul>
    <li>HTS leader Abu Mohammad al-Jolani indicated that his group will avoid engagement with Israel.</li>
    <li>Israel has conducted numerous airstrikes against Syria following the recent political changes.</li>
    <li>Al-Jolani mentioned providing Russia the opportunity to reassess its relations with Syria.</li>
    <li>He stated that the Syrian opposition does not harbor animosity towards Iran.</li>
    <li>After the departure of Iranian forces, al-Jolani argues that Israel lacks justification for its interventions in Syria.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“After Iranian forces left Syria, there is no justification for the Israeli regime to intervene in the Arab country.” - Abu Mohammad al-Jolani</blockquote>
<p>Al-Jolani's remarks indicate a focus on avoiding conflict while addressing regional relationships, particularly concerning Israel and Iran.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://en.mehrnews.com/news/225583/Al-Jolani-says-his-group-will-not-fight-occupying-Israel</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://en.mehrnews.com/news/225583/Al-Jolani-says-his-group-will-not-fight-occupying-Israel</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 18:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US secretary of state Antony Blinken admits of having 'direct contacts' with Syrian rebel group HTS - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/us-secretary-of-state-antony-blinken-admits-of-having-direct-contacts-with-syrian-rebel-group-hts/articleshow/116323254.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/us-secretary-of-state-antony-blinken-admits-of-having-direct-contacts-with-syrian-rebel-group-hts/articleshow/116323254.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 17:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mango founder Isak Andic dies in mountain accident - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/mango-founder-isak-andic-passes-away-in-mountain-accident/articleshow/116323460.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/mango-founder-isak-andic-passes-away-in-mountain-accident/articleshow/116323460.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 17:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina involved in forced disappearances, says Bangladesh inquiry commission - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Sheikh Hasina involved in forced disappearances, says Bangladesh inquiry commission</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/s83g3q/article68986412.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/YE-Top_Photos-Asia-Photo_Gallery_44407.jpg" alt="Soon after Ex-PM Hasina fled, several human rights activists revealed that they were kept imprisoned for years in the House of Mirrors (Aynaghar) in Dhaka, for intense and prolonged interrogation." title="Soon after Ex-PM Hasina fled, several human rights activists revealed that they were kept imprisoned for years in the House of Mirrors (Aynaghar) in Dhaka, for intense and prolonged interrogation.">
<figcaption>File Photo: Human rights activists imprisoned for intense interrogation.</figcaption>
<p>The Commission of Inquiry on Enforced Disappearance in Bangladesh has reported the involvement of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina in the enforced disappearances of individuals during her rule, recommending significant reforms and accountability measures.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The commission recorded 1,676 cases of enforced disappearances and believes the total could exceed 3,500.</li>
    <li>It recommended disbanding the Rapid Action Battalion, implicated in human rights abuses.</li>
    <li>Arrests were made following attacks on the Hindu minority, highlighting ongoing communal tensions.</li>
    <li>Statements from the commission suggest involvement of high-ranking officials in the enforced disappearances.</li>
    <li>The report indicates systematic efforts to obscure the cases of disappearances.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"You are doing a really very important job. We are ready to give you all kinds of support that you need." - Mohammad Yunus, Chief Adviser</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the report marks a significant step towards addressing past human rights abuses in Bangladesh and calls for accountability among its leaders, particularly in the context of enforced disappearances during Sheikh Hasina's administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/hasina-involved-in-forced-disappearances-says-bangladesh-inquiry-commission/article68986255.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/hasina-involved-in-forced-disappearances-says-bangladesh-inquiry-commission/article68986255.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 17:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hasina involved in forced disappearances, says Bangladesh inquiry commission - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Hasina involved in forced disappearances, says Bangladesh inquiry commission</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/s83g3q/article68986412.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/YE-Top_Photos-Asia-Photo_Gallery_44407.jpg" alt="Soon after Ex-PM Hasina fled, several human rights activists revealed that they were kept imprisoned for years in the House of Mirrors (Aynaghar) in Dhaka, for intense and prolonged interrogation." title="Soon after Ex-PM Hasina fled, several human rights activists revealed that they were kept imprisoned for years in the House of Mirrors (Aynaghar) in Dhaka, for intense and prolonged interrogation." fetchpriority="high">
<figcaption>Photo Credit: AP</figcaption>
<p>In a startling report, a Bangladesh inquiry commission has implicated former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina in enforced disappearances during her time in office, recommending the disbandment of the Rapid Action Battalion.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Commission of Inquiry on Enforced Disappearance reported Sheikh Hasina's involvement in over 1,676 cases, estimating the total could exceed 3,500 cases.</li>
    <li>The report calls for the disbandment of the Rapid Action Battalion due to its role in human rights abuses.</li>
    <li>Four individuals were arrested for attacks on a Hindu community in Sunamganj district, linked to communal tensions.</li>
    <li>The commission noted the involvement of several high-ranking officials, including Hasina's defense adviser.</li>
    <li>A further interim report is expected in March 2025, with a full review taking an additional year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“You are doing a really very important job. We are ready to give you all kinds of support that you need.” - Mohammad Yunus, Chief Adviser</blockquote>
<p>This inquiry underscores the systematic issues regarding enforced disappearances in Bangladesh, highlighting serious concerns over human rights under Sheikh Hasina's administration.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/hasina-involved-in-forced-disappearances-says-bangladesh-inquiry-commission/article68986255.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/hasina-involved-in-forced-disappearances-says-bangladesh-inquiry-commission/article68986255.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 17:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 dead after migrant boat with many Pakistanis capsizes off Greek island - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>5 dead after migrant boat with many Pakistanis capsizes off Greek island</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Saturday<br><strong>Source:</strong> Dawn</p>
<img src="https://i.dawn.com/news/2000x1200/1878730-capsized-boat.jpg" alt="Capsized boat" />
<figcaption>Illustration of the incident involving the migrant boat</figcaption>
<p>At least five migrants have drowned after their wooden boat capsized off the southern island of Gavdos, with many still reported missing as search operations continue.</p>
<ul>
    <li>39 men, mostly from Pakistan, have been rescued and transferred to Crete.</li>
    <li>The search includes coastguard boats, merchant vessels, an Italian frigate, and naval aircraft.</li>
    <li>A Malta-flagged cargo vessel rescued an additional 47 migrants off Gavdos.</li>
    <li>Another tanker assisted 88 migrants about 28 nautical miles from Gavdos.</li>
    <li>Initial beliefs suggest the boats departed together from Libya.</li>
    <li>Instances of migrant boat incidents have increased off Crete and Gavdos in the past year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“In 2023, hundreds of migrants drowned when an overcrowded vessel capsized and sank in international waters off the southwestern Greek coastal town of Pylos.”</blockquote>
<p>The tragedy highlights the ongoing dangers faced by migrants attempting to cross the Mediterranean Sea in search of a better life in Europe.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dawn.com/news/1878730</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dawn.com/news/1878730</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 16:56:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 6 safest cities in the world in 2024 - DNA India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxNTVpKNFdzR0NUb1luVklPQWFUMXY1dXB0VUtKN1Z5NjhsSk90U2xLUGQwSmowUTZ1LTczU2RFUkpBR2ZBMmt4YzM2UFYyaVQ2LTJQUGNnT3RDSFRocXVNcTV5N0NnX3Q1LW94bEpIazhIX1JsbWhZWUIwV1E0bEx0UzVuZ19jd2s0ZlFvX3hXTTBRWk14VFZPV0h6bHFsQdIBngFBVV95cUxNTVpKNFdzR0NUb1luVklPQWFUMXY1dXB0VUtKN1Z5NjhsSk90U2xLUGQwSmowUTZ1LTczU2RFUkpBR2ZBMmt4YzM2UFYyaVQ2LTJQUGNnT3RDSFRocXVNcTV5N0NnX3Q1LW94bEpIazhIX1JsbWhZWUIwV1E0bEx0UzVuZ19jd2s0ZlFvX3hXTTBRWk14VFZPV0h6bHFsQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMingFBVV95cUxNTVpKNFdzR0NUb1luVklPQWFUMXY1dXB0VUtKN1Z5NjhsSk90U2xLUGQwSmowUTZ1LTczU2RFUkpBR2ZBMmt4YzM2UFYyaVQ2LTJQUGNnT3RDSFRocXVNcTV5N0NnX3Q1LW94bEpIazhIX1JsbWhZWUIwV1E0bEx0UzVuZ19jd2s0ZlFvX3hXTTBRWk14VFZPV0h6bHFsQdIBngFBVV95cUxNTVpKNFdzR0NUb1luVklPQWFUMXY1dXB0VUtKN1Z5NjhsSk90U2xLUGQwSmowUTZ1LTczU2RFUkpBR2ZBMmt4YzM2UFYyaVQ2LTJQUGNnT3RDSFRocXVNcTV5N0NnX3Q1LW94bEpIazhIX1JsbWhZWUIwV1E0bEx0UzVuZ19jd2s0ZlFvX3hXTTBRWk14VFZPV0h6bHFsQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 16:21:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi FM joins Arab, US diplomats in calling for new, inclusive Syrian state - Arab News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saudi FM joins Arab, US diplomats in calling for new, inclusive Syrian state</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Arab News</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://www.arabnews.com/sites/default/files/pictures/December/17/2024/afp_20241212_36q99le_v4_highres_syriaconflictdrugscaptagon_renamed_on_20241214.jpeg" alt="Captagon Drug Seizures">
    <figcaption>The ousted president, HTS leader Abu Mohammed Al-Golani said, had caused the country to become “a major Captagon factory in the world, and today Syria is being cleansed of it.” (AFP)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For over a decade, Syria has been a center of Captagon production, raising concerns about the drug's massive impact across the Middle East, particularly among the youth in Gulf states like Saudi Arabia.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The New Lines Institute launched an online tool to track the Captagon trade on December 4.</li>
    <li>After the Syrian regime's collapse, numerous Captagon labs were found abandoned in former regime-held areas.</li>
    <li>HTS leader Abu Mohammed Al-Golani condemned the drug and blamed the Assad regime for its proliferation.</li>
    <li>Syria's reputation as a production hub is likely shifting, with new labs emerging in Iraq, Lebanon, and Turkiye.</li>
    <li>Reports indicate that Captagon production is continuing despite the regime's fall.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “I think what we’re going to see now is overspill...production is being squeezed inside Syria, but we are going to see the emergence of larger-scale Captagon production facilities in a few countries where alarm bells have already been ringing.” – Caroline Rose, New Lines Institute
</blockquote>
<p>Despite the regime's collapse, experts warn that the Captagon trade will continue with evolving dynamics, complicating regional security efforts against drug smuggling.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.arabnews.com/node/2583018/middle-east</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.arabnews.com/node/2583018/middle-east</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 16:18:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[18,000 Indians at risk of being deported from US as Trump vows immigration crackdown - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>18,000 Indians at risk of being deported from US as Trump vows immigration crackdown</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert source]</p>
<p>US President-elect Donald Trump is set to take office soon, and stricter immigration policies are beginning to take effect, placing approximately 18,000 undocumented Indians at risk of deportation.</p>
<ul>
    <li>ICE has released a list of 1.45 million people targeted for deportation, including nearly 18,000 Indians.</li>
    <li>Legalizing status for many undocumented Indians is complicated, often taking two to three years.</li>
    <li>India ranks 13th in the number of undocumented immigrants, with 17,940 individuals, while countries like Honduras and Guatemala have higher numbers.</li>
    <li>India is classified as an “uncooperative” country in the deportation process, alongside several others.</li>
    <li>Trump plans to implement significant deportation efforts, aiming to send thousands of undocumented Indians back to India.</li>
    <li>Over the past three years, about 90,000 Indians were apprehended attempting to enter the US illegally.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “I’ll get them into every country, or we won’t do business with those countries,” Trump stated. 
    “I want them out, and the countries have got to take them back. If they don’t take them back, we won’t do business with those countries, and we will impose substantial tariffs on them.”
</blockquote>
<p>The implementation of Trump's immigration policies is expected to pose serious challenges for undocumented Indians in the US, and may impact diplomatic relations between the US and India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/us-trump-immigration-crackdown-deportation-of-indians-9725087/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/us-trump-immigration-crackdown-deportation-of-indians-9725087/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 16:05:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What happened during Assad's final hours in Syria: Deception, despair and flight - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What happened during Assad's final hours in Syria: Deception, despair and flight</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Syria-4_1734190503069_1734190650507.jpg" alt="A torn poster shows ousted Syrian President Bashar Assad at the entrance of the notorious security detention centre called Palestine Branch, in Damascus, Syria." title="A torn poster shows ousted Syrian President Bashar Assad at the entrance of the notorious security detention centre called Palestine Branch, in Damascus, Syria.">
<figcaption>A torn poster shows ousted Syrian President Bashar Assad at the entrance of the notorious security detention centre called Palestine Branch, in Damascus, Syria, Saturday, Dec. 14, 2024.(AP)</figcaption>
<p>The article discusses the final hours of Bashar al-Assad's rule in Syria, detailing his secretive plans to flee the country amidst collapsing power and escalating rebel control.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Assad's departure was planned and executed without informing key aides and family members.</li>
    <li>On the eve of his flight, he assured military chiefs of Russian support while masking the true dire situation.</li>
    <li>He fled to Russia on December 8, 2024, after disguising the flight under radar.</li>
    <li>Significant unrest in Damascus accompanied Assad's departure, with civilians celebrating the fall of his regime.</li>
    <li>There were no military rescue efforts from Russia or Iran despite previous support during the civil war.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Assad didn't even make a last stand. He didn't even rally his own troops," said Nadim Houri, executive director of the Arab Reform Initiative.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Bashar al-Assad's flight marked the end of his 24-year rule and the demise of his family's long-standing power, leaving a pivotal moment in Syria's tumultuous history.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-russia-damascus-civil-war-101734190324252.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-russia-damascus-civil-war-101734190324252.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:50:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk reacts to Donald Trump’s viral meme featuring his mug shot - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-reacts-to-donald-trumps-viral-meme-featuring-his-mug-shot/articleshow/116321115.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-reacts-to-donald-trumps-viral-meme-featuring-his-mug-shot/articleshow/116321115.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi FM joins Arab, US diplomats to discuss Syria’s future - Arab News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saudi FM joins Arab, US diplomats to discuss Syria’s future</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 14, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Arab News</p>
<img src="https://www.arabnews.pk/sites/default/files/pictures/December/2999496/2024/syria_3_1.jpg" alt="Turkey's Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan" width="1200" height="707">
<figcaption>Turkey's Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan, left, speaks with US Secretary of State Antony Blinken during a meeting with the foreign ministers of the Arab Contact Group on Syria in Jordan's southern Red Sea coastal city of Aqaba, on Dec. 14, 2024. (AP)</figcaption>
<p>Top diplomats from the United States, Turkiye, the European Union, and Arab nations convened in Aqaba, Jordan, to discuss Syria's political future and the transition from President Bashar Assad's regime.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The meeting involved key players including US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan, and foreign ministers from various Arab nations.</li>
    <li>The focal point of discussions was the future of Syria and ensuring a political process that is inclusive and respects minority rights.</li>
    <li>Turkiye confirmed the resumption of its embassy operations in Damascus, indicating a major shift in its diplomatic stance.</li>
    <li>Russian and Iranian diplomats, Assad's primary supporters, were notably absent from the talks.</li>
    <li>Diplomats expressed concern over the importance of preventing a sectarian partition of Syria.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"It is a time of both opportunity but also real challenge for Syria." - Antony Blinken</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the meeting marks a significant step in international efforts to shape Syria's political landscape post-Assad, with a strong emphasis on collaboration among involved nations to support a stable and inclusive governance structure in the region.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.arabnews.com/node/2583018/middle-east</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.arabnews.com/node/2583018/middle-east</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:54:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive: Russia pulling back but not out of Syria, sources say - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/russia-pulling-back-not-out-syria-sources-say-2024-12-14/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/russia-pulling-back-not-out-syria-sources-say-2024-12-14/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:33:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“Starlink Killer” Tech! Russia Claims Developing Kalinka System That Can Locate, Detect & Disrupt Its Signals - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>“Starlink Killer" Tech! Russia Claims Developing Kalinka System That Can Locate, Detect & Disrupt Its Signals</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> EurAsian Times</p>
<figure>
    <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/91/Starlink_Mission_%2847926144123%29.jpg/800px-Starlink_Mission_%2847926144123%29.jpg" alt="Starlink - Wikipedia" width="800" height="450">
    <figcaption>Starlink – Wikipedia</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The Russian Federation has reportedly developed the Kalinka system, designed to locate and disrupt signals from SpaceX's Starlink, which has played a crucial role for Ukraine in the ongoing conflict.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Kalinka system aims to detect and counter Starlink communications used by Ukrainian forces.</li>
    <li>It is currently undergoing combat tests and can identify unmanned boats and drones.</li>
    <li>The system allows Russian forces to target Starlink-linked assets from a distance of up to 15 kilometers.</li>
    <li>Kalinka can detect both moving and stationary Starlink communication nodes.</li>
    <li>It is part of a broader initiative supported by Russia's United Russia party, involving over 200 defense technology companies.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    <p>“Before the introduction of Kalinka, unmanned boats were tracked visually.” - Andrei Bezrukov, chairman of the board of the Center for Unmanned Systems and Technologies</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The development of the Kalinka system highlights ongoing efforts to counter the advantages provided by Starlink technology in warfare, particularly in the context of the Russia-Ukraine conflict and concerns from China regarding Starlink's military utility.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/starlink-killer-tech-russia-claims-developing/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/starlink-killer-tech-russia-claims-developing/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:06:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Luigi Mangione's new lawyer is connected to Sean 'Diddy' Combs - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/how-luigi-mangiones-new-lawyer-is-connected-to-sean-diddy-combs/articleshow/116319921.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/how-luigi-mangiones-new-lawyer-is-connected-to-sean-diddy-combs/articleshow/116319921.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How the future job market in Saudi Arabia will evolve - Gulf News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>How the future job market in Saudi Arabia will evolve</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Gulf News</p>
<img src="https://imagevars.gulfnews.com/2024/12/14/How-the-future-job-market-in-Saudi-Arabia-will-evolve_193c5834c3d_medium.jpg" alt="How the future job market in Saudi Arabia will evolve">
<figcaption>Representational image. <span>Image Credit: Shutterstock</span></figcaption>
<p>The job market in Saudi Arabia is undergoing significant changes as the kingdom seeks to diversify its economy and reduce its reliance on oil in line with the ambitious Saudi Vision 2030 development plan.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The Saudi Vision 2030 plan aims to transform the economy by developing various sectors and creating new jobs in high technology and advanced industries.</li>
    <li>Khalil Al Dhiyabi highlights the focus on digital transformation, employment in emerging sectors, and promoting innovation and entrepreneurship.</li>
    <li>Key sectors expected to grow include artificial intelligence, information technology, cybersecurity, renewable energy, and health care.</li>
    <li>The government supports SMEs and digital qualification programs to provide job opportunities and reduce unemployment rates.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Now the Saudi market is witnessing major changes that depend on technological development and the shift to the non-oil sectors such as renewable energy, artificial intelligence, tourism, technology, and modern industries." - Khalil Al Dhiyabi</blockquote>
<p>The evolution of the job market is set to create numerous opportunities in various sectors, significantly altering the employment landscape in Saudi Arabia as it moves toward a more diversified economy.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://gulfnews.com/world/gulf/saudi/how-the-future-job-market-in-saudi-arabia-will-evolve-1.1734185288650</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gulfnews.com/world/gulf/saudi/how-the-future-job-market-in-saudi-arabia-will-evolve-1.1734185288650</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 14:04:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 most expensive foods in the world - Recipes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPOUdIb29ZamVBUFdIczRjMjRnSDVwci1VSVcyOFM1bnBSVVdsdXRURUZRam9OTUVvT0U1WkVVTmNiZFZBaEF0UGl1U2E3NWVicl85Vm1UWnl4ejU3Q1dMNDVpOXY3dEVDM3V2LVlqWEJFWVZZVWVrNG1GR2V2dmpicm03cFJoSjg5QlVpTUFVd2lMUWU2b0dQb0FXZDl1cnRva1dSelVBU2NIZ9IBqgFBVV95cUxPOUdIb29ZamVBUFdIczRjMjRnSDVwci1VSVcyOFM1bnBSVVdsdXRURUZRam9OTUVvT0U1WkVVTmNiZFZBaEF0UGl1U2E3NWVicl85Vm1UWnl4ejU3Q1dMNDVpOXY3dEVDM3V2LVlqWEJFWVZZVWVrNG1GR2V2dmpicm03cFJoSjg5QlVpTUFVd2lMUWU2b0dQb0FXZDl1cnRva1dSelVBU2NIZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPOUdIb29ZamVBUFdIczRjMjRnSDVwci1VSVcyOFM1bnBSVVdsdXRURUZRam9OTUVvT0U1WkVVTmNiZFZBaEF0UGl1U2E3NWVicl85Vm1UWnl4ejU3Q1dMNDVpOXY3dEVDM3V2LVlqWEJFWVZZVWVrNG1GR2V2dmpicm03cFJoSjg5QlVpTUFVd2lMUWU2b0dQb0FXZDl1cnRva1dSelVBU2NIZ9IBqgFBVV95cUxPOUdIb29ZamVBUFdIczRjMjRnSDVwci1VSVcyOFM1bnBSVVdsdXRURUZRam9OTUVvT0U1WkVVTmNiZFZBaEF0UGl1U2E3NWVicl85Vm1UWnl4ejU3Q1dMNDVpOXY3dEVDM3V2LVlqWEJFWVZZVWVrNG1GR2V2dmpicm03cFJoSjg5QlVpTUFVd2lMUWU2b0dQb0FXZDl1cnRva1dSelVBU2NIZw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baba Vanga's 2025 Predictions.. - Greatandhra]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Baba Vanga's 2025 Predictions</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<img src="https://www.greatandhra.com/newphotos10/teliphatic1734181084.jpeg" alt="Baba Vanga's 2025 Predictions">
<figcaption>Baba Vanga, the "Nostradamus of the Balkans."</figcaption>
<p>Baba Vanga, a blind Bulgarian mystic often called the "Nostradamus of the Balkans," remains a subject of fascination due to her intriguing prophecies.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Foresees a devastating war between the West and East, potentially leading to Europe's destruction.</li>
    <li>Predicts that Syria's fall will mark the beginning of catastrophic events.</li>
    <li>Claims of alien contact warn of a global crisis or even an apocalypse.</li>
    <li>Anticipates humanity achieving telepathic communication by 2025, influenced by technologies like Elon Musk's brain chip.</li>
    <li>Foresees groundbreaking scientific and medical advances, particularly in nanotechnology, while cautioning against potential misuse.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Baba Vanga's predictions remain both alarming and thought-provoking, drawing constant interest and debate."</blockquote>
<p>Overall, while many claim that Baba Vanga's predictions often come true, others believe they are merely random statements open to broad interpretation.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/baba-vangas-2025-predictions-142736</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.greatandhra.com/movies/news/baba-vangas-2025-predictions-142736</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:01:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Until my last breath’: Searching for relatives at Syria’s ‘slaughterhouse’ - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2024/12/14/until-my-last-breath-searching-for-relatives-at-syrias-slaughterhouse</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2024/12/14/until-my-last-breath-searching-for-relatives-at-syrias-slaughterhouse</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:00:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[F-22: Why This Jet Is Everyone’s Favorite ‘Almost’ Stealth Bomber - Indian Defence Review]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>F-22: Why This Jet Is Everyone’s Favorite ‘Almost’ Stealth Bomber</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> December 14, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Indian Defence Review</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://indiandefencereview.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/f-22-raptor-iconic-air-superiority-fighter-that-almost-became-stealth-bomber.jpg" alt="F-22 Raptor" width="1280" height="720">
    <figcaption>F-22: Why This Jet Is Everyone’s Favorite ‘Almost’ Stealth Bomber - © Indian Defence Review</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The F-22 Raptor, known for its unmatched capabilities as an air superiority fighter, was once considered for transformation into the FB-22 stealth bomber variant, a concept that reflects the changing dynamics of military aviation.</p>
<ul>
    <li>1999 Congressional report raised alarms about the aging bomber fleet and obsolescence of non-stealth aircraft.</li>
    <li>The FB-22 was proposed as an interim solution, adapting the F-22 airframe to meet strategic needs.</li>
    <li>Significant modifications included redesigned wings, enlarged weapon bays, and increased fuel capacity.</li>
    <li>The FB-22 aimed to triple the F-22's combat radius from 600 to 1,600 miles.</li>
    <li>The program was ultimately shelved due to budget constraints and shifting priorities, leading to the development of the B-21 Raider.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    "The FB-22’s proposed capabilities would have positioned it as a unique asset in the Air Force arsenal."
</blockquote>
<p>The cancellation of the FB-22 highlights the complexities of military planning, but its legacy continues to influence future innovations in airpower, emphasizing the importance of adaptability in modern warfare.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indiandefencereview.com/f-22-raptor-iconic-air-superiority-fighter-that-almost-became-stealth-bomber/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indiandefencereview.com/f-22-raptor-iconic-air-superiority-fighter-that-almost-became-stealth-bomber/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Faith leaders cautiously ‘optimistic’ about Trump's second term as president - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Faith leaders cautiously ‘optimistic’ about Trump's second term as president</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 06:16 PM IST</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/Trump-Seafood-0_1734083712157_1734180381774.jpg" alt="FILE - President Donald Trump attends a roundtable discussion with commercial fishermen at Bangor International Airport in Bangor, Maine, June 5, 2020. (AP Photo/Patrick Semansky, File)(AP)" title="FILE - President Donald Trump attends a roundtable discussion with commercial fishermen at Bangor International Airport in Bangor, Maine, June 5, 2020. (AP Photo/Patrick Semansky, File)(AP)">
<figcaption>FILE - President Donald Trump attends a roundtable discussion with commercial fishermen at Bangor International Airport in Bangor, Maine, June 5, 2020. (AP Photo/Patrick Semansky, File)(AP)</figcaption>
<p>Leaders of religious communities in the United States express a cautiously optimistic outlook regarding Donald Trump's second term as president, although some harbor significant concerns.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Religious leaders report a mixed reaction towards Trump's presidency, with some communities feeling optimistic while others remain concerned.</li>
    <li>Haris Tarin from the Muslim Public Affairs Council highlights "sceptical optimism" among faith leaders.</li>
    <li>Rabbi Jo David notes positive feelings within some Jewish communities, while acknowledging serious concerns in others.</li>
    <li>Leaders hope for the protection of civil rights for all Americans, particularly American Muslims.</li>
    <li>There is a desire for a cease-fire in the ongoing conflict in Gaza.</li>
    <li>Pastor Lorenzo Sewell believes Trump could become "the greatest president in history" with the right approach.</li>
    <li>Samuel Rodriguez emphasizes a potential focus on protecting religious freedom and a greater role for faith-based organizations in society.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
    “I think there's a mixed reaction, but there's a sceptical optimism.” - Haris Tarin
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
    “I also anticipate an administration that values the contributions of people of faith, not as something to tolerate but as an essential cornerstone of our nation.” - Samuel Rodriguez
</blockquote>
<p>The overall sentiment among faith leaders is one of cautious optimism, alongside hopes for safeguarding rights and navigating critical global issues during Trump's expected presidency.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/faith-leaders-cautiously-optimistic-about-trumps-second-term-as-president-101734178796923.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/faith-leaders-cautiously-optimistic-about-trumps-second-term-as-president-101734178796923.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:46:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korean demonstrators bring K-pop lights to impeachment protest; reigniting it as a symbol of resistance - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korean demonstrators bring K-pop lights to impeachment protest; reigniting it as a symbol of resistance</h1>
<p><strong>Published on:</strong> Dec 14, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/14/550x309/SOUTHKOREA-POLITICS--79_1734176851704_1734177428777.JPG" alt="South Koreans held a rally recently, as President Yoon Suk Yeol declared to pass martial law. The protestors gathered with K-pop lights, which are traditionally seen in K-pop concerts but became a symbol of resistance at the recent demonstrations." />
<figcaption>South Koreans held a rally recently, as President Yoon Suk Yeol declared to pass martial law. The protestors gathered with K-pop lights, which are traditionally seen in K-pop concerts but became a symbol of resistance at the recent demonstrations. (REUTERS/Kim Soo-hyeon)</figcaption>
<p>South Korean citizens held a rally to protest against President Yoon Suk Yeol's attempt to pass martial law, showcasing a vibrant display of K-pop lights as a symbol of resistance.</p>
<ul>
    <li>The protest included a large gathering of citizens dressed in colorful costumes.</li>
    <li>K-pop light sticks, while originally used at concerts, were prominently displayed by demonstrators.</li>
    <li>Protesters chanted for impeachment, holding their lights in various creative ways.</li>
    <li>Participants wore additional neon accessories, including goggles, to enhance their display.</li>
    <li>Alongside lights, many carried placards demanding action against the government's moves.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Their demands called for the impeachment, with chants echoing throughout the assembly." - AP Photo/Lee Jin-man</blockquote>
<p>This rally signifies the growing movement among South Koreans to express their dissent through creative and cultural symbols, as K-pop lights transform into a beacon of political resistance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/photos/south-korean-demonstrators-bring-k-pop-lights-to-impeachment-protest-reigniting-it-as-a-symbol-of-resistance-101734176874700.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/photos/south-korean-demonstrators-bring-k-pop-lights-to-impeachment-protest-reigniting-it-as-a-symbol-of-resistance-101734176874700.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:22:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>