<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 21:19:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 21:19:30 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Several Injured In Germany After Car Drove Into Crowd At Christmas Market; Driver Arrested: Police - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Several Injured In Germany After Car Drove Into Crowd At Christmas Market; Driver Arrested: Police</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 21, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Associated Press</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Several people were injured in the incident in Magdeburg, police said." title="Several people were injured in the incident in Magdeburg, police said."><figcaption>Several people were injured in the incident in Magdeburg, police said. [Courtesy: @CollinRugg/X]</figcaption><p>A car drove into a group of people at a Christmas market in the eastern German city of Magdeburg on Friday. The driver was arrested, and there was no immediate information on whether anyone was killed.</p><ul><li>A car drove into a crowd at a Christmas market in Magdeburg, Germany.</li><li>The driver was arrested by police.</li><li>The incident raised concerns due to a previous attack in 2016 where 13 people died in Berlin.</li><li>German Interior Minister stated there were no concrete indications of danger to Christmas markets this year.</li><li>This is an ongoing story and updates will follow.</li></ul><blockquote><p>On Dec. 19, 2016 in Berlin, an Islamic extremist attacker plowed through a crowd of Christmas market-goers with a truck, leaving 13 people dead and injuring dozens more.</p></blockquote><p>This incident has stirred up fears reminiscent of past attacks during the holiday season in Europe.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/several-injured-in-germany-as-car-drives-into-crowd-at-christmas-market-driver-arrested-police-9163440.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/several-injured-in-germany-as-car-drives-into-crowd-at-christmas-market-driver-arrested-police-9163440.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 19:50:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Key Ally To Canada PM Trudeau Says He Will Vote To Bring Him Down - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Key Ally to Canada PM Trudeau Says He Will Vote to Bring Him Down</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> NDTV</p>
<p>The head of a Canadian political party has announced support for a motion of no-confidence against Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, potentially leading to an election.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Jagmeet Singh, leader of the New Democratic Party, stated he would vote in favor of a no-confidence motion.</li>
  <li>If opposition parties unite, Trudeau's government may collapse, leading to a new election.</li>
  <li>The House of Commons is currently on break and the motion can only be introduced after January 27.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If all the opposition parties do vote together on a motion of no-confidence in the Liberal government, Trudeau will lose power and an election will occur.”</blockquote>
<p>This development marks a significant shift in Canadian politics as key support for Trudeau hangs in the balance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/key-ally-to-canada-pm-justin-trudeau-says-he-will-vote-to-bring-him-down-7296901</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/key-ally-to-canada-pm-justin-trudeau-says-he-will-vote-to-bring-him-down-7296901</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:23:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govt shutdown crisis averted? Elon Musk's 2-word reaction to new spending bill plan - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Govt shutdown crisis averted? Elon Musk's 2-word reaction to new spending bill plan</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> Recent date <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Times of India logo"><figcaption>Times of India</figcaption><p>The article discusses the recent approval of a new spending bill aimed at preventing a government shutdown, alongside Elon Musk's succinct two-word reaction.</p><ul><li>The government faced a potential shutdown due to funding disputes.</li><li>The new spending bill has garnered mixed reactions from political figures.</li><li>Elon Musk's brief response highlights his engagement with current events.</li></ul><blockquote>"The future is uncertain..." - Elon Musk</blockquote><p>This new spending bill represents a significant move in addressing government funding and avoiding shutdown crises.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/govt-shutdown-crisis-averted-elon-musks-2-word-reaction-to-new-spending-bill-plan/articleshow/116513667.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/govt-shutdown-crisis-averted-elon-musks-2-word-reaction-to-new-spending-bill-plan/articleshow/116513667.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Trudeau Failed In Biggest Job': Jagmeet Singh-led NDP To Vote To Bring Canada Govt Down - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>NDP to Vote Against Trudeau: A Critical Move for Canada</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 21, 2024<br /><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Jagmeet Singh's NDP parted ways with a supply-and-confidence deal with Trudeau's Liberal Party in September. (Reuters)" loading="eager" /><figcaption>Jagmeet Singh's NDP parted ways with a supply-and-confidence deal with Trudeau's Liberal Party in September. (Reuters)</figcaption></figure><p>Jagmeet Singh, leader of the New Democratic Party (NDP), has announced that his caucus will vote to bring down the Canadian government led by Prime Minister Justin Trudeau. Singh criticized Trudeau for failing to work for the people and indicated this move may jeopardize Trudeau's standing in government.</p><ul><li>Singh declared that the NDP will no longer support Trudeau's minority government.</li><li>He stated, "The Liberals don’t deserve another chance" and will introduce a no-confidence motion.</li><li>The NDP's decision significantly weakens Trudeau's government, which relies on their support.</li><li>The announcement follows recent calls for Trudeau to resign amidst rising dissatisfaction.</li></ul><blockquote><p>"Justin Trudeau failed in the biggest job a Prime Minister has: to work for people, not the powerful. The NDP will vote to bring this government down, and give Canadians a chance to vote for a government who will work for them." — Jagmeet Singh</p></blockquote><p>This pivotal move by the NDP could lead to significant political shifts in Canada, as Trudeau faces mounting pressure and calls for leadership change.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/canada-justin-trudeau-setback-jagmeet-singh-ndp-will-vote-to-bring-govt-down-liberal-party-latest-news-9163360.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/canada-justin-trudeau-setback-jagmeet-singh-ndp-will-vote-to-bring-govt-down-liberal-party-latest-news-9163360.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:47:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`This is his problem,` Trump says let the US govt shutdown happen under Biden admin - WION]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This is his problem, Trump says let the US govt shutdown happen under Biden admin</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> WIONews</p>
<img src="//cdn.wionews.com/sites/default/files/2024/09/26/456938-author-profilr.png?im=FitAndFill=(90,90)" alt="Prapti Upadhayay" loading="lazy">
<figcaption>Prapti Upadhayay is a New Delhi-based journalist who reports on key news developments across India and global affairs, with a special focus on US politics.</figcaption>
<p>Donald Trump has made his intentions clear regarding a possible government shutdown, insisting that it should occur under President Joe Biden’s administration.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump stated that government shutdowns should start now under Biden, labeling it a problem for Biden to address.</li>
  <li>House Republicans are preparing to pass a bill to prevent a shutdown, which requires only a simple majority.</li>
  <li>Elon Musk has faced criticism from Democrats regarding his influence in the Republican Party and his opposition to a bipartisan spending bill.</li>
  <li>Karoline Leavitt mentioned Trump's leading role in shaping Republican views on the continuing resolution.</li>
  <li>Senator Bernie Sanders criticized Musk's intervention in budget negotiations.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“If there is going to be a shutdown of government, let it begin now, under the Biden Administration, not after January 20th, under ‘TRUMP.’ This is a Biden problem to solve.” – Donald Trump</blockquote>
<p>This ongoing debate highlights the deepening partisan divide in U.S. politics, with significant implications for government funding and bipartisan relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wionews.com/world/this-is-his-problem-trump-says-let-the-us-govt-shutdown-happen-under-biden-admin-785664</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wionews.com/world/this-is-his-problem-trump-says-let-the-us-govt-shutdown-happen-under-biden-admin-785664</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 17:06:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Failed in biggest job a PM has’: Trudeau's ally says will vote to bring down Canadian government - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>‘Failed in biggest job a PM has’: Trudeau's ally says will vote to bring down Canadian government</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>An ally of Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has announced intentions to vote to bring down the government amidst severe criticism, highlighting the political turmoil currently facing the administration.</p><ul><li>Ally's claim of Trudeau failing in his responsibilities.</li><li>The vote aims to challenge the stability of the current government.</li><li>This move could lead to significant political shifts in Canada.</li></ul><blockquote>“Failed in biggest job a PM has”</blockquote><p>This development showcases the growing discontent within Trudeau's party, potentially indicating bigger political ramifications for Canada.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/failed-in-biggest-job-a-pm-has-trudeaus-ally-says-will-vote-to-bring-down-canadian-government/articleshow/116511676.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/failed-in-biggest-job-a-pm-has-trudeaus-ally-says-will-vote-to-bring-down-canadian-government/articleshow/116511676.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Syria’s de facto leader defends telling woman to cover her hair for photo - The Times of Israel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesofisrael.com/syrias-de-facto-leader-defends-telling-woman-to-cover-her-hair-for-photo/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesofisrael.com/syrias-de-facto-leader-defends-telling-woman-to-cover-her-hair-for-photo/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 16:38:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US bans drones in parts of New Jersey and New York, threatens use of ‘deadly force’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US bans drones in parts of New Jersey and New York, threatens use of ‘deadly force’</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><figure><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/Drone_1734152639153_1734706218686.jpg" alt="This photo provided by Brian Glenn shows what appears to be multiple drones flying over Bernardsville, N.J., on Thursday, Dec. 5, 2024 (Brian Glenn/TMX via AP, File)(AP)"><figcaption>This photo provided by Brian Glenn shows what appears to be multiple drones flying over Bernardsville, N.J., on Thursday, Dec. 5, 2024 (Brian Glenn/TMX via AP, File)(AP)</figcaption></figure><p>The Federal Aviation Authority (FAA) has implemented a ban on drones in parts of New Jersey due to public concerns stemming from mystery drone sightings. The ban has now been extended to critical infrastructure sites in New York City.</p><ul><li>The FAA's ban prohibits drone flights below 400 feet in specific areas of New Jersey, including Jersey City and Elizabeth.</li><li>Law enforcement will intercept any drones that violate the restrictions.</li><li>The ban in New Jersey will run through January 17, and the New York restrictions will last until January 19.</li><li>Officials describe the actions as precautionary and emphasize that currently, there are no threats to critical infrastructure.</li></ul><blockquote>“The fact that they are taking action is a first step.” - Michael Melham, Mayor of Belleville</blockquote><p>This ban reflects ongoing concerns about drone activities and the safety of public infrastructure. The FAA will continue to monitor the situation closely.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/us-bans-drones-in-parts-of-new-jersey-new-york-threatens-use-of-deadly-force-101734702351912.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/us-bans-drones-in-parts-of-new-jersey-new-york-threatens-use-of-deadly-force-101734702351912.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:51:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Buy more oil and gas from US or... ': Trump warns European Union over trade deficit - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Urges EU to Buy More US Oil and Gas Amid Trade Deficit Concerns</h1><p><strong>Published on: </strong>October 23, 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><p>In a recent statement, former President Donald Trump warned the European Union about its trade deficit with the United States, urging them to increase their imports of American oil and gas as a countermeasure.</p><ul><li>Trump emphasized the need for the EU to address the imbalance in trade with the US.</li><li>He highlighted the importance of energy independence and the benefits of US resources.</li><li>The remarks come amidst rising tensions regarding energy security in Europe.</li></ul><blockquote>"The EU must act now to buy more of our oil and gas or risk further economic repercussions." - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>The statement from Trump has reignited discussions on US-EU trade relations and the strategic importance of energy resources amidst global market fluctuations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/buy-more-oil-and-gas-from-us-or-trump-warns-european-union-over-trade-deficit/articleshow/116509028.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/buy-more-oil-and-gas-from-us-or-trump-warns-european-union-over-trade-deficit/articleshow/116509028.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump says shutdown should begin now and not after...: 'This is a Biden problem' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump Emphasizes Immediate Government Shutdown: 'This is a Biden Problem'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 1, 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Times</p>
<p>Former President Donald Trump has called for a government shutdown to begin immediately, asserting that the current administration is responsible for the issues facing the government.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump insists that the shutdown should not be delayed.</li>
  <li>He blames President Biden for the current state of affairs in Washington.</li>
  <li>The former president's comments reflect ongoing tensions within the Republican party regarding fiscal responsibility.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"This is a Biden problem; they need to deal with it now," Trump stated during a rally.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, Trump's remarks are part of a broader discussion within the GOP about government funding and priorities as Congress faces a budgetary crisis.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-says-shutdown-should-begin-now-and-not-after-this-is-a-biden-problem/articleshow/116508793.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-says-shutdown-should-begin-now-and-not-after-this-is-a-biden-problem/articleshow/116508793.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 14:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia strikes Kyiv with missiles, Ukraine says 6 embassies damaged; Portugal condemns attack - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia strikes Kyiv with missiles, Ukraine says 6 embassies damaged; Portugal condemns attack</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> December 20, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> Associated Press</p>
<img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-2024-12-20T191018.166-2024-12-fe99b64fd8b3e14f2bc34e0a82e36a83.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="Russia strikes Kyiv with missiles, Ukraine says 6 embassies damaged; Portugal condemns attack">
<figcaption>A woman paces past buildings destroyed by recent Russian attacks in Kyiv, Ukraine, Friday, Dec. 20, 2024. AP</figcaption>
<p>On December 20, 2024, Russia launched a missile attack on Kyiv that resulted in one death and extensive damage to diplomatic missions and civilian infrastructure.</p>
<ul>
<li>The attacks damaged six embassies including those of Albania, Argentina, North Macedonia, Palestine, Portugal, and Montenegro.</li>
<li>A total of 630 residential buildings, 16 medical facilities, and 30 schools lost heating due to the strikes.</li>
<li>Ukraine's air force intercepted five Iskander missiles targeting the city.</li>
<li>The bombing was a response to a recent Ukrainian missile strike on Rostov, Russia.</li>
<li>Portugal condemned the attack and summoned the Russian charge d'affaires.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There was a very intense attack by the Russian Federation on the city of Kyiv, and one of the explosions caused relatively light material damage to the diplomatic facilities of several countries, including the chancery of the Portuguese embassy,” - Paulo Rangel, Portuguese Foreign Minister.</blockquote>
<p>This attack marks the continuation of hostilities that began almost three years ago, highlighting ongoing tensions and the impact on both civilian life and diplomatic relations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/world/russia-strikes-kyiv-with-missiles-ukraine-says-6-embassies-damaged-portugal-condemns-attack-13846365.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/world/russia-strikes-kyiv-with-missiles-ukraine-says-6-embassies-damaged-portugal-condemns-attack-13846365.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:41:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[European markets slide; Novo Nordisk down 20% after obesity drug results - CNBC]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>European Markets Decline; Novo Nordisk Shares Drop After Drug Trial Results</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 20, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> CNBC</p>
<p>The European markets saw significant declines as investors reacted to political instability in the U.S. and monetary policy shifts across Europe. Novo Nordisk's stock suffered a major drop following disappointing results from a key drug trial.</p>
<ul>
  <li>European markets were overall down, with the pan-European Stoxx 600 index falling by 1.7%.</li>
  <li>Political turmoil in the U.S. contributed to market apprehension, with a partial government shutdown imminent due to legislative failures.</li>
  <li>Novo Nordisk experienced its largest drop, losing over 20% of its value after news from a trial of its CagriSema obesity drug.</li>
  <li>China kept its interest rates steady, reflecting careful economic management amid monetary policy updates from major western economies.</li>
  <li>Bitcoin prices fell by approximately 8%, marking volatility in the cryptocurrency market.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The U.S. president-elect has issued a fresh trade threat to the EU regarding oil and gas purchases.”</blockquote>
<p>Overall, the combination of global political events and underwhelming corporate performances have resulted in heightened volatility in the European markets.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/20/european-markets-live-updates-us-government-shutdown-data-and-stocks.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/20/european-markets-live-updates-us-government-shutdown-data-and-stocks.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biden cancels nearly $4.3 billion more in student loans, ‘I promised to…’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Biden Cancels Nearly $4.3 Billion in Student Loans for Public Sector Workers</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 20, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/20/550x309/BIDEN-HARRIS-DNC-8_1734315801451_1734700773471.jpg" alt="President Joe Biden has cancelled nearly $4.3 billion in student loans(Bloomberg)" title="President Joe Biden has cancelled nearly $4.3 billion in student loans(Bloomberg)">
<figcaption>President Joe Biden has cancelled nearly $4.3 billion in student loans(Bloomberg)</figcaption>
<p>President Joe Biden has recently cancelled nearly $4.3 billion in student loans as a final act of forgiveness before leaving office, affecting about 55,000 public sector workers. This brings the total number of individuals relieved of their student loans to nearly five million.</p>
<ul>
<li>Biden's cancellation targets public sector workers including teachers, nurses, and law enforcement officials.</li>
<li>The total amount of student debt forgiven during Biden's presidency has reached nearly $180 billion for about five million borrowers.</li>
<li>This decision is part of Biden's commitment made during his 2020 campaign to provide student debt relief.</li>
<li>Despite the actions taken, Biden encountered challenges, especially with the Supreme Court rejecting broader debt relief for over 40 million people.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“From day one of my administration, I promised to make sure that higher education is a ticket to the middle class, not a barrier to opportunity.” - Joe Biden</blockquote>
<p>The recent cancellation of student loans underscores a significant achievement for Biden's administration, providing relief to many public service workers and emphasizing the importance of accessible higher education.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/biden-cancels-nearly-4-3-billion-more-in-student-loans-i-promised-to-101734700071104.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/biden-cancels-nearly-4-3-billion-more-in-student-loans-i-promised-to-101734700071104.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:20:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Tired of writing about dead children’: US official resigns over Israel-Gaza policy - The Siasat Daily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Official Resigns Over Israel-Gaza Policy Amid Growing Disillusionment</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 18, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Guardian</p><figure><img src="https://cdn.siasat.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Gaza-dead-child-780x470.jpg" alt="A woman mourns as she holds the shrouded body of her child who was killed during an Israeli strike on a school in Gaza City." width="1200" height="900"/><figcaption>A woman mourns as she holds the shrouded body of her child who was killed during an Israeli strike on a school in Gaza City. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Mike Casey, deputy political counsellor for Gaza at the US State Department, resigned due to dissatisfaction with the administration’s policy regarding Israel's actions in Gaza. His resignation highlights the growing frustration among US officials regarding the humanitarian crisis in the region.</p><ul><li>Casey resigned in July after four years, citing increasing disillusionment with bureaucratic processes.</li><li>He criticized the US approach as effectively following Israeli directives without an independent Palestinian policy.</li><li>Other US officials have also resigned in protest since the war on Gaza began.</li></ul><blockquote>“I got tired of writing about dead children.” – Mike Casey</blockquote><p>Casey's resignation underscores a significant rift within the US government pertaining to its foreign policy in the Middle East, particularly concerning humanitarian issues in Gaza.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.siasat.com/tired-of-writing-about-dead-children-us-official-resigns-over-israel-gaza-policy-3151397/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.siasat.com/tired-of-writing-about-dead-children-us-official-resigns-over-israel-gaza-policy-3151397/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump blames 'whoever is President' on looming shutdown crisis as White House sees action - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Blames 'Whoever is President' on Looming Shutdown Crisis as White House Sees Action</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>Unknown</p>
<p>As the threat of a government shutdown looms, former President Trump has pointed fingers at the current administration, asserting that whoever is in office bears responsibility for the potential crisis.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trump made statements blaming the current president for the shutdown threat.</li>
  <li>The White House is reportedly taking steps to prevent a shutdown.</li>
  <li>This situation impacts government operations and federal employees.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"Whoever is President should take responsibility for this situation," Trump stated.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, as the deadline approaches, political maneuvering intensifies with stakes high for both parties.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/trump-blames-whoever-is-president-on-looming-shutdown-crisis-as-white-house-sees-action/articleshow/116506443.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/trump-blames-whoever-is-president-on-looming-shutdown-crisis-as-white-house-sees-action/articleshow/116506443.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ukraine War: F-35, NASAMS ‘Put Into Action’ To Defend Rzeszów, A Critical Transit Point For Military Aid To Kyiv - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxQc0VmQTNWSmJuaEJCcEFCcHJCbkRvYzVFeUJVSU9TRXFuUVQ1NGRPUnJFbUlMOWhWUUR6bFZyd0dSdFZEbHRqWDhqX3BLQ2ZfQ3E0b2JubkUxRWV0UmQ0aEFpQ1JKcTVCZGhWZEZUSWdBWUd4dzNESExOQlhpU2oyd21BUdIBgwFBVV95cUxQc0VmQTNWSmJuaEJCcEFCcHJCbkRvYzVFeUJVSU9TRXFuUVQ1NGRPUnJFbUlMOWhWUUR6bFZyd0dSdFZEbHRqWDhqX3BLQ2ZfQ3E0b2JubkUxRWV0UmQ0aEFpQ1JKcTVCZGhWZEZUSWdBWUd4dzNESExOQlhpU2oyd21BUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxQc0VmQTNWSmJuaEJCcEFCcHJCbkRvYzVFeUJVSU9TRXFuUVQ1NGRPUnJFbUlMOWhWUUR6bFZyd0dSdFZEbHRqWDhqX3BLQ2ZfQ3E0b2JubkUxRWV0UmQ0aEFpQ1JKcTVCZGhWZEZUSWdBWUd4dzNESExOQlhpU2oyd21BUdIBgwFBVV95cUxQc0VmQTNWSmJuaEJCcEFCcHJCbkRvYzVFeUJVSU9TRXFuUVQ1NGRPUnJFbUlMOWhWUUR6bFZyd0dSdFZEbHRqWDhqX3BLQ2ZfQ3E0b2JubkUxRWV0UmQ0aEFpQ1JKcTVCZGhWZEZUSWdBWUd4dzNESExOQlhpU2oyd21BUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:02:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US government shutdown looms: What will be its impact and has it happened before? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US government shutdown looms: What will be its impact and has it happened before?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 2023 | <strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p>
<p>The looming potential for a government shutdown raises concerns about its impact on various sectors and the historical precedents it sets. This article explores the implications of a shutdown, looking back at previous instances to provide context for the current situation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The last government shutdown occurred in early 2019, lasting 35 days, affecting federal employees and services.</li>
  <li>Potential impacts of a shutdown include delays in federal payments, disruptions in public services, and economic repercussions.</li>
  <li>Government shutdowns often result from political disagreements over budget allocations and policy disagreements between parties.</li>
  <li>Historical analysis shows that previous shutdowns have varying effects depending on their duration and timing within the fiscal year.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“A government shutdown is a political tool that can have real-world consequences for millions of Americans.”</blockquote>
<p>The article emphasizes the importance of understanding both the immediate and long-term consequences of a shutdown, highlighting the need for bipartisan cooperation to avert these crises.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/us-government-shutdown-looms-what-will-be-its-impact-and-has-it-happened-before/articleshow/116505440.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/us-government-shutdown-looms-what-will-be-its-impact-and-has-it-happened-before/articleshow/116505440.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Erdogan says Turkey will help Syria restructure state and draft constitution - Middle East Eye]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Erdogan says Turkey will help Syria restructure state and draft constitution</h1>
<p><strong>Published date:</strong> 20 December 2024 12:15 GMT | <strong>Source:</strong> Middle East Eye</p>
<img loading="lazy" srcset="/sites/default/files/styles/article_page/public/images-story/Turkey-Erdogan-Ankara--12-24-2024-Andrew-Caballero-Reynolds-Pool-AFP.jpg.webp?itok=G5lOpgYG 1x" width="1400" height="932" src="/sites/default/files/styles/max_2600x2600/public/images-story/Turkey-Erdogan-Ankara--12-24-2024-Andrew-Caballero-Reynolds-Pool-AFP.jpg.jpg?itok=kMY4Vpbj" alt="Turkey's President Recep Tayyip Erdogan" typeof="foaf:Image">
<figcaption>President Erdogan at Ankara Esenboga Airport on 12 December (AFP)</figcaption>
<p>President Recep Tayyip Erdogan announced that Turkey will assist the new Syrian administration in restructuring the state and drafting a new constitution.</p>
<ul>
    <li>Erdogan emphasized the importance of drafting an inclusive constitution for Syria's future.</li>
    <li>Turkey is already collaborating with Syrian figures to form the new constitution.</li>
    <li>The support includes energy and humanitarian aid, and reconstruction efforts in Syria.</li>
    <li>Ankara expects the return of Syrian refugees as a result of reconstruction.</li>
    <li>Erdogan aims to address the threats from Kurdish separatist groups on Turkey's southern borders.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“There are many elements that this new administration especially needs. We will not leave them alone on these issues.” - President Erdogan</blockquote>
<p>This initiative marks a significant step in Turkey's involvement in Syrian affairs as it hopes to stabilize the region post-conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.middleeasteye.net/news/turkey-will-help-syria-restructure-its-state-erdogan-says</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.middleeasteye.net/news/turkey-will-help-syria-restructure-its-state-erdogan-says</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['If government shuts down...': What Elon Musk said amid spending bill row - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/if-government-shuts-down-what-elon-musk-said-amid-spending-bill-row/articleshow/116505038.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/if-government-shuts-down-what-elon-musk-said-amid-spending-bill-row/articleshow/116505038.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Democrats Are Calling Elon Musk "President Musk" - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Explained: Why Democrats Are Calling Elon Musk 'President Musk'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Not specified</p><p>Elon Musk's growing influence in US politics, particularly within the Republican Party, has led to sarcastic references to him as 'President Musk' by frustrated Democrats.</p><ul><li>Musk's political prominence started when he was appointed to lead the Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) by President Trump.</li><li>His opposition to a bipartisan budget deal and public intervention has fueled speculation about his power.</li><li>Democrats express concern over Musk's influence undermining traditional political structures.</li><li>Potential political aspirations for Musk have been discussed among some Republican lawmakers.</li><li>Concerns about the relationship between billionaires and the government have been raised, with warnings from figures like Senator Bernie Sanders.</li></ul><blockquote>“At least we know who's in charge. He's president, and Trump is now vice president.” - Representative Jim McGovern</blockquote><p>The debate around Musk's role in politics raises questions about the future of American governance and the influence of wealthy individuals.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-democrats-have-started-referring-to-tesla-ceo-as-president-musk-7293683</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-democrats-have-started-referring-to-tesla-ceo-as-president-musk-7293683</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:44:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winter solstice: Bhubaneswar to witness year's shortest day tomorrow - OTV News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPM1R1YWctenJzM01NNGRaUko3emxxVlVrYTZVa1hSNFNZSXFWZUdibWdxUVFQekVqT1ZRdzh4dUNNeVg0aWQ2STVZdURSbmhZMVlobVV5TTdOQ3d6QklKNUlHUUp5c181Y1diU1BTUU4yY3ZkbFNQa1dWbVpzNjJld0JpbjMyMjdhdkdsWlZ2QmtGOWRscF9FQ0FfLUFORERKTDZMcThCOGZPUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPM1R1YWctenJzM01NNGRaUko3emxxVlVrYTZVa1hSNFNZSXFWZUdibWdxUVFQekVqT1ZRdzh4dUNNeVg0aWQ2STVZdURSbmhZMVlobVV5TTdOQ3d6QklKNUlHUUp5c181Y1diU1BTUU4yY3ZkbFNQa1dWbVpzNjJld0JpbjMyMjdhdkdsWlZ2QmtGOWRscF9FQ0FfLUFORERKTDZMcThCOGZPUQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:29:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After BRICS, Donald Trump issues ultimatum to European Union: ‘Buy US oil and gas or face tariffs’ | Today News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>After BRICS, Donald Trump issues ultimatum to European Union: ‘Buy US oil and gas or face tariffs’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Live Mint</p><p>US President-elect Donald Trump has issued a warning to the European Union to purchase US oil and gas on a large scale or face tariffs. This statement follows recent threats against BRICS nations regarding their financial dealings.</p><ul><li>Trump demanded large-scale purchases of US energy to offset the trade deficit.</li><li>EU countries are considering additional US energy imports to avoid a clash with the Trump administration.</li><li>The US has significantly increased energy exports to the EU amid the ongoing Russia-Ukraine conflict.</li><li>Data shows the US is a major provider of LNG and oil to the EU, accounting for 47% and 17% respectively.</li><li>Trump's administration has previously threatened tariffs against various trading partners, affecting global trade dynamics.</li></ul><blockquote>“I told the European Union that they must make up their tremendous deficit with the United States by the large-scale purchase of our oil and gas. Otherwise, it is TARIFFS all the way!!!” - Donald Trump</blockquote><p>The ultimatum highlights the tensions between the US and its trading partners and could have significant implications for international trade relations going forward.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/after-brics-donald-trump-issues-ultimatum-for-european-union-buy-us-oil-and-gas-or-face-tariffs-11734690691002.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/news/us-news/after-brics-donald-trump-issues-ultimatum-for-european-union-buy-us-oil-and-gas-or-face-tariffs-11734690691002.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump wants EU to buy more US oil and gas or face tariffs - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-says-eu-should-make-up-tremendous-deficit-with-us-by-purchasing-its-oil-2024-12-20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-says-eu-should-make-up-tremendous-deficit-with-us-by-purchasing-its-oil-2024-12-20/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:22:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russian missiles strike Kyiv on the eve of holiday season (Photos) - Kyiv Independent]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://kyivindependent.com/russian-missiles-strike-kyiv-on-the-eve-of-holiday-season/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kyivindependent.com/russian-missiles-strike-kyiv-on-the-eve-of-holiday-season/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:10:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US diplomats arrive in Syria to talk to Islamist rulers about country’s future - The Times of Israel]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.timesofisrael.com/us-diplomats-arrive-in-syria-to-talk-to-islamist-rulers-about-countrys-future/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.timesofisrael.com/us-diplomats-arrive-in-syria-to-talk-to-islamist-rulers-about-countrys-future/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:08:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Croatia: 7-year-old killed, 5 injured in knife attack in Zagreb school, attacker detained - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/croatia-7-year-old-killed-5-wounded-in-knife-attack-in-zagreb-school-101734692388931.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/croatia-7-year-old-killed-5-wounded-in-knife-attack-in-zagreb-school-101734692388931.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 11:04:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Malaysia to resume hunt for Flight MH370, 10 years after it vanished - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/malaysia-says-it-will-resume-search-wreckage-missing-flight-mh370-2024-12-20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/malaysia-says-it-will-resume-search-wreckage-missing-flight-mh370-2024-12-20/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:50:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fresh twist in Gautam Adani bribery case as US attorney who indicted billionaire businessman to... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Fresh twist in Gautam Adani bribery case as US attorney resigns</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 10, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> India.com</p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-2024-11-21T190039.385.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Fresh twist in Gautam Adani bribery case" /><figcaption></figcaption><p>Breon Peace, the US attorney who indicted Indian billionaire Gautam Adani, has announced his resignation effective January 10, 2024. He leaves behind a legacy of high-profile prosecutions.</p><ul><li>Breon Peace is stepping down as Brooklyn US attorney.</li><li>He oversaw the indictment of Gautam Adani in a bribery case.</li><li>Peace has handled significant cases including R Kelly's sex trafficking conviction.</li><li>Gautam Adani and his company deny the allegations against them.</li></ul><blockquote>“It was an honour for me to serve the United States as Attorney,” - Breon Peace</blockquote><p>Peace’s departure comes amidst ongoing investigations into the Adani Group, as he leaves a mixed legacy of impactful legal victories.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/business/fresh-twist-in-gautam-adani-bribery-case-as-us-attorney-who-indicted-billionaire-businessman-to-breon-peace-us-attorney-general-resign-7481056/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/business/fresh-twist-in-gautam-adani-bribery-case-as-us-attorney-who-indicted-billionaire-businessman-to-breon-peace-us-attorney-general-resign-7481056/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:32:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top US officials in Damascus to meet new Syrian rulers, State Department says - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/top-us-officials-damascus-meet-new-syrian-rulers-state-department-says-2024-12-20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/top-us-officials-damascus-meet-new-syrian-rulers-state-department-says-2024-12-20/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 10:14:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US raises alarm: Soon, Pakistan missiles could reach American soil - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>US Raises Alarm: Pakistan's Missiles Could Soon Reach American Soil</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="US-Pakistan Missile Threat"><figcaption>Pakistan's missile capabilities raise concerns in the US</figcaption><p>The article discusses escalating concerns within the United States regarding Pakistan's missile development program, suggesting that the advancements could eventually enable missiles to reach American territory.</p><ul><li>The US government has raised alarms over Pakistan’s evolving missile technology.</li><li>Military analysts express fears that new developments could alter the balance of power in South Asia.</li><li>Policy makers are debating potential responses and strategies to mitigate risks.</li><li>Experts highlight the importance of diplomatic engagement with Pakistan to address concerns.</li></ul><blockquote>“The evolution of Pakistan’s missile capabilities poses a significant challenge to US security interests and regional stability.” - Defense Analyst</blockquote><p>This development illustrates the complex security dynamics at play and underscores the need for proactive measures to ensure safety and mitigate threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/pakistan-nuclear-missiles-and-us-jon-finer-india-and-pakistan-us-sanctions-on-pakistan/articleshow/116498678.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/pakistan-nuclear-missiles-and-us-jon-finer-india-and-pakistan-us-sanctions-on-pakistan/articleshow/116498678.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>