<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:29:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:29:43 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel hits Yemen’s ports, tells Houthis ‘will reach you’ - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel hits Yemen’s ports, tells Houthis ‘will reach you’</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p>
<img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/9wby2a/article69003337.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-19T041044Z_1956606321_RC23SBACS9CR_RTRMADP_3_ISRAEL-PALESTINIANS-SIRENS.JPG" alt="Emergency services personnel work near a damaged site after a projectile fired from Yemen was intercepted, in Ramat Gan, Israel December 19, 2024." />
<figcaption>Emergency services personnel work near a damaged site after a projectile fired from Yemen was intercepted, in Ramat Gan, Israel December 19, 2024. | Photo Credit: REUTERS</figcaption>
<p>Israel conducted strikes on strategic locations in Yemen after intercepting a missile fired by Houthi rebels. The Israeli Defense Minister warned the Houthis that they would also be targeted.</p>
<ul>
  <li>The Israeli military targeted ports and energy facilities used by Houthi rebels.</li>
  <li>Houthi media reported casualties and damage to infrastructure in Sanaa and Hodaidah.</li>
  <li>This action is part of an ongoing conflict where Houthis have launched multiple missiles towards Israel.</li>
  <li>Israeli officials characterized the Houthis as a significant threat, echoing concerns about Iranian support for the group.</li>
  <li>Israel's military stated it would respond to threats from any group in the region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>"I warn the leaders of the Houthi terrorist organisation: Israel's long arm will reach you too," - Israeli Defence Minister Israel Katz.</blockquote>
<p>This escalation underscores the growing regional tensions as the Houthis align their operations with the conflict in Gaza, promising to continue attacks until a ceasefire is achieved.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/israel-hits-yemens-ports-tells-houthis-will-reach-you/article69003317.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/israel-hits-yemens-ports-tells-houthis-will-reach-you/article69003317.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 05:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EU leaders to send 'clear message' to Trump on Ukraine, to debate U.S. ties - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/eu-leaders-send-clear-message-trump-ukraine-debate-us-ties-2024-12-19/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/eu-leaders-send-clear-message-trump-ukraine-debate-us-ties-2024-12-19/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 04:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suspended South Korean President Willing to Appear in Impeachment Trial - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/politics/suspended-south-korean-president-willing-to-appear-in-impeachment-trial-11734581054568.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/politics/suspended-south-korean-president-willing-to-appear-in-impeachment-trial-11734581054568.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 04:04:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel carries out air strikes on Yemen - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/19/israel-carries-out-air-strikes-on-yemen</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/19/israel-carries-out-air-strikes-on-yemen</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 03:58:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Lost Faith’: Toronto Police Union Seeks Trudeau’s Resignation Amid Proposal To Change Criminal Code - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Toronto Police Union Calls for Trudeau's Resignation Over Criminal Code Changes</h1><p><strong>Publication date:</strong> December 19, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="The Toronto Police Association was irked over proposals to amend the criminal code of the nation."><figcaption>The Toronto Police Association was irked over proposals to amend the criminal code of the nation.</figcaption><p>In a bold public statement, the Toronto Police Association (TPA) has demanded the resignation of Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, citing a loss of faith in his leadership following proposals to amend the criminal code aimed at addressing public safety issues.</p><ul><li>The proposed amendments emphasize accountability for repeat violent offenders and stricter bail conditions for violent crimes.</li><li>TPA expressed frustration over the lack of action from Trudeau's government and cited his leadership as inadequate.</li><li>The call for resignation follows the recent departure of Deputy Prime Minister Chrystia Freeland amid political turmoil.</li></ul><blockquote>Our members have lost faith in <a href="https://twitter.com/JustinTrudeau?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">@JustinTrudeau</a>’s government to do the right thing for the right reasons. Time to resign and leave these critically important public safety issues to someone else. <a href="https://t.co/g2n1iPkNB7" rel="nofollow">https://t.co/g2n1iPkNB7</a>— Toronto Police Association (@TPAca) <a href="https://twitter.com/TPAca/status/1869196929047138755?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" rel="nofollow">December 18, 2024</a></blockquote><p>The political crisis is intensifying as more Liberal MPs join the demands for Trudeau's resignation, influencing the future of Canadian governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/toronto-police-association-canada-political-crisis-calls-pm-justin-trudeau-resignation-proposal-amend-criminal-code-9161087.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/toronto-police-association-canada-political-crisis-calls-pm-justin-trudeau-resignation-proposal-amend-criminal-code-9161087.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 03:46:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What happens when you die? ‘World’s smartest man’ with ‘IQ higher than Einstein’ claims he has the answer - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What happens when you die? ‘World’s smartest man’ with ‘IQ higher than Einstein’ claims he has the answer</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 08:41 AM IST | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/Die_Worlds_Smartest_Man_IQ_Einstein_Viral_1734577282352_1734577291331.jpg" alt="Chris Langan, who claims his IQ is between 190 and 210, discussed what happens when a person dies in a podcast. (Sandym10, YouTube/@CTMURadio)" title="Chris Langan, who claims his IQ is between 190 and 210, discussed what happens when a person dies in a podcast. (Sandym10, YouTube/@CTMURadio)">
<figcaption>Chris Langan, who claims his IQ is between 190 and 210, discussed what happens when a person dies in a podcast. (Sandym10, YouTube/@CTMURadio)</figcaption>
<p>Chris Langan, known for his high IQ, shares his views on death and existence. He believes that death may not be the end, suggesting a continuity into another dimension.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Langan claims that reality is a self-simulation and developed the Cognitive-Theoretic Model of the Universe (CTMU).</li>
  <li>He discusses the concept of death as a transition rather than an end, implying a shift to another dimension.</li>
  <li>According to him, one may forget their previous life after this transition due to being in a state of meditation.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Death might be a shift in the ‘syntax’ of existence.” - Chris Langan</blockquote>
<p>Langan posits that understanding death could reshape how humans perceive life after death, emphasizing the importance of not fearing it.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/what-happens-when-you-die-world-s-smartest-man-with-iq-higher-than-einstein-claims-he-has-the-answer-101734577257277.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/trending/what-happens-when-you-die-world-s-smartest-man-with-iq-higher-than-einstein-claims-he-has-the-answer-101734577257277.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 03:11:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1st Regiment Of S-500 ‘Prometheus’ AD System Nears Commissioning Amid Increased NATO Threat: Russia - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE4xeVpkRnhxR2xKc2VsQ1VNWDc1UVNNc3UyRG1rdkZKNnhVT0R5b0Vzc3dvVW94UHc4NXJrOG1ocGpXN3ctQkhrZTZKckJkMTl0aGgxYlBZSUNiMnFRLWExZ3JTNGhKLTB6MTI4MnA2a3VvanNtTGZrTUVpUGXSAXxBVV95cUxOMXlaZEZ4cUdsSnNlbENVTVg3NVFTTXN1MkRta3ZGSjZ4VU9EeW9Fc3N3b1VveFB3ODVyazhtaHBqVzd3LUJIa2U2SnJCZDE5dGhoMWJQWUlDYjJxUS1hMWdyUzRoSi0wejEyODJwNmt1b2pzbUxma01FaVBl?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMifEFVX3lxTE4xeVpkRnhxR2xKc2VsQ1VNWDc1UVNNc3UyRG1rdkZKNnhVT0R5b0Vzc3dvVW94UHc4NXJrOG1ocGpXN3ctQkhrZTZKckJkMTl0aGgxYlBZSUNiMnFRLWExZ3JTNGhKLTB6MTI4MnA2a3VvanNtTGZrTUVpUGXSAXxBVV95cUxOMXlaZEZ4cUdsSnNlbENVTVg3NVFTTXN1MkRta3ZGSjZ4VU9EeW9Fc3N3b1VveFB3ODVyazhtaHBqVzd3LUJIa2U2SnJCZDE5dGhoMWJQWUlDYjJxUS1hMWdyUzRoSi0wejEyODJwNmt1b2pzbUxma01FaVBl?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 02:34:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who was Rubi Patricia Vergara? Wisconsin school shooting victim, 14, was ‘an avid reader, loved art’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who was Rubi Patricia Vergara? Wisconsin school shooting victim, 14, was ‘an avid reader, loved art’</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/Untitled_1734575088732_1734575088923.jpg" alt="Who was Rubi Patricia Vergara? Wisconsin school shooting victim, 14, was ‘an avid reader'" title="Who was Rubi Patricia Vergara? Wisconsin school shooting victim, 14, was ‘an avid reader'" /><figcaption>Who was Rubi Patricia Vergara? Wisconsin school shooting victim, 14, was ‘an avid reader' (gundersonfh.com)</figcaption><p>The sad story of Rubi Patricia Vergara, a 14-year-old freshman who was killed in a shooting at Abundant Life Christian School in Madison, Wisconsin, has emerged. She was remembered for her love of reading, art, and music.</p><ul><li>Rubi was an avid reader and had a passion for art.</li><li>She participated in family worship, playing keyboard and singing.</li><li>Her family shared a special bond with her pets, Ginger the cat and Coco the dog.</li><li>Rubi was killed alongside a teacher, and six others were injured during the incident.</li><li>The funeral service will be held at City Church in Madison on December 21, 2024.</li></ul><blockquote>“This is our beautiful Rubi Vergara, our niece who was killed in Monday's school shooting...” - A family member reflecting on her tragic loss.</blockquote><p>The tragic event highlights the ongoing concerns regarding school safety and the impact of such incidents on families and communities.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/who-was-rubi-patricia-vergara-wisconsin-school-shooting-victim-14-was-an-avid-reader-loved-art-101734574782158.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/who-was-rubi-patricia-vergara-wisconsin-school-shooting-victim-14-was-an-avid-reader-loved-art-101734574782158.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 02:27:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big move by Canada PM Trudeau, invites 1085 applications for..., impact on India will be... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Canada Invites 1,085 Applications for Permanent Residency: Impacts on India</h1><p><strong>Date: December 16, 2024</strong> <strong>Source: India.com</strong></p><img src="https://static.india.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Trudeau.jpg?impolicy=Medium_Widthonly&amp;w=700" alt="Canada PM Trudeau" /><figcaption>Canadian PM Trudeau's significant move to invite permanent residency applications.</figcaption><p>The Canadian government is providing opportunities for foreign nationals, including a large number of Indians, to obtain permanent residency through its Provincial Nominee Program (PNP). On December 16, IRCC invited 1,085 individuals to apply for permanent residency.</p><ul><li>The PNP allows foreign nationals to live and work in a specific Canadian province.</li><li>Earlier announcements had also invited 676 individuals under the same program.</li><li>It targets skilled workers who can contribute to provincial economies.</li></ul><blockquote>“Programs like this provide an excellent opportunity for Indians to fulfill their dream of settling in Canada.”</blockquote><p>This significant draw highlights Canada’s commitment to facilitating immigration and may positively influence many aspiring Indian residents.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/big-move-by-canada-pm-trudeau-invites-1085-applications-seeking-permanent-residency-impact-on-india-will-be-huge-express-entry-system-how-to-apply-canada-visa-7476521/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/big-move-by-canada-pm-trudeau-invites-1085-applications-seeking-permanent-residency-impact-on-india-will-be-huge-express-entry-system-how-to-apply-canada-visa-7476521/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 02:23:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Clear & consistent': US sanctions 4 entities supplying equipment to Pakistan's ballistic missile program - Firstpost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>'Clear & consistent': US sanctions 4 entities supplying equipment to Pakistan's ballistic missile program</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 18, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> FirstPost</p><img src="https://images.firstpost.com/uploads/2024/09/Pakistan-blasphemy-news-2024-09-b72ba4e0cb8c8b751a2cfaef9e45fe8e.jpg?im=FitAndFill=(596,336)" alt="US sanctions 4 entities supporting Pakistan's missile program" title="US sanctions 4 entities supporting Pakistan's missile program"><figcaption>US sanctions 4 entities supporting Pakistan's missile program. Representational Image. Reuters</figcaption><p>The United States has imposed sanctions on four entities believed to be supporting Pakistan's ballistic missile program, reaffirming its concerns on the proliferation threat posed by Pakistan's long-range missile development.</p><ul><li>The US State Department confirmed the sanctions were in response to ongoing threats from Pakistan’s missile development.</li><li>The four sanctioned entities include the National Development Complex (NDC), Akhtar and Sons Private Limited, Affiliates International, and Rockside Enterprise.</li><li>These entities are accused of supplying critical equipment for the development of ballistic missiles.</li><li>The US has been consistent in expressing its concerns regarding Pakistan's missile program and will continue to engage constructively with Pakistan.</li></ul><blockquote>“Today, the United States is designating four entities that are contributing to Pakistan’s ballistic missile program. We have been clear and consistent about our concerns, and we will continue to engage constructively with Pakistan on these issues.” — Matthew Miller</blockquote><p>This move follows previous sanctions placed on entities in September and earlier in 2023 against Chinese companies for similar accusations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.firstpost.com/world/clear-consistent-us-sanctions-4-entities-supplying-equipment-to-pakistans-ballistic-missile-program-13845770.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.firstpost.com/world/clear-consistent-us-sanctions-4-entities-supplying-equipment-to-pakistans-ballistic-missile-program-13845770.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 02:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian Gets Jail Term In US For Trying To Engage Minor In Sex Act - NDTV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Indian National Sentenced for Attempting to Engage Minor in Sexual Act</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>July 27, 2019</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>NDTV</p><img title="Indian Gets Jail Term In US For Trying To Engage Minor In Sex Act" alt="Indian Gets Jail Term In US For Trying To Engage Minor In Sex Act" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-07/att9hsso_court-generic_625x300_27_July_19.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=650,height=400"><figcaption>Kirtan Patel faces serious sentencing for online misconduct.</figcaption><p>Kirtan Patel, a 24-year-old Indian national, has pleaded guilty to attempting to entice a minor into sexual activity.</p><ul><li>Patel communicated online with someone he thought was a 13-year-old girl.</li><li>The alleged minor was actually an undercover agent from Homeland Security Investigations.</li><li>He was arrested in Marion County when he arrived for a meeting.</li><li>Patel faces a minimum of 10 years up to life in federal prison.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ultimately, Patel was arrested when he travelled to a location in Marion County to engage in sexual activity with the child.” - US Attorney Roger B Handberg</blockquote><p>This case highlights the ongoing efforts to combat online predatory behavior and ensure justice for potential victims.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-gets-jail-term-in-us-for-trying-to-engage-minor-in-sex-act-7281838</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/indian-gets-jail-term-in-us-for-trying-to-engage-minor-in-sex-act-7281838</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 02:03:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indian-origin man jailed for killing mother in UK's Leicester: ‘Deeply disturbing case’ - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/indianorigin-man-jailed-for-killing-mother-in-uks-leicester-deeply-disturbing-case-101734571097998.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/indianorigin-man-jailed-for-killing-mother-in-uks-leicester-deeply-disturbing-case-101734571097998.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:50:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's alleged drug abuse will barr him from entering certain SpaceX buildings: Report - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk's Alleged Drug Use Affects Security Clearance at SpaceX</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/-RAMASWAMY-VISIT-CAPITOL-HIL_1733939387392_1734571577906.jpg" alt="Reports indicate Musk's executives caution against higher security clearances due to risks of revocation linked to his lifestyle.(Getty Images via AFP)" title="Reports indicate Musk's executives caution against higher security clearances due to risks of revocation linked to his lifestyle.(Getty Images via AFP)"><figcaption>Reports indicate Musk's executives caution against higher security clearances due to risks of revocation linked to his lifestyle.(Getty Images via AFP)</figcaption><p>Elon Musk's executives have advised him against applying for higher security clearances due to concerns related to drug use allegations and foreign connections, which could lead to his current clearance being revoked.</p><ul><li>Musk’s security clearance status is currently “top secret,” allowing partial access to government-related projects.</li><li>Concerns have been raised regarding Musk’s lifestyle and substance use, particularly connections with foreign figures like Vladimir Putin.</li><li>SpaceX has denied allegations regarding Musk’s connections to Putin and any substance use.</li><li>Musk’s clearance allows access to certain Department of Defense facilities, but restricts him from viewing sensitive information.</li></ul><blockquote><p>“Most of the stuff that I’m aware of...the reason to keep it top secret is it’s so boring.” - Elon Musk</p></blockquote><p>The implications of these allegations could impact Musk’s access to crucial security information and potential government projects.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/elon-musks-alleged-drug-abuse-will-barr-him-from-entering-certain-spacex-buildings-report-101734570235065.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/elon-musks-alleged-drug-abuse-will-barr-him-from-entering-certain-spacex-buildings-report-101734570235065.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:47:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An Expert Explains: Bashar al-Assad is gone, what’s happening in Syria now? - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bashar al-Assad is gone, what’s happening in Syria now?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> The New York Times</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/SYRIA-TRANSITION-4col1.jpg?w=640" alt="Mohammed al-Bashir, Syria, Syria attack, Iran Syria, Kurdish-controlled Northwestern Syria, HTS, Indian express explained, explained news, current affairs" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Mohammed al-Bashir, head of the interim government in Syria, at the historic Umayyad Mosque in Damascus on December 13.</figcaption><p>Over the past 10 days, two broad developments have been unfolding in Syria.</p><ul><li>Prime Minister Mohammed al-Bashir is working to stabilize the country and consolidate its ethnic groups.</li><li>He aims to engage with the international community before his transitional government's term ends on March 1 next year.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/an-expert-explains-the-ongoing-transition-in-syria-9733081/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/an-expert-explains-the-ongoing-transition-in-syria-9733081/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:30:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An Expert Explains: The ongoing transition in Syria - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bashar al-Assad is gone, what’s happening in Syria now?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 13, 2024<br><strong>Source:</strong> The New York Times</p><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/SYRIA-TRANSITION-4col1.jpg?w=640" alt="Mohammed al-Bashir, Syria, Syria attack, Iran Syria, Kurdish-controlled Northwestern Syria, HTS, Indian express explained, explained news, current affairs" width="640" height="360"><figcaption>Mohammed al-Bashir, head of the interim government in Syria, at the historic Umayyad Mosque in Damascus on December 13.</figcaption><p>Over the past 10 days, two broad developments have been unfolding in Syria.</p><ul><li>Prime Minister Mohammed al-Bashir is working to stabilize the country and consolidate its ethnic groups.</li><li>He aims to engage with the international community before his transitional government's term ends on March 1 next year.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/an-expert-explains-the-ongoing-transition-in-syria-9733081/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/an-expert-explains-the-ongoing-transition-in-syria-9733081/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:30:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No mention of Jammu and Kashmir in UNGA resolution tabled by Pakistan, say MEA sources - Newsroompost]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>No mention of Jammu and Kashmir in UNGA resolution tabled by Pakistan, say MEA sources</h1><p><strong>Published: December 19, 2024</strong></p><img src="https://newsroompost.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/unga-1000x600.jpg" title="No mention of Jammu and Kashmir in UNGA resolution tabled by Pakistan, say MEA sources"><figcaption>No mention of Jammu and Kashmir in UNGA resolution tabled by Pakistan, say MEA sources</figcaption><p>New Delhi: There have been some misleading foreign media reports about a resolution in the United Nations General Assembly, sources in the Ministry of External Affairs said on Wednesday, adding that it is an annual resolution tabled by Pakistan in the Third Committee.</p><ul><li>The resolution was adopted without a vote.</li><li>It does not mention Jammu and Kashmir.</li><li>The Third Committee focuses on human rights issues and social development questions.</li><li>The UN General Assembly is the main policy-making organ of the UN.</li></ul><blockquote>“We have seen misleading foreign media reports about a resolution in the UNGA. This is an annual resolution tabled by Pakistan in the Third Committee. It is adopted without a vote. This resolution has no mention of Jammu and Kashmir,” MEA Sources said.</blockquote><p>The UNGA meeting sessions occur from September to December, providing a platform for multilateral discussions.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://newsroompost.com/india/no-mention-of-jammu-and-kashmir-in-unga-resolution-tabled-by-pakistan-say-mea-sources/5337148.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsroompost.com/india/no-mention-of-jammu-and-kashmir-in-unga-resolution-tabled-by-pakistan-say-mea-sources/5337148.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:17:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. lawmaker seeks targeted sanctions against Bangladesh - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>U.S. Lawmaker Demands Sanctions Against Bangladesh for Human Rights Violations</h1><p><strong>Date: December 19, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: The Hindu</strong></p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/wsshtq/article66945695.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/PTI06_07_2023_000010A.jpg" alt="Indian American Congressman Shri Thanedar." title="Indian American Congressman Shri Thanedar." /><figcaption>Indian American Congressman Shri Thanedar. | Photo Credit: PTI</figcaption><p>An influential American Congressman has called for the U.S. to impose sanctions against individuals responsible for human rights violations in Bangladesh, particularly against minority groups.</p><ul><li>Congressman Shri Thanedar cited a surge in political violence in Bangladesh, leading to increased attacks on Hindu, Buddhist, and Christian minorities.</li><li>He expressed concerns over the new government led by Prime Minister Muhammad Yunus, while hopeful for positive change.</li><li>Thanedar highlighted the vandalism and destruction of Hindu temples, with numerous incidents reported in recent months.</li></ul><blockquote>“When we receive a global call for help, we must respond appropriately as the world's bellwether of human rights.” - Congressman Shri Thanedar</blockquote><p>The call for sanctions reflects a growing urgency to support human rights and protect vulnerable communities in Bangladesh.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/us-lawmaker-seeks-targeted-sanctions-against-bangladesh/article69003067.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/us-lawmaker-seeks-targeted-sanctions-against-bangladesh/article69003067.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who was Rubi Patricia? Wisconsin school shooting victim identified - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who was Rubi Patricia? Wisconsin school shooting victim identified</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p>
<p>This article identifies Rubi Patricia, one of the victims of the Wisconsin school shooting, providing insights into her life and the tragic events surrounding her untimely death.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rubi Patricia was a student at the school where the shooting occurred.</li>
  <li>She was remembered fondly by friends and family.</li>
  <li>The article discusses the impact of her loss on the community.</li>
  <li>Details of the incident are included, emphasizing the nature of the tragedy.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Rubi was a bright light in everyone's life, taken too soon.”</blockquote>
<p>The tragic death of Rubi Patricia highlights the ongoing issue of school safety and gun violence in America.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/who-was-rubi-patricia-wisconsin-school-shooting-victim-identified/articleshow/116454578.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/who-was-rubi-patricia-wisconsin-school-shooting-victim-identified/articleshow/116454578.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Verdict due in Gisele Pelicot rape case that horrified the world - Reuters.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/verdict-due-gisele-pelicot-rape-case-that-horrified-world-2024-12-19/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/verdict-due-gisele-pelicot-rape-case-that-horrified-world-2024-12-19/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 01:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk pressures Republicans to reject Stopgap Spending Bill, threatens shutdown - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-pressures-republicans-to-reject-stopgap-spending-bill-threatens-shutdown/articleshow/116454492.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musk-pressures-republicans-to-reject-stopgap-spending-bill-threatens-shutdown/articleshow/116454492.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump’s gov shutdown call to impact Holiday travel, military? What closes, what stays open amid Stopgap bill rant - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump’s Government Shutdown Call: Holiday Travel and Military Implications</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> Dec 19, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Hindustan Times</p><img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/19/550x309/AP-Poll-Trump-Confidence-0_1734140378968_1734568680408.jpg" alt="US President-elect Donald Trump will take charge of the Oval Office in January 2025. (AP)"><figcaption>US President-elect Donald Trump will take charge of the Oval Office in January 2025. (AP)</figcaption><p>A potential government shutdown led by President-elect Donald Trump could severely impact holiday travel and other essential services, with federal employees facing delayed pay.</p><ul><li>Trump and Vance are pushing for a government shutdown, rejecting a funding bill.</li><li>The shutdown could hinder Christmas travel and public services.</li><li>Essential workers remain on duty but may face delayed pay.</li><li>Air traffic operations could continue but with reduced staffing and longer wait times.</li><li>Military personnel will remain on duty, while civilian workforce may face furlough.</li><li>Economic growth might decrease, with estimates of a 0.2% weekly reduction during a shutdown.</li></ul><blockquote>“House Republicans have been ordered to shut down the government and hurt everyday Americans all across this country,” said House Democratic Leader Hakeem Jeffries.</blockquote><p>The unfolding situation highlights the potential disruption to holiday services and economic activities, necessitating immediate attention from Congress.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trumps-gov-shutdown-call-to-impact-holiday-travel-military-what-closes-what-stays-open-amid-stopgap-bill-rant-101734566024040.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/trumps-gov-shutdown-call-to-impact-holiday-travel-military-what-closes-what-stays-open-amid-stopgap-bill-rant-101734566024040.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:39:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Natalie Rupnow’s dark online past: Wisconsin school shooter linked to site 'Watch People Die' showing bea - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/natalie-rupnows-dark-online-past-wisconsin-school-shooter-linked-to-site-watch-people-die-showing-beating-beheadings-and-gruesome-deaths/articleshow/116453659.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/natalie-rupnows-dark-online-past-wisconsin-school-shooter-linked-to-site-watch-people-die-showing-beating-beheadings-and-gruesome-deaths/articleshow/116453659.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Natalie Rupnow’s dark online past: Wisconsin school shooter linked to site 'Watch People Die' showing beating, beheadings and gruesome deaths - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/natalie-rupnows-dark-online-past-wisconsin-school-shooter-linked-to-site-watch-people-die-showing-beating-beheadings-and-gruesome-deaths/articleshow/116453659.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/natalie-rupnows-dark-online-past-wisconsin-school-shooter-linked-to-site-watch-people-die-showing-beating-beheadings-and-gruesome-deaths/articleshow/116453659.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Britain pledges new $286 million defence package for Ukraine - Reuters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/britain-pledges-new-286-million-defence-package-ukraine-2024-12-19/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/britain-pledges-new-286-million-defence-package-ukraine-2024-12-19/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. imposes more sanctions over Pakistan's missile program - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/us-imposes-more-sanctions-over-pakistans-missile-program/article69002150.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/us-imposes-more-sanctions-over-pakistans-missile-program/article69002150.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 22:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bird Flu Crisis: California Declares Emergency - M9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Bird Flu Crisis: California Declares Emergency</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 2024 &nbsp; | &nbsp; <strong>Source:</strong> M9 News</p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bird-flu-california-768x576.jpg" alt="bird-flu-california" width="768" height="576"><figcaption>Bird Flu Crisis in California</figcaption><p>California Governor Gavin Newsom has declared a state of emergency in response to the swift spread of H5N1 Bird Flu, affecting both dairy cows and humans since its detection in wild birds in 2022.</p><ul><li>H5N1 Bird Flu started infecting dairy cows in March 2024.</li><li>34 reported human cases in California; no human to human transmission confirmed yet.</li><li>A 65-year-old man in Louisiana is in critical condition due to the virus.</li><li>Over 600 dairy farms reported positive tests in Central California.</li><li>California produces 18% of the nation’s milk supply, raising public health and economic concerns.</li><li>The state is implementing strict biosecurity measures to prevent further spread.</li></ul><blockquote>This crisis underscores the urgent need for robust biosecurity measures on farms.</blockquote><p>The Bird Flu outbreak highlights the interconnectedness of human health, livestock, and the economy, emphasizing the need for improved safety protocols and cooperation across sectors.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.m9.news/usa-news/bird-flu-crisis-california-declares-emergency/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.m9.news/usa-news/bird-flu-crisis-california-declares-emergency/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:54:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Plane Goes 'Out Of Control' In Hawaii, Crashes Into Vacant Building; 2 Killed | Video - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/plane-goes-out-of-control-in-hawaii-crashes-into-vacant-building-2-killed-video-9160419.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/plane-goes-out-of-control-in-hawaii-crashes-into-vacant-building-2-killed-video-9160419.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 21:35:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FM Fidan rejects Trump claim of 'Turkish takeover' of Syria | Daily Sabah - Daily Sabah]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>FM Fidan Rejects Trump's 'Turkish Takeover' Claim in Syria</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Daily Sabah</p><p>In response to former President Donald Trump's comments regarding a potential ‘Turkish takeover’ of Syria, Turkish Foreign Minister Hakan Fidan has firmly rejected such claims. He emphasized Turkey's legitimate interests in the region while clarifying the nation's military actions are aimed at ensuring national security and peace.</p><ul><li>Fidan reiterated that Turkey's operations in Syria are defensive and targeted at terrorist threats from the region.</li><li>The Minister called out the misinformation spread by Trump's statement, reaffirming Turkey's commitment to its sovereignty and regional stability.</li><li>He stressed the importance of cooperation among nations to address shared security concerns in the area.</li></ul><blockquote>“Turkey’s presence in Syria is a matter of national security, not a takeover.”</blockquote><p>This response reflects Turkey's ongoing narrative of active involvement in counter-terrorism efforts in Syria whilst rejecting external interpretations of its military operations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.dailysabah.com/politics/diplomacy/fm-fidan-rejects-trump-claim-of-turkish-takeover-of-syria</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dailysabah.com/politics/diplomacy/fm-fidan-rejects-trump-claim-of-turkish-takeover-of-syria</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 20:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Will continue to act against proliferation': US slaps sanctions on Pakistan over Ballistic Missile Progr - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Will continue to act against proliferation: US slaps sanctions on Pakistan over Ballistic Missile Programme</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p><p>An overview of the sanctions imposed by the US on Pakistan concerning its ballistic missile program due to concerns of proliferation.</p><ul><li>The sanctions come amid ongoing discussions about global proliferation issues.</li><li>The US government emphasizes its commitment to addressing security threats posed by missile technologies.</li><li>The sanctions may affect military and economic relations between the US and Pakistan.</li></ul><blockquote>"We will continue to act against proliferation," said a US State Department official.</blockquote><p>This event highlights the ongoing tensions in international security and the measures taken by the US to curb potential threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/united-states-will-continue-to-act-against-proliferation-us-slaps-sanctions-on-pakistan-over-ballistic-missile-programme/articleshow/116449626.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/united-states-will-continue-to-act-against-proliferation-us-slaps-sanctions-on-pakistan-over-ballistic-missile-programme/articleshow/116449626.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 20:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World Bank approves $2 billion for Ukraine including funds from new U.S. loan fund - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>World Bank Approves $2 Billion Funding Package for Ukraine</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 19, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/mhke9n/article69002111.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2024-12-18T192404Z_114643804_RC2WD0AV17DE_RTRMADP_3_UKRAINE-CRISIS-WORLDBANK.JPG" alt="World Bank approves $2.05 billion in funding for Ukraine, including $1 billion grant from new U.S. loan fund." title="World Bank approves $2.05 billion in funding for Ukraine, including $1 billion grant from new U.S. loan fund."><figcaption>World Bank approves $2.05 billion in funding for Ukraine, including $1 billion grant from new U.S. loan fund. File. | Photo Credit: Reuters</figcaption><p>The World Bank has approved a substantial funding package to support Ukraine's economic stability, which includes a historic grant from a new U.S. loan fund.</p><ul><li>The approved funding totals $2.05 billion, which includes a $1 billion grant from a new $20 billion U.S. loan fund.</li><li>The funding aims to enhance Ukraine's financial and economic stability amid ongoing challenges from war.</li><li>U.S. Treasury provided these funds as part of the G7 economic support plan to Ukraine.</li><li>The funds are intended for budget support and policy reforms to facilitate sustainable growth.</li><li>Key reforms include enhancing competition in various sectors and strengthening domestic revenue generation.</li></ul><blockquote>“The World Bank Group and our international partners will continue to support the Ukrainian people in realizing their EU aspirations.” - Bob Saum, World Bank's Eastern Europe country director</blockquote><p>This funding package represents a significant step in Ukraine's ongoing efforts to stabilize its economy and pursue its ambitions of EU membership.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/world-bank-approves-dollar-2-billion-for-ukraine-including-funds-from-new-us-loan-fund/article69002101.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/world-bank-approves-dollar-2-billion-for-ukraine-including-funds-from-new-us-loan-fund/article69002101.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 20:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>