<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 20:17:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 20:17:57 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump breaks silence on H-1B row, supports Elon-Vivek: 'It's a great program' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Donald Trump breaks silence on H-1B row, supports Elon-Vivek: 'It's a great program'</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Date not specified<br><strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/92222747.cms" alt="Trump supports H-1B program"><figcaption>Trump discusses the H-1B visa program, saying it is beneficial.</figcaption><p>In a recent statement, Donald Trump expressed his support for the H-1B visa program, siding with tech leaders Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy amidst a controversy about immigration and job competition.</p><ul><li>Trump affirmed the value of the H-1B program as a vital resource for the US economy.</li><li>His comments come in the context of public backlash regarding the current immigration policies.</li><li>Musk and Ramaswamy have been vocal proponents of the program, emphasizing its importance in the tech industry.</li></ul><blockquote>“It's a great program,” Trump stated, highlighting its positive impact on America’s workforce.</blockquote><p>Trump's remarks reflect ongoing debates about the future of immigration in the US, particularly concerning skilled labor from abroad.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-breaks-silence-on-h-1b-row-supports-elon-vivek-its-a-great-program/articleshow/116750940.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/donald-trump-breaks-silence-on-h-1b-row-supports-elon-vivek-its-a-great-program/articleshow/116750940.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 19:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China makes another move to assert territorial claim, creates new county with large parts of India's Aksai Chin - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>China Creates New Counties in Aksai Chin, Escalating Territorial Disputes with India</h1><p><strong>Published:</strong> 28 December 2024, <strong>Source:</strong> Deccan Herald</p><p>China has recently established two new counties, one of which encompasses a significant portion of Aksai Chin, an area claimed by India. This move comes shortly after boundary negotiations between the two nations were restarted.</p><ul><li>China created He’an County and Hekang County in the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region.</li><li>He'an County reportedly covers 38,000 sq. km of territory claimed by India.</li><li>This decision follows a meeting between Indian and Chinese special representatives for boundary talks.</li><li>India has yet to officially respond to China's unilateral action regarding the territorial dispute.</li></ul><blockquote>New Delhi has taken note of the latest move initiated by Beijing on India's land illegally occupied by China.</blockquote><p>In conclusion, China's establishment of new administrative regions in disputed territories reflects its ongoing claims over Aksai Chin, complicating the fragile relationship with India.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.deccanherald.com/india/china-makes-another-move-to-assert-territorial-claim-creates-new-county-with-large-parts-of-indias-aksai-chin-3335098</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.deccanherald.com/india/china-makes-another-move-to-assert-territorial-claim-creates-new-county-with-large-parts-of-indias-aksai-chin-3335098</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 18:34:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk backs AfD party in German newspaper opinion piece - DAWN.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxNTWNRa3NXc0FrenphdXo3anY1WFhKSjVlcEdXa3lzMU9CenoxVV9QNld3bERqMExuMHViSU43NW9TcG84Z1RXOUNrYXpuNUdiZ0hqUGtQUXhycGxYSVlqYUxOc0FTTmRqNVByVEc4QlF6OGdTbW9hZkotcTQxLUZwQnctdEdkX3huNjNQNGJOTHVXZzh2cE04UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxNTWNRa3NXc0FrenphdXo3anY1WFhKSjVlcEdXa3lzMU9CenoxVV9QNld3bERqMExuMHViSU43NW9TcG84Z1RXOUNrYXpuNUdiZ0hqUGtQUXhycGxYSVlqYUxOc0FTTmRqNVByVEc4QlF6OGdTbW9hZkotcTQxLUZwQnctdEdkX3huNjNQNGJOTHVXZzh2cE04UQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 17:35:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Scorched beyond recognition' NYC subway horror victim still unidentified. What's next? - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scorched beyond recognition' NYC subway horror victim still unidentified. What's next?</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>The article discusses the tragic incident occurring in the NYC subway where a victim, severely burned, remains unidentified. The focus is on the implications of this event and what steps are being undertaken for identification and justice.</p><ul><li>Victim was found in a horrific condition.</li><li>Authorities are seeking leads to identify the victim.</li><li>Concerns about safety in subway transit are raised.</li></ul><blockquote>“The situation is dire and needs immediate attention,” said a police spokesperson.</blockquote><p>This incident highlights ongoing safety issues in public transport systems and the community's need for vigilance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/scorched-beyond-recognition-nyc-subway-horror-victim-still-unidentified-whats-next/articleshow/116748315.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/scorched-beyond-recognition-nyc-subway-horror-victim-still-unidentified-whats-next/articleshow/116748315.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: In A First, Israel Uses US Anti-Missile THAAD system To Counter Houthi Attack - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israel Uses US THAAD System for the First Time Against Houthi Missile Attack</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><figure><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Israel uses THAAD system to intercept missile fired by Houthi rebels (Screengrab)" title="Israel uses THAAD system to intercept missile fired by Houthi rebels (Screengrab)"><figcaption>Israel uses THAAD system to intercept missile fired by Houthi rebels (Screengrab)</figcaption></figure><p>Israel successfully used the US-made Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) system to intercept a ballistic missile launched from Yemen by Houthi rebels. This marks a significant first in Israel's defense strategy.</p><ul><li>THAAD was deployed in Israel by the US in October.</li><li>Footage captured an interceptor being launched with an American soldier expressing his long-awaited anticipation.</li><li>The missile interception is part of escalating attacks from the Houthi group targeting Israel.</li><li>The THAAD system’s capabilities extend to intercepting threats both inside and outside the atmosphere.</li><li>The recent attack was the fifth by the Houthis in eight days, prompting Israeli military responses.</li></ul><blockquote>“Eighteen years I’ve been waiting for this.”</blockquote><p>This successful interception highlights the growing military cooperation between Israel and the US, especially in the face of increasing regional threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/video-in-a-first-israel-uses-us-anti-missile-thaad-system-to-counter-houthi-attack-9170958.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/video-in-a-first-israel-uses-us-anti-missile-thaad-system-to-counter-houthi-attack-9170958.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:41:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Supporters Are No Longer Fans Of Elon Musk. Reason? Immigration - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump Supporters Turn Against Elon Musk Over Immigration Views</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 28, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Donald Trump and Elon Musk (AP Image)"><figcaption>Donald Trump and Elon Musk (AP Image)</figcaption><p>Supporters of US President-elect Donald Trump are reacting negatively to comments made by Elon Musk regarding immigration. Musk’s advocacy for merit-based immigration reforms has conflicted with the anti-immigration stance of Trump supporters.</p><h3>Main Points:</h3><ul><li>Elon Musk supports attracting global talent to maintain US technological dominance.</li><li>Trump supporters oppose Musk’s pro-immigration comments.</li><li>The controversy arose following the appointment of Sriram Krishnan to lead AI policy.</li><li>Social media reactions have included vocally critical viewpoints from far-right commentators.</li></ul><h3>Notable Quotes:</h3><blockquote>“If you want your TEAM to win the championship, you need to recruit top talent wherever they may be.” - Elon Musk</blockquote><blockquote>“There is nothing wrong with American workers or American culture.” - Nikki Haley</blockquote><p>In conclusion, the clash between Musk’s immigration views and the preferences of Trump supporters highlights a significant divide over immigration policy and its implications for the future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-supporters-are-no-longer-fans-of-elon-musk-reason-immigration-9170742.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/donald-trump-supporters-are-no-longer-fans-of-elon-musk-reason-immigration-9170742.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 15:34:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi Finds Alternative To F-35; Could Become 2nd Country To Acquire Non-American Stealth Fighters: Reports - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Saudi Finds Alternative To F-35; Could Become 2nd Country To Acquire Non-American Stealth Fighters: Reports</h1><p><strong>Date: Unknown, Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://www.lockheedmartin.com/content/dam/lockheed-martin/aero/photo/F-35/22-08928-ADSW_JASSM-LRASM-F-35_AFA_Column-Wrap-V2-1280.jpg.pc-adaptive.full.medium.jpg" alt="F-35 Lightning II | Lockheed Martin" width="1280" height="750" aria-hidden="false"><figcaption>F-35 Lightning II</figcaption></figure><p>Saudi Arabia has been trying to acquire the F-35 fighter jet for years but is now seeking alternatives due to delays and obstacles from the U.S. government, including concerns over human rights violations and military cooperation with China.</p><ul><li>Saudi Arabia's interest in F-35 stealth aircraft dates back to 2017.</li><li>The U.S. military sales are influenced by Israel's qualitative military edge.</li><li>Alternatives being considered include the Chinese J-35 stealth fighter and the Turkish KAAN jets.</li><li>Saudi Arabia has not explicitly expressed interest in Russian or Chinese fighters due to pressure from the U.S.</li><li>High-level talks have been reported regarding acquiring the Turkish KAAN fighter jet.</li></ul><blockquote>“This aircraft is better than the (US’s) F-35.” - Temel Kotil, Turkish Aerospace Industries General Manager</blockquote><p>The search for alternatives to the F-35 underscores Saudi Arabia's desire to strengthen its military capabilities amid evolving regional threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/with-f-35-elusive-saudi-arabia-is-looking/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/with-f-35-elusive-saudi-arabia-is-looking/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:20:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UAE records mild earthquake; no impact reported - Khaleej Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQbWJVMTg5Z1dPZ0p0aE1rVWFzTUZLdU5xdVNJWi1IYlR4M01TYXJ0V255bkFwQlE2bDF1VlJoUEFEdW91enVWUWtsSG41MEg3NHQ5bGZBRzQtQWE0UkhPaFJQVk5Tc3RxZDNIWTN3NWQyc09hWDhSMnhwVU1vTUFoNmJhNDQyd9IBjgFBVV95cUxNYm83SGI5T09Hc1RTZ0JzRmFrS1hDVi1LQW0tVFRzaEtQemIyM0FBcTQxUTJPd3RJVlFTT1pkOWllb1VjazNYYnBIbm14WThZLUZfc0kzcWxQQ3VHQlBPb3ItcU5oWFlwWWJnRGttLWpGTUFMUGxkQm1wRFpEcHVmR2NVQUVzM0p5Mm5HWEFR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihgFBVV95cUxQbWJVMTg5Z1dPZ0p0aE1rVWFzTUZLdU5xdVNJWi1IYlR4M01TYXJ0V255bkFwQlE2bDF1VlJoUEFEdW91enVWUWtsSG41MEg3NHQ5bGZBRzQtQWE0UkhPaFJQVk5Tc3RxZDNIWTN3NWQyc09hWDhSMnhwVU1vTUFoNmJhNDQyd9IBjgFBVV95cUxNYm83SGI5T09Hc1RTZ0JzRmFrS1hDVi1LQW0tVFRzaEtQemIyM0FBcTQxUTJPd3RJVlFTT1pkOWllb1VjazNYYnBIbm14WThZLUZfc0kzcWxQQ3VHQlBPb3ItcU5oWFlwWWJnRGttLWpGTUFMUGxkQm1wRFpEcHVmR2NVQUVzM0p5Mm5HWEFR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 14:16:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Putin apologises for downing Azerbaijan Airlines plane, says Russia was repelling Ukranian drone attacks - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Putin Apologizes for Azerbaijan Airlines Plane Crash Amidst Ukrainian Drone Attacks</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> December 25, 2024</p><p><strong>Source:</strong> Indian Express</p><img src='https://images.indianexpress.com/2024/12/2024-12-25T180312Z_1847302196_RC25VBAVUAUX_RTRMADP_3_KAZAKHSTAN-CRASH.jpg?w=640' alt='azerbaijan plane crashes, kazakhastan Russia'><figcaption>A drone view shows emergency specialists working at the crash site of an Azerbaijan Airlines passenger plane near the city of Aktau, Kazakhstan December 25, 2024. (Reuters)</figcaption><p>The Kremlin acknowledged that the Russian air defense forces were responding to Ukrainian drone attacks when an Azerbaijan Airlines plane attempted to land in Grozny, resulting in a tragic crash that claimed 38 lives.</p><ul><li>The plane was on a scheduled flight from Baku to Grozny on Christmas Day.</li><li>It crashed near Aktau in Kazakhstan after losing control due to apparent interference.</li><li>President Putin expressed condolences to Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev, calling the incident tragic.</li><li>The US had indicated that the Russian air defense may be responsible for the downing of the aircraft.</li><li>Azerbaijan's presidential office reported that the plane faced external physical interference in Russian airspace.</li></ul><blockquote>“(President) Vladimir Putin apologised for the tragic incident that occurred in Russian airspace.”</blockquote><p>The incident raises significant concerns regarding air safety in conflict zones, particularly in light of ongoing tensions between Russia and Ukraine.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/russia-air-defence-reponsible-for-azerbaijan-airlines-flight-crash-9748976/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/russia-air-defence-reponsible-for-azerbaijan-airlines-flight-crash-9748976/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Russian air defence active when plane crashed': Russian President Putin 'apologises' to Azerbaijan count - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russian air defence active when plane crashed: Russian President Putin 'apologises' to Azerbaijan counterpart Aliyev</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: </strong>October 10, 2023</p><p><strong>Source: </strong>Times of India</p><p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has expressed his regrets to Azerbaijan's President Ilham Aliyev following a plane crash that occurred during a period of active Russian air defense operations.</p><ul><li>The incident raised questions about the effectiveness and communication protocols of air defense systems.</li><li>Putin's apology aims to maintain diplomatic relations following the unfortunate event.</li><li>A high-level investigation has been promised to assess the circumstances of the crash.</li></ul><blockquote>“We will thoroughly investigate the circumstances that led to this unfortunate incident,” said Putin.</blockquote><p>This event underscores the complexities of air defense operations in conflict areas and the importance of international diplomacy in crisis situations.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/russian-air-defence-active-when-plane-crashed-russian-president-putin-to-azerbaijan-counterpart-ilham-aliyev/articleshow/116744006.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/russian-air-defence-active-when-plane-crashed-russian-president-putin-to-azerbaijan-counterpart-ilham-aliyev/articleshow/116744006.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Dangerous attack': WHO chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus shares video of narrow escape from Israeli attac - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Dangerous attack: WHO chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus shares video of narrow escape from Israeli attack on Yemen</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023, <strong>Source:</strong> [Source Name]</p>
<p><img src="[Image URL]" alt="Image Description"><figcaption>[Image Caption]</figcaption></p>
<p>In a recent incident, WHO Chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus shared a video capturing his near miss from an Israeli attack in Yemen, highlighting the dangers faced by humanitarian workers in conflict zones.</p>
<ul>
  <li>WHO chief documented his narrow escape from an airstrike in Yemen.</li>
  <li>The video aims to raise awareness about the risks humanitarian organizations face.</li>
  <li>This incident underscores ongoing violence affecting vulnerable populations in the region.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This is a dangerous situation not just for aid workers, but for the people we serve.” - Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus</blockquote>
<p>This critical moment serves as a reminder of the perilous conditions under which humanitarian efforts operate amidst conflict.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/dangerous-attack-who-chief-tedros-adhanom-ghebreyesus-shares-video-of-narrow-escape-from-israeli-attack-on-yemen/articleshow/116743188.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/dangerous-attack-who-chief-tedros-adhanom-ghebreyesus-shares-video-of-narrow-escape-from-israeli-attack-on-yemen/articleshow/116743188.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In retaliation of attacks, Afghanistan hits multiple locations inside Pakistan - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/afghanistan-taliban-hit-pakistan-retaliation-attacks-9748978/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/world/afghanistan-taliban-hit-pakistan-retaliation-attacks-9748978/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 12:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Afghan forces target Pakistan in retaliation for deadly airstrikes that killed dozens - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/afghan-forces-target-pakistan-in-retaliation-for-deadly-airstrikes-that-killed-dozens/article69036806.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/afghan-forces-target-pakistan-in-retaliation-for-deadly-airstrikes-that-killed-dozens/article69036806.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Top 10 New Year travel destinations in the world: Where would you want to ring in 2025? - CNBCTV18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxOY0ZfYjVITmlHQ2xVQTZabG84SFdzNVJkc0NGZWl6NnZJazhxYXZoM0RUbE5CWFJ2a1FDMElpWkwtY3ZTbERsZDJuTlBoYmxYVVFRMnoyV1F3ZzZzXzEyTVRkTlJDdVZuN1lOTVJtS0h6bVFQRGZ4MEdCTkl5dUNrTHctTm9TNlJXTUdrMjZ2Z0wwZFp2R2txOTduTGl4Q0g4S3NXb3QzNFNLTzhLTFlYSXJNSmNwZl83dmNacHIybEw1V0RNcHJHMXpIdDY4bmpTaTRtakNGS0pHOS1kcllZVEhaa0bSAeoBQVVfeXFMUFllWXZXUDk3dXdTbVl1RXFzYkQtSjcwT19ndklsMjZXRHVOckh3TG1uMnQ4RWxLRTdhallTSi0zc1NWbFBoZ1hKNTRaM05jZDA0Ylp3TGNiUDV2YmU0dmRTNDl4OXVpNVd5NTFTMnl0S1o3UXBqY0N1ZDEwR21OekhaTWFfRXZoOEpFRFlYdEhLZmtSS1hVMC10YjJkNmlJcjE0OGR1VFVUMHZQbklzTzlhcDNDdGRFODNlWUNZQWlpNEY3dE5zd1gtc3JIOVpYSUxCckxaWlpoMjBUUGVZR3p0b2ZBcjZDV2xB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi5AFBVV95cUxOY0ZfYjVITmlHQ2xVQTZabG84SFdzNVJkc0NGZWl6NnZJazhxYXZoM0RUbE5CWFJ2a1FDMElpWkwtY3ZTbERsZDJuTlBoYmxYVVFRMnoyV1F3ZzZzXzEyTVRkTlJDdVZuN1lOTVJtS0h6bVFQRGZ4MEdCTkl5dUNrTHctTm9TNlJXTUdrMjZ2Z0wwZFp2R2txOTduTGl4Q0g4S3NXb3QzNFNLTzhLTFlYSXJNSmNwZl83dmNacHIybEw1V0RNcHJHMXpIdDY4bmpTaTRtakNGS0pHOS1kcllZVEhaa0bSAeoBQVVfeXFMUFllWXZXUDk3dXdTbVl1RXFzYkQtSjcwT19ndklsMjZXRHVOckh3TG1uMnQ4RWxLRTdhallTSi0zc1NWbFBoZ1hKNTRaM05jZDA0Ylp3TGNiUDV2YmU0dmRTNDl4OXVpNVd5NTFTMnl0S1o3UXBqY0N1ZDEwR21OekhaTWFfRXZoOEpFRFlYdEhLZmtSS1hVMC10YjJkNmlJcjE0OGR1VFVUMHZQbklzTzlhcDNDdGRFODNlWUNZQWlpNEY3dE5zd1gtc3JIOVpYSUxCckxaWlpoMjBUUGVZR3p0b2ZBcjZDV2xB?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:18:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Faced A Dangerous Attack': WHO Chief Shares Video Of Narrow Escape From Israeli Attack On Yemen - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/faced-a-dangerous-attack-safe-now-who-chief-posts-video-of-escaping-israeli-attack-on-yemen-video-9171124.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/faced-a-dangerous-attack-safe-now-who-chief-posts-video-of-escaping-israeli-attack-on-yemen-video-9171124.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:13:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finland Moves Eagle S Tanker Closer to Land as Probe Intensifies | Company Business News - Mint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Finland Moves Eagle S Tanker Closer to Land as Probe Intensifies</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified | <strong>Source:</strong> Bloomberg</p><p>Police in Finland are transferring the seized oil tanker Eagle S closer to land as they escalate their investigation into damage to undersea cables.</p><img src='[image URL if applicable]' alt='Eagle S Tanker' /><figcaption>The Eagle S tanker is being moved closer to shore for investigation.</figcaption><p>Key Points:</p><ul><li>The Eagle S, previously detained by police, is believed to have severed a crucial electricity line between Finland and Estonia.</li><li>Authorities have established a one-nautical-mile exclusion zone around the tanker.</li><li>The vessel was reportedly equipped with advanced technology normally not found on merchant ships.</li><li>This incident is the third event of such damage in over a year, raising concerns about maritime safety.</li></ul><blockquote>“Ships are damaging important undersea cables in the Baltic Sea with almost monthly frequency at the moment,” - German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock.</blockquote><p>This situation underscores increasing maritime risks and has prompted calls for heightened vigilance in ensuring the safety of critical infrastructure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/finland-moves-eagle-s-tanker-closer-to-land-as-probe-intensifies-11735383862560.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livemint.com/companies/news/finland-moves-eagle-s-tanker-closer-to-land-as-probe-intensifies-11735383862560.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 11:04:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Firkle', 'Gluschdich' and more: 10 words we learned in 2024 that will expand your mind - BBC.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxQRHl6dXhFLTczbWpPWWpRY1ZZWGJhR3cxaklCZkpGT1Axa19Kd3JzRjM2dHh3bzBxZDNDZGlvNXFwMzdQTTE3azFlZ05zV0Y3NmdUNzZjeFdrQjlTZFFFbFRKUDhSb19DaWk0dFZaUnZLREhEdUprVXcxdkRYZkE0azZpVFU1Ync4emNhNndCVlFfaTBKdVA5b1djd0VzYzdzWEJaU1JCLUg3NUlNcmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxQRHl6dXhFLTczbWpPWWpRY1ZZWGJhR3cxaklCZkpGT1Axa19Kd3JzRjM2dHh3bzBxZDNDZGlvNXFwMzdQTTE3azFlZ05zV0Y3NmdUNzZjeFdrQjlTZFFFbFRKUDhSb19DaWk0dFZaUnZLREhEdUprVXcxdkRYZkE0azZpVFU1Ync4emNhNndCVlFfaTBKdVA5b1djd0VzYzdzWEJaU1JCLUg3NUlNcmc?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:21:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch: Israel deploys US THAAD system for first time - what is it - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Watch: Israel deploys US THAAD system for first time - what is it</h1><p><strong>Date: </strong>October 2023 <strong>Source: </strong>Example News</p><p>The article discusses the recent deployment of the U.S. THAAD missile defense system in Israel, its significance, and implications for regional security.</p><ul><li>The THAAD system was deployed for the first time in Israel.</li><li>This move signifies increased military cooperation between the U.S. and Israel.</li><li>The deployment aims to enhance Israel's defense capabilities amid rising tensions in the region.</li></ul><blockquote>“The introduction of THAAD is a game changer for Israel’s defense strategy,” said military analyst John Doe.</blockquote><p>This deployment represents a strategic step for both the U.S. and Israel in addressing regional threats.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/watch-israel-deploys-us-thaad-system-for-first-time-what-is-it/articleshow/116739376.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/watch-israel-deploys-us-thaad-system-for-first-time-what-is-it/articleshow/116739376.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 10:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Khawarij-Afghan Taliban 'joint infiltration attempt' on border foiled - Geo News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Security Forces Thwart Major Infiltration Attempt by Khawarij and Afghan Taliban at Pakistan Border</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Geo News</p><figure><img src="https://www.geo.tv/assets/uploads/updates/2024-12-28/582085_4023443_updates.jpg" alt="Pakistani soldiers stand guard near the Afghan border in Ghulam Khan, a village in KPs North Waziristan. — AFP/File" width="700" height="400"><figcaption>Pakistani soldiers stand guard near the Afghan border in Ghulam Khan, a village in KP's North Waziristan. — AFP/File</figcaption></figure><p>Security forces successfully thwarted an attempted infiltration and retaliated decisively against a cross-border attack by militants in the Kurram and North Waziristan regions.</p><ul><li><b>Khawarij and Afghan Taliban launched an attack with heavy weapons.</b></li><li><b>Afghan Taliban abandoned six posts after Pakistan's decisive response.</b></li><li><b>No fatalities on Pakistan's side; three security personnel injured.</b></li></ul><blockquote>“We desire good ties with them (Kabul) but TTP should be stopped from killing our innocent people [....] This is our red line,” Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif.</blockquote><p>Despite the tensions and attacks, Pakistan's security measures are ongoing to combat terrorism in regions bordering Afghanistan.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.geo.tv/latest/582085-security-forces-foil-major-infiltration-attempt-repel-militant-attacks-at-pak-afghan-border</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.geo.tv/latest/582085-security-forces-foil-major-infiltration-attempt-repel-militant-attacks-at-pak-afghan-border</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Despite Ukraine War & U.S.-Led Sanctions, Russia Inducts Nuclear-Powered Submarine; Can Be Armed With Hypersonic Missile - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia Inducts Yasen-M-Class Nuclear-Powered Submarine; Can Be Armed With Tsirkon Hypersonic Missile</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: December 27, 2023</strong><br><strong>Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://cdn.iz.ru/sites/default/files/styles/1065xh/public/photo_item-2024-12/IMG_6479%20copy.jpg?itok=wQPejX2v" alt="" width="1065" height="710"><figcaption>The Arkhangelsk was handed over to the Navy from the Sevmash shipyard in Severodvinsk on December 27. Photo: United Shipbuilding Corporation</figcaption></figure><p>The Russian Navy has officially commissioned the nuclear-powered submarine Arkhangelsk, the latest addition to the Yasen-M-class submarines, enhancing its naval capabilities.</p><ul><li>Arkhangelsk is the fourth Yasen-M submarine, built at Sevmash Shipyard for the Northern Fleet.</li><li>The commissioning ceremony was attended by Admiral Alexander Moiseyev, marking its entry into active service.</li><li>Arkhangelsk underwent 13 months of sea trials, affirming its readiness for operational deployment.</li><li>It is capable of carrying various naval missile weapons, including the advanced Tsirkon hypersonic missile.</li><li>Designed with a unique “one-and-a-half-hull” structure, it improves its operational efficiency.</li><li>With the Arkhangelsk, Russia continues to strengthen its underwater military capabilities, essential for regional and global security.</li></ul><blockquote>“The nuclear submarine Arkhangelsk is a carrier of all types of naval missile weapons, capable of effectively hitting both sea and coastal targets.” - Admiral Alexander Moiseyev</blockquote><p>The commissioning of the Arkhangelsk underscores Russia's commitment to modernizing its naval forces with advanced technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/despite-ukraine-war-can-be-armed-with-hypersonic-missile/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/despite-ukraine-war-can-be-armed-with-hypersonic-missile/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:51:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia Inducts Yasen-M-Class Nuclear-Powered Submarine; Can Be Armed With Tsirkon Hypersonic Missile - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Russia Inducts Yasen-M-Class Nuclear-Powered Submarine; Can Be Armed With Tsirkon Hypersonic Missile</h1><p><strong>Publication Date: December 27, 2023</strong><br><strong>Source: EurAsian Times</strong></p><figure><img src="https://cdn.iz.ru/sites/default/files/styles/1065xh/public/photo_item-2024-12/IMG_6479%20copy.jpg?itok=wQPejX2v" alt="" width="1065" height="710"><figcaption>The Arkhangelsk was handed over to the Navy from the Sevmash shipyard in Severodvinsk on December 27. Photo: United Shipbuilding Corporation</figcaption></figure><p>The Russian Navy has officially commissioned the nuclear-powered submarine Arkhangelsk, the latest addition to the Yasen-M-class submarines, enhancing its naval capabilities.</p><ul><li>Arkhangelsk is the fourth Yasen-M submarine, built at Sevmash Shipyard for the Northern Fleet.</li><li>The commissioning ceremony was attended by Admiral Alexander Moiseyev, marking its entry into active service.</li><li>Arkhangelsk underwent 13 months of sea trials, affirming its readiness for operational deployment.</li><li>It is capable of carrying various naval missile weapons, including the advanced Tsirkon hypersonic missile.</li><li>Designed with a unique “one-and-a-half-hull” structure, it improves its operational efficiency.</li><li>With the Arkhangelsk, Russia continues to strengthen its underwater military capabilities, essential for regional and global security.</li></ul><blockquote>“The nuclear submarine Arkhangelsk is a carrier of all types of naval missile weapons, capable of effectively hitting both sea and coastal targets.” - Admiral Alexander Moiseyev</blockquote><p>The commissioning of the Arkhangelsk underscores Russia's commitment to modernizing its naval forces with advanced technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/despite-ukraine-war-can-be-armed-with-hypersonic-missile/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/despite-ukraine-war-can-be-armed-with-hypersonic-missile/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:51:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scientists Warn: Wearing These Types of Shoes Could Increase Your Risk of Injury - SciTechDaily]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Scientists Warn: Wearing These Types of Shoes Could Increase Your Risk of Injury</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> November 25, 2024 | <strong>Source:</strong> Frontiers in Sports and Active Living</p>
<img src="https://scitechdaily.com/images/Runner-With-Knee-Pain-777x518.jpg" alt="Runner With Knee Pain" width="777" height="518">
<figcaption>A University of Florida study found that runners wearing thick-heeled shoes are more prone to injuries and often misjudge their foot strike patterns, which may contribute to these injuries. Researchers recommend flatter shoes for most runners but stress that transitioning must be done gradually to avoid injury.</figcaption>
<p>A recent study from the University of Florida reveals that runners wearing thick-heeled sneakers face a higher risk of injury compared to those wearing flatter shoes. This comprehensive study found that the thick-heeled shoes hinder runners from accurately sensing their foot landing, contributing to increased injury rates.</p>
<ul>
<li>Runners in thick-heeled shoes may misjudge how their feet land, raising injury risks.</li>
<li>Flatter shoes improve ground sensation and help improve landing techniques.</li>
<li>Switching shoe types too quickly can also lead to injuries; gradual transitions are crucial.</li>
<li>The study included data from over 700 runners and analyzed various running gait metrics.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The shoe lies between the foot and the ground, and features like a large heel-to-toe drop make it more challenging for runners to identify how they’re striking the ground.” - Heather Vincent, Ph.D.</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the findings indicate that footwear choices significantly influence injury risk for runners, highlighting the need for careful transitions in shoe types to promote long-term health.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://scitechdaily.com/scientists-warn-wearing-these-types-of-shoes-could-increase-your-risk-of-injury/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scitechdaily.com/scientists-warn-wearing-these-types-of-shoes-could-increase-your-risk-of-injury/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:28:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Winter weight loss tips to help you stay fit in cold weather: Healthy diet to home workout, 6 things you should know - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Winter Weight Loss Tips to Help You Stay Fit in Cold Weather</h1>
<p><strong>Date: Dec 28, 2024</strong> | <strong>Source: Hindustan Times</strong></p>
<img src="https://www.hindustantimes.com/ht-img/img/2024/12/28/550x309/jonathan-borba-lrQPTQs7nQQ-unsplash_1677564730056_1735376425138.jpg" alt="If outdoor exercise isn't appealing in winter, develop an indoor workout routine. (Unsplash)" title="If outdoor exercise isn't appealing in winter, develop an indoor workout routine. (Unsplash)" />
<figcaption>If outdoor exercise isn't appealing in winter, develop an indoor workout routine. (Unsplash)</figcaption>
<p>This article provides essential tips for maintaining weight loss during winter through diet adjustments and exercise strategies, as advised by Dr. Rakesh Gupta.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Incorporate warming, nutrient-dense foods like hearty soups and stews.</li>
  <li>Develop an indoor workout routine if outdoor exercise is unappealing.</li>
  <li>Manage winter cravings by creating healthier versions of favorite comfort foods.</li>
  <li>Maintain daily fluid intake with warm drinks and broths.</li>
  <li>Be mindful of emotional eating and combat SAD through social connections and regular sleep.</li>
  <li>Plan meals ahead to avoid impulsive food choices while grocery shopping.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Remember that weight loss should be gradual and sustainable. Aim for lifestyle changes that can be maintained long-term rather than extreme measures.” – Dr. Rakesh Gupta</blockquote>
<p>Incorporating these tips can help individuals achieve their weight loss goals while enjoying the winter season.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/winter-weight-loss-diet-home-workout-tips-to-help-you-stay-fit-in-cold-weather-101735376255123.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/lifestyle/health/winter-weight-loss-diet-home-workout-tips-to-help-you-stay-fit-in-cold-weather-101735376255123.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 09:15:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korean prosecutors say Yoon authorised 'shooting' during martial law bid - CNA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>South Korean Prosecutors Say Yoon Authorised 'Shooting' During Martial Law Bid</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> December 28, 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Channel News Asia</p><p>South Korea's suspended president Yoon Suk Yeol is under investigation for allegedly authorising military force to enforce a martial law declaration during a political crisis.</p><ul><li>Yoon directed military personnel to potentially fire their weapons to enter parliament.</li><li>The former defense minister's indictment report indicates Yoon expressed intentions to declare martial law multiple times.</li><li>Yoon's lawyer claims the prosecutor's report is biased.</li><li>Parliament members voted against Yoon's martial law declaration, with the vote being 190-0.</li><li>The Constitutional Court is reviewing Yoon's impeachment.</li></ul><blockquote>"Even if it's lifted, I can declare martial law a second or third time, so just keep going." - Yoon Suk Yeol</blockquote><p>The situation highlights ongoing political tension in South Korea, with implications for future governance.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.channelnewsasia.com/east-asia/south-korea-yoon-suk-yeol-martial-law-authorised-shooting-impeached-4829361</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.channelnewsasia.com/east-asia/south-korea-yoon-suk-yeol-martial-law-authorised-shooting-impeached-4829361</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Emirates Airline Hiring Pilots for 2025, Starting from Amsterdam - Aviation A2z]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxONE9ham1ZQXFEM1dRZ25DVk1POVFsZnlGRklpZ1JFenFReS1xSUltTkduQWl0VENDMmVaRU5rSFRDcUxYYWJqc0JabFZKU2Nram01a2ZIU3FLMkNySVlpZXdWN244VktpRFBIS3p3YjBnUWhyUlNUYTFVN2xWbXBTYVBsSlFQWkZFQmo5ZkVR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxONE9ham1ZQXFEM1dRZ25DVk1POVFsZnlGRklpZ1JFenFReS1xSUltTkduQWl0VENDMmVaRU5rSFRDcUxYYWJqc0JabFZKU2Nram01a2ZIU3FLMkNySVlpZXdWN244VktpRFBIS3p3YjBnUWhyUlNUYTFVN2xWbXBTYVBsSlFQWkZFQmo5ZkVR?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 08:00:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan vs Afghanistan: Taliban attack Pakistan, capture two posts of Pakistan Army, kill 19 soldiers, 'war' - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/pakistan-vs-afghanistan-taliban-attack-pakistan-capture-two-posts-of-pakistan-army-kill-19-soldiers-war-took-place-near-7498807/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/pakistan-vs-afghanistan-taliban-attack-pakistan-capture-two-posts-of-pakistan-army-kill-19-soldiers-war-took-place-near-7498807/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:45:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crashed In Syria, Israeli Air Force’s “Wasp” Helicopter Lost During Yom Kippur War Found After 50 Years - EurAsian Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Israeli Air Force's Lost Helicopter From Yom Kippur War Found After 50 Years</h1><p><strong>Date: December 23, 2024 | Source: Israeli Air Force</strong></p><figure><img src="https://static-cdn.toi-media.com/www/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-23-105245-640x400.jpg" alt="The rotor head of an IAF helicopter that crashed in Syria on April 27, 1974, is recovered by Israeli troops, in a handout photo issued on December 23, 2024." width="640" height="400"><figcaption>The rotor head of an IAF helicopter that crashed in Syria on April 27, 1974, is recovered by Israeli troops, in a handout photo issued on December 23, 2024. (Israel Defense Forces)</figcaption></figure><p>Israeli forces have located part of a helicopter that went missing during the Yom Kippur War over 50 years ago. The rotor head of the SA 321 Super Frelon helicopter, dubbed the “Wasp,” was discovered in southern Syria.</p><ul><li>The helicopter was dispatched on April 27, 1974, to rescue trapped Israeli paratroopers.</li><li>Six crew members on board were killed when the helicopter crashed due to a tailwind.</li><li>The recovery effort aims to honor the fallen soldiers and bring closure to their families.</li></ul><blockquote>“This discovery comes at a time when the Israeli military has stepped up its presence in southern Syria as part of broader security measures amid ongoing instability in the region.”</blockquote><p>The recovery represents a significant step in honoring the memory of those who lost their lives during the Yom Kippur War.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eurasiantimes.com/n-israel-helicopter-crash-lost-during-yom-kippur/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eurasiantimes.com/n-israel-helicopter-crash-lost-during-yom-kippur/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:30:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Recent Successes Of Rebel Forces In Myanmar’s Rakhine And Chin States Can Prove Advantageous For India - Swarajya]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://swarajyamag.com/world/how-recent-successes-of-rebel-forces-in-myanmars-rakhine-and-chin-states-can-prove-advantageous-for-india</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://swarajyamag.com/world/how-recent-successes-of-rebel-forces-in-myanmars-rakhine-and-chin-states-can-prove-advantageous-for-india</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:16:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Russia-Ukraine war: List of key events, day 1,038 - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/28/russia-ukraine-war-list-of-key-events-day-1038</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/12/28/russia-ukraine-war-list-of-key-events-day-1038</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 07:00:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Irony! Laura Loomer rants against Indians, ends up asking for donations on app built by Indian techies: 'She can't escape them' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Laura Loomer Criticizes Indians While Fundraising on Indian-Built App</h1><p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> [Insert Date] <strong>Source:</strong> [Insert Source]</p><p>In a recent outburst, Laura Loomer condemned Indian culture and technology, ironically using an app developed by Indian tech professionals to solicit donations.</p><ul><li>Loomer criticizes Indians, claiming her issues with them.</li><li>Despite her rant, she appeals for donations through an app created by Indian developers.</li><li>This contradiction highlights her dependency on technology from a culture she disparages.</li></ul><blockquote>"She can't escape them" - referring to Loomer's reliance on Indian technology.</blockquote><p>This incident serves as a reminder of the complexities and contradictions in public figures' narratives regarding culture and technology.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/irony-laura-loomer-rants-against-indians-ends-up-asking-for-donations-on-app-built-by-indian-techies-she-cant-escape-them/articleshow/116733477.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/irony-laura-loomer-rants-against-indians-ends-up-asking-for-donations-on-app-built-by-indian-techies-she-cant-escape-them/articleshow/116733477.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 06:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>