<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[World Feed]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Latest [object Object] articles]]></description>
        <link>https://github.com/iMahir/newrss</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 17:17:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://github.com/iMahir/newrss/data/rss/World.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 17:17:44 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>600000</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Canada’s Trudeau announces decision to resign as Liberal Party leader, spelling end to time in power - The Hindu]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Trudeau Resigns as Leader of the Liberal Party</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Hindu</p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/z6zqci/article69069704.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2025-01-06T161518Z_2084869554_RC2B4CAUT1W0_RTRMADP_3_CANADA-POLITICS.JPG" alt="Canada’s Prime Minister Justin Trudeau speaks to reporters, announcing he intends to step down as Liberal Party leader and Prime Minister." title="Canada’s Prime Minister Justin Trudeau speaks to reporters, announcing he intends to step down as Liberal Party leader and Prime Minister."/><figcaption>Canada’s Prime Minister Justin Trudeau speaks to reporters, announcing he intends to step down as Liberal Party leader and Prime Minister.</figcaption><p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has announced his resignation as leader of the Liberal Party due to rising discontent with his leadership and internal turmoil within his government. He will remain in office until a new leader is chosen.</p><ul><li>Trudeau cited internal battles within the party as a reason for his decision.</li><li>His departure follows the resignation of key figures within his Cabinet, including the finance minister.</li><li>All three main opposition parties plan to initiate a no-confidence vote against the Liberal Party when Parliament resumes.</li><li>Trudeau acknowledged challenges he faced as Prime Minister, particularly regarding rising living costs and immigration issues.</li><li>He recognized the significance of the Liberal Party’s role in Canada’s democratic history and expressed excitement for the leadership transition process.</li></ul><blockquote>“I do this job because the interests of Canadians and the well being of democracy is something that I hold dear.” - Justin Trudeau</blockquote><p>Trudeau's announcement is expected to lead to a leadership race and potentially a spring election. His tenure has been marked by significant economic challenges and political controversies.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/canadas-trudeau-announces-decision-to-resign-as-liberal-party-leader-spelling-end-to-time-in-power/article69069539.ece</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/canadas-trudeau-announces-decision-to-resign-as-liberal-party-leader-spelling-end-to-time-in-power/article69069539.ece</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 16:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German diplomat Thomas Fielder found dead in Pakistan - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/german-diplomat-thomas-fielder-found-dead-in-pakistan/articleshow/116998443.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/pakistan/german-diplomat-thomas-fielder-found-dead-in-pakistan/articleshow/116998443.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-French leader Sarkozy on trial over alleged Gaddafi funds: All to know - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/6/ex-french-leader-sarkozy-on-trial-over-alleged-gaddafi-funds-all-to-know</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/6/ex-french-leader-sarkozy-on-trial-over-alleged-gaddafi-funds-all-to-know</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 14:15:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who Would Replace Trudeau As Liberal Party Leader? Two Indian-Origin Contenders Among 8 In Race - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who Would Replace Trudeau As Liberal Party Leader? Two Indian-Origin Contenders Among 8 In Race</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> January 07, 2025<br><strong>Source:</strong> News</p>
<img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Canadian PM Trudeau is battling a crisis amid soaring unpopularity and growing party dissent. (AP/File)">
<figcaption>Canadian PM Trudeau is battling a crisis amid soaring unpopularity and growing party dissent. (AP/File)</figcaption>
<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau announced his resignation as Liberal Party leader amidst party dissent and declining popularity, leading to a search for his successor.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trudeau's resignation is a response to growing pressure from his party, with 131 out of 153 MPs opposing him.</li>
  <li>Chrystia Freeland, Mark Carney, Dominic LeBlanc, Melanie Joly, and Francois-Philippe Champagne are among the top contenders to succeed Trudeau.</li>
  <li>Two Indian-origin MPs, Anita Anand and George Chahal, are also potential candidates for party leadership.</li>
  <li>The party faces urgent decisions on appointing an interim leader or holding a leadership contest.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Liberals would be in the hands of an interim prime minister not chosen by members, which has never happened in Canada before.”</blockquote>
<p>The Liberal Party's upcoming leadership change may significantly impact Canadian politics, as the party struggles with public support amid economic challenges.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/canada-justin-trudeau-resignation-liberal-party-leader-replacement-chrystia-freeland-indian-origin-mp-9179976.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/canada-justin-trudeau-resignation-liberal-party-leader-replacement-chrystia-freeland-indian-origin-mp-9179976.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:57:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who Could Replace Trudeau As Liberal Party Leader? Two Indian-Origin Contenders Among 8 In Race - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Who Would Replace Trudeau As Liberal Party Leader? Two Indian-Origin Contenders Among 8 In Race</h1><p><strong>Last Updated:</strong> January 07, 2025, 01:48 IST | <strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="Canadian PM Trudeau is battling a crisis amid soaring unpopularity and growing party dissent. (AP/File)" /><figcaption>Canadian PM Trudeau is battling a crisis amid soaring unpopularity and growing party dissent. (AP/File)</figcaption><p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau is likely to announce his resignation as Liberal Party leader following a revolt within his party and plummeting public support as polls predict a Conservative victory.</p><ul><li>Trudeau expected to resign before a national caucus meeting.</li><li>131 of 153 Liberal MPs reportedly want him to step down.</li><li>Contenders to replace Trudeau include Chrystia Freeland, Mark Carney, and Dominic LeBlanc.</li><li>Two Indian-origin MPs, Anita Anand and George Chahal, are in the running for leadership.</li></ul><blockquote>“The Liberal party faces a dire challenge if a leadership contest occurs before the election.”</blockquote><p>If Trudeau resigns, the party may appoint an interim leader or hold a shortened leadership contest.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/world/canada-justin-trudeau-resignation-liberal-party-leader-replacement-chrystia-freeland-indian-origin-mp-9179976.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/world/canada-justin-trudeau-resignation-liberal-party-leader-replacement-chrystia-freeland-indian-origin-mp-9179976.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:57:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk attacks PM Keir Starmer over 'Pakistani rape gangs', UK responds - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/uk-hits-back-at-elon-musk-for-misinformed-rape-gang-accusation-at-pm-starmer-101735983423681.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/uk-hits-back-at-elon-musk-for-misinformed-rape-gang-accusation-at-pm-starmer-101735983423681.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Father Marries Son’s Ex-Girlfriend Months After Convincing Him To Break Up - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Father Marries Son’s Ex-Girlfriend Months After Convincing Him To Break Up</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> January 07, 2025<br/><strong>Source:</strong> News18</p><img src="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2021/07/1627283897_news18_logo-1200x800.jpg?impolicy=website&amp;width=360&amp;height=270" alt="When the son discovered his ex-girlfriend was now his stepmother, he experienced a severe shock that necessitated hospitalisation. (Representative/Shutterstock)"/><figcaption>When the son discovered his ex-girlfriend was now his stepmother, he experienced a severe shock that necessitated hospitalisation. (Representative/Shutterstock)</figcaption><p>In a bizarre twist of familial relationships, Liu Lianghe convinced his son to break up with his girlfriend, only to marry her later.</p><ul><li>Lianghe, former chairman of the Bank of China, faced severe legal issues, including a suspended death sentence for corruption.</li><li>After manipulating his son's breakup, Lianghe pursued the ex-girlfriend and married her six months later.</li><li>The son was hospitalized after learning his ex was now his stepmother.</li><li>Lianghe's marriage and actions were overshadowed by his legal troubles, culminating in a death sentence in 2023.</li></ul><blockquote>“When the son discovered his ex-girlfriend was now his stepmother, he experienced a severe shock that necessitated hospitalization.”</blockquote><p>This situation highlights the turmoil that can arise from complex family dynamics and manipulative relationships.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/viral/father-marries-sons-ex-girlfriend-months-after-convincing-him-to-break-up-ws-ab-9179926.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/viral/father-marries-sons-ex-girlfriend-months-after-convincing-him-to-break-up-ws-ab-9179926.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:44:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Record-breaking winter storm slams US, 60m Americans under weather warnings, 1.3k flights canceled: All y - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Record-breaking winter storm slams US, 60m Americans under weather warnings</h1><p><strong>Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p><p>This article covers the unprecedented winter storm that has impacted over 60 million Americans, leading to significant travel disruptions and severe weather warnings across multiple states.</p><ul><li>The storm has resulted in the cancellation of approximately 1,300 flights.</li><li>Weather warnings are in effect for major parts of the northeastern United States.</li><li>Authorities are advising citizens to stay indoors and avoid unnecessary travel during the storm.</li><li>The storm is predicted to bring heavy snowfall and dangerous conditions in affected areas.</li></ul><blockquote>“We’re urging everyone to take these warnings seriously and stay safe indoors as much as possible,” said a meteorologist.</blockquote><p>The severe weather conditions are expected to continue over the next several days, causing further disruptions and posing risks to public safety.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/record-breaking-winter-storm-slams-us-60m-under-weather-warnings-1-3k-flights-canceled-all-you-need-to-know/articleshow/116997800.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/record-breaking-winter-storm-slams-us-60m-under-weather-warnings-1-3k-flights-canceled-all-you-need-to-know/articleshow/116997800.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Old Practice To Blame Neighbours': India Condemns Pakistan Airstrikes On Afghanistan - News18]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.news18.com/india/india-condemns-pakistan-airstrikes-on-afghanistan-old-practice-to-blame-neighbours-mea-9179410.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.news18.com/india/india-condemns-pakistan-airstrikes-on-afghanistan-old-practice-to-blame-neighbours-mea-9179410.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:29:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starmer responds: the child sex abuse scandal involving British Pakistani men, why Elon Musk is targeting UK PM over it - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/starmer-uk-child-sex-abuse-scandal-elon-musk-9763347/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/starmer-uk-child-sex-abuse-scandal-elon-musk-9763347/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starmer responds: the child sex abuse scandal involving British Pakistani men, why Elon Musk is targeting UK PM over it - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/starmer-uk-child-sex-abuse-scandal-elon-musk-9763347/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/starmer-uk-child-sex-abuse-scandal-elon-musk-9763347/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Child Tax Credit 2025 - Check Eligibility Criteria, Income Limits and How Can You Claim CTC? - BSEB Inter Org]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Child Tax Credit 2025 - Check Eligibility Criteria, Income Limits and How Can You Claim CTC?</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> N/A <strong>Source:</strong> N/A</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://bsebinter.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Child-Tax-Credit-2025-Check-Eligibility-Criteria-Income-Limits-and-How-Can-You-Claim-CTC-1024x683.jpg" alt="Child Tax Credit 2025 - Check Eligibility Criteria, Income Limits and How Can You Claim CTC?">
<figcaption>Child Tax Credit 2025 Overview</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The Child Tax Credit (CTC) for 2025 is experiencing significant changes that require families to act sooner than expected. This government program aims to provide financial assistance to qualifying families while introducing adjusted eligibility criteria along with income limits.</p>
<ul>
<li>The income eligibility limit will remain $400,000 for married couples filing jointly and $200,000 for all other filers.</li>
<li>Families will receive up to $2,000 per child, but the value of the credit may be diminished due to rising living costs.</li>
<li>The CTC is vital for American families, especially in light of increasing expenses for housing, healthcare, and education.</li>
<li>To claim the credit for the 2025 tax year, families need to file their tax returns by April 15, 2026.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The CTC and other government assistance programs play an important role in helping families, particularly those with lower incomes.”</blockquote>
<p>In conclusion, the adjustments to the Child Tax Credit highlight the need for families to prepare ahead and understand the eligibility prerequisites and claiming process to best utilize available financial support.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://bsebinter.org/child-tax-credit-2025-eligibility-how-can-you-claim-ctc/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bsebinter.org/child-tax-credit-2025-eligibility-how-can-you-claim-ctc/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:21:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Taliban threatens military-run businesses amid rising violence - Al Jazeera English]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/6/pakistan-taliban-threatens-military-run-businesses-amid-rising-violence</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/1/6/pakistan-taliban-threatens-military-run-businesses-amid-rising-violence</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk’s one-word take on Dalai Lama’s controversial immigration stance fuels online debate - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Elon Musk’s One-Word Take on Dalai Lama’s Controversial Immigration Stance Fuels Online Debate</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 | <strong>Source:</strong> Times of India</p>
<img src="https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/STABLE_DIFFUSION_OUTCROP/ESD/53fa0ae7-3540-4430-a440-dd4b024123db__UwTT2r0f.jpg" alt="Elon Musk" />
<figcaption>Elon Musk's reaction has sparked widespread discussion.</figcaption>
<p>The article discusses Elon Musk's brief yet impactful reaction to the Dalai Lama's controversial comments on immigration, which has triggered a heated debate on social media platforms.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Musk's response was concise, yet it resonated with many online.</li>
  <li>The Dalai Lama's immigration stance is viewed as divisive by some.</li>
  <li>Social media reactions highlight the polarizing nature of the issue.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“His words have ignited a firestorm of opinions across platforms.”</blockquote>
<p>This incident underscores the significant influence public figures like Musk have in shaping discussions around controversial topics.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musks-one-word-take-on-dalai-lamas-controversial-immigration-stance-fuels-online-debate/articleshow/116997086.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/elon-musks-one-word-take-on-dalai-lamas-controversial-immigration-stance-fuels-online-debate/articleshow/116997086.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thailands Youngest PM Is Ultra-Rich: $400 Million In Luxury Assets, 200 Handbags, 75 Watches, 23 Cars and More - Check Details - Zee News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Thailand's Youngest PM Is Ultra-Rich: $400 Million In Luxury Assets</h1><p><strong>Published on:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> Zee News</p><img src="https://english.cdn.zeenews.com/sites/default/files/2025/01/06/1626843-thai.jpg?im=Resize=(400)" alt="Thailand's Youngest Prime Minister"><figcaption>Paetongtarn Shinawatra, Thailand’s youngest Prime Minister, has declared assets exceeding $400 million.</figcaption><p>Paetongtarn Shinawatra, the youngest Prime Minister of Thailand and daughter of former PM Thaksin Shinawatra, has reported assets exceeding $400 million.</p><ul><li>Declared assets include over 200 luxury handbags worth $2 million.</li><li>She owns 75 luxury watches valued at nearly $5 million.</li><li>Her collection features 23 high-end vehicles, including Bentleys and Rolls-Royces.</li><li>Investments include properties in London and Japan, with over one billion baht in cash.</li><li>Paetongtarn is the fourth member of the Shinawatra family to lead Thailand.</li></ul><blockquote>“At 38, Paetongtarn Shinawatra combines political heritage and forward-thinking leadership.”</blockquote><p>This financial disclosure highlights the wealth of Thailand’s political elite, emphasizing the connection between politics and affluence in the country.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://zeenews.india.com/photos/business/thailands-youngest-pm-is-ultra-rich-400-million-in-luxury-assets-200-handbags-75-watches-23-cars-and-more-check-details-2840278</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zeenews.india.com/photos/business/thailands-youngest-pm-is-ultra-rich-400-million-in-luxury-assets-200-handbags-75-watches-23-cars-and-more-check-details-2840278</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five Indian-origin men charged with murder of Indian man in US; A look into Kuldeep Kumar's death probe - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/five-indian-origin-men-charged-with-murder-of-indian-man-in-us-a-look-into-kuldeep-kumars-death-probe-101736165156343.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.hindustantimes.com/world-news/us-news/five-indian-origin-men-charged-with-murder-of-indian-man-in-us-a-look-into-kuldeep-kumars-death-probe-101736165156343.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:13:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[France President Macron alleges Musk 'intervenes directly in elections, including Germany' - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>France President Macron alleges Musk 'intervenes directly in elections, including Germany'</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not Available <strong>Source:</strong> Not Available</p>
<p>In a recent statement, French President Emmanuel Macron accused Elon Musk of interfering in elections across Europe, particularly highlighting Germany. This assertion raises concerns about the influence of tech billionaires on democratic processes.</p>
<ul>
<li>Macron's comments were made during a press conference.</li>
<li>He emphasized the importance of regulating social media influence in politics.</li>
<li>The allegations suggest a broader issue of foreign interference in democratic elections.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We must ensure our elections remain free from external influence.”</blockquote>
<p>This issue has sparked discussions on the accountability of tech figures in political matters and the need for increased regulations worldwide.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/france-president-macron-alleges-musk-intervenes-directly-in-elections-including-germany/articleshow/116995404.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/europe/france-president-macron-alleges-musk-intervenes-directly-in-elections-including-germany/articleshow/116995404.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 12:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New twist in Hamas and Israel war as Hamas agrees to release 34 Israeli hostages but.... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/new-twist-in-hamas-and-israel-war-as-hamas-agrees-to-release-34-israeli-hostages-but-7518001/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/new-twist-in-hamas-and-israel-war-as-hamas-agrees-to-release-34-israeli-hostages-but-7518001/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:52:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New twist in Hamas and Israel war as Hamas agrees to release 34 Israeli hostages but.... - India.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://www.india.com/news/world/new-twist-in-hamas-and-israel-war-as-hamas-agrees-to-release-34-israeli-hostages-but-7518001/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.india.com/news/world/new-twist-in-hamas-and-israel-war-as-hamas-agrees-to-release-34-israeli-hostages-but-7518001/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:52:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta glasses, trip abroad: How Shamud-Din Jabbar planned New Orleans terror attack - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/meta-glasses-trip-abroad-how-shamud-din-jabbar-planned-new-orleans-terror-attack/articleshow/116994904.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/meta-glasses-trip-abroad-how-shamud-din-jabbar-planned-new-orleans-terror-attack/articleshow/116994904.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pope appoints Sr. Simona Brambilla as Vatican's first female prefect - Vatican News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxONGJZangydXkyQldVMEVMM2N4d1pzNklveEFBZ1lnT1lLcF92aDVSbFNXenhiaXhyM3dfVk83MG9XOXNiN2IzOHdGbjRkS2tDajNsTi1EdjY1ekVFU0tBbVQxYjI2Q3JaM2QyWWhxam55MW8xb1N0a2Y5RG9oc1Z2U01HM25lNmJEUnR1RlZYX3lNUm1NRHc3a01SOU9wdy1WemFlWmNPOEFpYklaUDBCdjRfSTNoQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxONGJZangydXkyQldVMEVMM2N4d1pzNklveEFBZ1lnT1lLcF92aDVSbFNXenhiaXhyM3dfVk83MG9XOXNiN2IzOHdGbjRkS2tDajNsTi1EdjY1ekVFU0tBbVQxYjI2Q3JaM2QyWWhxam55MW8xb1N0a2Y5RG9oc1Z2U01HM25lNmJEUnR1RlZYX3lNUm1NRHc3a01SOU9wdy1WemFlWmNPOEFpYklaUDBCdjRfSTNoQQ?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:29:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New air defense systems installed at Iran’s sensitive sites - Mehr News Agency - English Version]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxNbXlGYXVkUnd1bEVydENmTExMSFdLblRKMDNXUW10ejhzRm1PZHJmY0g2WWFJWElxalVJT0hqWkRCMm8wZXJKb1dqRS1rc0FXYWQzbndEZnF5YjZjUER4c04zTi1SaE9DbU5VUF9qWWdOVEJxTWVZNE5yVUFQLU1MRDBkUkd5ZlpDNWYtRFZ5UGRrSkpqNUYyQ2ZlY9IBS0FVX3lxTE5XSG41N3luMmJlYkRhRTk3aENiZ2xGQTBRWHdtVjJrSTFwRnZHMG9JMzJGcURvaDk2QXE1Ujl3T1FWRFVBYl8xZXVKaw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxNbXlGYXVkUnd1bEVydENmTExMSFdLblRKMDNXUW10ejhzRm1PZHJmY0g2WWFJWElxalVJT0hqWkRCMm8wZXJKb1dqRS1rc0FXYWQzbndEZnF5YjZjUER4c04zTi1SaE9DbU5VUF9qWWdOVEJxTWVZNE5yVUFQLU1MRDBkUkd5ZlpDNWYtRFZ5UGRrSkpqNUYyQ2ZlY9IBS0FVX3lxTE5XSG41N3luMmJlYkRhRTk3aENiZ2xGQTBRWHdtVjJrSTFwRnZHMG9JMzJGcURvaDk2QXE1Ujl3T1FWRFVBYl8xZXVKaw?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump allegedly narrows universal tariff plan to target critical imports - baha news]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxQeEpxN3dmQzRSR3FLYjNCaENPNmZXTnFPMVd0QkJHRDlEVDZkU1BVbmhFTzFuZE1JbVJwbHZReTNJQU9uSGJhYnczQV92OFNjTzNLNTJ2akhyWTN3UUZhREk2bDhMbDBrYlJJZlBRN0lsN3VEQkk4OGRnY2NfUlhFNjJvblg3bFlmMTBLT0YxTE40dzBIdHJqZndHWnZyTzZHMm5qbUEwcVRBaGZ2RXZhSDg0YmpteHMz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuAFBVV95cUxQeEpxN3dmQzRSR3FLYjNCaENPNmZXTnFPMVd0QkJHRDlEVDZkU1BVbmhFTzFuZE1JbVJwbHZReTNJQU9uSGJhYnczQV92OFNjTzNLNTJ2akhyWTN3UUZhREk2bDhMbDBrYlJJZlBRN0lsN3VEQkk4OGRnY2NfUlhFNjJvblg3bFlmMTBLT0YxTE40dzBIdHJqZndHWnZyTzZHMm5qbUEwcVRBaGZ2RXZhSDg0YmpteHMz?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iran 2025: Nuclear crisis awaits Trump - Axios]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Iran's Nuclear Challenge for Trump in 2025</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023 <strong>Source:</strong> Axios</p>
<img src="https://static.axios.com/img/axios-site/axios-placeholder-16x9.png" alt="Photo illustration of Donald Trump on an abstract collage background made up of elements of the Iranian flag, X's, O's, various schematics, maps, and government documents." height="1080" width="1920">
<figcaption>Photo illustration: Aïda Amer/Axios. Photo: Rebecca Noble/Getty Images</figcaption>
<p>As President-elect Trump prepares to take office, he faces a looming crisis with Iran's nuclear program, significantly advanced since his withdrawal from the previous nuclear deal.</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump has a critical decision to make: negotiate with Iran or consider military action.</li>
<li>Iran is described as a de facto 'nuclear threshold state', accelerating its nuclear capabilities.</li>
<li>International diplomats predict a crisis with Iran on the agenda in 2025, necessitating urgent attention.</li>
<li>The 'maximum pressure' campaign against Iran may need reevaluation given Iran's nuclear advancements.</li>
<li>Potential strikes against Iran's nuclear sites are being discussed, underscoring the seriousness of the situation.</li>
<li>Iran is willing to resume negotiations for a new nuclear deal, but significant challenges remain.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“Anything can happen,” Trump told Time. “It’s a very volatile situation.”</blockquote>
<p>The situation with Iran's nuclear capabilities is precarious, and the need for timely diplomatic resolutions is urgent as Trump assumes office.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.axios.com/2025/01/06/trump-iran-nuclear-deal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.axios.com/2025/01/06/trump-iran-nuclear-deal</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:08:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trump’s aides are exploring tariff plans that would be applied to every nation but only cover critical imports - WAPO - Forex Factory]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Trump’s Aides Explore Tariff Plans Targeting Critical Imports</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2025 | <strong>Source:</strong> The Washington Post</p>
<img src="https://assets.faireconomy.media/nfs/npd/2017/07/25/npd_08_19_07.v2.PNG" alt="" />
<figcaption>Trump’s Aides Explore Tariff Plans - WAPO</figcaption>
<p>US President-elect Donald Trump's transition team is reportedly reworking his campaign pledge of universal tariffs, focusing specifically on industries deemed vital to national security.</p>
<ul>
<li>The team is narrowing the tariff focus to key sectors rather than applying it universally to all imports.</li>
<li>Targeted sectors could include defense and other critical industries necessary for national security.</li>
<li>Concerns arise regarding the disruptive effects of a universal tariff on consumer goods prices and supply chains.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The sector-based universal tariff is a little bit easier for everybody to stomach out the gate.”</blockquote>
<p>This proposed approach may mitigate the immediate disruptive impact of tariffs similar to those seen in current debates around international trade.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.forexfactory.com/news/1321228-trumps-aides-are-exploring-tariff-plans-that-would</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forexfactory.com/news/1321228-trumps-aides-are-exploring-tariff-plans-that-would</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 11:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pakistani Grooming Gangs: After Elon Musk's attacks, UK PM Keir Starmer defends record - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Pakistani Grooming Gangs: After Elon Musk's attacks, UK PM Keir Starmer defends record</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> October 2023</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> News Outlet</p>
<p>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer addresses recent criticisms sparked by Elon Musk regarding grooming gangs in the UK, emphasizing his government's stance and actions taken to address the issue.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Elon Musk's comments on social media have reignited discussions about grooming gangs.</li>
  <li>Starmer reaffirms his commitment to tackling issues of safety and justice.</li>
  <li>The Prime Minister highlights recent government initiatives aimed at improving community safety.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“We must remain vigilant and ensure that justice is served.” - Keir Starmer</blockquote>
<p>Starmer's response aims to reassure the public that issues pertaining to grooming gangs are being taken seriously and that the government is actively working to resolve them.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/pakistani-grooming-gangs-after-elon-musks-attacks-uk-pm-keir-starmer-defends-record/articleshow/116993528.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/uk/pakistani-grooming-gangs-after-elon-musks-attacks-uk-pm-keir-starmer-defends-record/articleshow/116993528.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau likely to resign: How the Crown Prince of Woke Politics lost his ground - The Times of India]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Trudeau likely to resign: How the Crown Prince of Woke Politics lost his ground</h1>
<p><strong>Publication Date:</strong> Not specified <strong>Source:</strong> Times Of India</p>
<p>This article discusses the potential resignation of Justin Trudeau and analyzes the factors that have led to his diminishing support.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Analysis of Justin Trudeau's political downfall.</li>
  <li>Factors contributing to the loss of support amongst the electorate.</li>
  <li>Potential implications for the Canadian political landscape.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“This could mark a significant turning point in Canadian politics.”</blockquote>
<p>The article provides insights into how Trudeau's decisions have impacted his popularity, indicating that change may be necessary for future political success.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/trudeau-resign-woke-politics/articleshow/116992494.cms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/rest-of-world/trudeau-resign-woke-politics/articleshow/116992494.cms</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['A true miracle': 7-year-old boy survives 5 days in lion-infested game park in Zimbabwe - Deccan Herald]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQQXdibUxBVDYwRWxiUXpIeXV1cFRiUnowUnlXYkc3OWU3U1M0SDZRUnR4UWxqQ3FJQXQwdm5uY0V3NThHSGFQeEw0TERaNUtWZ0F6OWh0YlZDZ04tNkJ2T0F1OHBNejVPcHZOb2QxblBETEt5SW9TUjdLeEhteWZvblJxMUtZWDVqTlF2Z3Y0eHhDRmtPWjBLbVZIeGl1SDByYV9TUjlSYjVMN1g5dm5ZVHBjYU9nTnFHdzFCLTBqSUtlX3hHRkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMixgFBVV95cUxQQXdibUxBVDYwRWxiUXpIeXV1cFRiUnowUnlXYkc3OWU3U1M0SDZRUnR4UWxqQ3FJQXQwdm5uY0V3NThHSGFQeEw0TERaNUtWZ0F6OWh0YlZDZ04tNkJ2T0F1OHBNejVPcHZOb2QxblBETEt5SW9TUjdLeEhteWZvblJxMUtZWDVqTlF2Z3Y0eHhDRmtPWjBLbVZIeGl1SDByYV9TUjlSYjVMN1g5dm5ZVHBjYU9nTnFHdzFCLTBqSUtlX3hHRkE?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:19:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau to step down as head of Canada’s Liberal Party: What happens now - The Indian Express]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Justin Trudeau Set to Step Down as Liberal Party Leader Amid Political Turmoil</h1>
<p><strong>Date:</strong> January 6, 2024</p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> The Indian Express</p>
<p>Amidst widespread unpopularity, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau will likely step down as head of the Liberal Party. This move comes ahead of an impending parliamentary election and follows the withdrawal of support from the New Democratic Party (NDP).</p>
<ul>
  <li>Trudeau's resignation as party leader is expected but may not lead to his resignation as Prime Minister.</li>
  <li>The Liberal Party is facing pressure following historically low approval ratings.</li>
  <li>The NDP withdrew support, criticizing Trudeau for inadequate opposition to the Conservative Party.</li>
  <li>Trudeau's administration has been marked by rising political divisiveness and a housing crisis.</li>
  <li>If a no-confidence vote occurs, the Liberals may lose their governing power without NDP support.</li>
  <li>Options for Trudeau include electing an interim leader or proroguing parliament.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>“The Prime Minister no longer wanted her to serve as finance minister,” refers to the resignation of Trudeau's deputy, Chrystia Freeland.</blockquote>
<p>The political landscape in Canada is shifting dramatically, with early elections appearing likely in the near future.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/justin-trudeau-resign-party-canada-9762795/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/justin-trudeau-resign-party-canada-9762795/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 10:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Bring them home now': Gal Gadot after Hamas releases 19-year-old hostage's video - Hindustan Times]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[No summary available for this article. Click the link to read more.]]></description>
            <link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPdkVrN2ktN0gwRlllYzhQdGNkRWhtM0d0RWE5ZzFldnd6bXBOQlR5Ui1zd3VoQ1hGUUk3Z1lwN0hhLUJybU83TERpVVJGYkJsbHMwSDZScFJEY3RPalI1U0hVaFBKUzZmZXZ2QW9iQlhXckNqVF9hNTAzVV9ZcWFialB4Rzc5MmdyNDdfd3Z1NTVGemx2RFpyQkFsZnZJUUROeFU1WjZhRFNQVU5lSENpQWROcExkVnZ0V0hrOGoyeWNDTXFDaGlaUGVlVE94OTU1c1ZhZ2M5TdIB3AFBVV95cUxNNWRQa0h2amlXaV9BQTB1TmhELWFrSUx4QXlxOGFzTkdtc0o0dVY3RWUwbW9PNkhYenZkbldPbFdCZHpOZjB3WkVYdlpocjdxRm9VUzdOTWsyQjhGOG9La3h1cGIxY2tyS0xuMi0yS0tCVDdJd0p3QjBhOThxZm9mdkE0WHpobWpSYUNLM1pwcXkyODVVS0llYkNFc0JLRlM5RG1teE1DajBkQWZFNkhiOEw3WmtEalZCMkY1blN5T2lnYm94b0xvUnphYzJaTDdiNGVOYlU3WGl4Qkxf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi1wFBVV95cUxPdkVrN2ktN0gwRlllYzhQdGNkRWhtM0d0RWE5ZzFldnd6bXBOQlR5Ui1zd3VoQ1hGUUk3Z1lwN0hhLUJybU83TERpVVJGYkJsbHMwSDZScFJEY3RPalI1U0hVaFBKUzZmZXZ2QW9iQlhXckNqVF9hNTAzVV9ZcWFialB4Rzc5MmdyNDdfd3Z1NTVGemx2RFpyQkFsZnZJUUROeFU1WjZhRFNQVU5lSENpQWROcExkVnZ0V0hrOGoyeWNDTXFDaGlaUGVlVE94OTU1c1ZhZ2M5TdIB3AFBVV95cUxNNWRQa0h2amlXaV9BQTB1TmhELWFrSUx4QXlxOGFzTkdtc0o0dVY3RWUwbW9PNkhYenZkbldPbFdCZHpOZjB3WkVYdlpocjdxRm9VUzdOTWsyQjhGOG9La3h1cGIxY2tyS0xuMi0yS0tCVDdJd0p3QjBhOThxZm9mdkE0WHpobWpSYUNLM1pwcXkyODVVS0llYkNFc0JLRlM5RG1teE1DajBkQWZFNkhiOEw3WmtEalZCMkY1blN5T2lnYm94b0xvUnphYzJaTDdiNGVOYlU3WGl4Qkxf?oc=5&amp;hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 09:33:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>